<categories>
	<category>
		<label>Arcade</label>
		<thumb>meL2vpM.jpg</thumb>
		<banner>NRrREXI.jpg</banner>
		<fanart>qxeGXby.jpg</fanart>
		<logo>1hpPBHa.png</logo>
		<trailer>hem1azYuko</trailer>
		<plot>The main venue where people play arcade games such as video games, pinball machines, electro-mechanical games, redemption games, merchandisers (such as claw cranes), or coin-operated billiards or air hockey tables. In some countries, some types of arcades are also legally permitted to provide gambling machines such as slot machines or pachinko machines. Games are usually housed in cabinets. The term used for ancestors of these venues in the beginning of 20th century was penny arcades.[CR]Video games were introduced in amusement arcades in the late 1970s and were most popular during the golden age of arcade video games, the early 1980s. Arcades became popular with children and particularly adolescents, which led parents to be concerned that video game playing might cause them to skip school.</plot>
	</category>
	<category>
		<label>PC</label>
		<thumb>nvINSAe.jpg</thumb>
		<banner>VP4IHdW.jpg</banner>
		<fanart>tW41LPD.jpg</fanart>
		<logo>4Hj0KZ0.png</logo>
		<trailer>hem1azYuko</trailer>
		<plot>PC games, also known as computer games or personal computer games, are video games played on a personal computer rather than a dedicated video game console or arcade machine. Their defining characteristics include a more diverse and user determined gaming hardware and software, and a generally greater capacity in input, processing, and video output.[CR]Home computer games became popular following the video game crash of 1983 leading to the era of the bedroom coder. In the 1990s, PC games lost mass-market traction to console games before enjoying a resurgence in the mid-2000s through digital distribution.</plot>
	</category>
	<category>
		<label>8 Bit</label>
		<thumb>K1e1v5U.jpg</thumb>
		<banner>6OVLpqK.jpg</banner>
		<fanart>Y34TTgV.jpg</fanart>
		<logo>8H2FRQM.png</logo>
		<trailer>QaIoW1aL9GE</trailer>
		<plot>In computer architecture, 8-bit integers, memory addresses, or other data units are those that are 8 bits (1 octet) wide.  8-bit is also a generation of microcomputers in which 8-bit microprocessors were the norm.[CR]The first commercial 8-bit processor was the Intel 8008 (1972).  Modernized variants of these 8-bit machines are still one of the most common types of processor in embedded systems.[CR]In the history of computer and video games, the third generation (sometimes referred to as the 8-bit era) began on July 15, 1983, with the Japanese release of both the Family Computer (referred to in Japan in the abbreviated form "Famicom", and later known as the Nintendo Entertainment System, or NES, in the rest of the world) and SG-1000.[CR]This generation marked the end of the North American video game crash, a shift in the dominance of home video games from the United States to Japan, and the transition from block-based graphics to smooth hardware scrolling tile and sprite based graphics, which was a pivotal leap in game design.[CR]The best-selling console of this generation was the NES/Famicom, followed by the Master System and then the Atari 7800. Although the previous generation of consoles had also used 8-bit processors, it was at the end of this generation that home consoles were first labeled by their "bits".</plot>
	</category>
	<category>
		<label>16 Bit</label>
		<thumb>ZApJrXO.jpg</thumb>
		<banner>pY8sRHc.jpg</banner>
		<fanart>zIrDR9U.jpg</fanart>
		<logo>eUoLFKw.png</logo>
		<trailer>RAYXUOFiCHk</trailer>
		<plot>In computer architecture, 16-bit integers, memory addresses, or other data units are those that are 16 bits (2 octets) wide. Also, 16-bit CPU and ALU architectures are those that are based on registers, address buses, or data buses of that size. 16-bit microcomputers are computers in which 16-bit microprocessors were the norm[CR]In the history of computer and video games, the fourth generation (more commonly referred to as the 16-bit era) of games consoles began on October 30, 1987 with the Japanese release of NEC Home Electronics PC Engine (known as the TurboGrafx-16 in North America). Although NEC released the first fourth generation console, and was second to the Super Famicom in Japan, this eras sales were mostly dominated by the rivalry between Nintendo and Segas consoles in North America: the Super Nintendo Entertainment System (the Super Famicom in Japan) and the Sega Genesis (named the Mega Drive in other regions). Nintendo was able to capitalize on its previous success in the third generation and managed to win the largest worldwide market share in the fourth generation as well. Sega was extremely successful in this generation and began a new franchise, Sonic the Hedgehog, to compete with Nintendos Mario series of games..</plot>
	</category>
	<category>
		<label>32 Bit</label>
		<thumb>XHsVwAG.jpg</thumb>
		<banner>aSkz9PW.jpg</banner>
		<fanart>WphM5yl.jpg</fanart>
		<logo>fe0pbP7.png</logo>
		<trailer>KgiMzKb8dD0</trailer>
		<plot>In computer architecture, 32-bit integers, memory addresses, or other data units are those that are 32 bits (4 octets) wide. Also, 32-bit CPU and ALU architectures are those that are based on registers, address buses, or data buses of that size. 32-bit microcomputers are computers in which 32-bit microprocessors are the norm.[CR]The fifth-generation era (also known as the 32-bit era and the 3D era) refers to computer and video games, video game consoles and video game handhelds from approximately 1993 to 2001.[CR]For home consoles, the best-selling console was the PlayStation by a wide margin and then the Sega Saturn.[CR]For handhelds, this era was characterized by significant fragmentation, because the first handheld of the generation, the Genesis Nomad, had a lifespan of just two years, and the Virtual Boy had a lifespan of less than one. Both were discontinued before the other handhelds made their debut. The Neo Geo Pocket was released in 1998, but was dropped by SNK in favor of the fully backwards compatible Neo Geo Pocket Color just a year later. Nintendos Game Boy Color was the winner in handhelds by a large margin.</plot>
	</category>
	<category>
		<label>64 Bit</label>
		<thumb>KDEg1UP.jpg</thumb>
		<banner>meXlyf4.jpg</banner>
		<fanart>CzBZfsn.jpg</fanart>
		<logo>lYn9tLR.png</logo>
		<trailer>KgiMzKb8dD0</trailer>
		<plot>In computer architecture, 64-bit computing is the use of processors that have datapath widths, integer size, and memory address widths of 64 bits (eight octets). Also, 64-bit computer architectures for central processing units (CPUs) and arithmetic logic units (ALUs) are those that are based on processor registers, address buses, or data buses of that size. From the software perspective, 64-bit computing means the use of code with 64-bit virtual memory addresses.[CR]The Atari Jaguar was released in 1993 as the worlds first 64-bit system. However, sales at launch were well below the incumbent fourth generation consoles, and a small games library rooted in a shortage of third party support made it impossible for the Jaguar to catch up, selling below 250,000 units. The systems 64-bit nature was also questioned by many.  The Nintendo 64 was released in 1996. The systems delays and use of the cartridge format while all of its competitors used CDs made it an unpopular platform among third party developers. However, a number of wildly popular 1st party titles allowed the Nintendo 64 to maintain strong sales in the United States, though it still remained a distant second to the PlayStation.</plot>
	</category>
	<category>
		<label>Best of</label>
		<thumb>yGrfHaj.jpg</thumb>
		<banner>TLsTyv5.jpg</banner>
		<fanart>VzPHu9s.png</fanart>
		<logo>0WcYWVF.png</logo>
		<trailer>2F2i6EQsPZY</trailer>
		<plot>Best of lists.  These are the classics that everyone needs to play!</plot>
	</category>
	<category>
		<label>1970s</label>
		<thumb>XE5LWdX.jpg</thumb>
		<banner>JYt7Igk.jpg</banner>
		<fanart>HPefCQE.jpg</fanart>
		<logo>1pdtQ8o.png</logo>
		<trailer>40sZQ1_Sd3A</trailer>
		<plot>Games from the 1970s</plot>
	</category>
	<category>
		<label>1980s</label>
		<thumb>e9nr9DF.jpg</thumb>
		<banner>ZG2N2LW.jpg</banner>
		<fanart>glvcyWY.jpg</fanart>
		<logo>u2PxyeO.png</logo>
		<trailer>20d0DoOFgYM</trailer>
		<plot>Games from the 1980s</plot>
	</category>
	<category>
		<label>1990s</label>
		<thumb>8Q6xuG2.jpg</thumb>
		<banner>MtpbUMM.jpg</banner>
		<fanart>0qMUE7H.jpg</fanart>
		<logo>3NCic8n.png</logo>
		<trailer>eydpxj-FY_k</trailer>
		<plot>Games from the 1990s</plot>
	</category>
	<category>
		<label>2000s</label>
		<thumb>C1cMGxl.jpg</thumb>
		<banner>1z82BLP.jpg</banner>
		<fanart>ZKG9AjT.jpg</fanart>
		<logo>lUej5pP.png</logo>
		<trailer>vxyAdeDzzHI</trailer>
		<plot>Games from the 2000s</plot>
	</category>
	<category>
		<label>Handheld</label>
		<thumb>sdkHreq.jpg</thumb>
		<banner>5oWyLRK.jpg</banner>
		<fanart>riqytRq.jpg</fanart>
		<logo>cdPuR63.png</logo>
		<trailer>meQkxPgpflg</trailer>
		<plot>A handheld game console is a small, portable self-contained video game console with a built-in screen, game controls, and speakers.  Handheld game consoles are smaller than home video game consoles and contain the console, screen, speakers, and controls in one unit, allowing people to carry them and play them at any time or place.[CR]In 1976, Mattel introduced the first handheld electronic game with the release of Auto Race.  Later, several companies—including Coleco and Milton Bradley—made their own single-game, lightweight table-top or handheld electronic game devices.[CR]Nintendo is credited with popularizing the handheld console concept with the release of the Game Boy in 1989 and continues to dominate the handheld console market.</plot>
	</category>
	<category>
		<label>Console</label>
		<thumb>lcuGRmo.jpg</thumb>
		<banner>jc5zMtb.jpg</banner>
		<fanart>HxpWWxa.jpg</fanart>
		<logo>GHYjDh7.png</logo>
		<trailer>DdxH5rRFRbg</trailer>
		<plot>A home video game console, or simply console, is a video game device that is primarily used for home gamers, as opposed to in arcades or some other commercial establishment. Home consoles are one type of video game consoles, in contrast to the handheld game consoles which are smaller and portable, allowing people to carry them and play them at any time or place, along with microconsoles and dedicated consoles.</plot>
	</category>
	<category>
		<label>Amiga</label>
		<thumb>M6F8HiW.jpg</thumb>
		<banner>1FsUVti.jpg</banner>
		<fanart>Sg6P78e.png</fanart>
		<logo>BZYepHA.png</logo>
		<trailer>fg8uKYLa1Aw</trailer>
		<plot>The Amiga is a family of personal computers introduced by Commodore in 1985. The original model was part of a wave of 16 and 32 bit computers that featured 256 KB or more of RAM, mouse-based GUIs, and significantly improved graphics and audio over 8-bit systems. This wave included the Atari ST—released the same year—Apple Macintosh, and later the Apple IIGS. Based on the Motorola 68000 microprocessor, the Amiga differed from its contemporaries through the inclusion of custom hardware to accelerate graphics and sound, including sprites and a blitter, and a pre-emptive multitasking operating system called AmigaOS.</plot>
	</category>
	<category>
		<label>Atari</label>
		<thumb>MfJMrHS.jpg</thumb>
		<banner>Iu0p7z1.jpg</banner>
		<fanart>2usewYW.jpg</fanart>
		<logo>HfMnct9.png</logo>
		<trailer>H2CGmCcERrE</trailer>
		<plot>Atari is a corporate and brand name owned by several entities since its inception in 1972.  The original Atari, Inc., founded in Sunnyvale, California in 1972 by Nolan Bushnell and Ted Dabney, was a pioneer in arcade games, home video game consoles, and home computers. The companys products, such as Pong and the Atari 2600, helped define the electronic entertainment industry from the 1970s to the mid-1980s.[CR]In 1984, the original Atari Inc. was split due to its role in the video game crash of 1983, and the arcade division was turned into Atari Games Inc.  Atari Games received the rights to use the logo and brand name with appended text Games on arcade games, as well as rights to the original 1972–1984 arcade hardware properties.  In 1998, Hasbro Interactive acquired all Atari Corporation related properties, creating a new subsidiary, Atari Interactive.</plot>
	</category>
	<category>
		<label>Bandai</label>
		<thumb>68FnxB7.jpg</thumb>
		<banner>GorPl1C.jpg</banner>
		<fanart>qxD83Jr.jpg</fanart>
		<logo>pquJV3w.png</logo>
		<trailer>YEpnxE5zPos</trailer>
		<plot>Bandai is a Japanese toy maker and a producer of a large number of plastic model kits as well as a former video game company. It was the world's third-largest producer of toys in 2008 after Mattel and Hasbro. Some ex-Bandai group companies produce anime and tokusatsu programs. Its headquarters is located in Taito, Tokyo.[CR]Bandai released a series of handheld game consoles including the WonderSwan, WonderSwan Color and Swan Crystal. The systems were only released in Japan.</plot>
	</category>
	<category>
		<label>Coleco</label>
		<thumb>CZnY1tP.jpg</thumb>
		<banner>OG1fnQM.jpg</banner>
		<fanart>5qiBhyg.jpg</fanart>
		<logo>CcfGnx3.png</logo>
		<trailer>5l0T1f81Rao</trailer>
		<plot>Coleco Industries was an American company founded in 1932 by Maurice Greenberg as The Connecticut Leather Company. It became a highly successful toy company in the 1980s, known for its mass-produced version of Cabbage Patch Kids dolls and its video game consoles, the Coleco Telstar dedicated consoles and ColecoVision. While the company disappeared in 1988 as a result of bankruptcy, the Coleco brand was revived in 2005, and remains active to this day.</plot>
	</category>
	<category>
		<label>Commodore</label>
		<thumb>7oLxpHp.jpg</thumb>
		<banner>Bh7Ny7v.jpg</banner>
		<fanart>eR0R4JM.jpg</fanart>
		<logo>1NDnq4b.png</logo>
		<trailer>D_f3uIzEIxo</trailer>
		<plot>Commodore was an American home computer and electronics manufacturer founded by Jack Tramiel. Commodore International (CI), along with its subsidiary Commodore Business Machines (CBM), participated in the development of the home–personal computer industry in the 1970s and 1980s. The company developed and marketed the worlds best-selling desktop computer, the Commodore 64 (1982), and released its Amiga computer line in July 1985.</plot>
	</category>	
	<category>
		<label>Nintendo</label>
		<thumb>m1hCgnt.png</thumb>
		<banner>qnOKvsz.png</banner>
		<fanart>DMSWPh2.jpg</fanart>
		<logo>9LSgdwk.png</logo>
		<trailer>H2CGmCcERrE</trailer>
		<plot>Nintendo Co, Ltd is a Japanese multinational consumer electronics and video game company headquartered in Kyoto. Nintendo is one of the worlds largest video game companies by market capitalization, creating some of the best-known and top-selling video game franchises, such as Mario, The Legend of Zelda, and Pokemon.[CR]Founded on 23 September 1889 by Fusajiro Yamauchi, it originally produced handmade hanafuda playing cards. By 1963, the company had tried several small niche businesses, such as cab services and love hotels. Abandoning previous ventures in favor of toys in the 1960s, Nintendo then developed into a video game company in the 1970s, ultimately becoming one of the most influential in the industry and Japans third most-valuable company with a market value of over $85 billion.</plot>
	</category>
	<category>
		<label>Magnavox</label>
		<thumb>LWBGx4I.png</thumb>
		<banner>9WhX1zE.png</banner>
		<fanart>68PgE1K.jpg</fanart>
		<logo>PEv2MWt.png</logo>
		<trailer>H2EIsnr_cv4</trailer>
		<plot>Magnavox is an American electronics company founded in the United States. Today it is a subsidiary of electronics corporation Philips. In 1972 Magnavox introduced the Odyssey, the first video game console. In 1974, the Magnavox Company was acquired by Philips.</plot>
	</category>
	<category>
		<label>Mattel</label>
		<thumb>d7hvYCV.jpg</thumb>
		<banner>hXrqwRo.jpg</banner>
		<fanart>m0PMDQp.jpg</fanart>
		<logo>utW0Oan.png</logo>
		<trailer>MAyKNGudXzA</trailer>
		<plot>Mattel is an American multinational toy manufacturing company founded in 1945 with headquarters in El Segundo, California.  Mattel released the home video game console Intellivision in 1979. The name Intellivision is a portmanteau of "intelligent television". Development of the console began in 1977, the same year as the introduction of its main competitor, the Atari 2600.  In 1984 Mattel sold the Intellivision business to a former Mattel Electronics executive and investors that would become INTV Corporation. Games development started in 1978 and continued until 1990 when the Intellivision was discontinued.</plot>
	</category>
	<category>
		<label>Microsoft</label>
		<thumb>GvEBNa9.jpg</thumb>
		<banner>LKtTlLs.jpg</banner>
		<fanart>ykZdRMI.jpg</fanart>
		<logo>wWhdq7D.png</logo>
		<trailer>sforhbLiwLA</trailer>
		<plot>Microsoft Corporation (abbreviated as MS) is an American multinational technology company with headquarters in Redmond, Washington. It develops, manufactures, licenses, supports and sells computer software, consumer electronics, personal computers, and services. Its best known software products are the Microsoft Windows line of operating systems, the Microsoft Office suite, and the Internet Explorer and Edge web browsers. Its flagship hardware products are the Xbox video game consoles and the Microsoft Surface lineup of touchscreen personal computers.[CR]In classic gaming, Microsoft was known for the MSX.  The exact meaning of the "MSX" abbreviation remains a matter of debate. At the time, most people seemed to agree it meant "MicroSoft eXtended", referring to the built-in "Microsoft eXtended BASIC" (MSX-BASIC), specifically adapted by Microsoft for the MSX system.</plot>
	</category>
	<category>
		<label>Neo Geo</label>
		<thumb>3zfe25L.jpg</thumb>
		<banner>dzhGDLm.jpg</banner>
		<fanart>TMP2YTu.jpg</fanart>
		<logo>EOj2JKD.png</logo>
		<trailer>uCT5Q49O_x8</trailer>
		<plot>Neo Geo is a family of video game hardware developed by SNK. On the market from 1990 to 2004, the brand originated with the release of an arcade system, the Neo Geo MVS and its home console counterpart, the Neo Geo AES. Both the arcade system and console were powerful for the time and the AES allows for perfect compatibility of games released for the MVS.  The high price point for both the AES console and its games prevented it from directly competing with its contemporaries, the Sega Genesis, Super NES, and TurboGrafx-16. However, the MVS arcade became very successful in stores in Japan and North America.</plot>
	</category>
	<category>
		<label>NEC</label>
		<thumb>FH9F5NM.jpg</thumb>
		<banner>MrClwR0.jpg</banner>
		<fanart>8vnsy4B.jpg</fanart>
		<logo>zPWFfSr.png</logo>
		<trailer>jJ5drA5Q3cU</trailer>
		<plot>NEC Corporation is a Japanese multinational company, headquartered in Minato, Tokyo, Japan. It has also been the biggest PC vendor in Japan since the 1980s. The company was known as the Nippon Electric Company, before rebranding in 1983 as just NEC.[CR]NEC licensed technology from Hudson Soft, a video game manufacturer, to create a video game console called the PC-Engine (later released in 1989 as the TurboGrafx-16 in the North American market). Its successor, the PC-FX, was released in Japan in 1994. While the PC-Engine achieved a considerable following, it has been said that NEC held a much stronger influence on the video game industry through its role as a leading semiconductor manufacturer than through any of its direct video game products.</plot>
	</category>
	<category>
		<label>Panasonic</label>
		<thumb>wjaOOx1.jpg</thumb>
		<banner>pUDWDiG.jpg</banner>
		<fanart>Ha5SB6m.png</fanart>
		<logo>Sn0gqWr.png</logo>
		<trailer>tkqWvuM41-0</trailer>
		<plot>Panasonic Corporation, formerly known as Matsushita Electric Industrial Co., is a Japanese multinational electronics corporation headquartered in Kadoma, Osaka, Japan.[CR]Panasonic is also known for producing the first model of the 3DO console in 1993, and further renditions of the hardware were released in 1994 by GoldStar (now LG Corp) and in 1995 by Sanyo.[CR]Despite a highly promoted launch (including being named Time magazines 1993 Product of the Year) and a host of cutting-edge technologies, the 3DOs high price and an oversaturated console market prevented the system from achieving success comparable to veteran competitors Sega and Nintendo. As a result, it was discontinued in late 1996, three years after its initial release.</plot>
	</category>
	<category>
		<label>Philips</label>
		<thumb>qDTYYTY.jpg</thumb>
		<banner>uHi2dyq.jpg</banner>
		<fanart>Ggvg9jW.png</fanart>
		<logo>IUvoYAD.png</logo>
		<trailer>9ZIbnZuqUuo</trailer>
		<plot>Philips is a Dutch multinational technology company headquartered in Amsterdam currently focused in the area of healthcare. It was founded in Eindhoven in 1891, by Gerard Philips and his father Frederik. It was once one of the largest electronic conglomerates in the world.[CR]In 1991-1992, Philips along with their subsidiary Magnavox, released the Philips CD-i, a combined CD player and home video game console. It sold one million units and was discontinued in 1998 after being heavily criticized amongst the gaming community.</plot>
	</category>
	<category>
		<label>Sega</label>
		<thumb>Tyyx2SW.jpg</thumb>
		<banner>t8yGCvx.jpg</banner>
		<fanart>5mzkFL7.jpg</fanart>
		<logo>QJ2hpYO.png</logo>
		<trailer>XnJDGKeTjkU</trailer>
		<plot>Sega Games Co., originally short for Service Games and officially styled as SEGA, is a Japanese multinational video game developer and publisher headquartered in Tokyo, Japan, with offices around the world. Sega developed and manufactured numerous home video game consoles from 1983 to 2001, but after financial losses incurred from its Dreamcast console, the company restructured to focus on providing software as a third-party developer. Sega remains the world's most prolific arcade producer, with over 500 games in over 70 franchises on more than 20 different arcade system boards since 1981.[CR]Sega is also known for publishing several multi-million selling game franchises, notably Sonic the Hedgehog, Total War, and Yakuza.[CR]With the introduction of the Sega Genesis in North America in 1989, Sega of America launched an anti-Nintendo campaign to carry the momentum to the new generation of games, with its slogan Genesis does what Nintendont.  When Nintendo launched its Super Nintendo Entertainment System in North America in August 1991, Sega changed its slogan to Welcome to the next level.</plot>
	</category>
	<category>
		<label>Sinclair</label>
		<thumb>jT9C9IB.jpg</thumb>
		<banner>V3h7ERI.jpg</banner>
		<fanart>rYw84u3.jpg</fanart>
		<logo>Gr3fu8O.png</logo>
		<trailer>esAZ4h3liDg</trailer>
		<plot>Sinclair Research Ltd is a British consumer electronics company founded by Clive Sinclair in Cambridge. In 1980, Clive Sinclair entered the home computer market with the ZX80, at that time the cheapest personal computer for sale in the United Kingdom. In 1982 the ZX Spectrum was released, becoming the UK's best selling computer, and competing aggressively against Commodore and Amstrad.</plot>
	</category>
	<category>
		<label>Sony</label>
		<thumb>2efo9bF.jpg</thumb>
		<banner>JBrH8vO.jpg</banner>
		<fanart>ElpKwEj.jpg</fanart>
		<logo>j9aS8iA.png</logo>
		<trailer>wYEz7t3UbB4</trailer>
		<plot>Sony Corporation is a Japanese multinational conglomerate corporation headquartered in Tokyo.  Its diversified business includes consumer and professional electronics, gaming, entertainment and financial services.  The company is one of the leading manufacturers of electronic products for the consumer and professional markets.[CR]Sony Computer Entertainment is best known for producing the popular line of PlayStation consoles. The line grew out of a failed partnership with Nintendo. Originally, Nintendo requested for Sony to develop an addon for its console that would play Compact Discs. In 1991 Sony announced the addon, as well as a dedicated console known as the "Play Station". However, a disagreement over software licensing for the console caused the partnership to fall through. Sony then continued the project independently.</plot>
	</category>	
	<category>
		<label>Port</label>
		<thumb>2aaK9Du.jpg</thumb>
		<banner>JUkjU2j.jpg</banner>
		<fanart>FWb2KjC.jpg</fanart>
		<logo>mfRe4t1.png</logo>
		<trailer>_UAajimt4dE</trailer>
		<plot>Porting is also the term used when a video game designed to run on one platform, be it an arcade, video game console, or personal computer, is converted to run on a different platform. Earlier video game ports were often not true ports, but rather reworked versions of the games. However, many 21st century video games are developed using software (often in C++) that can output code for one or more consoles as well as for a PC without the need for actual porting (instead relying on the common porting of individual component libraries).</plot>
	</category>
	<category>
		<label>Favorites</label>
		<thumb>7ZCxVj4.jpg</thumb>
		<banner>cMi8AWY.jpg</banner>
		<fanart>G5PYNPY.jpg</fanart>
		<logo>CSH9UpX.png</logo>
		<trailer>NUx66ZEDjnQ</trailer>
		<plot>The best of the best.[CR]These are collections of Favorites.</plot>
	</category>
	<category>
		<label>default</label>
		<thumb>fYMsybe.jpg</thumb>
		<banner>pc540fV.jpg</banner>
		<fanart>G5PYNPY.jpg</fanart>
		<logo>nQfTbZq.png</logo>
		<plot></plot>
		<trailer></trailer>
	</category>
</categories>