<categories>
	<category>
		<label>Arcade</label>
		<thumb>66YzGnK.jpg</thumb>
		<banner>rfCYCbf.jpg</banner>
		<fanart>G5PYNPY.jpg</fanart>
		<logo>Auk2SQD.png</logo>
		<trailer>7NXIgj9CUQ8</trailer>
		<plot>An arcade game or coin-op is a coin-operated entertainment machine typically installed in public businesses such as restaurants, bars and amusement arcades. Most arcade games are video games, pinball machines, electro-mechanical games, redemption games or merchandisers.[CR]The classic or golden age of arcade video games was the era when arcade video games entered pop culture and became a dominant cultural force. The exact time period is disputed, but key moments include the release of Space Invaders in 1978 and the vector-based Asteroids in 1979—moments made possible by the increase in power and decrease in cost of computing technology. This led to the rise of both video game arcades and video games in other media, such as songs, cartoons, and movies like 1982s TRON. Other iconic games from this era include Centipede, Defender, Donkey Kong, and Pac-Man.</plot>
	</category>
	<category>
		<label>1st Person</label>
		<thumb>L38sFZu.jpg</thumb>
		<banner>wDyMq9m.jpg</banner>
		<fanart>G5PYNPY.jpg</fanart>
		<logo>T0AbSPu.png</logo>
		<trailer>7NXIgj9CUQ8</trailer>
		<plot>In video games, the first person refers to a graphical perspective rendered from the viewpoint of the players character. In many cases, this may be the viewpoint from the cockpit of a vehicle. Many different genres have made use of first-person perspectives, ranging from adventure games to flight simulators. The most notable genre to make use of this device is the first-person shooter, where the graphical perspective has a heavy impact on gameplay.</plot>
	</category>
		<category>
		<label>2D</label>
		<thumb>s5dVmDD.jpg</thumb>
		<banner>0DQNtfS.jpg</banner>
		<fanart>G5PYNPY.jpg</fanart>
		<logo>H25wTCi.png</logo>
		<trailer>7NXIgj9CUQ8</trailer>
		<plot>2D, or two-dimensional, is the concept of everything being on one plane of existence. A being within a two-dimensional plane can only move along the horizontal X-axis and the vertical Y-axis. The Z-axis, which defines depth, is considered null. A classic example of two dimensional graphics and gameplay is Super Mario Bros, a side-scrolling platformer in which the player is limited to movement left, right, up, and down. The game popularized a school of game design that influenced its genre for generations.</plot>
	</category>
	<category>
		<label>2.5D</label>
		<thumb>U5G2wEv.jpg</thumb>
		<banner>5iyfPzH.jpg</banner>
		<fanart>G5PYNPY.jpg</fanart>
		<logo>rS4CCgj.png</logo>
		<trailer>7NXIgj9CUQ8</trailer>
		<plot>Today the term 2.5D is primarily used to described games that combine both modern 3D polygonal graphics and traditional 2D game-play. For example, a platformer or fighting game that uses 3D models, but with a fixed sideways perspective. However, 2.5D can be used to describe any game that combines both 2D and 3D techniques together.[CR]The term 2.5D has also been used to describe early first-person shooters that use 2D sprites instead of 3D models, such as Doom and Duke Nukem 3D. Usually referring to the actually engine used to make them. Since the 3D perspective was faked due to limitations with the technology of the time.</plot>
	</category>
	<category>
		<label>3D</label>
		<thumb>EJ1Qvju.jpg</thumb>
		<banner>s20LkuL.jpg</banner>
		<fanart>G5PYNPY.jpg</fanart>
		<logo>aFti68p.png</logo>
		<trailer>7NXIgj9CUQ8</trailer>
		<plot>Adding 3D to gaming has been one of the major paradigm shifts since the industrys conception. The addition of a Z plane has changed graphics and in turn the way games are played in every game that uses it. Like most major changes, the first games to highlight it were considered revolutionary and it spread from there.[CR]3D polygon graphics first appeared in arcades and computers during the 1980s, before making its way onto consoles in the 1990s. While 3D polygons had previously been used for arcade games like Winning Run (1988) and Hard Drivin (1989), the first mainstream success for 3D graphics was Segas revolutionary early 90s arcade hits like Virtua Racing (1992), Virtua Fighter (1993), and Daytona USA (1993). Soon after, 3D gained mainstream attention on consoles with the 1994 launch of the Sega Saturn and Sony PlayStation, both of which emphasized 3D as selling points. The next breakthrough came in 1996, when the Nintendo 64 launched with Super Mario 64, which gave gamers a new way to experience Mario and new controls that supported it, made possible by Nintendos revolutionary analog stick controller.</plot>
	</category>
	<category>
		<label>3rd Person</label>
		<thumb>WFP0vAh.jpg</thumb>
		<banner>jCkA0M3.jpg</banner>
		<fanart>G5PYNPY.jpg</fanart>
		<logo>b2adfxY.png</logo>
		<trailer>7NXIgj9CUQ8</trailer>
		<plot>Third-person is a perspective in which the player can visibly see the body of the controlled character. This is seen in most third-person shooters and adventure games. It most commonly refers to a viewpoint behind the player character.[CR]Third-person perspective puts you in direct control of a character that you can actually see in front of you. Third-person, in grammar is referred to as he, she or it. This means that you are not directly the person you are controlling. You do not control his thoughts or what he looks at (the first-person perspective, the you, gives you better control over putting you into someone else's body even if, in a grammar sense, it does not really count as first-person).</plot>
	</category>
	<category>
		<label>Action</label>
		<thumb>hufaBxF.jpg</thumb>
		<banner>YUXExpk.jpg</banner>
		<fanart>G5PYNPY.jpg</fanart>
		<logo>7lVMV5T.png</logo>
		<trailer>7NXIgj9CUQ8</trailer>
		<plot>Action games emphasize physical challenges that require eye-hand coordination and motor skill to overcome. They center around the player, who is in control of most of the action. Most of the earliest video games were considered action games; today, it is still a vast genre covering all games that involve physical challenges.[CR]Action games are classified by many subgenres. Platform games and fighting games are among the best-known subgenres, while shooter games became and continue to be one of the dominant genres in video gaming since the 1990s. Action games usually involve elements of twitch gameplay.</plot>
	</category>
	<category>
		<label>Adventure</label>
		<thumb>YmKGSRA.jpg</thumb>
		<banner>U5CHSSg.jpg</banner>
		<fanart>G5PYNPY.jpg</fanart>
		<logo>bGdUYEA.png</logo>
		<trailer>7NXIgj9CUQ8</trailer>
		<plot>An adventure game is a video game in which the player assumes the role of a protagonist in an interactive story driven by exploration and puzzle-solving.  The genres focus on story allows it to draw heavily from other narrative-based media, literature and film, encompassing a wide variety of literary genres. Many adventure games (text and graphic) are designed for a single player, since this emphasis on story and character makes multi-player design difficult.</plot>
	</category>
	<category>
		<label>Fantasy</label>
		<thumb>m8ZaHH8.jpg</thumb>
		<banner>uegC5ny.jpg</banner>
		<fanart>G5PYNPY.jpg</fanart>
		<logo>bRa5bDH.png</logo>
		<trailer>7NXIgj9CUQ8</trailer>
		<plot>An fantasy game is a video game in which the player assumes the role of a protagonist in an interactive story driven by exploration and puzzle-solving.  The genres focus on story allows it to draw heavily from other narrative-based media, literature and film, encompassing the fantasy literary genre. Many fantasy games (text and graphic) are designed for a single player, since this emphasis on story and character makes multi-player design difficult.</plot>
	</category>	
	<category>
		<label>Ball and Paddle</label>
		<thumb>dO7DvZz.jpg</thumb>
		<banner>OhmVBME.jpg</banner>
		<fanart>G5PYNPY.jpg</fanart>
		<logo>JwtcJd2.png</logo>
		<trailer>7NXIgj9CUQ8</trailer>
		<plot>Ball and Paddle games are variants of one of the earliest arcade video games, Pong. It is typically a table tennis sports style game featuring simple two-dimensional graphics.</plot>
	</category>
	<category>
		<label>Beat Em Up</label>
		<thumb>srZBugA.jpg</thumb>
		<banner>fI14GTp.jpg</banner>
		<fanart>G5PYNPY.jpg</fanart>
		<logo>9PQcaVW.png</logo>
		<trailer>7NXIgj9CUQ8</trailer>
		<plot>Beat em up (also known as brawler) is a video game genre featuring hand-to-hand combat between the protagonist and an improbably large number of opponents. Traditional beat em ups take place in scrolling, two-dimensional (2D) levels, though some later games feature more open three-dimensional (3D) environments with yet larger numbers of enemies. These games are noted for their simple gameplay, a source of both critical acclaim and derision. Two-player cooperative gameplay and multiple player characters are also hallmarks of the genre. Most of these games take place in urban settings and feature crime-fighting and revenge-based plots, though some games may employ historical, science fiction or fantasy themes.</plot>
	</category>
	<category>
		<label>Beat-Em-Up</label>
		<thumb>srZBugA.jpg</thumb>
		<banner>fI14GTp.jpg</banner>
		<fanart>G5PYNPY.jpg</fanart>
		<logo>9PQcaVW.png</logo>
		<trailer>7NXIgj9CUQ8</trailer>
		<plot>Beat em up (also known as brawler) is a video game genre featuring hand-to-hand combat between the protagonist and an improbably large number of opponents. Traditional beat em ups take place in scrolling, two-dimensional (2D) levels, though some later games feature more open three-dimensional (3D) environments with yet larger numbers of enemies. These games are noted for their simple gameplay, a source of both critical acclaim and derision. Two-player cooperative gameplay and multiple player characters are also hallmarks of the genre. Most of these games take place in urban settings and feature crime-fighting and revenge-based plots, though some games may employ historical, science fiction or fantasy themes.</plot>
	</category>	
	<category>
		<label>Biking</label>
		<thumb>c1IHh6O.jpg</thumb>
		<banner>R1wPO9L.jpg</banner>
		<fanart>G5PYNPY.jpg</fanart>
		<logo>t5VJY2q.png</logo>
		<trailer>7NXIgj9CUQ8</trailer>
		<plot>Sub genre of sports games focusing on Biking</plot>
	</category>
	<category>
		<label>Board Games</label>
		<thumb>AP8lJVm.jpg</thumb>
		<banner>9Co2hbd.jpg</banner>
		<fanart>G5PYNPY.jpg</fanart>
		<logo>A3W7ABT.png</logo>
		<trailer>7NXIgj9CUQ8</trailer>
		<plot>A board game is a type of tabletop game that involves counters or pieces moved or placed on a pre-marked surface or board, according to a set of rules. Board or tabletop video games often have board game equivalents.  Some games are based on pure strategy, but many contain an element of chance; and some are purely chance, with no element of skill.</plot>
	</category>
	<category>
		<label>Breakout</label>
		<thumb>jwqddE1.jpg</thumb>
		<banner>2jiyDbe.jpg</banner>
		<fanart>G5PYNPY.jpg</fanart>
		<logo>Qf89f3c.png</logo>
		<trailer>7NXIgj9CUQ8</trailer>
		<plot>Breakout-style games are characterized by the addition of a wall of blocks or similar objects that the player chips away at with the ball as part of the main gameplay.  Since the release of the original Breakout arcade game in 1976, and Super Breakout two years later, there have been many clones and updates for various platforms. The profusion and notability of such games has been enough for them to also be referred to by some as a genre in their own right.</plot>
	</category>
	<category>
		<label>Card Battle</label>
		<thumb>NbSk93C.jpg</thumb>
		<banner>NsdTFUv.jpg</banner>
		<fanart>G5PYNPY.jpg</fanart>
		<logo>Hi6HABc.png</logo>
		<trailer>7NXIgj9CUQ8</trailer>
		<plot>A card battle game, also called a trading card game, is a kind of strategy card game that was created in 1993 and consists of specially designed sets of playing cards. These cards use proprietary artwork or images to embellish the card. Card battle games may depict anything from fantasy or science fiction genres, horror themes, cartoons, or even sports. Game text is also on the card and is used to interact with the other cards in a strategic fashion. Games are commonly played between two players, though multiplayer formats are also common. In video games, the central struggles of the game is typically resolved through drawing and playing cards.</plot>
	</category>
	<category>
		<label>Casino</label>
		<thumb>XJfFEKH.jpg</thumb>
		<banner>PL3YLJF.jpg</banner>
		<fanart>G5PYNPY.jpg</fanart>
		<logo>TWex80R.png</logo>
		<trailer>7NXIgj9CUQ8</trailer>
		<plot>Casino, or gambling simulation, video games mimic the official casino / vegas style games of chance.</plot>
	</category>
	<category>
		<label>Card</label>
		<thumb>XJfFEKH.jpg</thumb>
		<banner>PL3YLJF.jpg</banner>
		<fanart>G5PYNPY.jpg</fanart>
		<logo>TWex80R.png</logo>
		<trailer>7NXIgj9CUQ8</trailer>
		<plot>Card, or gambling simulation, video games mimic the official casino / vegas style games of chance.</plot>
	</category>
	<category>
		<label>Classics</label>
		<thumb>lyzl7uL.jpg</thumb>
		<banner>0Zi90Ox.jpg</banner>
		<fanart>G5PYNPY.jpg</fanart>
		<logo>lL9ruFm.png</logo>
		<trailer>7NXIgj9CUQ8</trailer>
		<plot>The classic or golden age of arcade video games was the era when arcade video games entered pop culture and became a dominant cultural force. The exact time period is disputed, but key moments include the release of Space Invaders in 1978 and the vector-based Asteroids in 1979—moments made possible by the increase in power and decrease in cost of computing technology. This led to the rise of both video game arcades and video games in other media, such as songs, cartoons, and movies like 1982s TRON. Other iconic games from this era include Centipede, Defender, Donkey Kong, and Pac-Man.</plot>
	</category>
	<category>
		<label>Climbing</label>
		<thumb>pO1uc7y.jpg</thumb>
		<banner>ZCO6tum.jpg</banner>
		<fanart>G5PYNPY.jpg</fanart>
		<logo>Cqj29DW.png</logo>
		<trailer>7NXIgj9CUQ8</trailer>
		<plot>A precursor to the platform game genre, climbing games such as Crazy Climber were the first video games revolving around climbing, specifically climbing buildings, before Nintendos 1981 release Donkey Kong.</plot>
	</category>
	<category>
		<label>Compilation</label>
		<thumb>FglGui6.jpg</thumb>
		<banner>D9Vp06K.jpg</banner>
		<fanart>G5PYNPY.jpg</fanart>
		<logo>PJPg6Mz.png</logo>
		<trailer>7NXIgj9CUQ8</trailer>
		<plot>Compilations refer to video games containing more than one previously released computer, arcade, or video game.  This includes video game remakes and multicarts.</plot>
	</category>
	<category>
		<label>Driving</label>
		<thumb>7EdNW1J.jpg</thumb>
		<banner>vVaPHmC.jpg</banner>
		<fanart>G5PYNPY.jpg</fanart>
		<logo>PJPg6Mz.png</logo>
		<trailer>7NXIgj9CUQ8</trailer>
		<plot>The driving video game genre is typically either in the first-person or third-person perspective, in which the player partakes in a racing competition with any type of land, water, air or space vehicles. They may be based on anything from real-world racing leagues to entirely fantastical settings. In general, they can be distributed along a spectrum anywhere between hardcore simulations, and simpler arcade racing games. Racing games may also fall under the category of sports games.</plot>
	</category>
	<category>
		<label>Drop</label>
		<thumb>cbu4a52.jpg</thumb>
		<banner>PimxqK1.jpg</banner>
		<fanart>G5PYNPY.jpg</fanart>
		<logo>tBiE8tC.png</logo>
		<trailer>7NXIgj9CUQ8</trailer>
		<plot>A drop game is the logical extension of Tetris. In drop games, the player usually manipulates a set of pieces which fall into a pit. The aim is to solve a real-time packing problem by forming complete rows, which then disappear and score points. Poor play leads to incomplete rows, caused by inefficient arrangements of tiles.  These rows do not disappear, giving the player progressively less space and less time to play subsequent pieces.  The aim is also often to form complete layers.</plot>
	</category>
	<category>
		<label>Toss</label>
		<thumb>GUEO5Ok.jpg</thumb>
		<banner>I5Y5F2O.jpg</banner>
		<fanart>G5PYNPY.jpg</fanart>
		<logo>S1q7CMc.png</logo>
		<trailer>7NXIgj9CUQ8</trailer>
		<plot>In toss games, the player controls a device which aims and fires balls, bubbles, or other objects on the screen. The color of objects fired is often randomly generated and chosen from the colors curretly on the screen. In many toss games, after every few throws, the playing arena shrinks slightly, giving the player progressively less space and less time to play subsequent throws. The number of shots between each toss is influenced by the number of items remaining.  The objective of the game is to clear the arena with area of play remaining.</plot>
	</category>	
	<category>
		<label>Educational</label>
		<thumb>AyW3kuN.jpg</thumb>
		<banner>f5RX2Zy.jpg</banner>
		<fanart>G5PYNPY.jpg</fanart>
		<logo>tGcAfQF.png</logo>
		<trailer>7NXIgj9CUQ8</trailer>
		<plot>An educational video game is a video game that provides learning or training value to the player. Edutainment describes an intentional merger of video games and educational software into a single product (and could therefore also comprise more serious titles sometimes described under childrens learning software). In the narrower sense used here, the term describes educational software which is primarily about entertainment, but tends to educate as well and sells itself partly under the educational umbrella. Normally software of this kind is not structured towards school curricula and does not involve educational advisors</plot>
	</category>
	<category>
		<label>Fighter</label>
		<thumb>q4tJYeD.jpg</thumb>
		<banner>RNlI82s.jpg</banner>
		<fanart>G5PYNPY.jpg</fanart>
		<logo>FddboGL.png</logo>
		<trailer>7NXIgj9CUQ8</trailer>
		<plot>A fighter game, or vs game, is a video game genre in which the player controls an on-screen character and engages in close combat with an opponent, which can be either an AI or controlled by another player. The fight matches typically consist of several rounds and take place in an arena, while each character has differing abilities but each is relatively viable to choose. Players must master techniques such as blocking, counter-attacking, and chaining attacks together into combos. Starting in the early 1990s, most fighting games allowed the player to execute special attacks by performing specific input combinations. The fighting game genre is related to but distinct from beat em ups, which involve large numbers of enemies against the human player</plot>
	</category>
	<category>
		<label>Fighting</label>
		<thumb>xqSDNw9.jpg</thumb>
		<banner>Uhyisgm.jpg</banner>
		<fanart>G5PYNPY.jpg</fanart>
		<logo>me07Iaj.png</logo>
		<trailer>7NXIgj9CUQ8</trailer>
		<plot>A fighting game, or vs game, is a video game genre in which the player controls an on-screen character and engages in close combat with an opponent, which can be either an AI or controlled by another player. The fight matches typically consist of several rounds and take place in an arena, while each character has differing abilities but each is relatively viable to choose. Players must master techniques such as blocking, counter-attacking, and chaining attacks together into combos. Starting in the early 1990s, most fighting games allowed the player to execute special attacks by performing specific input combinations. The fighting game genre is related to but distinct from beat em ups, which involve large numbers of enemies against the human player.</plot>
	</category>
	<category>
		<label>Field</label>
		<thumb>jjMiAzy.jpg</thumb>
		<banner>dh4c0gz.jpg</banner>
		<fanart>G5PYNPY.jpg</fanart>
		<logo>5sIWcfL.png</logo>
		<trailer>7NXIgj9CUQ8</trailer>
		<plot>Field games are typically shooter games (or simply shooters) where the environment is shown as a top down looking over the field of play.  The most famous of field games is Asteroids.</plot>
	</category>
	<category>
		<label>Walking</label>
		<thumb>LvyIyW0.jpg</thumb>
		<banner>bit7oAd.jpg</banner>
		<fanart>G5PYNPY.jpg</fanart>
		<logo>ryDH3N4.png</logo>
		<trailer>7NXIgj9CUQ8</trailer>
		<plot>Walking games are typically shooter games (or simply shooters) where the environment is shown as a top down looking over the field of play, and the controlled character is walking.  The most famous of walking games is Total Carnage.</plot>
	</category>
	<category>
		<label>Gallery</label>
		<thumb>aZS3Q9S.jpg</thumb>
		<banner>aQJKtjy.jpg</banner>
		<fanart>G5PYNPY.jpg</fanart>
		<logo>hqEyQBy.png</logo>
		<trailer>7NXIgj9CUQ8</trailer>
		<plot>Gallery games are typically shooter games (or simply shooters) where the environment is shown as a shooting gallery, looking forward toward the field of play.  The most famous of field games is Space Invaders.</plot>
	</category>
	<category>
		<label>Side Scroller</label>
		<thumb>oH4Wbri.jpg</thumb>
		<banner>vQuHMPm.jpg</banner>
		<fanart>G5PYNPY.jpg</fanart>
		<logo>F3F2nLB.png</logo>
		<trailer>7NXIgj9CUQ8</trailer>
		<plot>A side-scrolling game, or side-scroller, is a video game in which the gameplay action is viewed from a side-view camera angle, and the onscreen characters can generally only move to the left or right. These games make use of scrolling computer display technology. The move from single-screen or flip-screen graphics to scrolling graphics, during the golden age of video arcade games and during third-generation consoles, would prove to be a pivotal leap in game design.</plot>
	</category>
	<category>
		<label>Side-Scrolling</label>
		<thumb>oH4Wbri.jpg</thumb>
		<banner>vQuHMPm.jpg</banner>
		<fanart>G5PYNPY.jpg</fanart>
		<logo>F3F2nLB.png</logo>
		<trailer>7NXIgj9CUQ8</trailer>
		<plot>A side-scrolling game, or side-scroller, is a video game in which the gameplay action is viewed from a side-view camera angle, and the onscreen characters can generally only move to the left or right. These games make use of scrolling computer display technology. The move from single-screen or flip-screen graphics to scrolling graphics, during the golden age of video arcade games and during third-generation consoles, would prove to be a pivotal leap in game design.</plot>
	</category>	
	<category>
		<label>Scrolling</label>
		<thumb>oH4Wbri.jpg</thumb>
		<banner>vQuHMPm.jpg</banner>
		<fanart>G5PYNPY.jpg</fanart>
		<logo>F3F2nLB.png</logo>
		<trailer>7NXIgj9CUQ8</trailer>
		<plot>A side-scrolling game, or side-scroller, is a video game in which the gameplay action is viewed from a side-view camera angle, and the onscreen characters can generally only move to the left or right. These games make use of scrolling computer display technology. The move from single-screen or flip-screen graphics to scrolling graphics, during the golden age of video arcade games and during third-generation consoles, would prove to be a pivotal leap in game design.</plot>
	</category>	
	<category>
		<label>Vertical</label>
		<thumb>KMDbiRx.jpg</thumb>
		<banner>RnAB62i.jpg</banner>
		<fanart>G5PYNPY.jpg</fanart>
		<logo>vA3hLRS.png</logo>
		<trailer>7NXIgj9CUQ8</trailer>
		<plot>A vertically scrolling video game or vertical scroller is a video game in which the player views the field of play principally from a top-down perspective, while the background scrolls from the top of the screen to the bottom (or, less often, from the bottom to the top) to create the illusion that the player character is moving in the game world.[CR]Continuous vertical scrolling is designed to suggest the appearance of constant forward motion, such as driving. The game sets a pace for play, and the player must react quickly to the changing environment.</plot>
	</category>
	<category>
		<label>Versus</label>
		<thumb>FfONiAh.jpg</thumb>
		<banner>XZCD2px.jpg</banner>
		<fanart>G5PYNPY.jpg</fanart>
		<logo>7RDEShi.png</logo>
		<trailer>7NXIgj9CUQ8</trailer>
		<plot>A VS game, or fighter game, is a video game genre in which the player controls an on-screen character and engages in close combat with an opponent, usually controlled by another player. The VS matches typically consist of several rounds and take place in an arena, while each character has differing abilities but each is relatively viable to choose. Players must master techniques such as blocking, counter-attacking, and chaining attacks together into combos. Starting in the early 1990s, most fighting games allowed the player to execute special attacks by performing specific input combinations. The VS game genre is related to but distinct from beat em ups, which involve large numbers of enemies against the human player.</plot>
	</category>
	<category>
		<label>Versus Co-op</label>
		<thumb>E2jxl3h.jpg</thumb>
		<banner>QKU0Kqx.jpg</banner>
		<fanart>G5PYNPY.jpg</fanart>
		<logo>d1pzikh.png</logo>
		<trailer>7NXIgj9CUQ8</trailer>
		<plot>A VS Co-Op game, or Co-Op fighter game, is a video game genre in which the player and a partner, usually controlled by another player, engages in close combat with one or more opponents.</plot>
	</category>
	<category>
		<label>Fighting 2D</label>
		<thumb>jYupy63.jpg</thumb>
		<banner>2GjIboT.jpg</banner>
		<fanart>G5PYNPY.jpg</fanart>
		<logo>8DgX0af.png</logo>
		<trailer>7NXIgj9CUQ8</trailer>
		<plot>2D fighting games usually display on-screen fighters from a side view, and play largely within a 2D plane of motion.   Games usually confine characters to moving left and right and jumping, although some games such as Fatal Fury: King of Fighters allow players to move between parallel planes of movement.</plot>
	</category>
	<category>
		<label>Fighting 3D</label>
		<thumb>REhrMJO.jpg</thumb>
		<banner>jFGii40.jpg</banner>
		<fanart>G5PYNPY.jpg</fanart>
		<logo>me07Iaj.png</logo>
		<trailer>7NXIgj9CUQ8</trailer>
		<plot>Sega AM2s first attempt in the 3D fighting genre was the 1993 arcade game Burning Rival, but gained renown with the release of Virtua Fighter for the same platform the same year. It was the first fighting game with 3D polygon graphics and a viewpoint that zoomed and rotated with the action. Despite the graphics, players were confined to back and forth motion as seen in other fighting games. With only three buttons, it was easier to learn than Street Fighter and Mortal Kombat, having six and five buttons respectively. By the time the game was released for the Sega Saturn in Japan, the game and system were selling at almost a one-to-one ratio.</plot>
	</category>
	<category>
		<label>Flying</label>
		<thumb>ZKtLW72.jpg</thumb>
		<banner>to8ug2p.jpg</banner>
		<fanart>G5PYNPY.jpg</fanart>
		<logo>MZWXvqI.png</logo>
		<trailer>7NXIgj9CUQ8</trailer>
		<plot>Flying games are a genre in which a character leaves the ground and propels itself in the air. Many things can take flight, be it a plane or a man wearing a jet pack.[CR]Video games let characters fly in ways that are not possible in the real world. Rocket boots are a popular example of this. Characters have rockets strapped to each of their legs and manages to fly around. This would not be possible in the real world as it would be very hard to make both rockets propel in exactly the same direction. Also, it would be impossible to fly anywhere but up.[CR]Finally, when developers lack inspiration as to how to make a character fly, they just make him fly. This can be thanks to magic or super powers like Superman. Sometimes, characters can fly thanks to some kind of wacky object like a hat with wings on it.</plot>
	</category>
	<category>
		<label>Flight Simulator</label>
		<thumb>ZKtLW72.jpg</thumb>
		<banner>to8ug2p.jpg</banner>
		<fanart>G5PYNPY.jpg</fanart>
		<logo>MZWXvqI.png</logo>
		<trailer>7NXIgj9CUQ8</trailer>
		<plot>Flying games are a genre in which a character leaves the ground and propels itself in the air. Many things can take flight, be it a plane or a man wearing a jet pack.[CR]Video games let characters fly in ways that are not possible in the real world. Rocket boots are a popular example of this. Characters have rockets strapped to each of their legs and manages to fly around. This would not be possible in the real world as it would be very hard to make both rockets propel in exactly the same direction. Also, it would be impossible to fly anywhere but up.[CR]Finally, when developers lack inspiration as to how to make a character fly, they just make him fly. This can be thanks to magic or super powers like Superman. Sometimes, characters can fly thanks to some kind of wacky object like a hat with wings on it.</plot>
	</category>
	<category>
		<label>Game Show</label>
		<thumb>sxG6tkQ.jpg</thumb>
		<banner>ukx8XLe.jpg</banner>
		<fanart>G5PYNPY.jpg</fanart>
		<logo>BEta3lB.png</logo>
		<trailer>7NXIgj9CUQ8</trailer>
		<plot>Video games based on television game shows (Jeopardy, Wheel of Fortune, etc)</plot>
	</category>
	<category>
		<label>Gun</label>
		<thumb>9grl7rw.jpg</thumb>
		<banner>uWJbnFx.jpg</banner>
		<fanart>G5PYNPY.jpg</fanart>
		<logo>31d5BsM.png</logo>
		<trailer>7NXIgj9CUQ8</trailer>
		<plot>Light gun shooter, also called light gun game or simply gun game, is a shooter video game genre in which the primary design element is aiming and shooting with a gun-shaped controller. Light gun shooters revolve around the protagonist shooting targets, either antagonists or inanimate objects. Light gun shooters generally feature action or horror themes and some may employ a humorous, parodic treatment of these conventions. These games typically feature on-rails movement, which gives the player control only over aiming.  The protagonists other movements are determined by the game. Games featuring this device are sometimes termed rail shooters, though this term is also applied to games of other genres in which on-rails movement is a feature. Some, particularly later, games give the player greater control over movement and in still others the protagonist does not move at all.</plot>
	</category>
	<category>
		<label>Mahjong</label>
		<thumb>1z2CA0y.jpg</thumb>
		<banner>BUdzm3h.jpg</banner>
		<fanart>G5PYNPY.jpg</fanart>
		<logo>G11n417.png</logo>
		<trailer>7NXIgj9CUQ8</trailer>
		<plot>A Mahjong video game is a video game that is based on the classical Chinese game mahjong. However, many mahjong video games, especially among those released in Western territories, do not depict the actual game of mahjong but rather mahjong solitaire.</plot>
	</category>
	<category>
		<label>Adult</label>
		<thumb>fiGYT6r.jpg</thumb>
		<banner>TTPP07F.jpg</banner>
		<fanart>G5PYNPY.jpg</fanart>
		<logo>pG7CE95.png</logo>
		<trailer>7NXIgj9CUQ8</trailer>
		<plot>Mature or adult games refer to games meant for players older than 18, and often contain explicit languange and nudity.</plot>
	</category>
	<category>
		<label>Mature</label>
		<thumb>fiGYT6r.jpg</thumb>
		<banner>TTPP07F.jpg</banner>
		<fanart>G5PYNPY.jpg</fanart>
		<logo>pG7CE95.png</logo>
		<trailer>7NXIgj9CUQ8</trailer>
		<plot>Mature or adult games refer to games meant for players older than 18, and often contain explicit languange and nudity.</plot>
	</category>
	<category>
		<label>Maze</label>
		<thumb>iWdpGXL.jpg</thumb>
		<banner>aJwrxVN.jpg</banner>
		<fanart>G5PYNPY.jpg</fanart>
		<logo>CTMaZ6d.png</logo>
		<trailer>7NXIgj9CUQ8</trailer>
		<plot>Maze game is a video game genre description first used by journalists during the 1980s to describe any game in which the entire playing field was a maze. Quick player action is required to escape monsters, outrace an opponent, or navigate the maze within a time limit.</plot>
	</category>
	<category>
		<label>Mini-Games</label>
		<thumb>BGK8dW7.jpg</thumb>
		<banner>9reA4eL.jpg</banner>
		<fanart>G5PYNPY.jpg</fanart>
		<logo>IQimgfN.png</logo>
		<trailer>7NXIgj9CUQ8</trailer>
		<plot>A minigame (also spelled mini-game or mini game, sometimes called a subgame or microgame) is a short video game often contained within another video game, and sometimes in application software or on a display of any form of hardware. A minigame contains different gameplay elements than the main game, may be optional, and is often smaller or more simplistic than the game in which it is contained. Minigames are sometimes also offered separately for free to promote the main game.</plot>
	</category>
	<category>
		<label>Miscellaneous</label>
		<thumb>9tRZQ6f.jpg</thumb>
		<banner>pzF2XiO.jpg</banner>
		<fanart>G5PYNPY.jpg</fanart>
		<logo>wOItoBv.png</logo>
		<trailer>7NXIgj9CUQ8</trailer>
		<plot>Miscellaneous game genre refers to a game that does not otherwise fit well into any other specific genre.</plot>
	</category>
	<category>
		<label>Motorcycle</label>
		<thumb>ttwqTJk.jpg</thumb>
		<banner>NS3dBfw.jpg</banner>
		<fanart>G5PYNPY.jpg</fanart>
		<logo>D0ARtVR.png</logo>
		<trailer>7NXIgj9CUQ8</trailer>
		<plot>The motorcycle video game genre is typically either in the first-person or third-person perspective, in which the player partakes in a motorcycle racing competition. They may be based on anything from real-world racing leagues to entirely fantastical settings. In general, they can be distributed along a spectrum anywhere between hardcore simulations, and simpler arcade racing games.</plot>
	</category>
	<category>
		<label>Party</label>
		<thumb>iW3PyDk.jpg</thumb>
		<banner>Nhy2VzO.jpg</banner>
		<fanart>G5PYNPY.jpg</fanart>
		<logo>g9XqiQv.png</logo>
		<trailer>7NXIgj9CUQ8</trailer>
		<plot>Party games are games that are played at social gatherings to facilitate interaction and provide entertainment and recreation. Different games will generate different atmospheres so the party game may merely be intended as an icebreakers, or the sole purpose for or structure of the party. As such, party games aim to include players of various skill levels and player-elimination is rare.  Party games are intended to be played socially, and are designed to be easy for new players to learn.</plot>
	</category>
	<category>
		<label>Pinball</label>
		<thumb>8Gc8ict.jpg</thumb>
		<banner>6j5LPnm.jpg</banner>
		<fanart>G5PYNPY.jpg</fanart>
		<logo>J9PItRo.png</logo>
		<trailer>7NXIgj9CUQ8</trailer>
		<plot>Pinball is a type of arcade game, in which points are scored by a player manipulating one or more balls on a play field inside a cabinet called a pinball table (or pinball machine). The primary objective of the game is to score as many points as possible. Many modern pinball machines include a story line where the player must complete certain objectives in a certain fashion to complete the story, usually earning high scores for different methods of completing the game. Points are earned when the ball strikes different targets on the play field. A drain is situated at the bottom of the play field, partially protected by player-controlled plastic bats called flippers. A game ends after all the balls fall into the drain a certain number of times.</plot>
	</category>
	<category>
		<label>Platform</label>
		<thumb>8fB2AlY.jpg</thumb>
		<banner>HXlxpyv.jpg</banner>
		<fanart>G5PYNPY.jpg</fanart>
		<logo>wYRSKcE.png</logo>
		<trailer>7NXIgj9CUQ8</trailer>
		<plot>Platform games (or platformers) involve players jumping and climbing, while avoiding obstacles and battling enemies to navigate their environment. Settings are often vertically exaggerated with lots of uneven terrain that the player can leap to or fall off of. Characters in platform games are typically able to jump many times their own height and players are offered some control over their movement in midair as well as the height and distance of their jumps.[CR]Donkey Kong was one of the earliest and best-known platformers; the American gaming press classified it using the term climbing game at the time. Super Mario Bros. was one of the best-selling games of all time; more than 40 million copies were sold (excluding Game Boy Advance and Virtual Console sales). Jumping Flash! was the first console platformer to incorporate 3D graphics.</plot>
	</category>
	<category>
		<label>Puzzle</label>
		<thumb>2XTzf25.jpg</thumb>
		<banner>hiur3pP.jpg</banner>
		<fanart>G5PYNPY.jpg</fanart>
		<logo>9p0P24E.png</logo>
		<trailer>7NXIgj9CUQ8</trailer>
		<plot>Puzzle video games make up a unique genre of video games that emphasize puzzle solving. The types of puzzles can test many problem-solving skills including logic, pattern recognition, sequence solving, and word completion. The player may have unlimited time or infinite attempts to solve a puzzle, or there may be a time limit, or simpler puzzles may be made difficult by having to complete them in real time, as in Tetris.[CR]The genre is very broad, but it generally involves some level of abstraction and may make use of colors, shapes, numbers, physics, or complex rules. Unlike many video games, puzzle video games often challenge a player by limiting the number of tries. In puzzle video games, players often try for a high score or to progress to the next level by getting to a certain place or achieving some criteria.</plot>
	</category>
	<category>
		<label>Quiz</label>
		<thumb>PSayMhS.jpg</thumb>
		<banner>YBEq3LW.jpg</banner>
		<fanart>G5PYNPY.jpg</fanart>
		<logo>OdVOos3.png</logo>
		<trailer>7NXIgj9CUQ8</trailer>
		<plot>A quiz game is a form of mind sport, in which the players (as individuals or in teams) attempt to answer questions correctly. It is a game to test your knowledge about a certain subject. In some countries, a quiz is also a brief assessment used in education and similar fields to measure growth in knowledge, abilities, and skills.[CR]Quizzes are usually scored in points and many quizzes are designed to determine a winner from a group of participants - usually the participant with the highest score.</plot>
	</category>
	<category>
		<label>Racing</label>
		<thumb>QDwMnyR.jpg</thumb>
		<banner>2QB45FX.jpg</banner>
		<fanart>G5PYNPY.jpg</fanart>
		<logo>stwObFa.png</logo>
		<trailer>7NXIgj9CUQ8</trailer>
		<plot>The racing video game genre is the genre of video games, either in the first-person or third-person perspective, in which the player partakes in a racing competition with any type of land, water, air or space vehicles. They may be based on anything from real-world racing leagues to entirely fantastical settings. In general, they can be distributed along a spectrum anywhere between hardcore simulations, and simpler arcade racing games.</plot>
	</category>
	<category>
		<label>Rhythm</label>
		<thumb>u5zF0En.jpg</thumb>
		<banner>jYQt8NZ.jpg</banner>
		<fanart>G5PYNPY.jpg</fanart>
		<logo>pJkDOzH.png</logo>
		<trailer>7NXIgj9CUQ8</trailer>
		<plot>Rhythm game or rhythm action is a genre of music-themed action video game that challenges a players sense of rhythm. Games in the genre typically focus on dance or the simulated performance of musical instruments, and require players to press buttons in a sequence dictated on the screen. Doing so causes the games protagonist or avatar to dance or to play their instrument correctly, which increases the players score. Many rhythm games include multiplayer modes in which players compete for the highest score or cooperate as a simulated musical ensemble. While conventional control pads may be used as input devices, rhythm games often feature novel game controllers that emulate musical instruments. Certain dance-based games require the player to physically dance on a mat, with pressure-sensitive pads acting as the input device.</plot>
	</category>
	<category>
		<label>Role-Playing</label>
		<thumb>ZYImPOC.jpg</thumb>
		<banner>87DMcu8.jpg</banner>
		<fanart>G5PYNPY.jpg</fanart>
		<logo>GwmdGb5.png</logo>
		<trailer>7NXIgj9CUQ8</trailer>
		<plot>A role playing video game (commonly referred to as an RPG) is a video game genre where the player controls the actions of a character (or several party members) immersed in some well-defined world. Many role-playing video games have origins in tabletop role-playing games, such as Dungeons and Dragons, and use much of the same terminology, settings and game mechanics. Other major similarities with pen-and-paper games include developed story-telling and narrative elements, player character development, complexity, as well as replayability and immersion. The electronic medium removes the necessity for a gamemaster and increases combat resolution speed. RPGs have evolved from simple text-based console-window games into visually rich 3D experiences.</plot>
	</category>
	<category>
		<label>RPG</label>
		<thumb>ZYImPOC.jpg</thumb>
		<banner>87DMcu8.jpg</banner>
		<fanart>G5PYNPY.jpg</fanart>
		<logo>GwmdGb5.png</logo>
		<trailer>7NXIgj9CUQ8</trailer>
		<plot>A role playing video game (commonly referred to as an RPG) is a video game genre where the player controls the actions of a character (or several party members) immersed in some well-defined world. Many role-playing video games have origins in tabletop role-playing games, such as Dungeons and Dragons, and use much of the same terminology, settings and game mechanics. Other major similarities with pen-and-paper games include developed story-telling and narrative elements, player character development, complexity, as well as replayability and immersion. The electronic medium removes the necessity for a gamemaster and increases combat resolution speed. RPGs have evolved from simple text-based console-window games into visually rich 3D experiences.</plot>
	</category>
	<category>
		<label>Run and Gun</label>
		<thumb>qUBAkaS.jpg</thumb>
		<banner>eJK7Le3.jpg</banner>
		<fanart>G5PYNPY.jpg</fanart>
		<logo>KYBQXFc.png</logo>
		<trailer>7NXIgj9CUQ8</trailer>
		<plot>The run and gun genre was popularized by Konamis classic Contra. Gunstar Heroes and Metal Slug are also among the most popular examples of this style. Side-scrolling run and gun games are an attempt to marry platform games with shoot em ups, characterized by a minimal focus on precise platform jumping and a major emphasis on multi-directional shooting. These games are sometimes called platform shooters. This genre has strong arcade roots, and as such, these games are generally known for being very difficult, and having very linear, one-way game progression.[CR]There are games which feature a heavy degree of shooting but do not fall into this subgenre. Mega Man, Metroid, Vectorman, Jazz Jackrabbit, Earthworm Jim and Turrican are all platformers with a heavy focus on action and shooting, but unlike Contra or Metal Slug, platform jumping elements, as well as exploration and back-tracking, still figure prominently. Run and guns are generally very pure, and while they may have vehicular sequences or other changes in style, they stay focused on shooting throughout.</plot>
	</category>
	<category>
		<label>Shoot Em Up</label>
		<thumb>bJpWQ2l.jpg</thumb>
		<banner>eZVhc0S.jpg</banner>
		<fanart>G5PYNPY.jpg</fanart>
		<logo>Unal3Wz.png</logo>
		<trailer>7NXIgj9CUQ8</trailer>
		<plot>Shoot em ups are a specific subgenre of shooters wherein the player may move up and down and left and right around the screen, typically firing straight forward.  Shoot em ups share common gameplay, but are often categorized by viewpoint. This includes fixed shooters on fixed screens, such as Space Invaders and Galaxian; scrolling shooters that mainly scroll in a single direction, such as Xevious and Darius; top-down shooters (sometimes referred to as twin-stick shooters) where the levels are controlled from an overhead viewpoint, such as Bosconian and Time Pilot; rail shooters where player movement is automatically guided down a fixed forward-scrolling rail, such as Buck Rogers: Planet of Zoom and Space Harrier; and isometric shooters which use an isometric perspective, such as Zaxxon and Viewpoint. This genre also includes run and gun games which emphasize greater maneuvering or even jumping, such as Thexder, Contra and Metal Slug.</plot>
	</category>
	<category>
		<label>Shooter</label>
		<thumb>MuNRDRV.jpg</thumb>
		<banner>fIPnZ2k.jpg</banner>
		<fanart>G5PYNPY.jpg</fanart>
		<logo>RcfzH9e.png</logo>
		<trailer>7NXIgj9CUQ8</trailer>
		<plot>In shooter games (or simply shooters), players use ranged weapons to participate in the action, which takes place at a distance. Most shooters involve violent gameplay; lethal weaponry is used to damage opponents. However, some shooters, such as Splatoon, have non-violent objectives.[CR]Shooters, aside from subgenre classifications, can be further classified by their perspective of play. First-person shooters are played within the protagonists perspective; they often include a heads-up display displaying key information such as the current health of the protagonist. In third-person shooters, the protagonists body can be seen fully, the environment is rendered from a distance. Some shooters incorporate both perspectives.</plot>
	</category>
	<category>
		<label>Rail Shooter</label>
		<thumb>CBj2o0W.jpg</thumb>
		<banner>VgtD9IR.jpg</banner>
		<fanart>G5PYNPY.jpg</fanart>
		<logo>zq6KcJq.png</logo>
		<trailer>7NXIgj9CUQ8</trailer>
		<plot>Rail shooters limit the player to moving around the screen while the game follows a specific route.  These games often feature an into the screen viewpoint, with which the action is seen from behind the player character, and moves into the screen, while the player retains control over dodging.[CR]Examples include Space Harrier (1985), Captain Skyhawk (1990), Star Wars Rebel Assault (1993), Panzer Dragoon (1995), Star Fox 64 (1997), and Sin and Punishment (2000).</plot>
	</category>	
	<category>
		<label>Shooters Horizontal</label>
		<thumb>t3ohJUD.jpg</thumb>
		<banner>apcVBnL.jpg</banner>
		<fanart>G5PYNPY.jpg</fanart>
		<logo>xDsctfC.png</logo>
		<trailer>7NXIgj9CUQ8</trailer>
		<plot>In shooter games (or simply shooters), players use ranged weapons to participate in the action, which takes place at a distance. Most shooters involve violent gameplay; lethal weaponry is used to damage opponents. However, some shooters, such as Splatoon, have non-violent objectives.[CR]Shooters, aside from subgenre classifications, can be further classified by their perspective of play, such as horizonally scrolling, typically from left to right.</plot>
	</category>
	<category>
		<label>Horizontal Shooters</label>
		<thumb>t3ohJUD.jpg</thumb>
		<banner>apcVBnL.jpg</banner>
		<fanart>G5PYNPY.jpg</fanart>
		<logo>xDsctfC.png</logo>
		<trailer>7NXIgj9CUQ8</trailer>
		<plot>In shooter games (or simply shooters), players use ranged weapons to participate in the action, which takes place at a distance. Most shooters involve violent gameplay; lethal weaponry is used to damage opponents. However, some shooters, such as Splatoon, have non-violent objectives.[CR]Shooters, aside from subgenre classifications, can be further classified by their perspective of play, such as horizonally scrolling, typically from left to right.</plot>
	</category>	
	<category>
		<label>Shooters Vertical</label>
		<thumb>NKPMAHq.jpg</thumb>
		<banner>MkINbTv.jpg</banner>
		<fanart>G5PYNPY.jpg</fanart>
		<logo>04wJhXe.png</logo>
		<trailer>7NXIgj9CUQ8</trailer>
		<plot>In shooter games (or simply shooters), players use ranged weapons to participate in the action, which takes place at a distance. Most shooters involve violent gameplay; lethal weaponry is used to damage opponents. However, some shooters, such as Splatoon, have non-violent objectives.[CR]Shooters, aside from subgenre classifications, can be further classified by their perspective of play, such as vertically scrolling, typically from bottom to top.</plot>
	</category>
	<category>
		<label>Vertical Shooters</label>
		<thumb>NKPMAHq.jpg</thumb>
		<banner>MkINbTv.jpg</banner>
		<fanart>G5PYNPY.jpg</fanart>
		<logo>04wJhXe.png</logo>
		<trailer>7NXIgj9CUQ8</trailer>
		<plot>In shooter games (or simply shooters), players use ranged weapons to participate in the action, which takes place at a distance. Most shooters involve violent gameplay; lethal weaponry is used to damage opponents. However, some shooters, such as Splatoon, have non-violent objectives.[CR]Shooters, aside from subgenre classifications, can be further classified by their perspective of play, such as vertically scrolling, typically from bottom to top.</plot>
	</category>
	<category>
		<label>Simulation</label>
		<thumb>Hx1xvCQ.jpg</thumb>
		<banner>Nu0K6S0.jpg</banner>
		<fanart>G5PYNPY.jpg</fanart>
		<logo>1SEUOBf.png</logo>
		<trailer>7NXIgj9CUQ8</trailer>
		<plot>A simulation video game describes a diverse super-category of video games, generally designed to closely simulate real world activities.[CR]A simulation game attempts to copy various activities from real life in the form of a game for various purposes such as training, analysis, or prediction. Usually there are no strictly defined goals in the game, with the player instead allowed to control a character freely.  Well-known examples are war games, business games, and role play simulation.[CR]From three basic types of strategic, planning, and learning exercises: games, simulations, and case studies, a number of hybrids may be considered, including simulation games that are used as case studies.</plot>
	</category>
	<category>
		<label>Sports</label>
		<thumb>wakflWN.jpg</thumb>
		<banner>DqhE8VX.jpg</banner>
		<fanart>G5PYNPY.jpg</fanart>
		<logo>8iAZfXx.png</logo>
		<trailer>7NXIgj9CUQ8</trailer>
		<plot>Some video games simulate the playing of sports. Most sports have been recreated by video games, including team sports, athletics and extreme sports. Some games emphasize playing the sport (such as the Madden NFL series), whilst others emphasize strategy and organization (such as Championship Manager). Some, such as Arch Rivals, satirize the sport for comic effect. This genre has been popular throughout the history of video games, and is competitive, just like real-world sports. A number of game series feature the names and characteristics of real teams and players, and are updated annually to reflect real-world changes.</plot>
	</category>
	<category>
		<label>Baseball</label>
		<thumb>OTqc9oe.jpg</thumb>
		<banner>MVyTOFl.jpg</banner>
		<fanart>G5PYNPY.jpg</fanart>
		<logo>Tj1kQwL.png</logo>
		<trailer>7NXIgj9CUQ8</trailer>
		<plot>Sub genre of sports games focusing on Baseball</plot>
	</category>
	<category>
		<label>Basketball</label>
		<thumb>44G3RW8.jpg</thumb>
		<banner>CZq2f5g.jpg</banner>
		<fanart>G5PYNPY.jpg</fanart>
		<logo>535hCbR.png</logo>
		<trailer>7NXIgj9CUQ8</trailer>
		<plot>Sub genre of sports games focusing on Basketball</plot>
	</category>
	<category>
		<label>Bowling</label>
		<thumb>cfhgiMs.jpg</thumb>
		<banner>v9it0b1.jpg</banner>
		<fanart>G5PYNPY.jpg</fanart>
		<logo>uapVeuc.png</logo>
		<trailer>7NXIgj9CUQ8</trailer>
		<plot>Sub genre of sports games focusing on Bowling</plot>
	</category>
	<category>
		<label>Boxing</label>
		<thumb>lxc4dLs.jpg</thumb>
		<banner>wTMMvZQ.jpg</banner>
		<fanart>G5PYNPY.jpg</fanart>
		<logo>khw7E9T.png</logo>
		<trailer>7NXIgj9CUQ8</trailer>
		<plot>Sub genre of sports games focusing on Boxing</plot>
	</category>
	<category>
		<label>Cricket</label>
		<thumb>s3XR98T.jpg</thumb>
		<banner>0fAUPI8.jpg</banner>
		<fanart>G5PYNPY.jpg</fanart>
		<logo>ylY9Dil.png</logo>
		<trailer>7NXIgj9CUQ8</trailer>
		<plot>Sub genre of sports games focusing on Cricket</plot>
	</category>
	<category>
		<label>Fishing</label>
		<thumb>vV6SYUs.jpg</thumb>
		<banner>Kx6wPtP.jpg</banner>
		<fanart>G5PYNPY.jpg</fanart>
		<logo>rxz7gGn.png</logo>
		<trailer>7NXIgj9CUQ8</trailer>
		<plot>Sub genre of sports games focusing on Fishing</plot>
	</category>
	<category>
		<label>Football</label>
		<thumb>9aEXbYk.jpg</thumb>
		<banner>oqrdWKK.jpg</banner>
		<fanart>G5PYNPY.jpg</fanart>
		<logo>J1H6prH.png</logo>
		<trailer>7NXIgj9CUQ8</trailer>
		<plot>Sub genre of sports games focusing on American Football</plot>
	</category>
	<category>
		<label>Futuristic</label>
		<thumb>BTUb01s.jpg</thumb>
		<banner>0uhrqnv.jpg</banner>
		<fanart>G5PYNPY.jpg</fanart>
		<logo>gb9Iqwu.png</logo>
		<trailer>7NXIgj9CUQ8</trailer>
		<plot></plot>
	</category>
	<category>
		<label>Golf</label>
		<thumb>XSLqhvW.jpg</thumb>
		<banner>Z79IMPU.jpg</banner>
		<fanart>G5PYNPY.jpg</fanart>
		<logo>aUEWmc2.png</logo>
		<trailer>7NXIgj9CUQ8</trailer>
		<plot>Sub genre of sports games focusing on Golf</plot>
	</category>
	<category>
		<label>Handball</label>
		<thumb>CXPCCEr.jpg</thumb>
		<banner>aYsxT46.jpg</banner>
		<fanart>G5PYNPY.jpg</fanart>
		<logo>FszFVu9.png</logo>
		<trailer>7NXIgj9CUQ8</trailer>
		<plot>Sub genre of sports games focusing on Handball</plot>
	</category>
	<category>
		<label>Hockey</label>
		<thumb>WYCUnvy.jpg</thumb>
		<banner>itin33m.jpg</banner>
		<fanart>G5PYNPY.jpg</fanart>
		<logo>6VTsg6Z.png</logo>
		<trailer>7NXIgj9CUQ8</trailer>
		<plot>Sub genre of sports games focusing on Hockey</plot>
	</category>
	<category>
		<label>Horse Racing</label>
		<thumb>eugowCu.jpg</thumb>
		<banner>mVbSlCN.jpg</banner>
		<fanart>G5PYNPY.jpg</fanart>
		<logo>DTXpab5.png</logo>
		<trailer>7NXIgj9CUQ8</trailer>
		<plot>Sub genre of sports games focusing on Horse Racing</plot>
	</category>
	<category>
		<label>Hunting</label>
		<thumb>A7qFssV.jpg</thumb>
		<banner>UwMMKLt.jpg</banner>
		<fanart>G5PYNPY.jpg</fanart>
		<logo>nDLeYGU.png</logo>
		<trailer>7NXIgj9CUQ8</trailer>
		<plot>Sub genre of sports games focusing on Hunting</plot>
	</category>
	<category>
		<label>Olympic</label>
		<thumb>1Rd7XMj.jpg</thumb>
		<banner>dnBWdwT.jpg</banner>
		<fanart>G5PYNPY.jpg</fanart>
		<logo>cAhwpQz.png</logo>
		<trailer>7NXIgj9CUQ8</trailer>
		<plot>Sub genre of sports games focusing on Olympic games</plot>
	</category>
	<category>
		<label>Dart</label>
		<thumb>Km4uBUj.jpg</thumb>
		<banner>7J4sjhJ.jpg</banner>
		<fanart>G5PYNPY.jpg</fanart>
		<logo>pEKZB56.png</logo>
		<trailer>7NXIgj9CUQ8</trailer>
		<plot>Sub genre of sports games focusing on Darts</plot>
	</category>
	<category>
		<label>Pool</label>
		<thumb>Km4uBUj.jpg</thumb>
		<banner>7J4sjhJ.jpg</banner>
		<fanart>G5PYNPY.jpg</fanart>
		<logo>pEKZB56.png</logo>
		<trailer>7NXIgj9CUQ8</trailer>
		<plot>Sub genre of sports games focusing on Pool or Snooker</plot>
	</category>
	<category>
		<label>Pool and Dart</label>
		<thumb>Km4uBUj.jpg</thumb>
		<banner>7J4sjhJ.jpg</banner>
		<fanart>G5PYNPY.jpg</fanart>
		<logo>pEKZB56.png</logo>
		<trailer>7NXIgj9CUQ8</trailer>
		<plot>Sub genre of sports games focusing on Darts, Pool, or Snooker</plot>
	</category>
	<category>
		<label>Rugby</label>
		<thumb>YYmzZlU.jpg</thumb>
		<banner>HQngsD0.jpg</banner>
		<fanart>G5PYNPY.jpg</fanart>
		<logo>8f6Zd2l.png</logo>
		<trailer>7NXIgj9CUQ8</trailer>
		<plot>Sub genre of sports games focusing on Rugby</plot>
	</category>
	<category>
		<label>Skateboarding</label>
		<thumb>0SoEIUX.jpg</thumb>
		<banner>rNZJqul.jpg</banner>
		<fanart>G5PYNPY.jpg</fanart>
		<logo>WuOjrle.png</logo>
		<trailer>7NXIgj9CUQ8</trailer>
		<plot>Sub genre of sports games focusing on Skateboarding</plot>
	</category>
	<category>
		<label>Skating</label>
		<thumb>fzUxGhX.jpg</thumb>
		<banner>uDftIyH.jpg</banner>
		<fanart>G5PYNPY.jpg</fanart>
		<logo>9i131gN.png</logo>
		<trailer>7NXIgj9CUQ8</trailer>
		<plot>Sub genre of sports games focusing on Skating</plot>
	</category>
	<category>
		<label>Skiing</label>
		<thumb>EXK3RsH.jpg</thumb>
		<banner>LBcbntN.jpg</banner>
		<fanart>G5PYNPY.jpg</fanart>
		<logo>DsK0EnT.png</logo>
		<trailer>7NXIgj9CUQ8</trailer>
		<plot>Sub genre of sports games focusing on Skiing</plot>
	</category>
	<category>
		<label>Snowboarding</label>
		<thumb>GgNwDV9.jpg</thumb>
		<banner>kkQMSpw.jpg</banner>
		<fanart>G5PYNPY.jpg</fanart>
		<logo>737s65Z.png</logo>
		<trailer>7NXIgj9CUQ8</trailer>
		<plot>Sub genre of sports games focusing on Snowboarding</plot>
	</category>
	<category>
		<label>Soccer</label>
		<thumb>gpYgL9r.jpg</thumb>
		<banner>8Wo5cGZ.jpg</banner>
		<fanart>G5PYNPY.jpg</fanart>
		<logo>UnMbG4N.png</logo>
		<trailer>7NXIgj9CUQ8</trailer>
		<plot>Sub genre of sports games focusing on Soccer</plot>
	</category>
	<category>
		<label>Surfing</label>
		<thumb>uYb33PF.jpg</thumb>
		<banner>4xGNB2n.jpg</banner>
		<fanart>G5PYNPY.jpg</fanart>
		<logo>hoETqkA.png</logo>
		<trailer>7NXIgj9CUQ8</trailer>
		<plot>Sub genre of sports games focusing on Surfing</plot>
	</category>
	<category>
		<label>Tennis</label>
		<thumb>84exMV2.jpg</thumb>
		<banner>fYS1abc.jpg</banner>
		<fanart>G5PYNPY.jpg</fanart>
		<logo>symMBu0.png</logo>
		<trailer>7NXIgj9CUQ8</trailer>
		<plot>Sub genre of sports games focusing on Tennis</plot>
	</category>
	<category>
		<label>Track and Field</label>
		<thumb>OgYXy9h.jpg</thumb>
		<banner>xxMycrc.jpg</banner>
		<fanart>G5PYNPY.jpg</fanart>
		<logo>7edOz8i.png</logo>
		<trailer>7NXIgj9CUQ8</trailer>
		<plot>Sub genre of sports games focusing on Track and Field</plot>
	</category>
	<category>
		<label>Volleyball</label>
		<thumb>otZlWhU.jpg</thumb>
		<banner>3OCVwUa.jpg</banner>
		<fanart>G5PYNPY.jpg</fanart>
		<logo>tjZzqej.png</logo>
		<trailer>7NXIgj9CUQ8</trailer>
		<plot>Sub genre of sports games focusing on Volleyball</plot>
	</category>
	<category>
		<label>Wakeboarding</label>
		<thumb>Lu9XVdc.jpg</thumb>
		<banner>F2PBBwP.jpg</banner>
		<fanart>G5PYNPY.jpg</fanart>
		<logo>UkB1Wkr.png</logo>
		<trailer>7NXIgj9CUQ8</trailer>
		<plot>Sub genre of sports games focusing on Wakeboarding</plot>
	</category>
	<category>
		<label>Wrestling</label>
		<thumb>WH3nFcw.jpg</thumb>
		<banner>9DEonWA.jpg</banner>
		<fanart>G5PYNPY.jpg</fanart>
		<logo>dY9coxB.png</logo>
		<trailer>7NXIgj9CUQ8</trailer>
		<plot>Sub genre of sports games focusing on Wrestling.  It also includes professional wrestling (often shortened to pro wrestling or simply wrestling) can be described as a performing art which combines athletics with theatrical performance.</plot>
	</category>
	<category>
		<label>Strategy</label>
		<thumb>9N5miVc.jpg</thumb>
		<banner>o2b3Wc5.jpg</banner>
		<fanart>G5PYNPY.jpg</fanart>
		<logo>GHfukAj.png</logo>
		<trailer>7NXIgj9CUQ8</trailer>
		<plot>Strategy video game is a video game that focuses on skillful thinking and planning to achieve victory.  It emphasizes strategic, tactical, and sometimes logistical challenges. Many games also offer economic challenges and exploration. They are generally categorized into four sub-types, depending on whether the game is turn-based or real-time, and whether the game focuses on strategy or tactics.</plot>
	</category>
	<category>
		<label>Tabletop</label>
		<thumb>4je8OaC.jpg</thumb>
		<banner>w8eyBTV.jpg</banner>
		<fanart>G5PYNPY.jpg</fanart>
		<logo>8F3iPbD.png</logo>
		<trailer>7NXIgj9CUQ8</trailer>
		<plot>A tabletop game is typically a type of strategy game where players take turns when playing. This is distinguished from real time strategy, in which all players play simultaneously.  Tabletop video games often have board game equivalents.</plot>
	</category>
	<category>
		<label>Virtual Life</label>
		<thumb>X32K9wB.jpg</thumb>
		<banner>v4YyBeR.jpg</banner>
		<fanart>G5PYNPY.jpg</fanart>
		<logo>NI2S8Wu.png</logo>
		<trailer>7NXIgj9CUQ8</trailer>
		<plot>Life simulation games (or virtual life games) are a subgenre of simulation video games in which the player lives or controls one or more artificial lifeforms.  A life simulation game can revolve around individuals and relationships, or it could be a simulation of an ecosystem.</plot>
	</category>
	<category>
		<label>Water</label>
		<thumb>nv1deM8.jpg</thumb>
		<banner>PQxmPio.jpg</banner>
		<fanart>G5PYNPY.jpg</fanart>
		<logo>Cb27QR3.png</logo>
		<trailer>7NXIgj9CUQ8</trailer>
		<plot>Sub genre of sports games focusing on water sports such as swimming, toobing, etc.</plot>
	</category>
	<category>
		<label>Unknown</label>
		<thumb>fYMsybe.jpg</thumb>
		<banner>pc540fV.jpg</banner>
		<fanart>G5PYNPY.jpg</fanart>
		<logo>nQfTbZq.png</logo>
		<plot>These games have an unknown genre or no genre was identified</plot>
		<trailer>7NXIgj9CUQ8</trailer>
	</category>
	<category>
		<label>default</label>
		<thumb>fYMsybe.jpg</thumb>
		<banner>pc540fV.jpg</banner>
		<fanart>G5PYNPY.jpg</fanart>
		<logo>nQfTbZq.png</logo>
		<plot></plot>
		<trailer>7NXIgj9CUQ8</trailer>
	</category>
</categories>