<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<datafile>
	<header>
		<emu_name>Sega 32X</emu_name>
		<emu_description>32X</emu_description>
		<emu_category>Sega, 1990s, Console, 32 Bit</emu_category>
		<emu_version>04012018</emu_version>
		<emu_date>03/03/2015</emu_date>
		<emu_author>Zach Morris</emu_author>
		<emu_visibility>visible</emu_visibility>
		<emu_homepage>http://www.no-intro.org</emu_homepage>
		<emu_baseurl>https://archive.org/download/</emu_baseurl>
		<emu_launcher>retroplayer</emu_launcher>
		<emu_default_addon>none</emu_default_addon>
		<emu_ext_launch_cmd>none</emu_ext_launch_cmd>
		<emu_downloadpath>default</emu_downloadpath>
		<emu_postdlaction>none</emu_postdlaction>
		<emu_comment>No Intro Sega 32X list.  Filtered to remove duplicates, betas, etc.[CR]The Sega 32X, codenamed Project Mars, is an add-on for the Mega Drive/Genesis video game console by Sega. Its aim was to increase the lifespan of the aging Mega Drive/Genesis system, which was facing stiff competition from the SNES. While connecting it to Mega Drive did increase its capabilities, reluctance to adapt due to the previous failure of the Mega-CD and the upcoming Sega Saturn system led to low sales and a short lifespan. It was distributed under the name Sega Super 32X in Japan, Sega Genesis 32X in North America, Sega Mega Drive 32X in the PAL region, and Sega Mega 32X in Brazil.[CR]Developer:  Sega[CR]Manufacturer:  Sega[CR]CPU:  2 x SH-2 32-bit RISC[CR]Memory:  256 kB program RAM[CR]Graphics:  N/A[CR]Sound:  Stereo 10-bit PWM (Pulse Width Modulation)[CR]Display:  320 x 240[CR]Media:  Cartridge[CR]Max. Controllers:  2
		</emu_comment>
		<emu_thumb>YggZ48K.jpg</emu_thumb>
		<emu_banner>ssqCrqM.jpg</emu_banner>
		<emu_fanart>vFW1FWg.jpg</emu_fanart>
		<emu_logo>8P37HjF.png</emu_logo>
		<emu_trailer>kxVOpWNlbDE</emu_trailer>
	</header>
	<game name="After Burner Complete (Europe)">
		<description>After Burner Complete (Europe)</description>
		<rom crc="029106F5" name="Sega_32X/After%20Burner%20Complete%20%28Europe%29.32x" sha1="C7D56CC75DC9A5206FDA6A080CBEDAE9F48C82BC" size="1066717" />
		<title_clean>After Burner Complete</title_clean>
		<plot>[CR][B]Overview:[/B][CR]After Burner, is an arcade flight sim/shooter, developed by SEGA and first released in 1987 in Japanese Arcades. It was designed by legendary Sega game developer Yu Suzuki. It was ported onto many systems, including Sega's own Sega Master System just a few months after the Arcade launch, but most of them weren't able to match the original Arcade version's visceral speed and graphical/sound quality.It is the first game among a series of franchise sequels such as After Burner II, After Burner III and the 2006 release of After Burner Climax which ran on the then newly developed SEGA Lindbergh arcade hardware. After Burner II was re-released in 2004 for the Playstation 2, in the SEGA AGES 2500 series of budget anniversary re-releases.After Burner Arcade MachineIn After Burner the player controls a F-14 Tomcat, a type of jet, and the object of the game is simply to shoot down other enemy jets while evading their return fire with deft maneuvers. The player-controlled Tomcat is equipped with a machine gun and a small number of missiles as a secondary weapon which replenishes after each completed stage.The original After Burner machine is a rarity, exclusively available in the Japanese Arcades. It was controlled with a simulating flight stick, with buttons that controlled the cannon and missile weapons. Movement such as dropping/gaining altitude and barrelrolling was also perfomed by movements with the flight stick.The arcade version also featured a deluxe cabinet, which rotated according to the player's movements (much like Space Harrier and Galaxy Force). This was featured in the arcade scene of the 1991 hit movie Terminator 2: Judgement Day, where it was being played by a teenage John Connor. [CR]</plot>
		<releasedate>13/8/1994</releasedate>
		<year>1994</year>
		<genre>Action</genre>
		<studio>Sega</studio>
		<nplayers>1</nplayers>
		<perspective>3rd-Person</perspective>
		<rating>3.5</rating>
		<thegamesdb_id>26762</thegamesdb_id>
		<mobygames_url>https://www.mobygames.com/game/sega-32x/after-burner</mobygames_url>
		<giantbomb_url>https://www.giantbomb.com/after-burner/3030-3629/</giantbomb_url>
		<consolegrid_url>http://consolegrid.com/games/14055</consolegrid_url>
		<boxart1>IbghH2o.jpg</boxart1>
		<boxart2>9INWjXN.jpg</boxart2>
		<snapshot1>25FQc0P.png</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>nWRYzs9.png</snapshot2>
		<snapshot3>wyM3jxb.png</snapshot3>
		<snapshot4>jYCurvR.png</snapshot4>
		<snapshot5>yhVQ2B4.png</snapshot5>
		<snapshot6>7jTg9yB.png</snapshot6>
		<snapshot7>8p9xhRf.png</snapshot7>
		<snapshot8>xepBR3W.jpg</snapshot8>
		<snapshot9>ePjHE7t.jpg</snapshot9>
		<snapshot10>CACi05G.png</snapshot10>
		<banner1>Wnp4H31.png</banner1>
		<clearlogo1>tmGfbDb.png</clearlogo1>
	</game>
	<game name="After Burner Complete - After Burner (Japan, USA)">
		<description>After Burner Complete - After Burner (Japan, USA)</description>
		<rom crc="204044C4" name="Sega_32X/After%20Burner%20Complete%20-%20After%20Burner%20%28Japan%2C%20USA%29.32x" sha1="9CF575FEB036E2F26E78350154D5EB2FD3825325" size="1067405" />
		<title_clean>After Burner Complete - After Burner</title_clean>
		<plot>[CR][B]Overview:[/B][CR]After Burner, is an arcade flight sim/shooter, developed by SEGA and first released in 1987 in Japanese Arcades. It was designed by legendary Sega game developer Yu Suzuki. It was ported onto many systems, including Sega's own Sega Master System just a few months after the Arcade launch, but most of them weren't able to match the original Arcade version's visceral speed and graphical/sound quality.It is the first game among a series of franchise sequels such as After Burner II, After Burner III and the 2006 release of After Burner Climax which ran on the then newly developed SEGA Lindbergh arcade hardware. After Burner II was re-released in 2004 for the Playstation 2, in the SEGA AGES 2500 series of budget anniversary re-releases.After Burner Arcade MachineIn After Burner the player controls a F-14 Tomcat, a type of jet, and the object of the game is simply to shoot down other enemy jets while evading their return fire with deft maneuvers. The player-controlled Tomcat is equipped with a machine gun and a small number of missiles as a secondary weapon which replenishes after each completed stage.The original After Burner machine is a rarity, exclusively available in the Japanese Arcades. It was controlled with a simulating flight stick, with buttons that controlled the cannon and missile weapons. Movement such as dropping/gaining altitude and barrelrolling was also perfomed by movements with the flight stick.The arcade version also featured a deluxe cabinet, which rotated according to the player's movements (much like Space Harrier and Galaxy Force). This was featured in the arcade scene of the 1991 hit movie Terminator 2: Judgement Day, where it was being played by a teenage John Connor. [CR]</plot>
		<releasedate>13/8/1994</releasedate>
		<year>1994</year>
		<genre>Action</genre>
		<studio>Sega</studio>
		<nplayers>1</nplayers>
		<perspective>3rd-Person</perspective>
		<rating>3.5</rating>
		<thegamesdb_id>26762</thegamesdb_id>
		<mobygames_url>https://www.mobygames.com/game/sega-32x/after-burner</mobygames_url>
		<giantbomb_url>https://www.giantbomb.com/after-burner/3030-3629/</giantbomb_url>
		<consolegrid_url>http://consolegrid.com/games/4247</consolegrid_url>
		<boxart1>G9jpPxQ.jpg</boxart1>
		<boxart2>ZOEFHES.png</boxart2>
		<boxart3>YvDmA4L.jpg</boxart3>
		<snapshot1>25FQc0P.png</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>nWRYzs9.png</snapshot2>
		<snapshot3>wyM3jxb.png</snapshot3>
		<snapshot4>jYCurvR.png</snapshot4>
		<snapshot5>yhVQ2B4.png</snapshot5>
		<snapshot6>7jTg9yB.png</snapshot6>
		<snapshot7>8p9xhRf.png</snapshot7>
		<snapshot8>xepBR3W.jpg</snapshot8>
		<snapshot9>ePjHE7t.jpg</snapshot9>
		<snapshot10>CACi05G.png</snapshot10>
		<banner1>iFeYeAL.png</banner1>
		<clearlogo1>tmGfbDb.png</clearlogo1>
	</game>
	<game name="Amazing Spider-Man - Web of Fire (USA)">
		<description>Amazing Spider-Man - Web of Fire (USA)</description>
		<rom crc="29DCE257" name="Sega_32X/Amazing%20Spider-Man%2C%20The%20-%20Web%20of%20Fire%20%28USA%29.32x" sha1="7CC2EA1E10F110338AD880BD3E7FF3BCE72E7E9E" size="2401681" />
		<title_clean>Amazing Spider-Man - Web of Fire</title_clean>
		<plot>An electric plasma grid has left New York in a state of chaos, and only Spider-Man and Daredevil can save the city from total destruction.[CR]Lead Spidey through side-scrolling levels filled with a range of enemies and puzzles and take on HYDRA, the source of the evil, head on.</plot>
		<releasedate>13/8/1996</releasedate>
		<year>1996</year>
		<genre>Action</genre>
		<studio>Sega</studio>
		<nplayers>1</nplayers>
		<perspective>Side-Scrolling</perspective>
		<rating>2.9</rating>
		<ESRB>E - Everyone</ESRB>
		<videoid>v2QmZdFvJZw</videoid>
		<thegamesdb_id>4925</thegamesdb_id>
		<mobygames_url>https://www.mobygames.com/game/sega-32x/amazing-spider-man-web-of-fire</mobygames_url>
		<giantbomb_url>https://www.giantbomb.com/the-amazing-spider-man-web-of-fire/3030-4219/</giantbomb_url>
		<boxart1>xvP5Pr1.jpg</boxart1>
		<boxart2>0GLXfM5.jpg</boxart2>
		<snapshot1>GmAiaJJ.gif</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>3g1eEf4.gif</snapshot2>
		<snapshot3>KRcDkoh.gif</snapshot3>
		<snapshot4>0vEgEN6.gif</snapshot4>
		<snapshot5>WN2F9Ii.gif</snapshot5>
		<snapshot6>lAsghJx.gif</snapshot6>
		<snapshot7>Xu0REBn.gif</snapshot7>
		<snapshot8>F40WTmM.gif</snapshot8>
		<snapshot9>RTs0aG3.gif</snapshot9>
		<snapshot10>wCghq90.gif</snapshot10>
		<fanart1>MazzECl.jpg</fanart1>
	</game>
	<game name="BC Racers (USA)">
		<description>BC Racers (USA)</description>
		<rom crc="936C3D27" name="Sega_32X/BC%20Racers%20%28USA%29.32x" sha1="9B5FD499EAA442D48A2C97FCEB1D505DC8E8DDFF" size="1116437" />
		<title_clean>BC Racers</title_clean>
		<plot>PLOTMillstone Rockafella, the millionarie playboy has organized a series of bike races, the winner of which will recieve the Ultimate Boulderdash Bike.GAMEPLAYThe game has four difficulty settings, each of which have eight circuits. Unfortunately, this game didn't take a page from Mario Kart. There are no powerups except for the occasional boost. The game has been criticisized due to the fact that the driving is a little bit too responsive. Very much more so than other racing games of the era.[CR]</plot>
		<releasedate>13/8/1995</releasedate>
		<year>1995</year>
		<genre>Driving, Racing</genre>
		<studio>Front Street Publishing</studio>
		<nplayers>1-2 Alt</nplayers>
		<perspective>3rd-Person</perspective>
		<rating>2.7</rating>
		<thegamesdb_id>4913</thegamesdb_id>
		<mobygames_url>https://www.mobygames.com/game/sega-32x/bc-racers</mobygames_url>
		<giantbomb_url>https://www.giantbomb.com/bc-racers/3030-16086/</giantbomb_url>
		<consolegrid_url>http://consolegrid.com/games/14056</consolegrid_url>
		<boxart1>e2Uwoix.jpg</boxart1>
		<boxart2>BB2JY0b.jpg</boxart2>
		<snapshot1>HWGDieH.jpg</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>JkWf8Xn.jpg</snapshot2>
		<snapshot3>h9KsAbH.jpg</snapshot3>
		<snapshot4>aJhyrbU.jpg</snapshot4>
		<snapshot5>LQOpo8d.jpg</snapshot5>
		<snapshot6>hsvnkJt.png</snapshot6>
		<snapshot7>n1iGQld.png</snapshot7>
		<snapshot8>lWnHZ0C.png</snapshot8>
		<snapshot9>r4LlP08.png</snapshot9>
		<snapshot10>acgWuGb.png</snapshot10>
		<banner1>mJJAeWz.png</banner1>
		<clearlogo1>cssNM8T.png</clearlogo1>
	</game>
	<game name="Blackthorne (USA)">
		<description>Blackthorne (USA)</description>
		<rom crc="D1A60A47" name="Sega_32X/Blackthorne%20%28USA%29.32x" sha1="4BF120CF056FE1417CA5B02FA0372EF33CB8EC11" size="1412837" />
		<title_clean>Blackthorne</title_clean>
		<plot>[CR][B]Overview:[/B][CR]BlackThorne is a 1994 action platformer, developed by Blizzard and published by Interplay. The player is put in control of the game's protagonist, Kyle "BlackThorne" Vlaros as he progresses through the games many levels, attempting to thwart the evil Sarlac.The game was initially released in 1994 for both the Super Nintendo and the PC. It was then later ported to Sega 32X, Mac, and Game Boy Advance. In 2013, the game was released as a free PC download via Battle.net.[CR][B]Gameplay:[/B][CR]BlackThorne on the 32XThe games levels are large and winding, and are filled with puzzles and enemies. Kyle will have to run, jump and climb in order to get around each level, utilizing a number of weapons and items. The game's control is generally slower than most platformers. The player loses a lot of control when they run, and running is best for long, straight corridors and long jumps. For the most part, the player will progress slowly, climbing up ledges and making tough jumps.Combat in BlackThorne is slow and strategic. The player wields a shotgun with unlimited ammo, and can use grenades in combat as well, though these are best used to destroy doors. When an enemy is encountered, they will often back up and wait before attacking. Kyle can also back up to avoid their shots. Enemies will reload and move after shooting, which is when the player should take advantage and eliminate their foe.Items play a large role in BlackThorne. They are numerous, and are used in many instances for puzzles and clearing obstacles. There are also a number of interactive items in the environment that Kyle must use.ItemsThe LevitatorHover Bomb: A basic grenade-like item that explodes on contact. Will kill most enemies in one strike, but is most useful for destroying doorways.Bridge Key: Electronic keys that activate bridges. Bridge keys can be removed and work on any bridge.Remote Wasp: A floating bomb that Kyle can control remotely. He is defenseless when using the bomb.Potion: Refills Kyle's stamina.Levitator: A triangular platform that extends into a pillar that Kyle can stand on to reach high areas.Iron Key: A key that deactivates laser fields.Fire Bomb: Bombs that damage anything they contact and explode the moment they hit the ground.[CR]</plot>
		<releasedate>13/8/1995</releasedate>
		<year>1995</year>
		<genre>Action</genre>
		<studio>Interplay Productions</studio>
		<nplayers>1</nplayers>
		<perspective>Platform</perspective>
		<rating>3.5</rating>
		<ESRB>T - Teen</ESRB>
		<videoid>YW-HYI-wqts</videoid>
		<thegamesdb_id>9074</thegamesdb_id>
		<mobygames_url>https://www.mobygames.com/game/sega-32x/blackthorne</mobygames_url>
		<giantbomb_url>https://www.giantbomb.com/blackthorne/3030-4549/</giantbomb_url>
		<consolegrid_url>http://consolegrid.com/games/14302</consolegrid_url>
		<boxart1>Ag4Tor8.jpg</boxart1>
		<boxart2>0Yy53MH.jpg</boxart2>
		<snapshot1>qSEokyU.gif</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>y430E6b.gif</snapshot2>
		<snapshot3>33QD5Wc.gif</snapshot3>
		<snapshot4>3OxW1gj.gif</snapshot4>
		<snapshot5>WpqTV7d.gif</snapshot5>
		<snapshot6>a9du0Q2.gif</snapshot6>
		<snapshot7>v42bzjw.gif</snapshot7>
		<snapshot8>Oes1vaU.gif</snapshot8>
		<snapshot9>JHU0pOK.jpg</snapshot9>
		<snapshot10>j8UQUuW.jpg</snapshot10>
		<banner1>i2Cc2wq.jpg</banner1>
		<clearlogo1>VGRMUA7.png</clearlogo1>
	</game>
	<game name="Brutal Unleashed - Above the Claw (USA)">
		<description>Brutal Unleashed - Above the Claw (USA)</description>
		<rom crc="7A72C939" name="Sega_32X/Brutal%20Unleashed%20-%20Above%20the%20Claw%20%28USA%29.32x" sha1="40AA2C787F37772CDBD7280B8BE06B15421FABAE" size="2004340" />
		<title_clean>Brutal Unleashed - Above the Claw</title_clean>
		<plot>As with the original Brutal: Paws of Fury, the game involves a martial arts tournament set up by the Dalai Llama. A selection of 12 anthropomorphic animals are involved; choose from them for the cartoon-styled beat 'em up action.  [CR]Characters each have their own fighting style, array of moves, and storyline.  As you progress through the game, you unlock more moves for each character.  There's also a progressive conquest mode which challenges you to take over the entire Brutal Island.</plot>
		<releasedate>13/8/1995</releasedate>
		<year>1995</year>
		<studio>GameTek</studio>
		<nplayers>1-2 Alt</nplayers>
		<ESRB>T - Teen</ESRB>
		<thegamesdb_id>5295</thegamesdb_id>
		<mobygames_url>https://www.mobygames.com/game/sega-32x/brutal-above-the-claw</mobygames_url>
		<giantbomb_url>https://www.giantbomb.com/brutal-above-the-claw/3030-2337/</giantbomb_url>
		<boxart1>BGnqIrq.jpg</boxart1>
		<boxart2>7GjwZaD.jpg</boxart2>
		<boxart3>d3NOZ3j.jpg</boxart3>
		<snapshot1>fcWmCK6.png</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>MBGlxFB.png</snapshot2>
		<snapshot3>hPKFCXe.png</snapshot3>
		<snapshot4>Ebe8RDE.png</snapshot4>
		<snapshot5>oC4kd1T.png</snapshot5>
		<snapshot6>wnbaccI.png</snapshot6>
		<snapshot7>txPGfyO.png</snapshot7>
		<snapshot8>yT7hwcx.png</snapshot8>
		<snapshot9>PO2TPFu.png</snapshot9>
		<snapshot10>p3mOtlP.png</snapshot10>
	</game>
	<game name="Chaotix - Knuckles' Chaotix (Japan, USA)">
		<description>Chaotix - Knuckles' Chaotix (Japan, USA)</description>
		<rom crc="D0B0B842" name="Sega_32X/Chaotix%20-%20Knuckles%20Chaotix%20%28Japan%2C%20USA%29.32x" sha1="0C2FFF7BC79ED26507C08AC47464C3AF19F7CED7" size="1702710" />
		<title_clean>Chaotix - Knuckles' Chaotix</title_clean>
		<plot>[CR][B]Overview:[/B][CR]  Left to right: Vector, Knuckles, Espio, Mighty, Charmy Knuckles' Chaotix (known in Japan simply as Chaotix) is a side-scrolling action platformer developed and published by  Sega for the Sega 32X on April 20, 1995. It is the only game from the  Sonic the Hedgehog franchise to be released on the short-lived add-on for the Sega Genesis, pushing the limits of the console while introducing new characters and gameplay mechanics.  Knuckles' Chaotix is the first game in the franchise to not feature either Sonic the Hedgehog or Miles "Tails" Prower as playable characters. Instead, player one can pick from five playable characters (including  Knuckles the Echidna, who was previously playable in Sonic &amp; Knuckles, and  Mighty the Armadillo, who was previously playable in SegaSonic the Hedgehog) while player two (either human or computer-controlled) is chosen in a "crane game" fashion (including spots for the two "booby trap" characters). The game introduces the Chaotix, a three-man dysfunctional team of animals who help Knuckles and Mighty save Carnival Island from the evil Dr. Robotnik (and his robot lackey,  Metal Sonic). The game also introduces Heavy and Bomb, two of Dr. Robotnik's former 'badniks' who also assist the protagonists. Each character has their own unique traits and abilities:  Knuckles the Echidna - Like his appearance in Sonic &amp; Knuckles, Knuckles has the ability to glide through the air (by holding down the Jump button) and freely climb walls. Mighty the Armadillo - Mighty is the fastest character in the game and has the ability to wall jump (by tapping the Jump button at the wall, then tapping it again). Espio the Chameleon - Espio can walk upright on walls and ceilings (by holding down the Jump button while approaching a wall) and can destroy most enemies by charging at them. Charmy Bee - The shortest character of the group, Charmy is unable to attack enemies, but can fly indefinitely while being able to carry the other player with him (by holding down a direction and pressing the Jump button in mid-air). Vector the Crocodile - The tallest character of the group, Vector can perform a dash attack (by pressing the Jump button in mid-air) and can climb up walls (like Knuckles, only it's required to hold down the Jump button).Heavy - Although Heavy is invincible to all attacks (and can destroy enemies by colliding with them), he has low jumping ability and is extremely hard to pull around by other players.Bomb - Although lightweight, Bomb explodes (and then regenerates) when it collides with an enemy, causing damage to all nearby objects (both enemies and the other player).[CR][B]Gameplay:[/B][CR]The 'Hold' mechanism Whilst Knuckles Chaotix is similar to previous 2D Sonic the Hedgehog games in terms of working through a 2D platform level with elements of speed, collecting rings a long the way, Knuckles' Chaotix introduced a buddy system where two characters are connected at all times by a ring. This connection can be stretched like an elastic band, and so can be used to propel characters along the levels either horizontally or vertically, and is also used to open doors and complete some small puzzles when one character stands still and 'holds' the ring whilst the other character runs in a direction to stretch the link between them. This system is used for multiplayer cooperative play between two players that operate on the same screen, or can be controlled by the computer within single player. [CR][B]Stages:[/B][CR]Similar to how characters can be chosen using the 'Combi-Catcher' between stages, the stages themselves are also chosen at random using a similar device. There are up to five 'acts' and each are chosen randomly, rather than completed in turn, with a boss at the end of each stage. When a stage is complete, it cannot be selected anymore. The stages are:Speed SliderBotanic BaseA lush green area of the island within a greenhouse that holds beautiful plants and deadly badniks.Speed SliderBased on past Sonic levels such as Casino Night, Speed Slider is a speedy rollercoaster-based level with dips and slides and a merry-go-round, and a section within the middle of the stage that dips up and down.Amazing ArenaAt the start of this stage, the area is grey with full music. You must find the light switch to 'switch on' the stage into a colourful musical stage. This stage is maze-like with many different teleporters and platforms.Marina MadnessA stage based on a cruise, the 'ship' moves up and down the stage, revealing different platforming areas.Techno TowerA futuristic tower, where you must climb all the way to the very top![CR]Bonus and Special Stage[CR]The Special Stage By finding large hidden rings, you can access the Bonus Stage if you have 20 rings. The bonus stage is a vertical free falling mini-game where you navigate past blocks to pick up power ups, extra rings, lives and other bonuses, such as the ability to move the 'Combi-Catcher' freely when selecting a character. You lose rings as you float down the bonus stage, which ends when you either touch a 'End' block or run out of rings.The Special Stage is accessed by a large ring at the end of each stage act if you have 50 rings. Here, you move your character along a hexagon-shaped tube collecting blue spheres whilst avoiding pitfalls, spikebombs and other traps. Similar to the Bonus Stage, your rings are your timer and count down, ending the stage when you run out. By collecting all of the 'Chaos Rings', you can unlock a better ending.[CR]</plot>
		<releasedate>13/8/1995</releasedate>
		<year>1995</year>
		<genre>Action</genre>
		<studio>Sega</studio>
		<nplayers>1-2 Co-Op</nplayers>
		<perspective>Platform</perspective>
		<rating>3.7</rating>
		<ESRB>E - Everyone</ESRB>
		<thegamesdb_id>2290</thegamesdb_id>
		<mobygames_url>https://www.mobygames.com/game/sega-32x/knuckles-chaotix</mobygames_url>
		<giantbomb_url>https://www.giantbomb.com/knuckles-chaotix/3030-8284/</giantbomb_url>
		<consolegrid_url>http://consolegrid.com/games/7849</consolegrid_url>
		<boxart1>aEVQOyh.jpg</boxart1>
		<boxart2>mqDe4BA.jpg</boxart2>
		<boxart3>IhDDkoP.jpg</boxart3>
		<boxart4>6eHR51O.jpg</boxart4>
		<boxart5>crsHzTa.jpg</boxart5>
		<snapshot1>m5nOv2d.jpg</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>tFzqMkP.gif</snapshot2>
		<snapshot3>MbPG3Qq.gif</snapshot3>
		<snapshot4>QII4FIc.gif</snapshot4>
		<snapshot5>3dp9WlY.gif</snapshot5>
		<snapshot6>u2F8Gdv.gif</snapshot6>
		<snapshot7>tYIgaV9.gif</snapshot7>
		<snapshot8>xJhmcAe.gif</snapshot8>
		<snapshot9>PvbOlH9.gif</snapshot9>
		<snapshot10>zXZ1val.png</snapshot10>
		<banner1>JPDKUfM.png</banner1>
	</game>
	<game name="Cosmic Carnage (Europe)">
		<description>Cosmic Carnage (Europe)</description>
		<rom crc="9F3FDBC2" name="Sega_32X/Cosmic%20Carnage%20%28Europe%29.32x" sha1="900E8ECDCC4460B4C4AF3873E1D6BC83DA4AEE99" size="1620317" />
		<title_clean>Cosmic Carnage</title_clean>
		<plot>[CR][B]Overview:[/B][CR] Cosmic Carnage is a 2-D fighting game, released in 1994 for Sega's 32X. Cosmic Carnage features eight playable characters and is designed to use the six button controller, but the standard three button controller may be used. The Japanese title is "Cyber Brawl".[CR][B]Story:[/B][CR] Cosmic Carnage is about a group of intergalactic prisoners who are being shipped off to a space mine. During the trip to the mine the prisoners end up taking over the ship, but in the process damage the ship. While trying to hijack another ship to escape, they ram their own ship into it thus destroying all but one of the escape pods and killing all but eight total people from both of the ships. Now those eight survivors fight for control of the last escape pod.  [CR][B]Characters:[/B][CR] There are eight total characters, four from the prisoner ship and four from the military ship.  PrisonersSoldiers Talmac Cyclic Yug Zena-Lan Naja Naruto Deamon  Tyr[CR]</plot>
		<releasedate>13/8/1994</releasedate>
		<year>1994</year>
		<genre>Action</genre>
		<studio>Sega</studio>
		<nplayers>1-2 VS</nplayers>
		<perspective>3rd-Person</perspective>
		<rating>2.3</rating>
		<ESRB>T - Teen</ESRB>
		<thegamesdb_id>4914</thegamesdb_id>
		<mobygames_url>https://www.mobygames.com/game/sega-32x/cosmic-carnage</mobygames_url>
		<giantbomb_url>https://www.giantbomb.com/cosmic-carnage/3030-13797/</giantbomb_url>
		<boxart1>Xph5YOT.jpg</boxart1>
		<boxart2>Nvl2BNv.jpg</boxart2>
		<boxart3>VU7r2VO.jpg</boxart3>
		<snapshot1>bITWNSK.jpg</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>blqImC0.gif</snapshot2>
		<snapshot3>4X9K5mX.gif</snapshot3>
		<snapshot4>khBL3kv.gif</snapshot4>
		<snapshot5>USOGDqi.gif</snapshot5>
		<snapshot6>GcvuF4z.gif</snapshot6>
		<snapshot7>kxOaHEd.gif</snapshot7>
		<snapshot8>0kKeKR6.gif</snapshot8>
		<snapshot9>6VcVG3O.jpg</snapshot9>
		<snapshot10>9qqYIOY.jpg</snapshot10>
	</game>
	<game name="Cyber Brawl - Cosmic Carnage (Japan, USA)">
		<description>Cyber Brawl - Cosmic Carnage (Japan, USA)</description>
		<rom crc="7C7BE6A2" name="Sega_32X/Cyber%20Brawl%20-%20Cosmic%20Carnage%20%28Japan%2C%20USA%29.32x" sha1="9A563ED821B483148339561EBD2B876EFA58847B" size="1620409" />
		<title_clean>Cyber Brawl - Cosmic Carnage</title_clean>
		<plot>[CR][B]Overview:[/B][CR] Cosmic Carnage is a 2-D fighting game, released in 1994 for Sega's 32X. Cosmic Carnage features eight playable characters and is designed to use the six button controller, but the standard three button controller may be used. The Japanese title is "Cyber Brawl".[CR][B]Story:[/B][CR] Cosmic Carnage is about a group of intergalactic prisoners who are being shipped off to a space mine. During the trip to the mine the prisoners end up taking over the ship, but in the process damage the ship. While trying to hijack another ship to escape, they ram their own ship into it thus destroying all but one of the escape pods and killing all but eight total people from both of the ships. Now those eight survivors fight for control of the last escape pod.  [CR][B]Characters:[/B][CR] There are eight total characters, four from the prisoner ship and four from the military ship.  PrisonersSoldiers Talmac Cyclic Yug Zena-Lan Naja Naruto Deamon  Tyr[CR]</plot>
		<releasedate>13/8/1994</releasedate>
		<year>1994</year>
		<genre>Action</genre>
		<studio>Sega</studio>
		<nplayers>1-2 VS</nplayers>
		<perspective>3rd-Person</perspective>
		<rating>2.3</rating>
		<ESRB>T - Teen</ESRB>
		<thegamesdb_id>4914</thegamesdb_id>
		<mobygames_url>https://www.mobygames.com/game/sega-32x/cosmic-carnage</mobygames_url>
		<giantbomb_url>https://www.giantbomb.com/cosmic-carnage/3030-13797/</giantbomb_url>
		<boxart1>kTqpmMB.jpg</boxart1>
		<boxart2>Nvl2BNv.jpg</boxart2>
		<boxart3>VU7r2VO.jpg</boxart3>
		<snapshot1>bITWNSK.jpg</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>blqImC0.gif</snapshot2>
		<snapshot3>4X9K5mX.gif</snapshot3>
		<snapshot4>khBL3kv.gif</snapshot4>
		<snapshot5>USOGDqi.gif</snapshot5>
		<snapshot6>GcvuF4z.gif</snapshot6>
		<snapshot7>kxOaHEd.gif</snapshot7>
		<snapshot8>0kKeKR6.gif</snapshot8>
		<snapshot9>6VcVG3O.jpg</snapshot9>
		<snapshot10>9qqYIOY.jpg</snapshot10>
	</game>
	<game name="Darxide (Europe) (En,Fr,De,Es)">
		<description>Darxide (Europe) (En,Fr,De,Es)</description>
		<rom crc="22D7C906" name="Sega_32X/Darxide%20%28Europe%29%20%28En%2CFr%2CDe%2CEs%29.32x" sha1="108B4FFED8643ABDEFA921CFB58389B119B47F3D" size="856303" />
		<title_clean>Darxide</title_clean>
		<plot>One of the last 32X games released (and exclusively in Europe), DarXide is a 3-D space shooter, inspired in part by the arcade gameplay of Asteroids. It is one of the few 32X games to used texture-mapped polygons. [CR]Players control a lone starship rushing to destroy oncoming asteroids and alien vessels before they annihilate defenseless human miners and colonies. Asteroids break apart into smaller rocks, which much also be hunted down and destroyed. Aliens likewise arrive in larger, more dangerous vessels.[CR]Asteroids broken down to their smallest size and then vaporized will sometimes drop shield or energy recharges, to repair damage caused by laser blasts or collisions. New weapons can also be found. Players have a time limit to meet all objectives in a stage before they are forced to land and try again. The right side of the HUD shows asteroids remaining (and their approximate size), while the left shows the player's distance to their base (and so, time remaining in the stage).</plot>
		<releasedate>13/8/1995</releasedate>
		<year>1995</year>
		<genre>Action</genre>
		<studio>Sega</studio>
		<nplayers>1</nplayers>
		<perspective>3rd-Person</perspective>
		<ESRB>RP - Rating Pending</ESRB>
		<thegamesdb_id>9075</thegamesdb_id>
		<mobygames_url>https://www.mobygames.com/game/sega-32x/darxide</mobygames_url>
		<giantbomb_url>https://www.giantbomb.com/darxide/3030-41013/</giantbomb_url>
		<boxart1>XIovGHA.jpg</boxart1>
		<boxart2>3MnPJUD.jpg</boxart2>
		<snapshot1>9PqvRss.png</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>Ai36nEt.png</snapshot2>
		<snapshot3>5SAMNRX.png</snapshot3>
		<snapshot4>F58jBtm.png</snapshot4>
		<snapshot5>3MmhRgv.png</snapshot5>
		<snapshot6>JboRPIV.png</snapshot6>
		<snapshot7>dYFSUpL.png</snapshot7>
		<snapshot8>zdat54e.png</snapshot8>
		<snapshot9>YtMbfF2.png</snapshot9>
	</game>
	<game name="Doom (Japan, USA)">
		<description>Doom (Japan, USA)</description>
		<rom crc="208332FD" name="Sega_32X/Doom%20%28Japan%2C%20USA%29.32x" sha1="B68E9C7AF81853B8F05B8696033DFE4C80327E38" size="1490743" />
		<title_clean>Doom</title_clean>
		<plot>[CR][B]Overview:[/B][CR]Doom is a sci-fi horror first-person shooter developed and published by id for the PC (running MS-DOS) on December 10, 1993.As a nameless space marine, players trek through over 24 levels (split up into three episodes), where they liberate space stations from demon infestation in both Phobos and Deimos, only to take on Hell. The game's engine (later known as id Tech 1) is known to pioneer new features to the genre, including non-perpendicular walls, complex rooms (known as "sectors") with varying height differences, multiplayer (both co-operatively and competitively, for up to four players at a time) and the concept of packaging the game's content (levels, sounds, and music) into singular data files (WAD files) for easier modification and distribution, leading to the birth of the modern mod-making community.The lore of the game, set sometime into the future, involves the Union Aerospace Corporation (U.A.C.), a multi-planetary conglomerate that has been utilized by the Earth military to secretly experiment on alien teleportation technology discovered on the moons of Mars. As they try to establish a gateway between the two moons using this technology, the experiment goes awry and the demons of Hell use the portals to invade the two moons. As the last man standing guarding the Hangar of the U.A.C. space station on Phobos, the lone space marine must fight through the onslaught to keep them from attacking Earth.While the original game was a shareware mail-order release, a special edition of the game (known as The Ultimate Doom) was later distributed in retail boxed format. Also released as a free upgrade for those who own the original game, The Ultimate Doom added a new epilogue episode (Thy Flesh Consumed) bridging the game with its sequel, Doom II: Hell on Earth. The original game also spawned multiple sequels and reboots, numerous console ports, a 2005 sci-fi action film, and a wide variety of unofficial source ports and enhancements (thanks to the decision to release the source code with minimal restriction).[CR][B]Gameplay:[/B][CR]In Doom, players progress through each level, blasting away enemies while solving puzzles (involving switches, keycards, and skull-shaped key devices), avoiding environmental hazards (such as crushing ceilings, radioactive acid, and burning lava), and collecting weapons, ammo, and other items (including first-aid kits, body armor, suits that protect from radiation, night-vision goggles, computer maps, and supernatural orbs that grant a special bonus to the player). Unlike id's previous first-person shooter, Spear of Destiny, Doom does not include a scoring or lives system. Players who die can retry the level at the cost of resetting their inventory and stats.Episodes and DifficultiesThe game's campaign is split up into three episodes (each with eight normal levels and one secret level):Knee-Deep in the Dead - The only episode playable in the shareware version, the first episode deals with the marine's journey through the base established on Phobos.The Shores of Hell - After defeating the two big bruisers guarding the teleportation gateway, the marine passes through into Deimos. As the invasion continues, the base becomes more distorted with hellish architecture. The second episode deals with the marine's liberation of demons from the Deimos base.Inferno - Eventually, the marine fights a giant anomaly of flesh and metal (known as the Cyberdemon) in the "Tower of Babel", only to find out Deimos has been teleported to the infernal afterlife, and that the tower connects the moon to Hell itself! The third (and final) episode has the marine blindly wreaking havoc in Hell until he can find the mastermind behind the invasion.Players who are starting a new game can start at the beginning of an episode (starting with no armor and a pistol with 50 bullets). Starting from the second episode, players can find two new cell energy weapons (the uncommon Plasma Gun and the rare BFG-9000) and two new common enemies (the Cacodemon and the Lost Soul). Players can pick between five difficulties (known as "skill levels"):I'm too young to die. - Fewer monsters and more items. Double ammo granted on weapon and ammo pickups. Players take half damage.Hey, not too rough. - Fewer monsters and more items.Hurt me plenty. - Normal difficulty.Ultra-Violence. - More monsters and fewer items.Nightmare! - Added in v1.2. Cheat codes are disabled. More monsters and fewer items. Double ammo granted on weapon and ammo pickups. Monsters react and move faster, and respawn shortly after death.[CR][B]Weapons:[/B][CR]FistFistDamage: 10 per punch, 200 with Berserk PackOne of two starting weapons. The fist is simple and effective against weaker enemies but when a Berserk Pack power up is activated it boosts the attack power of the fist considerably allowing the Doom marine to tear through and even gib many enemies with ease.From the manual: "Can be used to punch enemies. It will always be with you."ChainsawChainsawDamage: 20 per 'hit'A powerful melee weapon capable of stunning some enemies.From the manual: "Cuts down the baddies like standing timber, but you have to get close."PistolPistolDamage: 10 per bulletThe second starting weapon. The pistol is one of two weapons to utilize bullets as its ammunition.From the manual: "Your standard military-issue weapon. It will stay with you, so don't forget about it if things get tough."ShotgunShotgunDamage: 10 per pellet, 7 pellets per shell, 70 damage maximumThe shotgun is a very effective weapon to use on most enemies the Doom marine will encounter. Its multi-pellet spread is very useful for crowds. The shotgun is the only weapon to use shells as its ammunition.From the manual: "Deliver a heavy punch at close range and a generous pelting from a distance."ChaingunChaingunDamage: 10 per bulletThe chaingun, like the pistol, uses bullets as its source of ammunition. This rapid-firing machine gun can stun some enemies so it is most effective against a single enemy.From the manual: "Direct heavy firepower into your opponent, making him do the chaingun cha-cha."Rocket LauncherRocket LauncherDamage: 200 per rocketThe Rocket Launcher is one of three weapons capable of gibbing enemies. Rockets deliver splash damage very well so they are ideal for dealing with crowds. This weapon is the only one in the game to use rockets as its ammunition.From the manual: "Deliver an explosive rocket that can turn one bad dude inside-out."Plasma RiflePlasma RifleDamage: 20 per cellThe fastest firing weapon in the game, this weapon is very powerful and effective against whatever it is the Doom marine may encounter. The plasma rifle is one of two weapons to utilize cells as its ammunition.From the manual: "Shoot multiple rounds of plasma energy - frying some demon butt!"BFG 9000BFG 9000Damage: 1000 per blast, 40 cells expendedThe BFG 9000 fires a huge plasma ball which moves slowly through the air. Upon impact, the target it hits receives a huge amount of damage and lots of splash damage as well.From the manual: "The prize of the military arsenal. Great for clearing the room of an unwelcome guest. Shoot it and see for yourself."[CR][B]Enemies:[/B][CR]Former HumanHealth: 20Total in single player (ultra violence) : 311From the manual: "Once a marine, always a marine-- except in this case. These guys may look like your old buddies, but now they're nothing more than pistol-toting bi-pedal maggots. Waste em!"Former Human SergeantHealth: 30Total in single player (ultra violence) : 426From the manual: "Ditto. Except these guys are meaner and tougher. These walking shotguns will provide you with a few extra holes if you're not careful."ImpHealth: 60Total in single player (ultra violence) : 719From the manual: "You though an imp was a cute little dude in a red suit with a pitchfork. Think again. This Imp heaves balls of fire down your throat and takes several bullets to die. It's time to find a better weapon than a pistol if you're going to face more than one of these mutants."DemonHealth: 140Total in single player (ultra violence) : 389From the manual: "Sorta like shaved gorillas, except with big heads and lots of teeth. They don't kill easy. Get too close and they'll rip your sorry head off."SpectreHealth: 140Total in single player (ultra violence) : 114From the manual: "Great. Just what you needed. An invisible (nearly) monster. Did you expect a walk in the park?"Lost SoulHealth: 100Total in single player (ultra violence) : 242From the manual: "Dumb. Tough. Flies. On Fire. 'Nuff said."CacodemonHealth: 400Total in single player (ultra violence) : 126From the manual: "They float in the air, belch ball lightning, and have one horrendously big mouth. If you get too close to one of these monstrosities, You're Toast."Baron of HellHealth: 1000Total in single player (ultra violence) : 37From the manual: "Tough as a dump truck and nearly as big, these goliaths are the worst thing on two legs since Tyrannosaurus Rex."CyberdemonHealth: 4000Total in single player (ultra violence) : 2From the manual: "Half unfeeling machine, half raging horned devil. This walking nightmare has a rocket launcher for an arm and will definitely reach out and touch you. Make sure you're loaded for bear before you get to this guy."Spiderdemon (Spider Mastermind)Health: 3000Total in single player (ultra violence) : 1From the manual: "Maybe cybernetics wasn't such a great idea after all. Look what the demons have done with it. It somehow seems unfair that you're not the only guy in Hell with a chaingun. Nope, she has a Super-Chaingun don't you just love it?"[CR]Episodes and Maps[CR]Knee-Deep in the Dead (E1)Level NameMap SlotDesignerPar TimeHangerE1M1John Romero0:30Nuclear PlantE1M2John Romero1:15Toxin RefineryE1M3John Romero2:00Command ControlE1M4Tom Hall, John Romero1:30Phobos LabE1M5John Romero2:45Central ProcessingE1M6John Romero3:00Computer StationE1M7John Romero3:00Phobos AnomalyE1M8Sandy Petersen, Tom HallN/AMilitary Base (secret level)E1M9John Romero2:45Sewers (Xbox only secret map)E1M10David Calvin0:00The Shores of Hell (E2)Level NameMap SlotDesignerPar timeDeimos AnomalyE2M1Sandy Petersen, Tom Hall1:30Containment AreaE2M2Tom Hall, Sandy Petersen1:30RefineryE2M3Tom Hall, Sandy Petersen1:30Deimos LabE2M4Tom Hall, Sandy Petersen2:00Command CenterE2M5Sandy Petersen1:30Hall of the DamnedE2M6Sandy Petersen6:00Spawning VatsE2M7Tom Hall, Sandy Petersen4:00Tower of BabelE2M8Sandy PetersenN/AFortress of MysteryE2M9Sandy Petersen2:50Inferno (E3)Level NameMap SlotDesignerPar TimeHell KeepE3M1Sandy Petersen1:30Slough of DespairE3M2Sandy Petersen0:45PandemoniumE3M3Tom Hall, Sandy Petersen1:30House of PainE3M4Sandy Petersen2:30Unholy CathedralE3M5Sandy Petersen1:30Mt. ErebusE3M6Sandy Petersen1:30LimboE3M7Tom Hall, Sandy Petersen2:45DisE3M8Sandy PetersenN/AWarrensE3M9Sandy Petersen2:15[CR]Official Ports[CR]Atari JaguarThe first console port developed by id Software, the Jaguar version of Doom was released in 1994. The game engine was largely developed by John Carmack. 22 of the original 27 levels are included, though modified and simplified, and two new maps are included. Music is only included during the title screen and between-level screens. Two player multiplayer Deathmatch and Co-op modes are available through JagLink.The code developed for this port served as the basis for future ports including the Sega 32X (which was released before the Jaguar version), the 3DO, GameBoy Advance, and PlayStation.Game Boy AdvanceBased on the Jaguar port, the GBA version of Doom was released by David A. Palmer Productions in 2001. Five new multiplayer-only maps were designed for this version.iPhone / iPod TouchAn official iOS port of Doom, titled Classic Doom, was released by id Software in 2009. The port is based on the source port PrBoom which allows for OpenGL rendering.LinuxThe Linux port of Doom was created by Dave Taylor of id Software and released in 1994. The source code of this port was made available to the public in 1997 and is the basis for all subsequent source ports.MS-DOSThe original version of Doom.PlayStationDoom on the Sony PlayStation is more of a re-imagining. It features slight variations of levels from The Ultimate Doom and Doom II: Hell on Earth. This version of the game uses modified versions of the Jaguar maps.There was more of an emphasis on mood and atmosphere compared to the PC version and utilized colored lighting. The game's soundtrack differs from the PC version and many enemy and weapon sounds were also changed to make them more intimidating. These changes made for a more darker and atmospheric tone for the franchise which carried forward into DOOM 3.Enemies from Doom II were added to levels from the first game for an added challenge. Fans of the game in Doom's active modding community have brought it to the PC using the ZDoom source port to add in the various graphical enhancements unique to this version of Doom.PlayStation 3Released in 2012 in a collection called "Doom Classic Complete" which features The Ultimate Doom, Doom 2, Master Levels for Doom 2. This collection also includes the previously exclusive No Rest for the Living bonus episode from the Xbox 360 release of Doom 2. This port features a stripped down version of idtech 5 for networking and other PSN specific code written during the development of RAGE.Sega 32xPublished by Sega in 1994 this version of the game features 17 levels from episodes 1 and 2 but none from episode 3. The port was criticized for not running in full screen and not including the BFG-9000 weapon although it can be acquired using cheat codes. Just like the Super Nintendo version only the front facing sprites for monsters were included thus eliminating the possibility of monster infighting.When the player finishes level 15 while using cheat codes they are presented with a standard DOS prompt which will remain on screen until the console's reset button is pressed. Only when the player has progressed to level 16 without using cheat codes the gameplay will continue properly. The manual states that the player will start again at level 1 with cheat codes disabled after this point but it does not.Sega SaturnThe Saturn version is very similar to the PlayStation version but does not include the colored lighting. The low frame rate compared to the PlayStation version has this version lacking Doom's trademark fast-paced gameplay. It was said to include link support for Deathmatch and Cooperative multiplayer but was only included in the European and Japanese releases.SNESDoom on the Super Nintendo was released in September 1995 by Williams Entertainment is one of the few games to include a Super-FX 2 chip. This version includes twenty-two levels from the PC version and features the five missing levels from the Jaguar version but instead is missing five different levels and does not include support for saving game progress.Due to hardware limitations monsters can only be viewed from the front making monster infighting impossible, floors and ceilings are not texture mapped and the Spectre enemy is not included being replaced by the regular demon instead. Other limitations include not being able to play Episode 2: The Shores of Hell on I'm too young to die (very easy), and hey not too rough (easy), Episode 3: Inferno can only be played on the ultra violence (very hard) and nightmare (hardest) difficulties. Nightmare difficulty was changed to not have respawning monsters although they are still fast like in the PC version. The shotgun does not spread out but instead fires a single projectile equal to a hit from all particles in the PC version.Automap support utilizes Mode 7 scaling and rotation to allow the map to rotate around the player instead of the player's icon rotating inside of the automap itself a feature unique to this version of the game.The two boss demons, the Spider Mastermind and the Cyberdemon, are included in this version of the game which were missing from other ports of that era. Multiplayer support was included for players with X-BAND modems.WindowsBill Gates at a Microsoft event in 1995Known as WinDoom or Doom95, developed for Windows, unveiled in 1995 and released in 1996, this port capitalized on the popularity of Doom and was used by Microsoft to showcase their new DirectX technology. It supports screen resolutions up to 640x480 and features a GUI launcher allowing easy selection of episode, map, difficulty, custom wads, and multiplayer settings.XboxThis version of Doom was included on the disc with the collectors edition of Doom 3 along with Doom II. This version includes an exclusive secret map in episode 1.Xbox 360Released in 2006, this port was developed by Nerve Software and was made available for download in the Xbox Live Arcade. Single player contains all four episodes and supports multiplayer (splitscreen or online via Xbox Live) Deathmatch and Co-op with up to four players. The Xbox version includes achievements and leaderboards.[CR]Source Code Release[CR]Also see: Source PortOn December 23 1997, Doom's source code was made available to the public. This has now spawned many new 'Doom' engines, such as Boom, ZDoom, GZDoom (OpenGL), and Legacy, these engines and many like them have been developed to 'update' id Software's original engine and most now support all modern windows platforms, run in high resolutions, have optimized online code, free-look (up/down), jumping &amp; crouching, a console, and cross-hairs.These engines require the original DOOM.wad or IWADs to run, and are of course able to play modifications of these files such as NeoDoom.[CR]Unofficial Source Ports[CR]These ports were done after the release of idtech 1's Source Code in 1997. Some of these ports may require additional hardware or software to function.AmigaDoom was ported to the Amiga sometime in 1998 after the release of the source code.AndroidThere are a variety of ports available on the google play store which can be converted into the full version with the WAD files from the PC version.Sega DreamcastThe Sega Dreamcast has several source ports available. DoomDC, last updated in 2002 this source port was the first to be released. This version requires the Dreamcast Keyboard to use some functions such as switching weapons.Another source port is nxDoom which is based on DoomDC. nxDoom runs faster than DoomDC and supports saving, user WADs, .MOD music files, and has all of the games actions mapped to the controller.GP2xPrBoom and ZDoom were ported to this platform.Nintendo DSDSDoom is a port of Doom for the Nintendo DS. This version displays the game on the top screen while displaying the UI as well as automap or console output on the bottom screen. This version supports network play with any prBoom server. Music and custom control layouts are not supported.Nintendo WiiWiiDoom is a port of PrBoom. Doom, Doom 2, Ultimate Doom and Final Doom are supported. The only available control scheme utilizes the Wii Remote and Nunchuck attachment.Sony Playstation 3PrBoom was ported to this platform. This was the only way to play Doom on the Playstation 3 before the release of Doom Classic Complete.Sony Playstation PortableThe original Doom source code as well as Doom Legacy have been ported to this platform.Tapwave ZodiacZdoomZ, a PalmOS port of Linux Doom, runs on the Tapwave Zodiac.Microsoft XboxDoomX is a port of the original source code to the Microsoft Xbox. System Link is supported unlike the port included with Doom 3 Collectors Edition.Microsoft Zune HDDoom for the Zune HD was ported in 2010. Movement is controlled by either tilt or touch controls along with touch buttons for other game actions.[CR]Esoteric Source Ports[CR]Kodak DigitaOS Digital CamerasA dedicated Doom handheld was created using this port as a hackaday project.Doom 3 TerminalsPerhaps the strangest of them all this port requires a copy of the original release of Doom 3 and a PWAD. Once installed the mod includes a test map with a terminal which runs the original doom. Try it out.Garry's ModGMDoom is a partial source port of Doom to Garry's Mod. Weapons, enemies and their behavior can be added in while playing. The mod was released in march 2013 on Steam Workshop.iPodThis source port requires the RockBox alternative firmware. Due to the iPod's media-centric button layout harder difficulties such as ultra violence and nightmare may prove more difficult to play in this versions of the game. Installation instructions can be found here.TI-Nspire CalculatorsnDoom supports all retail wads for Doom, Doom 2, Ultimate Doom, and Final Doom.[CR]System Requirements[CR]Minimum System Requirements386sx IBM compatible computerMS-DOS v3.3 or higherVGA (320x200x256) graphics4mb RAMHard Drive - 4.8 MB (Shareware), 12 MB (Mail-order)[CR]Original Release Versions[CR]Shareware VersionIncludes one of the three episodesIncludes network and modem supportMail-order VersionAll shareware featuresIncludes all three episodes (three episodes each with eight levels and a secret level)Includes Plasma rifleIncludes BFG 9000Versionsv0.2 - February 4, 1993 (alpha version)v0.4 - April 2, 1993 (alpha version)v0.5 - May 22, 1993 (alpha version)v1.0 - December 10, 1993 (uses v0.99 engine)v1.1 - December 16, 1993v1.2 - February 17, 1994 (introduced modem support and Nightmare mode)v1.3 - undocumented / never releasedv1.4 - June 1994 (Internet Beta version)v1.5 - July 8, 1994 (Internet Beta version)v1.6 - August 1994 (Internet Beta version)v1.666 - September 1994v1.7 - October 11, 1994v1.7a - November 8, 1994v1.8 - January 23, 1995v1.9 - February 1, 1995 (the final version)Ultimate Doom, released April 1995, used a slightly modified version of the engine however the version number was not updated.On December 23 1997 the Doom source code was released, this code has the version number 1.10Referencing this new version, source port authors (e.g., ZDoom) often began their versions with 1.11On October 4, 1993 an early beta version of the game was made available to journalists. While this version of the game is similar to the final version (unlike the earlier alpha versions) their are still several key differences most notably the BFG9000 which fired 40 quick bursts of plasma gun ammo. This was changed due to the large number of sprites on screen causing the PC to slowdown. Also, this version has a scoring system. The player could gain score by killing enemies and collecting score giving items such as the Demonic Dagger. The scoring system and scoring items did not make it into the final version of the game.[CR]</plot>
		<releasedate>13/8/1994</releasedate>
		<year>1994</year>
		<genre>Action</genre>
		<studio>Sega</studio>
		<nplayers>1</nplayers>
		<perspective>1st-Person</perspective>
		<rating>2.7</rating>
		<ESRB>M - Mature</ESRB>
		<thegamesdb_id>4917</thegamesdb_id>
		<mobygames_url>https://www.mobygames.com/game/sega-32x/doom</mobygames_url>
		<giantbomb_url>https://www.giantbomb.com/doom/3030-7326/</giantbomb_url>
		<boxart1>sgS4x89.jpg</boxart1>
		<boxart2>56ATDQQ.jpg</boxart2>
		<boxart3>99jFzCk.jpg</boxart3>
		<boxart4>cQksTEa.jpg</boxart4>
		<boxart5>Lxu9XIb.jpg</boxart5>
		<snapshot1>QHw8KlT.jpg</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>cERGgic.gif</snapshot2>
		<snapshot3>29TWMvM.gif</snapshot3>
		<snapshot4>oljl9wz.gif</snapshot4>
		<snapshot5>P9QMqoc.gif</snapshot5>
		<snapshot6>lDyIh44.gif</snapshot6>
		<snapshot7>EW07ygc.gif</snapshot7>
		<snapshot8>MuVeLsp.gif</snapshot8>
		<snapshot9>5hWLivC.png</snapshot9>
		<snapshot10>nbXDsHC.png</snapshot10>
		<fanart1>gZdpqh0.jpg</fanart1>
		<fanart2>8eoNg7W.jpg</fanart2>
		<fanart3>ChyLM5c.jpg</fanart3>
		<banner1>HrHEpAU.jpg</banner1>
		<clearlogo1>6LsdlQb.png</clearlogo1>
	</game>
	<game name="Doom (Europe)">
		<description>Doom (Europe)</description>
		<rom crc="53734E3A" name="Sega_32X/Doom%20%28Europe%29.32x" sha1="4EC03C2114EBFFBBCD16859583340D4EA4CD8DD5" size="1490927" />
		<title_clean>Doom</title_clean>
		<plot>[CR][B]Overview:[/B][CR]Doom is a sci-fi horror first-person shooter developed and published by id for the PC (running MS-DOS) on December 10, 1993.As a nameless space marine, players trek through over 24 levels (split up into three episodes), where they liberate space stations from demon infestation in both Phobos and Deimos, only to take on Hell. The game's engine (later known as id Tech 1) is known to pioneer new features to the genre, including non-perpendicular walls, complex rooms (known as "sectors") with varying height differences, multiplayer (both co-operatively and competitively, for up to four players at a time) and the concept of packaging the game's content (levels, sounds, and music) into singular data files (WAD files) for easier modification and distribution, leading to the birth of the modern mod-making community.The lore of the game, set sometime into the future, involves the Union Aerospace Corporation (U.A.C.), a multi-planetary conglomerate that has been utilized by the Earth military to secretly experiment on alien teleportation technology discovered on the moons of Mars. As they try to establish a gateway between the two moons using this technology, the experiment goes awry and the demons of Hell use the portals to invade the two moons. As the last man standing guarding the Hangar of the U.A.C. space station on Phobos, the lone space marine must fight through the onslaught to keep them from attacking Earth.While the original game was a shareware mail-order release, a special edition of the game (known as The Ultimate Doom) was later distributed in retail boxed format. Also released as a free upgrade for those who own the original game, The Ultimate Doom added a new epilogue episode (Thy Flesh Consumed) bridging the game with its sequel, Doom II: Hell on Earth. The original game also spawned multiple sequels and reboots, numerous console ports, a 2005 sci-fi action film, and a wide variety of unofficial source ports and enhancements (thanks to the decision to release the source code with minimal restriction).[CR][B]Gameplay:[/B][CR]In Doom, players progress through each level, blasting away enemies while solving puzzles (involving switches, keycards, and skull-shaped key devices), avoiding environmental hazards (such as crushing ceilings, radioactive acid, and burning lava), and collecting weapons, ammo, and other items (including first-aid kits, body armor, suits that protect from radiation, night-vision goggles, computer maps, and supernatural orbs that grant a special bonus to the player). Unlike id's previous first-person shooter, Spear of Destiny, Doom does not include a scoring or lives system. Players who die can retry the level at the cost of resetting their inventory and stats.Episodes and DifficultiesThe game's campaign is split up into three episodes (each with eight normal levels and one secret level):Knee-Deep in the Dead - The only episode playable in the shareware version, the first episode deals with the marine's journey through the base established on Phobos.The Shores of Hell - After defeating the two big bruisers guarding the teleportation gateway, the marine passes through into Deimos. As the invasion continues, the base becomes more distorted with hellish architecture. The second episode deals with the marine's liberation of demons from the Deimos base.Inferno - Eventually, the marine fights a giant anomaly of flesh and metal (known as the Cyberdemon) in the "Tower of Babel", only to find out Deimos has been teleported to the infernal afterlife, and that the tower connects the moon to Hell itself! The third (and final) episode has the marine blindly wreaking havoc in Hell until he can find the mastermind behind the invasion.Players who are starting a new game can start at the beginning of an episode (starting with no armor and a pistol with 50 bullets). Starting from the second episode, players can find two new cell energy weapons (the uncommon Plasma Gun and the rare BFG-9000) and two new common enemies (the Cacodemon and the Lost Soul). Players can pick between five difficulties (known as "skill levels"):I'm too young to die. - Fewer monsters and more items. Double ammo granted on weapon and ammo pickups. Players take half damage.Hey, not too rough. - Fewer monsters and more items.Hurt me plenty. - Normal difficulty.Ultra-Violence. - More monsters and fewer items.Nightmare! - Added in v1.2. Cheat codes are disabled. More monsters and fewer items. Double ammo granted on weapon and ammo pickups. Monsters react and move faster, and respawn shortly after death.[CR][B]Weapons:[/B][CR]FistFistDamage: 10 per punch, 200 with Berserk PackOne of two starting weapons. The fist is simple and effective against weaker enemies but when a Berserk Pack power up is activated it boosts the attack power of the fist considerably allowing the Doom marine to tear through and even gib many enemies with ease.From the manual: "Can be used to punch enemies. It will always be with you."ChainsawChainsawDamage: 20 per 'hit'A powerful melee weapon capable of stunning some enemies.From the manual: "Cuts down the baddies like standing timber, but you have to get close."PistolPistolDamage: 10 per bulletThe second starting weapon. The pistol is one of two weapons to utilize bullets as its ammunition.From the manual: "Your standard military-issue weapon. It will stay with you, so don't forget about it if things get tough."ShotgunShotgunDamage: 10 per pellet, 7 pellets per shell, 70 damage maximumThe shotgun is a very effective weapon to use on most enemies the Doom marine will encounter. Its multi-pellet spread is very useful for crowds. The shotgun is the only weapon to use shells as its ammunition.From the manual: "Deliver a heavy punch at close range and a generous pelting from a distance."ChaingunChaingunDamage: 10 per bulletThe chaingun, like the pistol, uses bullets as its source of ammunition. This rapid-firing machine gun can stun some enemies so it is most effective against a single enemy.From the manual: "Direct heavy firepower into your opponent, making him do the chaingun cha-cha."Rocket LauncherRocket LauncherDamage: 200 per rocketThe Rocket Launcher is one of three weapons capable of gibbing enemies. Rockets deliver splash damage very well so they are ideal for dealing with crowds. This weapon is the only one in the game to use rockets as its ammunition.From the manual: "Deliver an explosive rocket that can turn one bad dude inside-out."Plasma RiflePlasma RifleDamage: 20 per cellThe fastest firing weapon in the game, this weapon is very powerful and effective against whatever it is the Doom marine may encounter. The plasma rifle is one of two weapons to utilize cells as its ammunition.From the manual: "Shoot multiple rounds of plasma energy - frying some demon butt!"BFG 9000BFG 9000Damage: 1000 per blast, 40 cells expendedThe BFG 9000 fires a huge plasma ball which moves slowly through the air. Upon impact, the target it hits receives a huge amount of damage and lots of splash damage as well.From the manual: "The prize of the military arsenal. Great for clearing the room of an unwelcome guest. Shoot it and see for yourself."[CR][B]Enemies:[/B][CR]Former HumanHealth: 20Total in single player (ultra violence) : 311From the manual: "Once a marine, always a marine-- except in this case. These guys may look like your old buddies, but now they're nothing more than pistol-toting bi-pedal maggots. Waste em!"Former Human SergeantHealth: 30Total in single player (ultra violence) : 426From the manual: "Ditto. Except these guys are meaner and tougher. These walking shotguns will provide you with a few extra holes if you're not careful."ImpHealth: 60Total in single player (ultra violence) : 719From the manual: "You though an imp was a cute little dude in a red suit with a pitchfork. Think again. This Imp heaves balls of fire down your throat and takes several bullets to die. It's time to find a better weapon than a pistol if you're going to face more than one of these mutants."DemonHealth: 140Total in single player (ultra violence) : 389From the manual: "Sorta like shaved gorillas, except with big heads and lots of teeth. They don't kill easy. Get too close and they'll rip your sorry head off."SpectreHealth: 140Total in single player (ultra violence) : 114From the manual: "Great. Just what you needed. An invisible (nearly) monster. Did you expect a walk in the park?"Lost SoulHealth: 100Total in single player (ultra violence) : 242From the manual: "Dumb. Tough. Flies. On Fire. 'Nuff said."CacodemonHealth: 400Total in single player (ultra violence) : 126From the manual: "They float in the air, belch ball lightning, and have one horrendously big mouth. If you get too close to one of these monstrosities, You're Toast."Baron of HellHealth: 1000Total in single player (ultra violence) : 37From the manual: "Tough as a dump truck and nearly as big, these goliaths are the worst thing on two legs since Tyrannosaurus Rex."CyberdemonHealth: 4000Total in single player (ultra violence) : 2From the manual: "Half unfeeling machine, half raging horned devil. This walking nightmare has a rocket launcher for an arm and will definitely reach out and touch you. Make sure you're loaded for bear before you get to this guy."Spiderdemon (Spider Mastermind)Health: 3000Total in single player (ultra violence) : 1From the manual: "Maybe cybernetics wasn't such a great idea after all. Look what the demons have done with it. It somehow seems unfair that you're not the only guy in Hell with a chaingun. Nope, she has a Super-Chaingun don't you just love it?"[CR]Episodes and Maps[CR]Knee-Deep in the Dead (E1)Level NameMap SlotDesignerPar TimeHangerE1M1John Romero0:30Nuclear PlantE1M2John Romero1:15Toxin RefineryE1M3John Romero2:00Command ControlE1M4Tom Hall, John Romero1:30Phobos LabE1M5John Romero2:45Central ProcessingE1M6John Romero3:00Computer StationE1M7John Romero3:00Phobos AnomalyE1M8Sandy Petersen, Tom HallN/AMilitary Base (secret level)E1M9John Romero2:45Sewers (Xbox only secret map)E1M10David Calvin0:00The Shores of Hell (E2)Level NameMap SlotDesignerPar timeDeimos AnomalyE2M1Sandy Petersen, Tom Hall1:30Containment AreaE2M2Tom Hall, Sandy Petersen1:30RefineryE2M3Tom Hall, Sandy Petersen1:30Deimos LabE2M4Tom Hall, Sandy Petersen2:00Command CenterE2M5Sandy Petersen1:30Hall of the DamnedE2M6Sandy Petersen6:00Spawning VatsE2M7Tom Hall, Sandy Petersen4:00Tower of BabelE2M8Sandy PetersenN/AFortress of MysteryE2M9Sandy Petersen2:50Inferno (E3)Level NameMap SlotDesignerPar TimeHell KeepE3M1Sandy Petersen1:30Slough of DespairE3M2Sandy Petersen0:45PandemoniumE3M3Tom Hall, Sandy Petersen1:30House of PainE3M4Sandy Petersen2:30Unholy CathedralE3M5Sandy Petersen1:30Mt. ErebusE3M6Sandy Petersen1:30LimboE3M7Tom Hall, Sandy Petersen2:45DisE3M8Sandy PetersenN/AWarrensE3M9Sandy Petersen2:15[CR]Official Ports[CR]Atari JaguarThe first console port developed by id Software, the Jaguar version of Doom was released in 1994. The game engine was largely developed by John Carmack. 22 of the original 27 levels are included, though modified and simplified, and two new maps are included. Music is only included during the title screen and between-level screens. Two player multiplayer Deathmatch and Co-op modes are available through JagLink.The code developed for this port served as the basis for future ports including the Sega 32X (which was released before the Jaguar version), the 3DO, GameBoy Advance, and PlayStation.Game Boy AdvanceBased on the Jaguar port, the GBA version of Doom was released by David A. Palmer Productions in 2001. Five new multiplayer-only maps were designed for this version.iPhone / iPod TouchAn official iOS port of Doom, titled Classic Doom, was released by id Software in 2009. The port is based on the source port PrBoom which allows for OpenGL rendering.LinuxThe Linux port of Doom was created by Dave Taylor of id Software and released in 1994. The source code of this port was made available to the public in 1997 and is the basis for all subsequent source ports.MS-DOSThe original version of Doom.PlayStationDoom on the Sony PlayStation is more of a re-imagining. It features slight variations of levels from The Ultimate Doom and Doom II: Hell on Earth. This version of the game uses modified versions of the Jaguar maps.There was more of an emphasis on mood and atmosphere compared to the PC version and utilized colored lighting. The game's soundtrack differs from the PC version and many enemy and weapon sounds were also changed to make them more intimidating. These changes made for a more darker and atmospheric tone for the franchise which carried forward into DOOM 3.Enemies from Doom II were added to levels from the first game for an added challenge. Fans of the game in Doom's active modding community have brought it to the PC using the ZDoom source port to add in the various graphical enhancements unique to this version of Doom.PlayStation 3Released in 2012 in a collection called "Doom Classic Complete" which features The Ultimate Doom, Doom 2, Master Levels for Doom 2. This collection also includes the previously exclusive No Rest for the Living bonus episode from the Xbox 360 release of Doom 2. This port features a stripped down version of idtech 5 for networking and other PSN specific code written during the development of RAGE.Sega 32xPublished by Sega in 1994 this version of the game features 17 levels from episodes 1 and 2 but none from episode 3. The port was criticized for not running in full screen and not including the BFG-9000 weapon although it can be acquired using cheat codes. Just like the Super Nintendo version only the front facing sprites for monsters were included thus eliminating the possibility of monster infighting.When the player finishes level 15 while using cheat codes they are presented with a standard DOS prompt which will remain on screen until the console's reset button is pressed. Only when the player has progressed to level 16 without using cheat codes the gameplay will continue properly. The manual states that the player will start again at level 1 with cheat codes disabled after this point but it does not.Sega SaturnThe Saturn version is very similar to the PlayStation version but does not include the colored lighting. The low frame rate compared to the PlayStation version has this version lacking Doom's trademark fast-paced gameplay. It was said to include link support for Deathmatch and Cooperative multiplayer but was only included in the European and Japanese releases.SNESDoom on the Super Nintendo was released in September 1995 by Williams Entertainment is one of the few games to include a Super-FX 2 chip. This version includes twenty-two levels from the PC version and features the five missing levels from the Jaguar version but instead is missing five different levels and does not include support for saving game progress.Due to hardware limitations monsters can only be viewed from the front making monster infighting impossible, floors and ceilings are not texture mapped and the Spectre enemy is not included being replaced by the regular demon instead. Other limitations include not being able to play Episode 2: The Shores of Hell on I'm too young to die (very easy), and hey not too rough (easy), Episode 3: Inferno can only be played on the ultra violence (very hard) and nightmare (hardest) difficulties. Nightmare difficulty was changed to not have respawning monsters although they are still fast like in the PC version. The shotgun does not spread out but instead fires a single projectile equal to a hit from all particles in the PC version.Automap support utilizes Mode 7 scaling and rotation to allow the map to rotate around the player instead of the player's icon rotating inside of the automap itself a feature unique to this version of the game.The two boss demons, the Spider Mastermind and the Cyberdemon, are included in this version of the game which were missing from other ports of that era. Multiplayer support was included for players with X-BAND modems.WindowsBill Gates at a Microsoft event in 1995Known as WinDoom or Doom95, developed for Windows, unveiled in 1995 and released in 1996, this port capitalized on the popularity of Doom and was used by Microsoft to showcase their new DirectX technology. It supports screen resolutions up to 640x480 and features a GUI launcher allowing easy selection of episode, map, difficulty, custom wads, and multiplayer settings.XboxThis version of Doom was included on the disc with the collectors edition of Doom 3 along with Doom II. This version includes an exclusive secret map in episode 1.Xbox 360Released in 2006, this port was developed by Nerve Software and was made available for download in the Xbox Live Arcade. Single player contains all four episodes and supports multiplayer (splitscreen or online via Xbox Live) Deathmatch and Co-op with up to four players. The Xbox version includes achievements and leaderboards.[CR]Source Code Release[CR]Also see: Source PortOn December 23 1997, Doom's source code was made available to the public. This has now spawned many new 'Doom' engines, such as Boom, ZDoom, GZDoom (OpenGL), and Legacy, these engines and many like them have been developed to 'update' id Software's original engine and most now support all modern windows platforms, run in high resolutions, have optimized online code, free-look (up/down), jumping &amp; crouching, a console, and cross-hairs.These engines require the original DOOM.wad or IWADs to run, and are of course able to play modifications of these files such as NeoDoom.[CR]Unofficial Source Ports[CR]These ports were done after the release of idtech 1's Source Code in 1997. Some of these ports may require additional hardware or software to function.AmigaDoom was ported to the Amiga sometime in 1998 after the release of the source code.AndroidThere are a variety of ports available on the google play store which can be converted into the full version with the WAD files from the PC version.Sega DreamcastThe Sega Dreamcast has several source ports available. DoomDC, last updated in 2002 this source port was the first to be released. This version requires the Dreamcast Keyboard to use some functions such as switching weapons.Another source port is nxDoom which is based on DoomDC. nxDoom runs faster than DoomDC and supports saving, user WADs, .MOD music files, and has all of the games actions mapped to the controller.GP2xPrBoom and ZDoom were ported to this platform.Nintendo DSDSDoom is a port of Doom for the Nintendo DS. This version displays the game on the top screen while displaying the UI as well as automap or console output on the bottom screen. This version supports network play with any prBoom server. Music and custom control layouts are not supported.Nintendo WiiWiiDoom is a port of PrBoom. Doom, Doom 2, Ultimate Doom and Final Doom are supported. The only available control scheme utilizes the Wii Remote and Nunchuck attachment.Sony Playstation 3PrBoom was ported to this platform. This was the only way to play Doom on the Playstation 3 before the release of Doom Classic Complete.Sony Playstation PortableThe original Doom source code as well as Doom Legacy have been ported to this platform.Tapwave ZodiacZdoomZ, a PalmOS port of Linux Doom, runs on the Tapwave Zodiac.Microsoft XboxDoomX is a port of the original source code to the Microsoft Xbox. System Link is supported unlike the port included with Doom 3 Collectors Edition.Microsoft Zune HDDoom for the Zune HD was ported in 2010. Movement is controlled by either tilt or touch controls along with touch buttons for other game actions.[CR]Esoteric Source Ports[CR]Kodak DigitaOS Digital CamerasA dedicated Doom handheld was created using this port as a hackaday project.Doom 3 TerminalsPerhaps the strangest of them all this port requires a copy of the original release of Doom 3 and a PWAD. Once installed the mod includes a test map with a terminal which runs the original doom. Try it out.Garry's ModGMDoom is a partial source port of Doom to Garry's Mod. Weapons, enemies and their behavior can be added in while playing. The mod was released in march 2013 on Steam Workshop.iPodThis source port requires the RockBox alternative firmware. Due to the iPod's media-centric button layout harder difficulties such as ultra violence and nightmare may prove more difficult to play in this versions of the game. Installation instructions can be found here.TI-Nspire CalculatorsnDoom supports all retail wads for Doom, Doom 2, Ultimate Doom, and Final Doom.[CR]System Requirements[CR]Minimum System Requirements386sx IBM compatible computerMS-DOS v3.3 or higherVGA (320x200x256) graphics4mb RAMHard Drive - 4.8 MB (Shareware), 12 MB (Mail-order)[CR]Original Release Versions[CR]Shareware VersionIncludes one of the three episodesIncludes network and modem supportMail-order VersionAll shareware featuresIncludes all three episodes (three episodes each with eight levels and a secret level)Includes Plasma rifleIncludes BFG 9000Versionsv0.2 - February 4, 1993 (alpha version)v0.4 - April 2, 1993 (alpha version)v0.5 - May 22, 1993 (alpha version)v1.0 - December 10, 1993 (uses v0.99 engine)v1.1 - December 16, 1993v1.2 - February 17, 1994 (introduced modem support and Nightmare mode)v1.3 - undocumented / never releasedv1.4 - June 1994 (Internet Beta version)v1.5 - July 8, 1994 (Internet Beta version)v1.6 - August 1994 (Internet Beta version)v1.666 - September 1994v1.7 - October 11, 1994v1.7a - November 8, 1994v1.8 - January 23, 1995v1.9 - February 1, 1995 (the final version)Ultimate Doom, released April 1995, used a slightly modified version of the engine however the version number was not updated.On December 23 1997 the Doom source code was released, this code has the version number 1.10Referencing this new version, source port authors (e.g., ZDoom) often began their versions with 1.11On October 4, 1993 an early beta version of the game was made available to journalists. While this version of the game is similar to the final version (unlike the earlier alpha versions) their are still several key differences most notably the BFG9000 which fired 40 quick bursts of plasma gun ammo. This was changed due to the large number of sprites on screen causing the PC to slowdown. Also, this version has a scoring system. The player could gain score by killing enemies and collecting score giving items such as the Demonic Dagger. The scoring system and scoring items did not make it into the final version of the game.[CR]</plot>
		<releasedate>13/8/1994</releasedate>
		<year>1994</year>
		<genre>Action</genre>
		<studio>Sega</studio>
		<nplayers>1</nplayers>
		<perspective>1st-Person</perspective>
		<rating>2.7</rating>
		<ESRB>M - Mature</ESRB>
		<thegamesdb_id>4917</thegamesdb_id>
		<mobygames_url>https://www.mobygames.com/game/sega-32x/doom</mobygames_url>
		<giantbomb_url>https://www.giantbomb.com/doom/3030-7326/</giantbomb_url>
		<boxart1>iBLxTbK.png</boxart1>
		<boxart2>56ATDQQ.jpg</boxart2>
		<boxart3>99jFzCk.jpg</boxart3>
		<boxart4>cQksTEa.jpg</boxart4>
		<boxart5>Lxu9XIb.jpg</boxart5>
		<snapshot1>QHw8KlT.jpg</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>cERGgic.gif</snapshot2>
		<snapshot3>29TWMvM.gif</snapshot3>
		<snapshot4>oljl9wz.gif</snapshot4>
		<snapshot5>P9QMqoc.gif</snapshot5>
		<snapshot6>lDyIh44.gif</snapshot6>
		<snapshot7>EW07ygc.gif</snapshot7>
		<snapshot8>MuVeLsp.gif</snapshot8>
		<snapshot9>5hWLivC.png</snapshot9>
		<snapshot10>nbXDsHC.png</snapshot10>
		<fanart1>gZdpqh0.jpg</fanart1>
		<fanart2>8eoNg7W.jpg</fanart2>
		<fanart3>ChyLM5c.jpg</fanart3>
		<banner1>HrHEpAU.jpg</banner1>
		<clearlogo1>6LsdlQb.png</clearlogo1>
	</game>
	<game name="ECCO the Dolphin CinePak Demo (Japan, USA) (Developer Cart)">
		<description>ECCO the Dolphin CinePak Demo (Japan, USA) (Developer Cart)</description>
		<rom crc="B06178DF" name="Sega_32X/ECCO%20the%20Dolphin%20CinePak%20Demo%20%28Japan%2C%20USA%29%20%28Developer%20Cart%29.32x" sha1="10409F2245B058E8A32CBA51E1EA391CA4480108" size="1749084" />
		<title_clean>ECCO the Dolphin CinePak Demo</title_clean>
	</game>
	<game name="FIFA Soccer '96 (Europe) (En,Fr,De,Es,It,Sv)">
		<description>FIFA Soccer '96 (Europe) (En,Fr,De,Es,It,Sv)</description>
		<rom crc="FB14A7C8" name="Sega_32X/FIFA%20Soccer%2096%20%28Europe%29%20%28En%2CFr%2CDe%2CEs%2CIt%2CSv%29.32x" sha1="131EBB717DEE4DD1D8F5AB2B9393C23785D3A359" size="1286907" />
		<title_clean>FIFA Soccer '96</title_clean>
		<plot>"Aiming to be the first football simulation that is realistic in the true sense of the word, FIFA Soccer 96 was extremely popular at the time of release. It was hailed as the first really successful FIFA release, and opened the way for yearly revisions of the concept.[CR]There were a number of factors that made FIFA96 stand out from the crowd of other football sims. Firstly, the game's commentary was revolutionary at the time -- the renowned British commentator John Motson comments all the incidents and happenings on the pitch in real-time. The ambient commentary is varied, and systems with more than the minimum memory level get extra commentary phrases.[CR]The Virtual Stadium technology has numerous pre-defined camera angles. The game even has a SVGA mode for better-than-minimum system[CR]FIFA96 boasts eleven leagues from all around the world, ranging from the unknown players of the Malaysian league to the celebrated stars of the English and Italian leagues. 59 International teams are also featured, and it's possible to match the teams you want to against each other through friendlies, or you can also choose to play domestic tournaments or International ones such as the World Cup. If you're not satisfied with the composition of the various teams, you can create your own dream team through the custom team creator.</plot>
		<releasedate>13/8/1995</releasedate>
		<year>1995</year>
		<studio>Electronic Arts</studio>
		<nplayers>1-2 Sim</nplayers>
		<videoid>BH1dMPIcMB8</videoid>
		<thegamesdb_id>20522</thegamesdb_id>
		<mobygames_url>https://www.mobygames.com/game/sega-32x/fifa-soccer-96</mobygames_url>
		<consolegrid_url>http://consolegrid.com/games/4459</consolegrid_url>
		<boxart1>bFqbOSI.jpg</boxart1>
		<boxart2>x1crK4H.jpg</boxart2>
		<snapshot1>RXJo8FO.png</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>r1QI6SG.png</snapshot2>
		<snapshot3>SLplxpN.png</snapshot3>
		<snapshot4>yzMlNPS.png</snapshot4>
		<snapshot5>ci6xZkc.png</snapshot5>
		<snapshot6>u8sTl0a.png</snapshot6>
		<snapshot7>G9VefXW.png</snapshot7>
		<snapshot8>SQMjiPH.png</snapshot8>
		<banner1>SRRWyQW.png</banner1>
		<clearlogo1>9WvQAqS.png</clearlogo1>
	</game>
	<game name="Golf Magazine 36 Great Holes Starring Fred Couples (Europe)">
		<description>Golf Magazine 36 Great Holes Starring Fred Couples (Europe)</description>
		<rom crc="6EF99202" name="Sega_32X/Golf%20Magazine%2036%20Great%20Holes%20Starring%20Fred%20Couples%20%28Europe%29.32x" sha1="55848F7C54533FD2A19011DB661EF261CD8BDB22" size="1988981" />
		<title_clean>Golf Magazine 36 Great Holes Starring Fred Couples</title_clean>
		<plot>As the title implies, in 36 Great Holes the player takes control of 24 different digitized golfers  12 males and 12 females  playing in 27 historic courses in the U.S. including Disney's Eagle Pines and Tidewater Golf Club, playing 36 authentic holes.  [CR]There are seven different modes (Stroke Play, Tournament, Skins, Shoot-out, Scramble, Practice and Match Play) and three different types of golf club heads including wood, metal and graphite. There is a battery back-up to keep track of 16 different categories of stats and does feature the voice of Fred Couples, even though he is not a playable character.</plot>
		<releasedate>13/8/1994</releasedate>
		<year>1994</year>
		<genre>Sports</genre>
		<studio>Sega</studio>
		<nplayers>1-8 Sim</nplayers>
		<perspective>3rd-Person</perspective>
		<rating>3.5</rating>
		<ESRB>E - Everyone</ESRB>
		<thegamesdb_id>4911</thegamesdb_id>
		<mobygames_url>https://www.mobygames.com/game/sega-32x/golf-magazine-presents-36-great-holes-starring-fred-couples</mobygames_url>
		<giantbomb_url>https://www.giantbomb.com/golf-magazine-presents-36-great-holes-starring-fre/3030-21309/</giantbomb_url>
		<boxart1>Gs3xULm.jpg</boxart1>
		<boxart2>iFsrGK1.jpg</boxart2>
		<boxart3>4astGiI.jpg</boxart3>
		<snapshot1>WMk7aA8.png</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>6QqxSZZ.png</snapshot2>
		<snapshot3>bfTrYZ9.png</snapshot3>
		<snapshot4>CGLZjVG.png</snapshot4>
		<snapshot5>ltHx5vV.png</snapshot5>
		<snapshot6>R1Hykh5.png</snapshot6>
		<snapshot7>18LwSyG.png</snapshot7>
		<snapshot8>oTdZLYI.png</snapshot8>
		<snapshot9>mcXd23U.png</snapshot9>
		<snapshot10>0soMLfY.png</snapshot10>
	</game>
	<game name="Golf Magazine 36 Great Holes Starring Fred Couples (Japan, USA)">
		<description>Golf Magazine 36 Great Holes Starring Fred Couples (Japan, USA)</description>
		<rom crc="D3D0A2FE" name="Sega_32X/Golf%20Magazine%2036%20Great%20Holes%20Starring%20Fred%20Couples%20%28Japan%2C%20USA%29.32x" sha1="DC77B1E5C888C2C4284766915A5020BB14EE681D" size="1989159" />
		<title_clean>Golf Magazine 36 Great Holes Starring Fred Couples</title_clean>
		<plot>As the title implies, in 36 Great Holes the player takes control of 24 different digitized golfers  12 males and 12 females  playing in 27 historic courses in the U.S. including Disney's Eagle Pines and Tidewater Golf Club, playing 36 authentic holes.  [CR]There are seven different modes (Stroke Play, Tournament, Skins, Shoot-out, Scramble, Practice and Match Play) and three different types of golf club heads including wood, metal and graphite. There is a battery back-up to keep track of 16 different categories of stats and does feature the voice of Fred Couples, even though he is not a playable character.</plot>
		<releasedate>13/8/1994</releasedate>
		<year>1994</year>
		<genre>Sports</genre>
		<studio>Sega</studio>
		<nplayers>1-8 Sim</nplayers>
		<perspective>3rd-Person</perspective>
		<rating>3.5</rating>
		<ESRB>E - Everyone</ESRB>
		<thegamesdb_id>4911</thegamesdb_id>
		<mobygames_url>https://www.mobygames.com/game/sega-32x/golf-magazine-presents-36-great-holes-starring-fred-couples</mobygames_url>
		<giantbomb_url>https://www.giantbomb.com/golf-magazine-presents-36-great-holes-starring-fre/3030-21309/</giantbomb_url>
		<boxart1>srrTggS.jpg</boxart1>
		<boxart2>iFsrGK1.jpg</boxart2>
		<boxart3>4astGiI.jpg</boxart3>
		<snapshot1>WMk7aA8.png</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>6QqxSZZ.png</snapshot2>
		<snapshot3>bfTrYZ9.png</snapshot3>
		<snapshot4>CGLZjVG.png</snapshot4>
		<snapshot5>ltHx5vV.png</snapshot5>
		<snapshot6>R1Hykh5.png</snapshot6>
		<snapshot7>18LwSyG.png</snapshot7>
		<snapshot8>oTdZLYI.png</snapshot8>
		<snapshot9>mcXd23U.png</snapshot9>
		<snapshot10>0soMLfY.png</snapshot10>
	</game>
	<game name="Knuckles' Chaotix (Europe)">
		<description>Knuckles' Chaotix (Europe)</description>
		<rom crc="41D63572" name="Sega_32X/Knuckles%20Chaotix%20%28Europe%29.32x" sha1="5C1A2E327A656217604D4BAE7E141764A7E59922" size="1703062" />
		<title_clean>Knuckles' Chaotix</title_clean>
		<plot>[CR][B]Overview:[/B][CR]  Left to right: Vector, Knuckles, Espio, Mighty, Charmy Knuckles' Chaotix (known in Japan simply as Chaotix) is a side-scrolling action platformer developed and published by  Sega for the Sega 32X on April 20, 1995. It is the only game from the  Sonic the Hedgehog franchise to be released on the short-lived add-on for the Sega Genesis, pushing the limits of the console while introducing new characters and gameplay mechanics.  Knuckles' Chaotix is the first game in the franchise to not feature either Sonic the Hedgehog or Miles "Tails" Prower as playable characters. Instead, player one can pick from five playable characters (including  Knuckles the Echidna, who was previously playable in Sonic &amp; Knuckles, and  Mighty the Armadillo, who was previously playable in SegaSonic the Hedgehog) while player two (either human or computer-controlled) is chosen in a "crane game" fashion (including spots for the two "booby trap" characters). The game introduces the Chaotix, a three-man dysfunctional team of animals who help Knuckles and Mighty save Carnival Island from the evil Dr. Robotnik (and his robot lackey,  Metal Sonic). The game also introduces Heavy and Bomb, two of Dr. Robotnik's former 'badniks' who also assist the protagonists. Each character has their own unique traits and abilities:  Knuckles the Echidna - Like his appearance in Sonic &amp; Knuckles, Knuckles has the ability to glide through the air (by holding down the Jump button) and freely climb walls. Mighty the Armadillo - Mighty is the fastest character in the game and has the ability to wall jump (by tapping the Jump button at the wall, then tapping it again). Espio the Chameleon - Espio can walk upright on walls and ceilings (by holding down the Jump button while approaching a wall) and can destroy most enemies by charging at them. Charmy Bee - The shortest character of the group, Charmy is unable to attack enemies, but can fly indefinitely while being able to carry the other player with him (by holding down a direction and pressing the Jump button in mid-air). Vector the Crocodile - The tallest character of the group, Vector can perform a dash attack (by pressing the Jump button in mid-air) and can climb up walls (like Knuckles, only it's required to hold down the Jump button).Heavy - Although Heavy is invincible to all attacks (and can destroy enemies by colliding with them), he has low jumping ability and is extremely hard to pull around by other players.Bomb - Although lightweight, Bomb explodes (and then regenerates) when it collides with an enemy, causing damage to all nearby objects (both enemies and the other player).[CR][B]Gameplay:[/B][CR]The 'Hold' mechanism Whilst Knuckles Chaotix is similar to previous 2D Sonic the Hedgehog games in terms of working through a 2D platform level with elements of speed, collecting rings a long the way, Knuckles' Chaotix introduced a buddy system where two characters are connected at all times by a ring. This connection can be stretched like an elastic band, and so can be used to propel characters along the levels either horizontally or vertically, and is also used to open doors and complete some small puzzles when one character stands still and 'holds' the ring whilst the other character runs in a direction to stretch the link between them. This system is used for multiplayer cooperative play between two players that operate on the same screen, or can be controlled by the computer within single player. [CR][B]Stages:[/B][CR]Similar to how characters can be chosen using the 'Combi-Catcher' between stages, the stages themselves are also chosen at random using a similar device. There are up to five 'acts' and each are chosen randomly, rather than completed in turn, with a boss at the end of each stage. When a stage is complete, it cannot be selected anymore. The stages are:Speed SliderBotanic BaseA lush green area of the island within a greenhouse that holds beautiful plants and deadly badniks.Speed SliderBased on past Sonic levels such as Casino Night, Speed Slider is a speedy rollercoaster-based level with dips and slides and a merry-go-round, and a section within the middle of the stage that dips up and down.Amazing ArenaAt the start of this stage, the area is grey with full music. You must find the light switch to 'switch on' the stage into a colourful musical stage. This stage is maze-like with many different teleporters and platforms.Marina MadnessA stage based on a cruise, the 'ship' moves up and down the stage, revealing different platforming areas.Techno TowerA futuristic tower, where you must climb all the way to the very top![CR]Bonus and Special Stage[CR]The Special Stage By finding large hidden rings, you can access the Bonus Stage if you have 20 rings. The bonus stage is a vertical free falling mini-game where you navigate past blocks to pick up power ups, extra rings, lives and other bonuses, such as the ability to move the 'Combi-Catcher' freely when selecting a character. You lose rings as you float down the bonus stage, which ends when you either touch a 'End' block or run out of rings.The Special Stage is accessed by a large ring at the end of each stage act if you have 50 rings. Here, you move your character along a hexagon-shaped tube collecting blue spheres whilst avoiding pitfalls, spikebombs and other traps. Similar to the Bonus Stage, your rings are your timer and count down, ending the stage when you run out. By collecting all of the 'Chaos Rings', you can unlock a better ending.[CR]</plot>
		<releasedate>13/8/1995</releasedate>
		<year>1995</year>
		<genre>Action</genre>
		<studio>Sega</studio>
		<nplayers>1-2 Co-Op</nplayers>
		<perspective>Platform</perspective>
		<rating>3.7</rating>
		<ESRB>E - Everyone</ESRB>
		<thegamesdb_id>2290</thegamesdb_id>
		<mobygames_url>https://www.mobygames.com/game/sega-32x/knuckles-chaotix</mobygames_url>
		<giantbomb_url>https://www.giantbomb.com/knuckles-chaotix/3030-8284/</giantbomb_url>
		<consolegrid_url>http://consolegrid.com/games/7849</consolegrid_url>
		<boxart1>aEVQOyh.jpg</boxart1>
		<boxart2>mqDe4BA.jpg</boxart2>
		<boxart3>IhDDkoP.jpg</boxart3>
		<boxart4>6eHR51O.jpg</boxart4>
		<boxart5>crsHzTa.jpg</boxart5>
		<snapshot1>m5nOv2d.jpg</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>tFzqMkP.gif</snapshot2>
		<snapshot3>MbPG3Qq.gif</snapshot3>
		<snapshot4>QII4FIc.gif</snapshot4>
		<snapshot5>3dp9WlY.gif</snapshot5>
		<snapshot6>u2F8Gdv.gif</snapshot6>
		<snapshot7>tYIgaV9.gif</snapshot7>
		<snapshot8>xJhmcAe.gif</snapshot8>
		<snapshot9>PvbOlH9.gif</snapshot9>
		<snapshot10>zXZ1val.png</snapshot10>
		<banner1>JPDKUfM.png</banner1>
	</game>
	<game name="Kolibri (USA, Europe)">
		<description>Kolibri (USA, Europe)</description>
		<rom crc="20CA53EF" name="Sega_32X/Kolibri%20%28USA%2C%20Europe%29.32x" sha1="191AE0B525ECF32664086D8D748E0B35F776DDFE" size="1629243" />
		<title_clean>Kolibri</title_clean>
		<plot>Kolibri is a hummingbird hero in this unusual side scrolling shooter for the 32X.  Deep inside the earth's core, there is a crystal from another world.  This crystal is the earth's life force, and essential to it's survival.  One day, a dark crystal falls from the sky and damages the earth's crystal.  Desperate, the earth's crystal rockets to the surface and empowers Kolibri with the abilities he needs to defeat the dark crystal.[CR]This game features 19 levels set in a variety of detailed natural settings.  Your goal in some levels is to destroy enemy bugs, in others your goal is to merely survive.</plot>
		<releasedate>13/8/1995</releasedate>
		<year>1995</year>
		<genre>Action</genre>
		<studio>Sega</studio>
		<nplayers>1-2 Co-Op</nplayers>
		<perspective>Side-Scrolling</perspective>
		<rating>4.1</rating>
		<ESRB>E - Everyone</ESRB>
		<thegamesdb_id>2609</thegamesdb_id>
		<mobygames_url>https://www.mobygames.com/game/sega-32x/kolibri</mobygames_url>
		<giantbomb_url>https://www.giantbomb.com/kolibri/3030-18959/</giantbomb_url>
		<boxart1>huToF7x.jpg</boxart1>
		<boxart2>xr4akks.jpg</boxart2>
		<snapshot1>h8Vj9aJ.jpg</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>qn9hRNM.jpg</snapshot2>
		<snapshot3>NT8oav6.gif</snapshot3>
		<snapshot4>3kqMz4D.png</snapshot4>
		<snapshot5>6aA1zAd.gif</snapshot5>
		<snapshot6>ZtKJdHt.gif</snapshot6>
		<snapshot7>OXb8pz2.gif</snapshot7>
		<snapshot8>l0YATnV.gif</snapshot8>
		<snapshot9>uEWUDuJ.png</snapshot9>
		<snapshot10>3uuVYBQ.png</snapshot10>
	</game>
	<game name="Metal Head (Europe) (En,Ja)">
		<description>Metal Head (Europe) (En,Ja)</description>
		<rom crc="BF9B8376" name="Sega_32X/Metal%20Head%20%28Europe%29%20%28En%2CJa%29.32x" sha1="2A7767024E23B55FE193D586A96A3BA3C92E7EA8" size="2319039" />
		<title_clean>Metal Head</title_clean>
		<plot>It's 5 years after the formation of the Worldwide Federation.  Although war has been averted, terrorist cells around the world threaten the stability of the federation.  To combat this menace, the Federation has created a bi-pedal armored tank known as the Metal Head.  You are a Metal Head pilot, and you have to use all the weapons at your disposal to take out the terrorists.[CR]Metal Head is a bit of a variation on the usual giant robot combat game.  The game's mission areas bear more resemblance to a first-person shooter than a simulation.  The graphics are all rendered in texture mapped polygons, which is unusual for a 32X game.</plot>
		<releasedate>13/8/1994</releasedate>
		<year>1994</year>
		<genre>Action, Simulation</genre>
		<studio>Sega</studio>
		<nplayers>1</nplayers>
		<perspective>1st-Person</perspective>
		<rating>3.1</rating>
		<ESRB>E - Everyone</ESRB>
		<thegamesdb_id>4918</thegamesdb_id>
		<mobygames_url>https://www.mobygames.com/game/sega-32x/metal-head</mobygames_url>
		<giantbomb_url>https://www.giantbomb.com/metal-head/3030-4621/</giantbomb_url>
		<boxart1>JtSu7CV.jpg</boxart1>
		<boxart2>CkFS15U.jpg</boxart2>
		<boxart3>rZO4yjw.jpg</boxart3>
		<snapshot1>hqFqKGg.gif</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>eQttwYl.gif</snapshot2>
		<snapshot3>vFukcJq.gif</snapshot3>
		<snapshot4>DmisBZs.gif</snapshot4>
		<snapshot5>w6W3Yq6.gif</snapshot5>
		<snapshot6>RmflWFQ.gif</snapshot6>
		<snapshot7>8EapRpg.gif</snapshot7>
		<snapshot8>omThKjo.gif</snapshot8>
		<snapshot9>Fzc3nCa.gif</snapshot9>
		<snapshot10>O6yejxO.gif</snapshot10>
	</game>
	<game name="Metal Head (Japan, USA) (En,Ja)">
		<description>Metal Head (Japan, USA) (En,Ja)</description>
		<rom crc="EF5553FF" name="Sega_32X/Metal%20Head%20%28Japan%2C%20USA%29%20%28En%2CJa%29.32x" sha1="4E872FBB44ECB2BD730ABD8CC8F32F96B10582C0" size="2319049" />
		<title_clean>Metal Head</title_clean>
		<plot>It's 5 years after the formation of the Worldwide Federation.  Although war has been averted, terrorist cells around the world threaten the stability of the federation.  To combat this menace, the Federation has created a bi-pedal armored tank known as the Metal Head.  You are a Metal Head pilot, and you have to use all the weapons at your disposal to take out the terrorists.[CR]Metal Head is a bit of a variation on the usual giant robot combat game.  The game's mission areas bear more resemblance to a first-person shooter than a simulation.  The graphics are all rendered in texture mapped polygons, which is unusual for a 32X game.</plot>
		<releasedate>13/8/1994</releasedate>
		<year>1994</year>
		<genre>Action, Simulation</genre>
		<studio>Sega</studio>
		<nplayers>1</nplayers>
		<perspective>1st-Person</perspective>
		<rating>3.1</rating>
		<ESRB>E - Everyone</ESRB>
		<thegamesdb_id>4918</thegamesdb_id>
		<mobygames_url>https://www.mobygames.com/game/sega-32x/metal-head</mobygames_url>
		<giantbomb_url>https://www.giantbomb.com/metal-head/3030-4621/</giantbomb_url>
		<boxart1>caxDFH1.jpg</boxart1>
		<boxart2>CkFS15U.jpg</boxart2>
		<boxart3>rZO4yjw.jpg</boxart3>
		<snapshot1>hqFqKGg.gif</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>eQttwYl.gif</snapshot2>
		<snapshot3>vFukcJq.gif</snapshot3>
		<snapshot4>DmisBZs.gif</snapshot4>
		<snapshot5>w6W3Yq6.gif</snapshot5>
		<snapshot6>RmflWFQ.gif</snapshot6>
		<snapshot7>8EapRpg.gif</snapshot7>
		<snapshot8>omThKjo.gif</snapshot8>
		<snapshot9>Fzc3nCa.gif</snapshot9>
		<snapshot10>O6yejxO.gif</snapshot10>
	</game>
	<game name="Mortal Kombat II (Japan, USA)">
		<description>Mortal Kombat II (Japan, USA)</description>
		<rom crc="773C0A85" name="Sega_32X/Mortal%20Kombat%20II%20%28Japan%2C%20USA%29.32x" sha1="D55964BD935110AC2D9CBD3B085B7E8B71B11DF2" size="3354882" />
		<title_clean>Mortal Kombat II</title_clean>
		<plot>[CR][B]Overview:[/B][CR]Advertisement featuring four of the new playable charactersMortal Kombat II is a 2D fighting game developed and released by Midway in 1993 for arcades. Like the previous game, it was ported to numerous fourth-generation consoles (and some fifth-generation ones).It is the direct sequel to the original Mortal Kombat, adding new characters and content while revamping the fighting system for a smoother, faster experience. The game introduced multiple Fatalities (gruesome finishing moves) per character, Babalities (finishing moves that humiliates the opponent by turning their character into a baby), and Friendships (finishing moves that trade brutal punishment for a friendly gesture). The game introduces more easter eggs, including a playable version of Pong and the iconic "Toasty!" sound clip. The score system from the original (as well as the Test Your Might! minigame and endurance matches) has been removed in favor of a tally system that tracks the number of consecutive matches won.Taking place sometime after the events of the last Mortal Kombat tournament, the story shifts the location to an alternate realm called Outworld, where it's emperor, Shao Kahn, plans to take over Earthrealm by defeating the warriors of Earth in a tournament (with the help of his half-tiger, half-human bodyguard, Kintaro, and the restored Shang Tsung). Other sub-plots involve Liu Kang's plan for revenge for the assault of his Shaolin monastery (with the help of his close friend, Kung Lao), Jax's mission to rescue the captured Sonya and Kano, and the tensions between female ninja assassins Kitana and Mileena.[CR][B]Gameplay:[/B][CR]Mortal Kombat II builds upon the original Mortal Kombat's gameplay. The five-button layout (in an "X" formation) returns, with four attack buttons (High Punch, High Kick, Low Punch, and Low Kick) and a dedicated Block button. Some normal attacks have different attributes (for example, roundhouse kicks now launch opponents into the air, whether they are on the ground or not), and crouching punches have been added (in the original game, crouching and pressing either punch causes the character to throw an uppercut).Finishing MovesBaraka performing a gruesome new Fatality: the Blade Lift.One significant addition to Mortal Kombat II is the expansion of each character's arsenal of finishing moves. Each of the twelve playable characters now has two Fatalities (glorified execution moves) instead of one (with the exception of Shang Tsung, who has three). Three stages have special Stage Fatalities: The Dead Pool, The Kombat Tomb, and The Pit II. Unlike the original Mortal Kombat (where the Stage Fatality is done with a simple uppercut), Stage Fatalities must be performed with a unique button combination. The button combination for both The Kombat Tomb and The Pit II are unique for each character, with the button combination for The Dead Pool being universal for all characters.Mortal Kombat II introduces two alternate types of finishing moves: Babalities and Friendships. Babalities humiliate the opponent by turning their character into a baby, while Friendships makes the character show a friendly gesture (from autographing a picture to giving a gift). Both can only be performed if the winning player does not press any of the punch buttons during the winning round.[CR][B]Characters:[/B][CR]The game includes twelve playable characters, two unplayable bosses, and three unplayable secret characters. All of the previous cast returns except Goro, Kano, and Sonya (though Kano and Sonya are seen as chained prisoners in Shao Kahn's Arena). Most of the cast have received new appearances, special moves, and Fatalities. This is the first game where Reptile and Shang Tsung are playable.After choosing a character, the player progresses through the game by defeating all twelve playable characters (with Shang Tsung always being the last opponent), and then battle the two new bosses: Kintaro and Shao Kahn. Unlike the previous game, there are no "endurance matches" or special mini-games.The new playable characters include Kung Lao (a Shaolin Monk and friend of Liu Kang), Jax (a U.S. Special Forces major who is sent to rescue Sonya), the Tarkatan creature Baraka, and the female ninjas Kitana and Mileena. The two boss characters include Shao Kahn (the evil emperor of Outworld) and his bodyguard, Kintaro. Much like the original Mortal Kombat, the game includes three secret opponents that are palette swaps of either the male or female ninjas: Jade (who can only be fought by winning a round using only the Low Kick button in the match before the "?" symbol), Smoke (who can only be fought by waiting for the "Toasty!" indicator on The Portal stage and pressing down on the joystick and the Start button), and Noob Saibot (who can only be fought by winning 50 rounds in a row). [CR] Liu Kang [CR]Actor:  Ho Sung PakFatality 1: Liu Kang morphs into a screen-high dragon before biting down on his opponent, leaving behind only a standing pair of legs.Fatality 2:  Liu Kang revisits his non-lethal fatality from the original Mortal Kombat, executing a butterfly-kick into the opponent before uppercutting him or her into the air.[CR] Kung Lao [CR] (not available in the Game Boy, Game Gear, and Sega Master System versions) Actor:  Anthony MarquezFatality 1: Using a downward slash, Kung Lao bisects the victim with the brim of his hat. The victim falls to his or her knees before splitting apart down the center in two opposing directions.Fatality 2: Kung Lao throws his hat from a distance with a slight upward arc, catching the victim just under the neck and decapitating him or her.[CR] Johnny Cage [CR] (not available in the Game Boy, Game Gear, and Sega Master System versions) Actor:  Daniel Pesina Fatality 1: Cage rips the torso off of his victim and tosses it away, leaving only a pair of standing legs.Fatality 2: Cage revisits his fatality from the original game, using an uppercut to decapitate his victim. A special button combination can be executed during the fatality to guarantee that two more heads are punched off (out of thin air, natch).[CR] Reptile [CR]Actor: Daniel PesinaFatality 1: Reptile removes his mask, revealing his true reptilian face. He then opens wide, snaring the opponent's head with his long tongue, rips it clean off, and eats it.Fatality 2: While invisible, Reptile pops his victim's torso up into the air and away from the legs.[CR] Sub-Zero[CR]Actor: Daniel Pesina Fatality 1: Sub-Zero freezes his victim in showers of ice. He then executes a powerful uppercut which causes his victim to explode in a shower of guts, legs and arms. Note: This requires two separate inputs: one for the ice shower, and one for the uppercut. The ice shower can be executed and followed up by any other move, including Sub-Zero's other fatality, if so desired.Fatality 2: Sub-Zero generates an "ice grenade" in his hands, hurls it towards his victim, and waits as the grenade blows his victim's torso into pieces--leaving nothing but a pair of standing legs.[CR] Shang Tsung [CR] (sub-boss) Actor: Philip Ahn M.D. Fatality 1: Shang Tsung enters his victim's body via the ear canal. Shortly thereafter, he "bursts out" of his victim, causing the body to explode.Fatality 2: Shang Tsung lifts his victim into the air with one hand, sucking out the victim's soul into the other hand. What remains of the victim is a shriveled, desiccated body.Hidden Fatality: Shang Tsung morphs into Kintaro and, with one powerful punch, knocks his victim's torso clean off of his/her legs.[CR] Kitana [CR]Actor:  Katalin Zamiar Fatality 1: Kitana whips out her razor-sharp fan and decapitates her victim.Fatality 2: Kitana plants a lovely kiss on her victim which in fact causes the victim's body to expand to the point of explosion.[CR] Jax [CR]Actor:  John Parrish Fatality 1: Jax claps both of his hands on the victim's head, causing it to shatter into pieces.Fatality 2: Jax grabs ahold of both of his victim's arms and rips them off with one yank. The victim then stands in shock as showers of blood gush through his/her arm sockets. The victim doesn't immediately die (of blood loss).[CR] Mileena [CR]Actor: Katalin Zamiar Fatality 1: Mileena pulls out both of her sai and, in rapid-fire style, repeatedly stabs her victim in the torso, leaving behind a massive spray of blood.Fatality 2: Mileena removes her mask, revealing Tarkatan teeth. She then inhales her victim, then turns around and spits out a plethora of shiny bones.[CR] Baraka [CR] (not available in the Game Boy, Game Gear, and Sega Master System versions) Actor:  Richard Divizio Fatality 1: Baraka decapitates his victim with one swipe of his arm blades.Fatality 2: Baraka unleashes both of his arm blades and impales his victim through the chest. As the victim struggles and slowly dies, his/her body slides down the blades before stopping and hanging in the air.[CR] Scorpion [CR]Actor: Daniel PesinaFatality 1: Reprising his original Fatality, Scorpion removes his mask, revealing only a ghastly skull. He then breaths a ball of fire at his victim, who then bursts into flame--flesh burning away instantly--before exploding into a shower of flaming bones.Fatality 2: Scorpion takes the blade of his spear and slashes open his victim's jugular. As a long river of blood spurts through the neck, Scorpion then follows it up by slicing and separating his victim's torso from the legs.[CR] Raiden [CR] (known as Rayden in some home versions, not available in the Game Boy, Game Gear, and Sega Master System versions) Actor:  Carlos Pesina Fatality 1: Raiden unleashes a powerful uppercut which shatters his victim's body into pieces.Fatality 2: Raiden grabs ahold of and shocks his victim until the body explodes.[CR]  Kintaro [CR](sub-boss, unplayable) [CR]  Shao Kahn [CR](boss, unplayable)Actor:  Brian Glynn [CR]  Jade [CR](secret opponent, unplayable)Actor: Katalin Zamiar[CR]  Smoke [CR](secret opponent, unplayable)Actor: Daniel Pesina[CR] Noob Saibot [CR](secret opponent, unplayable, not available in the Game Boy, Game Gear, and Sega Master System versions)Actor: Daniel Pesina[CR]Arenas[CR]There are nine playable stages, which are built into a simple, looping rotation. However, Shao Kahn's Arena is always the stage in Kintaro and Shao Kahn matches. The stages that include special Stage Fatalities are The Dead Pool (where the player uppercuts the opponent into acid), The Kombat Tomb (where the player uppercuts the opponent into previously hidden ceiling spikes), and The Pit II (where the player uppercuts the opponent off the side of the bridge and into the rocky ground below). The Dead PoolThe Living Forest The Kombat Tomb The Wasteland The Tower The Living Forest  The Armory The Pit II The Portal Shao Kahn's Arena [CR]Versions and Ports[CR]The original release of Mortal Kombat II on the Midway T-Unit arcade board went through four released revisions (1.1, 1.4, 2.1, and 3.1). While revisions 1.1 and 1.4 were available to the public, they were considered unfinished, missing some Fatalities, some special moves, all endings, all Friendships, all Babalities, all secret opponents, and all Stage Fatalities. Revision 3.1 is the final version, featuring all Fatalities, special moves, endings, Friendships, Babalities, secret opponents, Stage Fatalities, and bugfixes. The arcade release was considered a smash hit, with special guards on the arcade machines to protect the arcade board from being stolen.Almost a year later, the game was ported to various consoles. Home versions hit the market on &#8220;Mortal Friday&#8221; September 10, 1993 for the Sega Genesis, Super Nintendo, Nintendo Game Boy, and Sega Game Gear. The SNES version of the original Mortal Kombat was criticized for its lack of blood, so blood was included in the SNES version of MKII. It was featured in the launch library for the Sega 32X when it launched in November 1994. Versions for the PC and Amiga were released in late-1994 as well. Rare versions of the game were released for the Sony PlayStation and Sega Saturn in 1996. The PlayStation version was released only in Japan, and featured excessive loading times. For example, if Shang Tsung morphed into another character, the game would pause mid-match to load this new character, then pause for each consecutive move that required new animations or sound to load in.The original arcade release was later included in Midway Arcade Treasures 2 for the GameCube, PlayStation 2, and Xbox, Midway Arcade Treasures Deluxe Edition for the PC, Midway Arcade Treasures: Extended Play for the PlayStation Portable, and Mortal Kombat Arcade Kollection for the Xbox 360 (via Xbox Live Arcade), PlayStation 3 (via PlayStation Network), and PC (via Steam). The game was also included as an unlockable in Mortal Kombat: Shaolin Monks for the PlayStation 2 and Xbox.On April 12, 2007, the game was released on the PlayStation 3 as a downloadable title on the PlayStation Network for $4.99, featuring online play.[CR]</plot>
		<releasedate>13/8/1995</releasedate>
		<year>1995</year>
		<genre>Action</genre>
		<studio>Acclaim Entertainment</studio>
		<nplayers>1-2 VS</nplayers>
		<perspective>3rd-Person</perspective>
		<rating>4.2</rating>
		<ESRB>M - Mature</ESRB>
		<thegamesdb_id>4919</thegamesdb_id>
		<mobygames_url>https://www.mobygames.com/game/sega-32x/mortal-kombat-ii</mobygames_url>
		<giantbomb_url>https://www.giantbomb.com/mortal-kombat-ii/3030-3571/</giantbomb_url>
		<consolegrid_url>http://consolegrid.com/games/4641</consolegrid_url>
		<boxart1>sR2vt0Y.jpg</boxart1>
		<boxart2>rSwr36l.jpg</boxart2>
		<boxart3>1Hs1Fgd.jpg</boxart3>
		<boxart4>PKWWtYi.jpg</boxart4>
		<snapshot1>ShAfl54.gif</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>LpicAcg.gif</snapshot2>
		<snapshot3>Fz69aP6.gif</snapshot3>
		<snapshot4>vBXoLiQ.gif</snapshot4>
		<snapshot5>dTV5CgV.gif</snapshot5>
		<snapshot6>qUh10cu.gif</snapshot6>
		<snapshot7>X1T42DK.gif</snapshot7>
		<snapshot8>7GNV9YP.gif</snapshot8>
		<snapshot9>9HNRKw7.gif</snapshot9>
		<snapshot10>vxTWeJ5.gif</snapshot10>
		<fanart1>FGI5bhG.jpg</fanart1>
		<fanart2>FGQcgpP.jpg</fanart2>
		<banner1>sCzAcw6.jpg</banner1>
		<clearlogo1>9vbazuf.png</clearlogo1>
	</game>
	<game name="Mortal Kombat II (Europe)">
		<description>Mortal Kombat II (Europe)</description>
		<rom crc="211085CE" name="Sega_32X/Mortal%20Kombat%20II%20%28Europe%29.32x" sha1="F75698DE887D0EF980F73E35FC4615887A9AD58F" size="3329689" />
		<title_clean>Mortal Kombat II</title_clean>
		<plot>[CR][B]Overview:[/B][CR]Advertisement featuring four of the new playable charactersMortal Kombat II is a 2D fighting game developed and released by Midway in 1993 for arcades. Like the previous game, it was ported to numerous fourth-generation consoles (and some fifth-generation ones).It is the direct sequel to the original Mortal Kombat, adding new characters and content while revamping the fighting system for a smoother, faster experience. The game introduced multiple Fatalities (gruesome finishing moves) per character, Babalities (finishing moves that humiliates the opponent by turning their character into a baby), and Friendships (finishing moves that trade brutal punishment for a friendly gesture). The game introduces more easter eggs, including a playable version of Pong and the iconic "Toasty!" sound clip. The score system from the original (as well as the Test Your Might! minigame and endurance matches) has been removed in favor of a tally system that tracks the number of consecutive matches won.Taking place sometime after the events of the last Mortal Kombat tournament, the story shifts the location to an alternate realm called Outworld, where it's emperor, Shao Kahn, plans to take over Earthrealm by defeating the warriors of Earth in a tournament (with the help of his half-tiger, half-human bodyguard, Kintaro, and the restored Shang Tsung). Other sub-plots involve Liu Kang's plan for revenge for the assault of his Shaolin monastery (with the help of his close friend, Kung Lao), Jax's mission to rescue the captured Sonya and Kano, and the tensions between female ninja assassins Kitana and Mileena.[CR][B]Gameplay:[/B][CR]Mortal Kombat II builds upon the original Mortal Kombat's gameplay. The five-button layout (in an "X" formation) returns, with four attack buttons (High Punch, High Kick, Low Punch, and Low Kick) and a dedicated Block button. Some normal attacks have different attributes (for example, roundhouse kicks now launch opponents into the air, whether they are on the ground or not), and crouching punches have been added (in the original game, crouching and pressing either punch causes the character to throw an uppercut).Finishing MovesBaraka performing a gruesome new Fatality: the Blade Lift.One significant addition to Mortal Kombat II is the expansion of each character's arsenal of finishing moves. Each of the twelve playable characters now has two Fatalities (glorified execution moves) instead of one (with the exception of Shang Tsung, who has three). Three stages have special Stage Fatalities: The Dead Pool, The Kombat Tomb, and The Pit II. Unlike the original Mortal Kombat (where the Stage Fatality is done with a simple uppercut), Stage Fatalities must be performed with a unique button combination. The button combination for both The Kombat Tomb and The Pit II are unique for each character, with the button combination for The Dead Pool being universal for all characters.Mortal Kombat II introduces two alternate types of finishing moves: Babalities and Friendships. Babalities humiliate the opponent by turning their character into a baby, while Friendships makes the character show a friendly gesture (from autographing a picture to giving a gift). Both can only be performed if the winning player does not press any of the punch buttons during the winning round.[CR][B]Characters:[/B][CR]The game includes twelve playable characters, two unplayable bosses, and three unplayable secret characters. All of the previous cast returns except Goro, Kano, and Sonya (though Kano and Sonya are seen as chained prisoners in Shao Kahn's Arena). Most of the cast have received new appearances, special moves, and Fatalities. This is the first game where Reptile and Shang Tsung are playable.After choosing a character, the player progresses through the game by defeating all twelve playable characters (with Shang Tsung always being the last opponent), and then battle the two new bosses: Kintaro and Shao Kahn. Unlike the previous game, there are no "endurance matches" or special mini-games.The new playable characters include Kung Lao (a Shaolin Monk and friend of Liu Kang), Jax (a U.S. Special Forces major who is sent to rescue Sonya), the Tarkatan creature Baraka, and the female ninjas Kitana and Mileena. The two boss characters include Shao Kahn (the evil emperor of Outworld) and his bodyguard, Kintaro. Much like the original Mortal Kombat, the game includes three secret opponents that are palette swaps of either the male or female ninjas: Jade (who can only be fought by winning a round using only the Low Kick button in the match before the "?" symbol), Smoke (who can only be fought by waiting for the "Toasty!" indicator on The Portal stage and pressing down on the joystick and the Start button), and Noob Saibot (who can only be fought by winning 50 rounds in a row). [CR] Liu Kang [CR]Actor:  Ho Sung PakFatality 1: Liu Kang morphs into a screen-high dragon before biting down on his opponent, leaving behind only a standing pair of legs.Fatality 2:  Liu Kang revisits his non-lethal fatality from the original Mortal Kombat, executing a butterfly-kick into the opponent before uppercutting him or her into the air.[CR] Kung Lao [CR] (not available in the Game Boy, Game Gear, and Sega Master System versions) Actor:  Anthony MarquezFatality 1: Using a downward slash, Kung Lao bisects the victim with the brim of his hat. The victim falls to his or her knees before splitting apart down the center in two opposing directions.Fatality 2: Kung Lao throws his hat from a distance with a slight upward arc, catching the victim just under the neck and decapitating him or her.[CR] Johnny Cage [CR] (not available in the Game Boy, Game Gear, and Sega Master System versions) Actor:  Daniel Pesina Fatality 1: Cage rips the torso off of his victim and tosses it away, leaving only a pair of standing legs.Fatality 2: Cage revisits his fatality from the original game, using an uppercut to decapitate his victim. A special button combination can be executed during the fatality to guarantee that two more heads are punched off (out of thin air, natch).[CR] Reptile [CR]Actor: Daniel PesinaFatality 1: Reptile removes his mask, revealing his true reptilian face. He then opens wide, snaring the opponent's head with his long tongue, rips it clean off, and eats it.Fatality 2: While invisible, Reptile pops his victim's torso up into the air and away from the legs.[CR] Sub-Zero[CR]Actor: Daniel Pesina Fatality 1: Sub-Zero freezes his victim in showers of ice. He then executes a powerful uppercut which causes his victim to explode in a shower of guts, legs and arms. Note: This requires two separate inputs: one for the ice shower, and one for the uppercut. The ice shower can be executed and followed up by any other move, including Sub-Zero's other fatality, if so desired.Fatality 2: Sub-Zero generates an "ice grenade" in his hands, hurls it towards his victim, and waits as the grenade blows his victim's torso into pieces--leaving nothing but a pair of standing legs.[CR] Shang Tsung [CR] (sub-boss) Actor: Philip Ahn M.D. Fatality 1: Shang Tsung enters his victim's body via the ear canal. Shortly thereafter, he "bursts out" of his victim, causing the body to explode.Fatality 2: Shang Tsung lifts his victim into the air with one hand, sucking out the victim's soul into the other hand. What remains of the victim is a shriveled, desiccated body.Hidden Fatality: Shang Tsung morphs into Kintaro and, with one powerful punch, knocks his victim's torso clean off of his/her legs.[CR] Kitana [CR]Actor:  Katalin Zamiar Fatality 1: Kitana whips out her razor-sharp fan and decapitates her victim.Fatality 2: Kitana plants a lovely kiss on her victim which in fact causes the victim's body to expand to the point of explosion.[CR] Jax [CR]Actor:  John Parrish Fatality 1: Jax claps both of his hands on the victim's head, causing it to shatter into pieces.Fatality 2: Jax grabs ahold of both of his victim's arms and rips them off with one yank. The victim then stands in shock as showers of blood gush through his/her arm sockets. The victim doesn't immediately die (of blood loss).[CR] Mileena [CR]Actor: Katalin Zamiar Fatality 1: Mileena pulls out both of her sai and, in rapid-fire style, repeatedly stabs her victim in the torso, leaving behind a massive spray of blood.Fatality 2: Mileena removes her mask, revealing Tarkatan teeth. She then inhales her victim, then turns around and spits out a plethora of shiny bones.[CR] Baraka [CR] (not available in the Game Boy, Game Gear, and Sega Master System versions) Actor:  Richard Divizio Fatality 1: Baraka decapitates his victim with one swipe of his arm blades.Fatality 2: Baraka unleashes both of his arm blades and impales his victim through the chest. As the victim struggles and slowly dies, his/her body slides down the blades before stopping and hanging in the air.[CR] Scorpion [CR]Actor: Daniel PesinaFatality 1: Reprising his original Fatality, Scorpion removes his mask, revealing only a ghastly skull. He then breaths a ball of fire at his victim, who then bursts into flame--flesh burning away instantly--before exploding into a shower of flaming bones.Fatality 2: Scorpion takes the blade of his spear and slashes open his victim's jugular. As a long river of blood spurts through the neck, Scorpion then follows it up by slicing and separating his victim's torso from the legs.[CR] Raiden [CR] (known as Rayden in some home versions, not available in the Game Boy, Game Gear, and Sega Master System versions) Actor:  Carlos Pesina Fatality 1: Raiden unleashes a powerful uppercut which shatters his victim's body into pieces.Fatality 2: Raiden grabs ahold of and shocks his victim until the body explodes.[CR]  Kintaro [CR](sub-boss, unplayable) [CR]  Shao Kahn [CR](boss, unplayable)Actor:  Brian Glynn [CR]  Jade [CR](secret opponent, unplayable)Actor: Katalin Zamiar[CR]  Smoke [CR](secret opponent, unplayable)Actor: Daniel Pesina[CR] Noob Saibot [CR](secret opponent, unplayable, not available in the Game Boy, Game Gear, and Sega Master System versions)Actor: Daniel Pesina[CR]Arenas[CR]There are nine playable stages, which are built into a simple, looping rotation. However, Shao Kahn's Arena is always the stage in Kintaro and Shao Kahn matches. The stages that include special Stage Fatalities are The Dead Pool (where the player uppercuts the opponent into acid), The Kombat Tomb (where the player uppercuts the opponent into previously hidden ceiling spikes), and The Pit II (where the player uppercuts the opponent off the side of the bridge and into the rocky ground below). The Dead PoolThe Living Forest The Kombat Tomb The Wasteland The Tower The Living Forest  The Armory The Pit II The Portal Shao Kahn's Arena [CR]Versions and Ports[CR]The original release of Mortal Kombat II on the Midway T-Unit arcade board went through four released revisions (1.1, 1.4, 2.1, and 3.1). While revisions 1.1 and 1.4 were available to the public, they were considered unfinished, missing some Fatalities, some special moves, all endings, all Friendships, all Babalities, all secret opponents, and all Stage Fatalities. Revision 3.1 is the final version, featuring all Fatalities, special moves, endings, Friendships, Babalities, secret opponents, Stage Fatalities, and bugfixes. The arcade release was considered a smash hit, with special guards on the arcade machines to protect the arcade board from being stolen.Almost a year later, the game was ported to various consoles. Home versions hit the market on &#8220;Mortal Friday&#8221; September 10, 1993 for the Sega Genesis, Super Nintendo, Nintendo Game Boy, and Sega Game Gear. The SNES version of the original Mortal Kombat was criticized for its lack of blood, so blood was included in the SNES version of MKII. It was featured in the launch library for the Sega 32X when it launched in November 1994. Versions for the PC and Amiga were released in late-1994 as well. Rare versions of the game were released for the Sony PlayStation and Sega Saturn in 1996. The PlayStation version was released only in Japan, and featured excessive loading times. For example, if Shang Tsung morphed into another character, the game would pause mid-match to load this new character, then pause for each consecutive move that required new animations or sound to load in.The original arcade release was later included in Midway Arcade Treasures 2 for the GameCube, PlayStation 2, and Xbox, Midway Arcade Treasures Deluxe Edition for the PC, Midway Arcade Treasures: Extended Play for the PlayStation Portable, and Mortal Kombat Arcade Kollection for the Xbox 360 (via Xbox Live Arcade), PlayStation 3 (via PlayStation Network), and PC (via Steam). The game was also included as an unlockable in Mortal Kombat: Shaolin Monks for the PlayStation 2 and Xbox.On April 12, 2007, the game was released on the PlayStation 3 as a downloadable title on the PlayStation Network for $4.99, featuring online play.[CR]</plot>
		<releasedate>13/8/1995</releasedate>
		<year>1995</year>
		<genre>Action</genre>
		<studio>Acclaim Entertainment</studio>
		<nplayers>1-2 VS</nplayers>
		<perspective>3rd-Person</perspective>
		<rating>4.2</rating>
		<ESRB>M - Mature</ESRB>
		<thegamesdb_id>4919</thegamesdb_id>
		<mobygames_url>https://www.mobygames.com/game/sega-32x/mortal-kombat-ii</mobygames_url>
		<giantbomb_url>https://www.giantbomb.com/mortal-kombat-ii/3030-3571/</giantbomb_url>
		<consolegrid_url>http://consolegrid.com/games/4641</consolegrid_url>
		<boxart1>pSPyyPY.png</boxart1>
		<boxart2>rSwr36l.jpg</boxart2>
		<boxart3>1Hs1Fgd.jpg</boxart3>
		<boxart4>PKWWtYi.jpg</boxart4>
		<snapshot1>ShAfl54.gif</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>LpicAcg.gif</snapshot2>
		<snapshot3>Fz69aP6.gif</snapshot3>
		<snapshot4>vBXoLiQ.gif</snapshot4>
		<snapshot5>dTV5CgV.gif</snapshot5>
		<snapshot6>qUh10cu.gif</snapshot6>
		<snapshot7>X1T42DK.gif</snapshot7>
		<snapshot8>7GNV9YP.gif</snapshot8>
		<snapshot9>9HNRKw7.gif</snapshot9>
		<snapshot10>vxTWeJ5.gif</snapshot10>
		<fanart1>FGI5bhG.jpg</fanart1>
		<fanart2>FGQcgpP.jpg</fanart2>
		<banner1>sCzAcw6.jpg</banner1>
		<clearlogo1>9vbazuf.png</clearlogo1>
	</game>
	<game name="Motocross Championship (Europe)">
		<description>Motocross Championship (Europe)</description>
		<rom crc="AE3364E9" name="Sega_32X/Motocross%20Championship%20%28Europe%29.32x" sha1="AF0CB8626825E1B431EBA07B8A9B571186745C16" size="862655" />
		<title_clean>Motocross Championship</title_clean>
		<plot>Motocross Championship is the only dirtbike racing game for the 32X.  The action takes place from a behind-the-bike perspective, and makes use of the 32X's hardware bitmap scaling to present a 3D graphical effect.[CR]Like the title suggests, the main game mode is a points based championship.  You can compete in one of 3 motorcycle classes over 12 indoor and outdoor tracks.  There's also two player split screen mode so you can share off-road fun with a friend.</plot>
		<releasedate>13/8/1994</releasedate>
		<year>1994</year>
		<genre>Driving, Racing, Sports</genre>
		<studio>Sega</studio>
		<nplayers>1-2 VS</nplayers>
		<perspective>3rd-Person</perspective>
		<rating>2.9</rating>
		<ESRB>E - Everyone</ESRB>
		<thegamesdb_id>9076</thegamesdb_id>
		<mobygames_url>https://www.mobygames.com/game/sega-32x/motocross-championship</mobygames_url>
		<giantbomb_url>https://www.giantbomb.com/motocross-championship/3030-4838/</giantbomb_url>
		<consolegrid_url>http://consolegrid.com/games/12654</consolegrid_url>
		<boxart1>2vKBr6S.jpg</boxart1>
		<boxart2>1o8Yw2r.jpg</boxart2>
		<boxart3>d9ngBqo.jpg</boxart3>
		<snapshot1>3ZQUAId.gif</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>S3tRhL9.gif</snapshot2>
		<snapshot3>HPFhVE8.gif</snapshot3>
		<snapshot4>amsjqAC.gif</snapshot4>
		<snapshot5>grjyOxZ.gif</snapshot5>
		<snapshot6>5yIxy0y.gif</snapshot6>
		<snapshot7>tX8Q4K8.gif</snapshot7>
		<snapshot8>KwhSWcM.jpg</snapshot8>
		<snapshot9>3lHVJfm.png</snapshot9>
		<snapshot10>sD4pTBW.png</snapshot10>
		<banner1>31SlBSB.jpg</banner1>
	</game>
	<game name="Motocross Championship (USA)">
		<description>Motocross Championship (USA)</description>
		<rom crc="A21C5761" name="Sega_32X/Motocross%20Championship%20%28USA%29.32x" sha1="5F1A107991AAF9EFF0B3CE864B2E3151F56ABE7B" size="862646" />
		<title_clean>Motocross Championship</title_clean>
		<plot>Motocross Championship is the only dirtbike racing game for the 32X.  The action takes place from a behind-the-bike perspective, and makes use of the 32X's hardware bitmap scaling to present a 3D graphical effect.[CR]Like the title suggests, the main game mode is a points based championship.  You can compete in one of 3 motorcycle classes over 12 indoor and outdoor tracks.  There's also two player split screen mode so you can share off-road fun with a friend.</plot>
		<releasedate>13/8/1994</releasedate>
		<year>1994</year>
		<genre>Driving, Racing, Sports</genre>
		<studio>Sega</studio>
		<nplayers>1-2 VS</nplayers>
		<perspective>3rd-Person</perspective>
		<rating>2.9</rating>
		<ESRB>E - Everyone</ESRB>
		<thegamesdb_id>9076</thegamesdb_id>
		<mobygames_url>https://www.mobygames.com/game/sega-32x/motocross-championship</mobygames_url>
		<giantbomb_url>https://www.giantbomb.com/motocross-championship/3030-4838/</giantbomb_url>
		<consolegrid_url>http://consolegrid.com/games/12654</consolegrid_url>
		<boxart1>7goXgyP.jpg</boxart1>
		<boxart2>1o8Yw2r.jpg</boxart2>
		<boxart3>d9ngBqo.jpg</boxart3>
		<snapshot1>3ZQUAId.gif</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>S3tRhL9.gif</snapshot2>
		<snapshot3>HPFhVE8.gif</snapshot3>
		<snapshot4>amsjqAC.gif</snapshot4>
		<snapshot5>grjyOxZ.gif</snapshot5>
		<snapshot6>5yIxy0y.gif</snapshot6>
		<snapshot7>tX8Q4K8.gif</snapshot7>
		<snapshot8>KwhSWcM.jpg</snapshot8>
		<snapshot9>3lHVJfm.png</snapshot9>
		<snapshot10>sD4pTBW.png</snapshot10>
		<banner1>31SlBSB.jpg</banner1>
	</game>
	<game name="NBA Jam - Tournament Edition (World)">
		<description>NBA Jam - Tournament Edition (World)</description>
		<rom crc="6B7994AA" name="Sega_32X/NBA%20Jam%20-%20Tournament%20Edition%20%28World%29.32x" sha1="C8AF3E74C49514669BA6652EC0C81BCCF77873B6" size="2287364" />
		<title_clean>NBA Jam - Tournament Edition</title_clean>
		<plot>[CR][B]Overview:[/B][CR]NBA Jam Tournament Edition is the second game in Midway&#8217;s basketball arcade series, featuring two-on-two fast paced matches with NBA players from the 1993-94 season (1994-95 on consoles). In total, the game features over 120 NBA athletes and over 40 hidden characters. Improvements include additional power-ups, more detailed player attributes, player substitutions after each quarter, and a new soundtrack. The namesake "Tournament Mode" turns off all cheats and power-ups, and rewards players with expanded rosters for nearly all teams if the player beats all 27 teams.In addition to these features, console releases added practice and &#8220;juice&#8221; modes, optional game toggles like "hotspots" and power-up icons, and an "injury" stat that lowers a character's stats. Later console releases (Jaguar, Saturn, PlayStation) also featured larger character sprites and scaling effects to match those of the Arcade version.[CR][B]Gameplay:[/B][CR]The core gameplay is largely unchanged from the original NBA Jam. Players still have the ability to do all the crazy dunks from the original, and all actions (running, passing, shooting) can be enhanced by holding down the "Turbo" button. Turbo drains while active, and replenishes quickly when not in use. Players also have the series-staple ability to go on fire after making 3 unanswered scores in a row - giving the player temporary unlimited sprint and the ability to goal tend without being penalized. Small, but significant changes in the T.E. include slightly improved A.I., game speed, new dunks, and court changes matching the color of the home team. Up to four players can play at once, with the A.I. filling in any empty slots.More stats in the T.E.The most significant changes in the Tournament Edition are expanding each player's stats, and expanding each team's roster to three players (with some exceptions due to trades or retirement, such as Dallas, which only has two players). Players are graded from 0 to 9 in eight categories: Speed, Dunk, 3-Point, Block, Power, Clutch, and Pass. Stats directly affect a player's success for each particular action, and players can be substituted out at halftime to respond to the changing needs of the game. For example, the player can send in a player with high Power and Pass ratings if ahead, to minimize getting shoved or picked and secure their lead. If trailing in the 4th, send in players with a high Clutch rating. These changes bring an added level of strategy somewhat missing from the original.Every version of the game also contains the Tournament Mode, where all cheats, power-ups, and special characters are disabled. Players are challenged to beat all 27 NBA teams, with progress stored to their initials (inputted at the start of the game). If a player beats all challenging teams, they unlock new characters and challenges. In the Arcade version, this unlocked the "???" team for play, consisting of NBA All-Stars and secret characters. These characters would also populate opposing teams, and always come with the "Quick Hands" and "Max Power" power-ups (except in Tournament Mode). On consoles, beating Tournament Mode unlocks 2 new players for almost every team's roster, plus a new difficulty level.All versions of the game also include "Power-up" codes to input at the Tonight's Matchup screen. These are secret combinations of button presses and stick moves that grant abilities akin to cheats (such as infinite turbo and power dunks). Playing in Tournament Mode disables these.An owner dipswitch option in the Arcade allowed the winning team out of a game of four players to continue playing for free, adding extra incentive to beat any challengers lined up.ConsolesHotspots enabledSome additional modes were added for console releases, and could be individually toggled in the options screen off the main menu. "Hot Spots" place marked circles randomly around the court and reward the player with extra points (up to a 9-point shot) for sinking a basket while standing inside them. Each spot clearly displays its value within the circle. "Power-up" icons add randomly-appearing icons around the court that bestow an effect when touched (such as enhanced accuracy, instant "on fire," or an earthquake knocking down all other players). Finally, some releases included a "Juice" mode that increased the game's speed by a factor of four. Once again, playing in Tournament Mode disables all of these.The console releases also added an "Injury" stat for each player. This stat increases as the player is repeatedly shoved to the ground, and decrease all his other stats proportionally. Substitutions are also increased for each quarter, encouraging injured players to be swapped out for a quarter and come back refreshed. It also adds a further layer of possible tactics, as a strong player could be shut down with repeated shoving.Console releases also include an optional "Tag Mode" where the player always control the athlete holding the ball. Passing to a player switches control to that player as soon as the ball connects. This mode can be helpful for anyone not content with the A.I. teammate's handling and decisions.Computer AI AnalysisThe computer artificial intelligence seems to have two different modes. In one mode (mostly seen in early tournament matches) the computer adopts a more passive defensive strategy. They will rarely ever try to push the player over, and the player can often simply run the length of the court and put up a three, or go for an easy dunk without ever worrying about passing. On offense, they tend to often go for three pointers, and will almost always make them if the player doesn't steal or block the ball first (especially if the player is ahead in score). The AI will rarely ever go inside the paint for a lay up or a dunk in this mode.In the second mode (mostly seen in later tournament matches) the computer is much more aggressive. They will often try to push the player over, making it almost impossible to progress the ball up the length of the court without passing the ball to the other player frequently. Also, if the player tries to put up a three, they will almost always get shoved by the opposing computer controlled AI player if he is nearby. This makes it hard to get three pointers up, and the player can end up getting pummeled if they do not pass frequently. On offense, the AI will frequently go for dunks and attack the paint. However, if the player leaves them wide open on the perimeter they will pull up a three and make it almost all the time.In general, AI in the first mode is much easier to deal with than the aggressive second mode. The one advantage the first mode has to the second mode is on the offensive side because they will often go for three pointers and will make them almost all the time meaning they can come back quickly if the player is sloppy on the offensive end. However, because of the second modes extremely aggressive defensive, it is more often than not much harder to deal with. Though if the player can manage to get a huge lead on them, it is a lot harder for this mode to make a come back because they often don't put up three pointers.Always going for dunks is a good strategy when in the leadHowever, it is hard to get a big lead on either types of AI because of the Rubber Band AI effect. As the player's lead grows, the probability of making shots becomes progressively lower, while the AI's probability of success progressively increases. One strategy to deal with this is to always go for dunks after starting to get a lead bigger than two possessions (4 points), because dunks have a very high probability of going in. Likewise, never go for three pointers because the probability of a three pointer going in is very small when the player has a lead. Also increasing the defense on the perimeter is recommended because the computer's probability of making a three pointer when the player has a big lead is nearly 100%. This is why the second computer AI mode is easier to get a big lead on because they tend to not go for three pointers and have tougher defense on the perimeter than they do in the paint.It is interesting to note that if, in the last seconds before half-time or the end of the match, the computer has the ball and they throw up a full court shot it will always go in (a 100% probability) regardless of the score, but if they advance the ball to half court and shoot it from there their probability of making the shot is significantly reduced. For the player, the probability of making a full court shot is very small, giving the computer a competitive edge at the end of the game. Also in the last ten seconds before halftime or the end of the game the computer will become extremely aggressive (even more so than the second AI mode) regardless of the type of AI the player may be facing. If the player has the ball the computer will sprint full speed towards him/her and try to steal the ball and take a quick shot. So if the player is not careful, the computer can score 4 or 6 points in the final 10 seconds using quick steals and shots.[CR]Teams and Players[CR]NBA Team RostersKevin WillisAtlanta Hawks: Stacey Augmon, Mookie Blaylock, Kevin WillisBoston Celtics: Dee Brown, Dino Radja, Dominique Wilkins ( Xavier McDaniel, Eric Montross)Charlotte Hornets: Muggsy Bogues, Larry Johnson, Alonzo Mourning ( Dell Curry, Hersey Hawkins)Chicago Bulls: B.J. Armstrong, Toni Kukoc, Scottie Pippen ( Luc Longley)Cleveland Cavaliers: Brad Daugherty, Mark Price, Gerald Wilkins ( John Williams)Dallas Mavericks: Terry Davis, Jim Jackson, Jamal Mashburn ( Tony Dumas, Jason Kidd)Denver Nuggets: Mahmoud Abdul-Rauf, LaPhonso Ellis, Dikembe Mutombo ( Robert Pack, Jalen Rose)Detroit Pistons: Joe Dumars, Oliver Miller, Terry Mills ( Bill Curley, Grant Hill)Golden State Warriors: Tom Gugliotta, Rony Seikaly, Latrell Sprewell ( Tim Hardaway, Chris Mullin)Houston Rockets: Robert Horry, Hakeem Olajuwon, Otis Thorpe ( Sam Cassell, Vernon Maxwell)Indiana Pacers: Derrick McKey, Reggie Miller, Rik Smits ( Antonio Davis)Los Angeles Clippers: Pooh Richardson, Stanley Roberts, Malik Sealy ( Loy Vaught)Los Angeles Lakers: Vlade Divac, Anthony Peeler, Nick Van Exel ( Eddie Jones, James Worthy)Miami Heat: Harold Miner, Glen Rice, Steve Smith ( Billy Owens, Khalid Reeves)Milwaukee Bucks: Vin Baker, Todd Day, Eric Murdock ( Eric Mobley, Glenn Robinson)Minnesota Timberwolves: Christian Laettner, Isaiah Rider, Doug West ( Donyell Marshall, Sean Rooks)Penny HardawayNew Jersey Nets: Kenny Anderson, Derrick Coleman, Kevin Edwards ( Armen Gilliam, Yinka Dare)New York Knicks: Patrick Ewing, Charles Oakley, John Starks ( Derek Harper, Anthony Mason)Orlando Magic: Nick Anderson, Horace Grant, Penny Hardaway ( Dennis Scott)Philadelphia 76ers: Shawn Bradley, Jeff Malone, Clarence Weatherspoon ( Dana Barros, Sharone Wright)Phoenix Suns: Kevin Johnson, Danny Manning, Dan Majerle ( Wayman Tisdale, A.C. Green)Portland Trail Blazers: Clyde Drexler, Terry Porter, Clifford Robinson ( Aaron McKie, Rod Strickland)Sacramento Kings: Mitch Richmond, Lionel Simmons, Spud Webb ( Bobby Hurley)San Antonio Spurs: Sean Elliott, David Robinson, Dennis Rodman ( Terry Cummings, Wesley Person)Seattle SuperSonics: Shawn Kemp, Gary Payton, Detlef Schrempf ( Kendall Gill)Utah Jazz: Jeff Hornacek, Karl Malone, John Stockton ( David Benoit)Washington Bullets: Calbert Cheaney, Scott Skiles, Chris Webber ( Rex Chapman)(players in brackets are unlocked after beating all 27 teams in tournament mode)New PlayersThe Following players are new to the franchise (They did not appear in the original NBA Jam):Jason KiddDoug WestDennis ScottBill CurleyYinka DareTony DumasGrant HillEddie JonesJason KiddDonyell MarshallAaron McKieEric MobleyWesley PersonKhalid ReevesGlenn RobinsonJalen RoseBrooks ThompsonMonty WIlliams (Tavares Montgomery Williams)Sharone WrightGary PaytonTerry DavisRobert PackSam CassellRobert HorryOtis ThorpeStanley RobertsMalik SealyLoy VaughtAnthony PeelerSean RooksDoug WestA.C. GreenRod StricklandBobby HurleyLionel SimmonsTerry CummingsDennis RodmanDavid BenoitKevin WillisXavier McDanielEric MontrossMuggsy Bogues (Tyrone Curtis Bogues)Dell CurryToni KukocLuc LongleyGerald WilkinsJohn "Hot Rod" WilliamsOliver MillerAntonio DavisBilly OwensSteve SmithTodd DayKevin EdwardsArmen GilliamAnthony MasonDennis ScottDana BarrosShawn BradleyJeff MaloneRex ChapmanHidden Players (Varies Depending on Version)Former U.S. President Bill Clinton, one of the hidden playersAir DogEd BoonBrutahJohn CarltonChow-ChowSal DaVitaFacimeFalcusDan FordenTony GoskieHillKabukiKid SilkKirbyShawn LiptakJay MoonMoosekaMuskettJamie RivettScooter PieSnakeMark TurmellWeaselRandall CunninghamFrank ThomasLarry BirdCarol Blazejowski/BlazeFresh PrinceDJ Jazzy JeffMike D. (Beastie Boys)ADROCK (Beastie Boys)MCA (Beastie Boys)Heavy DBill ClintonHillary ClintonAl GorePrince CharlesBenny (Chicago Bulls Mascot)Crunch (Minnesota Timberwolves Mascot)Hugo (Charlotte Hornets Mascot)Suns Gorilla (Phoenix Suns Mascot)Sub-Zero ( Mortal Kombat. Removed due to video game violence controversy)Raiden (Mortal Kombat. Removed due to video game violence controversy)Reptile (Mortal Kombat. Removed due to video game violence controversy)Tony Goskie from Midway [CR]</plot>
		<releasedate>13/8/1995</releasedate>
		<year>1995</year>
		<genre>Action, Sports</genre>
		<studio>Acclaim Entertainment</studio>
		<nplayers>1-2 VS</nplayers>
		<perspective>3rd-Person</perspective>
		<rating>3.7</rating>
		<ESRB>E - Everyone</ESRB>
		<thegamesdb_id>9077</thegamesdb_id>
		<mobygames_url>https://www.mobygames.com/game/sega-32x/nba-jam-tournament-edition</mobygames_url>
		<giantbomb_url>https://www.giantbomb.com/nba-jam-tournament-edition/3030-14792/</giantbomb_url>
		<consolegrid_url>http://consolegrid.com/games/4655</consolegrid_url>
		<boxart1>wmkCSVp.jpg</boxart1>
		<boxart2>oems50j.jpg</boxart2>
		<boxart3>oMoAo9v.jpg</boxart3>
		<snapshot1>MmpDtyJ.png</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>pi1Narl.png</snapshot2>
		<snapshot3>grg6PBo.png</snapshot3>
		<snapshot4>Olm3QDW.png</snapshot4>
		<snapshot5>j1motbQ.png</snapshot5>
		<snapshot6>BKWQFLd.png</snapshot6>
		<snapshot7>ammXR3u.png</snapshot7>
		<snapshot8>6VcjsSg.png</snapshot8>
		<snapshot9>58cXFKR.png</snapshot9>
		<snapshot10>WnMrt2z.png</snapshot10>
		<fanart1>dp12eKv.jpg</fanart1>
		<banner1>WsiVBw3.jpg</banner1>
		<clearlogo1>5d2vMmP.png</clearlogo1>
	</game>
	<game name="NFL Quarterback Club (World)">
		<description>NFL Quarterback Club (World)</description>
		<rom crc="0BC7018D" name="Sega_32X/NFL%20Quarterback%20Club%20%28World%29.32x" sha1="A0DC24F2F3A7FC5BFD12791CF25AF7F7888843CF" size="2027895" />
		<title_clean>NFL Quarterback Club</title_clean>
		<plot>One of the earliest in the NFL Quarterback series, this version features the standard game modes such as Exhibition, Season, Playoffs, etc. and features a full NFL license with players and their teams respective names and logos.  One feature that is present in this game is the Quarterback Skills Challenge where the player can choose from 13 different quarterbacks such as John Elway, Steve Young, Dan Marino and many others in a QB competition.  The goal is to complete a series of drills such as hitting a bulls-eyes, throwing long distances, competing in obstacle courses or test out their throwing accuracy.  It also has a two-player option where friends can compete head-to-head.</plot>
		<releasedate>13/8/1995</releasedate>
		<year>1995</year>
		<genre>Simulation, Sports</genre>
		<studio>Acclaim Entertainment</studio>
		<nplayers>1-2 VS</nplayers>
		<perspective>3rd-Person</perspective>
		<ESRB>E - Everyone</ESRB>
		<thegamesdb_id>14262</thegamesdb_id>
		<mobygames_url>https://www.mobygames.com/game/sega-32x/nfl-quarterback-club__</mobygames_url>
		<giantbomb_url>https://www.giantbomb.com/nfl-quarterback-club/3030-22136/</giantbomb_url>
		<consolegrid_url>http://consolegrid.com/games/4667</consolegrid_url>
		<boxart1>gs26ESc.jpg</boxart1>
		<boxart2>tWsXpTm.jpg</boxart2>
		<snapshot1>uSbA0pK.png</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>Gg6BkTo.png</snapshot2>
		<snapshot3>T496x6q.png</snapshot3>
		<snapshot4>pplOdE5.png</snapshot4>
		<snapshot5>tjBRM2Z.png</snapshot5>
		<snapshot6>tweAgTc.png</snapshot6>
		<snapshot7>EZJzfDO.png</snapshot7>
		<snapshot8>YeXzcNZ.png</snapshot8>
		<snapshot9>fX4hAVo.png</snapshot9>
		<snapshot10>HA4Rnph.png</snapshot10>
	</game>
	<game name="Parasquad - Zaxxon's Motherbase 2000 (Japan, USA)">
		<description>Parasquad - Zaxxon's Motherbase 2000 (Japan, USA)</description>
		<rom crc="447D44BE" name="Sega_32X/Parasquad%20-%20Zaxxons%20Motherbase%202000%20%28Japan%2C%20USA%29.32x" sha1="60C390F76C394BDD221936C21AECBF98AEC49A3D" size="1052750" />
		<title_clean>Parasquad - Zaxxon's Motherbase 2000</title_clean>
		<plot>This 32X-exclusive sci-fi shooter has gameplay is somewhat like Sega arcade classic Zaxxon. The graphics consist of a diagonally scrolling playfield which creates a pseudo 3D environment.  The backgrounds are drawn using 2D scrolling planes, but the enemy and ship objects are drawn using 3D flat-shaded polygons.[CR]Although the basic goal of each of the 9 levels is to shoot everything without getting shot, the game has a strategic element.  Your basic spacecraft has very little firepower, and can only sustain one hit.  To make matters worse, there are very few power-ups.  In order to survive, you have to jump on top of enemies and take control of their weapons systems.  This system allows for a large variety of player-controllable ships.</plot>
		<releasedate>13/8/1995</releasedate>
		<year>1995</year>
		<genre>Action</genre>
		<studio>Sega</studio>
		<nplayers>1</nplayers>
		<perspective>Isometric</perspective>
		<rating>3.2</rating>
		<ESRB>E - Everyone</ESRB>
		<thegamesdb_id>9083</thegamesdb_id>
		<mobygames_url>https://www.mobygames.com/game/sega-32x/zaxxons-motherbase-2000</mobygames_url>
		<giantbomb_url>https://www.giantbomb.com/zaxxons-motherbase-2000/3030-7390/</giantbomb_url>
		<boxart1>WD5BzkZ.jpg</boxart1>
		<boxart2>DmAUMDW.jpg</boxart2>
		<boxart3>MJtNA4J.jpg</boxart3>
		<boxart4>KEv8lDk.jpg</boxart4>
		<snapshot1>n7VENX7.gif</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>z8s79c8.gif</snapshot2>
		<snapshot3>lrlzp6c.gif</snapshot3>
		<snapshot4>qEq2tY6.gif</snapshot4>
		<snapshot5>sUhI5s0.gif</snapshot5>
		<snapshot6>2FvEQrT.gif</snapshot6>
		<snapshot7>kAQytNd.gif</snapshot7>
		<snapshot8>ajcYu5q.png</snapshot8>
		<snapshot9>uKydgyk.png</snapshot9>
		<snapshot10>0zVcvn1.jpg</snapshot10>
	</game>
	<game name="Pitfall - The Mayan Adventure (USA)">
		<description>Pitfall - The Mayan Adventure (USA)</description>
		<rom crc="F9126F15" name="Sega_32X/Pitfall%20-%20The%20Mayan%20Adventure%20%28USA%29.32x" sha1="EE864D1677C6D976D0846EB5F8D8EDB839ACFB76" size="2247413" />
		<title_clean>Pitfall - The Mayan Adventure</title_clean>
		<plot>[CR][B]Overview:[/B][CR]Released in 1994 for the Super Nintendo Entertainment System, Sega Genesis, and Sega CD. In 1995, it was released for the Sega 32X, Atari Jaguar, and PC. In 2001, it was ported to the Game Boy Advance. In 2009, the Sega Genesis version was released on the Nintendo Wii's Wii Shop as a Virtual Console title.[CR][B]Plot:[/B][CR]Pitfall Harry, from the original Atari 2600 classic Pitfall!, has gotten himself into trouble, and it's up to his son, Pitfall Harry Jr. to save him.[CR]Easter Eggs[CR]As an Easter Egg, the original Atari 2600 game can be played by finding a secret door marked by a sprite of a scorpion from the original game.[CR]</plot>
		<releasedate>13/8/1995</releasedate>
		<year>1995</year>
		<genre>Action</genre>
		<studio>Activision</studio>
		<nplayers>1</nplayers>
		<perspective>3rd-Person</perspective>
		<rating>3.0</rating>
		<ESRB>T - Teen</ESRB>
		<thegamesdb_id>9079</thegamesdb_id>
		<mobygames_url>https://www.mobygames.com/game/sega-32x/pitfall-the-mayan-adventure</mobygames_url>
		<giantbomb_url>https://www.giantbomb.com/pitfall-the-mayan-adventure/3030-9331/</giantbomb_url>
		<consolegrid_url>http://consolegrid.com/games/4721</consolegrid_url>
		<boxart1>NkXb5B5.jpg</boxart1>
		<snapshot1>JdITSnw.jpg</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>mC7ZESI.png</snapshot2>
		<snapshot3>TEBYv0A.png</snapshot3>
		<snapshot4>Nc43PAI.png</snapshot4>
		<snapshot5>HMzk4vR.png</snapshot5>
		<snapshot6>OpfpaKy.png</snapshot6>
		<snapshot7>K6DSw9a.png</snapshot7>
		<snapshot8>f44wVt9.png</snapshot8>
		<snapshot9>9pHAVzD.png</snapshot9>
		<snapshot10>2B3tGow.png</snapshot10>
		<banner1>WnLmrTX.png</banner1>
		<clearlogo1>ArZfKss.png</clearlogo1>
	</game>
	<game name="Primal Rage (USA, Europe)">
		<description>Primal Rage (USA, Europe)</description>
		<rom crc="E78A4D28" name="Sega_32X/Primal%20Rage%20%28USA%2C%20Europe%29.32x" sha1="5084DCCA51D76173C383AB7D04CBC661673545F7" size="2960121" />
		<title_clean>Primal Rage</title_clean>
		<plot>[CR][B]Overview:[/B][CR]Primal Rage is a 2D fighting game developed and released by Atari for arcades in 1994. Players control one of seven giant beasts (who are rendered in stop-motion animation) who must battle each other to conquer a post-apocalyptic neo-Stone Age Earth (known in the game as "Urth"). Although not as popular as the also-violent Mortal Kombat franchise, the game spawned toys, comic books, and a novel, as well as many ports.A sequel (simply named Primal Rage II) was in development, but was canceled (though some early prototypes have been found). [CR][B]Gameplay:[/B][CR]Primal Rage plays like a traditional 2D fighting game. Along with a joystick, each player has four buttons arranged in a square (horizontally from Quick to Fierce and vertically from High to Low). Pressing both High Quick and High Fierce simultaneously executes a powerful High Power attack, while pressing both Low Quick and Low Fierce simultaneously executes a powerful Low Power attack. Unlike traditional fighting games, where special moves are executed by first moving the joystick in a combination and then pressing one or more buttons, Primal Rage includes a system where special moves are executed by holding down certain buttons and then moving the joystick. Fatalities (glorified execution moves that can only be performed at the end of the winner's winning round) are also performed in this way. However, later arcade versions and most ports also include the traditional special move/fatality execution alongside this way.During the fight, human worshipers from the tribes of both fighters are scattered in the background. All characters have a special move (with unique combinations) which allows them to devour humans that enter the foreground (giving back some of the player's health). Devouring enemy worshipers also grant the player bonus points, while devouring friendly worshipers take away from the player's score.After defeating all seven opponents In the single-player campaign, the player has dominated Urth. But the beast still needs to prepare for one giant final battle to keep its place as "king of the hill". A bonus round occurs where the player has a limited amount of time to devour friendly worshipers (with no point loss) and flying pterodactyls for bonus health (that is used after the player's health has depleted in the final battle). During the final battle in the hellish "dinosaur graveyard", the player must survive against all seven opponents consecutively in one giant round. If the player loses both the initial health and the bonus health, he can immediately restore his initial health by continuing. The player is granted more points at the end of the campaign by using less continues.[CR]Characters [CR] The character select screen with the seven playable characters.The game includes seven playable characters. (Six in the Game Boy and Game Gear versions) A final boss character was planned for the final stage, but was scrapped. Sauron and Diablo are palette swaps of each other, while Blizzard and Chaos are also palette swaps. (However, Diablo and Chaos are smaller than Sauron and Blizzard in terms of size) Sauron Talon Vertigo (not available in the Game Boy and Game Gear versions) Blizzard Chaos Armadon Diablo[CR]</plot>
		<releasedate>13/8/1995</releasedate>
		<year>1995</year>
		<genre>Action</genre>
		<studio>Time Warner Interactive</studio>
		<nplayers>1-2 VS</nplayers>
		<perspective>Side-Scrolling</perspective>
		<rating>3.6</rating>
		<ESRB>T - Teen</ESRB>
		<thegamesdb_id>4922</thegamesdb_id>
		<mobygames_url>https://www.mobygames.com/game/sega-32x/primal-rage</mobygames_url>
		<giantbomb_url>https://www.giantbomb.com/primal-rage/3030-14078/</giantbomb_url>
		<consolegrid_url>http://consolegrid.com/games/4730</consolegrid_url>
		<boxart1>myJ5aE9.jpg</boxart1>
		<boxart2>IOsPB7a.jpg</boxart2>
		<boxart3>04u41TD.jpg</boxart3>
		<snapshot1>bfBJY8f.png</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>JSUbqX0.png</snapshot2>
		<snapshot3>milrJkH.png</snapshot3>
		<snapshot4>rACaqEJ.jpg</snapshot4>
		<snapshot5>bSTjRX1.jpg</snapshot5>
		<snapshot6>yPc7eIR.jpg</snapshot6>
		<snapshot7>thXai2b.jpg</snapshot7>
		<snapshot8>cnIYFGp.jpg</snapshot8>
		<snapshot9>4a4h9wg.jpg</snapshot9>
		<snapshot10>ZWiv1wJ.jpg</snapshot10>
		<banner1>2IFStc0.jpg</banner1>
		<clearlogo1>eFf2hx3.png</clearlogo1>
	</game>
	<game name="RBI Baseball '95 (USA)">
		<description>RBI Baseball '95 (USA)</description>
		<rom crc="FF795FDC" name="Sega_32X/RBI%20Baseball%2095%20%28USA%29.32x" sha1="4F90433A4403FD74CAFEEA49272689046DE4AE43" size="1244997" />
		<title_clean>RBI Baseball '95</title_clean>
		<plot>[CR][B]Overview:[/B][CR]RBI Baseball '95 is a baseball game developed and published by Time Warner Interactive for the Sega 32X platform.[CR][B]Gameplay:[/B][CR]RBI Baseball '95 plays like a typical baseball game at the time with multiple modes of play. The game had the MLBPA license to use specific players from the MLB but did not have the full MLB license so none of the real MLB teams are present. The teams were only named after the cities of real MLB teams and even used colors that were very similar to the MLB teams.ModesStadium Tour - The season mode of the game.Play Ball - An exhibition game which the player can choose both teams and play.Home Run Derby - The player gets 20 pitches from a pitching machine to get as many home runs as possible.Defense Practice - In defense practice the computer players team bats from a post so the player can practice playing as the defense.Game Breakers - In the game breakers mode the player chooses a famous situation in baseball history and the goal is to re-create it.[CR]</plot>
		<releasedate>13/8/1995</releasedate>
		<year>1995</year>
		<genre>Simulation, Sports</genre>
		<studio>Time Warner Interactive</studio>
		<nplayers>1-2 Co-Op, 1-2 VS</nplayers>
		<perspective>3rd-Person</perspective>
		<ESRB>E - Everyone</ESRB>
		<thegamesdb_id>9080</thegamesdb_id>
		<mobygames_url>https://www.mobygames.com/game/sega-32x/rbi-baseball-95</mobygames_url>
		<giantbomb_url>https://www.giantbomb.com/rbi-baseball-95/3030-24882/</giantbomb_url>
		<consolegrid_url>http://consolegrid.com/games/4742</consolegrid_url>
		<boxart1>5hFG6c1.jpg</boxart1>
		<boxart2>o4X2h7d.jpg</boxart2>
		<snapshot1>ku9oJj6.png</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>LdVuoAu.png</snapshot2>
		<snapshot3>fk7DvH4.png</snapshot3>
		<snapshot4>eIQCx6h.png</snapshot4>
		<snapshot5>QkF97tE.png</snapshot5>
		<snapshot6>A2tqkud.png</snapshot6>
		<snapshot7>o6myRjm.png</snapshot7>
		<snapshot8>qzovkeU.png</snapshot8>
		<snapshot9>7pP2zkc.png</snapshot9>
		<snapshot10>yMRkJDy.png</snapshot10>
		<banner1>cYypY1e.jpg</banner1>
	</game>
	<game name="Sangokushi IV (Japan)">
		<description>Sangokushi IV (Japan)</description>
		<rom crc="E4DE7625" name="Sega_32X/Sangokushi%20IV%20%28Japan%29.32x" sha1="74A3BA27C55CFF12409BF6C9324ECE6247ABBAD1" size="3197088" />
		<title_clean>Sangokushi IV</title_clean>
		<plot>[CR][B]Overview:[/B][CR]Romance of the Three Kingdoms IV: Wall of Fire (JP: Sangokushi IV) is the fourth entry in Koei's long-running strategy game franchise based on the historical novel Romance of the Three Kingdoms. The subtitle "Wall of Fire" is a reference to the Battle of Chibi (Battle of Red Cliff) in which a navy commanded by Cao Cao of Wei was destroyed in a successful fire attack. The loss stunted his conquest's momentum and was partially responsible for allowing two other kingdoms, Wu and Shu, to rise to power.[CR][B]Gameplay:[/B][CR]As in other entries of the series, Wall of Fire is a turn-based strategy game in which the player takes control of a ruling officer with the ultimate goal of conquering all of China through warfare and diplomacy. Each in-game turn spans a single month, during which time officers under the player's control can be assigned various domestic, diplomatic and militaristic tasks. These tasks rage from overseeing farmland and attempting to court officers to the player's side to drafting and training new soldiers.When going to battle, the player must first organize the troops under the participating officers by assigning specific numbers of soldiers to each officer, as well as assigning a unit type. In battle, each turn lasts a single day, during which each unit under the player's control is granted one movement action and one attack or special action such as taunting the enemy or proposing a duel.[CR]</plot>
		<releasedate>28/7/1995</releasedate>
		<year>1995</year>
		<genre>Strategy</genre>
		<studio>KOEI Co.</studio>
		<nplayers>1</nplayers>
		<perspective>Isometric</perspective>
		<rating>3.9</rating>
		<thegamesdb_id>20519</thegamesdb_id>
		<mobygames_url>https://www.mobygames.com/game/sega-32x/romance-of-the-three-kingdoms-iv-wall-of-fire</mobygames_url>
		<giantbomb_url>https://www.giantbomb.com/romance-of-the-three-kingdoms-iv-wall-of-fire/3030-6057/</giantbomb_url>
		<boxart1>o3yPHA0.jpg</boxart1>
		<snapshot1>rpNR6VF.png</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>vSS3FsK.png</snapshot2>
		<snapshot3>EliEq4A.png</snapshot3>
		<snapshot4>PskeGhj.png</snapshot4>
		<snapshot5>cQozfFK.jpg</snapshot5>
		<snapshot6>ACQfZFg.jpg</snapshot6>
		<snapshot7>FGMLCdc.jpg</snapshot7>
		<snapshot8>Ylm2NKC.jpg</snapshot8>
		<snapshot9>gYNNZmM.jpg</snapshot9>
		<snapshot10>afuvEkJ.jpg</snapshot10>
	</game>
	<game name="Shadow Squadron - Stellar Assault (USA, Europe)">
		<description>Shadow Squadron - Stellar Assault (USA, Europe)</description>
		<rom crc="60C49E4D" name="Sega_32X/Shadow%20Squadron%20-%20Stellar%20Assault%20%28USA%2C%20Europe%29.32x" sha1="561C8C63DBCABC0B1B6F31673CA75A0BDE7ABC72" size="470657" />
		<title_clean>Shadow Squadron - Stellar Assault</title_clean>
		<plot>Shadow Squadron is a space shooter game that is a little more complex than fellow 32X game Star Wars Arcade, closer in style to games such as Wing Commander.  It features 6 missions, and the player can select between two ships with different attributes. The game outlines your objective prior to each mission, which is usually to destroy a number of smaller fighters as well as some larger cruisers or capital ships.  These larger ships feature impressive destructibility, especially for a game of this era, as multiple pieces can be blown off of these ships before they explode entirely.  The game has two difficulties: easy and hard. Players have access to a standard laser weapon, as well as a lock on torpedo system that depletes a weapon energy gauge. If all weapon energy is lost, shield energy can be converted to weapon energy. The player dies once all energy is depleted. The game starts players off with 3 credits. Although the game is playable with a 3- button controller, this can be difficult, as in addition to the two weapon types players can also speed up, slow down, and rotate their craft, as well as change view modes. Not all control options are available with a 3- button controller, so a 6-button controller is required to take full advantage of the controls on offer. The game can be played either from a cockpit view or a chase camera perspective. [CR]</plot>
		<releasedate>13/8/1995</releasedate>
		<year>1995</year>
		<genre>Action</genre>
		<studio>Sega</studio>
		<nplayers>1-2 Sim</nplayers>
		<perspective>1st-Person</perspective>
		<rating>3.9</rating>
		<thegamesdb_id>4923</thegamesdb_id>
		<mobygames_url>https://www.mobygames.com/game/sega-32x/shadow-squadron</mobygames_url>
		<giantbomb_url>https://www.giantbomb.com/shadow-squadron/3030-11386/</giantbomb_url>
		<consolegrid_url>http://consolegrid.com/games/8486</consolegrid_url>
		<boxart1>XsmOcPE.jpg</boxart1>
		<boxart2>TDyyciI.jpg</boxart2>
		<boxart3>JW6VVOw.jpg</boxart3>
		<boxart4>sbfcjQ1.jpg</boxart4>
		<snapshot1>EUo7hws.gif</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>iBhelkH.gif</snapshot2>
		<snapshot3>1DsoFgO.gif</snapshot3>
		<snapshot4>ftCyWdM.gif</snapshot4>
		<snapshot5>b01S54I.gif</snapshot5>
		<snapshot6>UPRnZFB.gif</snapshot6>
		<snapshot7>P3d2U1b.gif</snapshot7>
		<snapshot8>WMlnWZz.gif</snapshot8>
		<snapshot9>Hx27QgH.png</snapshot9>
		<snapshot10>4HXiQ7q.jpg</snapshot10>
		<banner1>E0Biix5.jpg</banner1>
	</game>
	<game name="Soulstar X (USA) (Proto)">
		<description>Soulstar X (USA) (Proto)</description>
		<rom crc="6472BAE4" name="Sega_32X/Soulstar%20X%20%28USA%29%20%28Proto%29.32x" sha1="9583545E15266D3F90A5CB57961908206E4543F7" size="1171786" />
		<title_clean>Soulstar X</title_clean>
		<plot>Core Design's original Sega CD game Soul Star  is an awesome shooter featuring colorful sprite-based graphics, smooth scaling, and a behind-the-ship view. The upgraded Soul Star X would have made a fine showcase title for the 32x, especially with enhanced graphics and additional levels.[CR]Soul Star is pseudo-3D, cockpit-view space shooting game from Core -- the peaceful six planets of the Soulstar have been invaded by the Myrkoids, and you are the last hope as a space warrior with blazing weapons.[CR]Soul Star X was never released</plot>
		<genre>Shooter</genre>
		<nplayers>1</nplayers>
		<thegamesdb_id>35756</thegamesdb_id>
		<boxart1>7uVOaue.png</boxart1>
		<boxart2>1ydqjX7.png</boxart2>
	</game>
	<game name="Space Harrier (Europe)">
		<description>Space Harrier (Europe)</description>
		<rom crc="5CAC3587" name="Sega_32X/Space%20Harrier%20%28Europe%29.32x" sha1="8B0495257FA5392EF9DDCC9C3BA1860AE58F4F3D" size="868735" />
		<title_clean>Space Harrier</title_clean>
		<plot>[CR][B]Overview:[/B][CR]"Welcome to the Fantasy Zone, get ready!"Space Harrier (&#12473;&#12506;&#12540;&#12473;&#12495;&#12522;&#12450;&#12540; Sup&#275;su Hari&#257;) is a third-person rail shooter game. It was developed by Sega AM2 and created by legendary developer, Yu Suzuki, responsible for many popular Sega games. The game was published by Sega and originally released in the arcades in October 1985. Since then, the game has been released on a number of platforms and spawned many sequels.Using Sega's Super Scaler 16-bit graphics technology, the game produced pseudo-3D sprite-scaling at high frame rates, with the ability to scale as many as 32,000 sprites and fill a moving landscape with them, along with 6144 colors on screen out of a 98,304 color palette (15-bit RGB high color depth with shadow &amp; highlight).It also introduced a true analog flight stick for movement, with the ability to register movement in any direction as well as measure the degree of push, which could move the player character at different speeds depending on how far the stick is pushed in a certain direction. It also introduced a motion-based, hydraulic cockpit arcade cabinet, which moved in the direction the player moved the joystick. The game was also an early example of a third-person shooter; it was influenced by the earlier 1982 Sega game Buck Rogers: Planet of Zoom, and Space Harrier in turn influenced later 3D shooters such as Nintendo's Star Fox (Starwing) in 1993.Running on the Sega Space Harrier arcade system board previously used by Hang-On, the pseudo-3D sprite/tile scaling in the game was handled in a similar manner to textures in later texture-mapped polygonal 3D games of the 1990s. Yu Suzuki stated that his "designs were always 3D from the beginning. All the calculations in the system were 3D, even from Hang-On. I calculated the position, scale, and zoom rate in 3D and converted it backwards to 2D. So I was always thinking in 3D."[1] The game's success established Suzuki as the leading arcade game designer at the time.[2]Space Harrier later saw ports to many home game systems.Space Harrier's release on the Sega Master System home console is particularly notable, as there were two versions: one was a port of the arcade game, while the other, entitled Space Harrier 3-D (1988), supported the SegaScope stereoscopic 3D glasses. The game also spawned the sequel Space Harrier II (1988) and the spin-off Planet Harriers (2000).[CR][B]Gameplay:[/B][CR]The bonus stage.The game takes place in a unique place called the "Fantasy Zone" (no deeper plot is associated with Space Harrier). The Fantasy zone is a place filled with many strange creatures like one-eyed mammoths, alien pods, strange looking dragons, robots and flying mushrooms etc. The main character is a man with a giant gun/rocket that allows him to fly around. He runs along in a pseudo 3D level blasting anything that comes at him.The game has the player moving forward at all times and many enemies will get in the player's way, blasting projectiles and moving along in a certain pattern. The player must also do his or her best to move out of harm's way while shooting at anything that's presented on screen. Most objects are destructible, but some are not. If the player gets hit once, he or she will lose a life. The player starts off with two lives, and an extra life can be gained if the player racks up 5,000,000 points.The arcade version.The points will gradually increase as the player keeps moving. More points will be given for every thing that is destroyed by the player.There are eighteen stages in the game and a boss fight is presented in the end of sixteen of the stages. Two of the stages, stage 5 and stage 12, are bonus levels. The main character will jump on a dragon-like creature and destroy as many objects - trees, stone poles and bushes - as he or she can.StagesThe third stage, Amar.Stage 1: MootStage 2: GeezaStage 3: AmarStage 4: CiecielStage 5: Bonus StageStage 6: OlisisStage 7: LucasiaStage 8: IdaStage 9: ReviStage 10: MiniaStage 11: ParmsStage 12: Bonus StageStage 13: DrailStage 14: AsuteStage 15: VicelStage 16: NaturaStage 17: NarkStage 18: Absymbel[CR]Arcade cabinets[CR]There were several different arcade cabinets. The first two were the standard upright and sit-down cabinets, which introduced the use of an analog flight stick that, for the first time, detected movement in 360 directions as well as the degree of push. The first port to feature similar analog stick controls was the version that appeared in Shenmue for the Dreamcast in 1999.The third was a new type of deluxe cabinet: the "rolling" cabinet. The "rolling" type moved the entire cabinet in the direction the player moved the analog flight stick, left/right and forward/backward, simulating flight movement for the first time in an arcade cabinet. The first port to simulate the rolling type deluxe arcade cabinet was Space Harrier 3D, which utilized the Nintendo 3DS's gyroscope motion sensor, in 2012.[CR]Sega Space Harrier arcade hardware[CR]The arcade hardware used to run the game is widely known as the Sega Space Harrier system, or less commonly known as the Sega Hang-On system. It utilized two boards: the CPU (Central Processing Unit) mother board, and the Super Scaler graphics board which handled the game's complex sprite-scaling. The game displayed 128 sprites per frame, at 60 frames per second, scaling 7680 sprites per second. The graphics board itself is capable of scaling up to 32,000 sprites per second with more memory, as was the case with later Super Scaler titles.Technical specificationsCPU (Central Processing Unit) mother boardMain CPU processors: 2x Motorola MC 68000 (16/32-bit) @ 10 MHz each Performance: 3.5 MIPS (Million Instructions Per Second)Additional CPU: Intel 8751 (8-bit) @ 8 MHzSound CPU: Zilog Z80 (8-bit) @ 4 MHz Performance: 580,000 IPS (Instructions Per Second)Stereo sound chips FM (Frequency Modulation) synthesis chip: Yamaha YM2203 @ 4 MHz Channels: 3 FM channels, 3 SSG (Software-controlled Sound Generator) channelsPCM (Pulse-Code Modulation) chip: SegaPCM @ 8 MHz Channels: 16 PCM 8-bit channels @ 31.25 KHz sampling rateRAM (Random Access Memory) Program RAM: 32 KBAudio RAM: 2 KBROM (Read-Only Memory) Program EPROM (Erasable Programmable ROM) memory: 448 KBAudio EPROM: 192 KBAudio ROM for PCM audio samples: Up to 16 MBSuper Scaler GPU (Graphics Processing Unit) boardGPU: Sega Super Scaler 171-5320 graphics card Sega 315-5011 sprite line comparitorSega 315-5012 sprite generator2x Sega 315-5049 tilemap chipsSega PAL chipset: 2x Sega 315-5107 horizontal timing controlSega 315-5108 vertical timing controlSega 315-5122 timing chipDisplay resolution: 320 x 224 pixelsColours on screen: 6,144Colour palette: 32,768 (15-bit colour)Frame rate: 60 frames per secondSprites displayed per frame: 128Sprites displayed per second: 7680Sprites scaled per second: Up to 32,000Hardware layers: 2 tile layers1 text layer1 sprite layer with hardware sprite zooming1 road layerTranslucent shadowsVRAM (Video RAM) memory: 192 KB high-speed SRAM (Static RAM)Graphics EPROM: 1152 KB[CR]Console ports[CR]The game was ported to several Sega consoles, such as the Sega 32X, and Sega Saturn. It also found its way to numerous computers and consoles of its era, often with various compromises in quality. The 32X version is one of the earliest ports to match quality with the arcade game, though even it cuts a couple of corners here and there. The Saturn version, released in Japan as "Sega Ages: Space Harrier" is also a pretty faithful version of the game. This version of the game also appeared in the US with two other games on a compilation disc simply called Sega Ages.The two Master System versions, including Space Harrier 3-D, reduced the graphical quality and speed quite a bit, but still managed to be a recognizable port of the original game. The first Master System version, released in 1986, was the first home video game cartridge to feature 2 Megabits (256 Kilobytes) of memory. The second Master System version, Space Harrier 3-D, featured the use of stereoscopic 3D graphics. The Master System versions also contain a new final boss fight against two glowing dragon creatures known as "Haya Oh." This new boss fight also appears in the X68000 version of the game. The Game Gear version of the game shares some of the basic quality issues as the Master System release, but contains different levels, an adjusted resolution, and a password system for continuing from later levels.Space Harrier, featured in Shenmue.The game was also featured in the game Shenmue. Space Harrier was located in the "You Arcade" building in the Dobuita area of the game; the player has to pay one-hundred yen to play the game. The "Sega Saturn" version of Space Harrier was also featured as a prize in the raffle in some of the convenience stores. The Sega Saturn version can be played on Ryo's Sega Saturn that is located in his living room.A polygonal remake of the game was made as part of Sega's Sega Ages series in Japan. The polygonal version of Space Harrier was released outside of Japan in the form of Sega Classics Collection.[CR][B]Reception:[/B][CR]Arcade versionThe arcade game was well received upon release. It became one of 1986's chart hits in the arcades. Computer and Video Games magazine reviewed the arcade game in its March 1986 issue, after reviewer Clare Edgeley played it at the 1986 ATEI (Amusement Trades Exhibition International) show in London, along with the arcade version of Super Mario Bros. She stated, "Perhaps the games to steal the show were" Space Harrier along with Shrike Avenger (1986), praising their hydraulic cockpit cabinets that "twist, turn and move" in the same direction as the joystick, making them "the most realistic" simulators "to date". She praised Space Harrier's "excellent graphics" for being "all in 3D with amazing technicolour landscapes" and a "multitude of objects" on screen, as well as "the sounds of the battle" output by "large speakers" where "you could almost lose touch with reality". She also praised the gameplay for being "exciting" and "very fast" paced, as well as the continue feature, but stated the game can be "very difficult."Clare Edgeley gave the arcade game a retrospective review in the February 1987 issue of Sinclair User, where she noted it had one of the first hydraulic arcade cabinets she had seen, along with 1986's Shrike Avenger. She stated that Space Harrier's "fabulously colourful 3D graphics" and "the movement of the sit-in cabinet were, and still are, breathtaking", noting "the seat-belt" and "turbulent" ride which "hurls you up, down, left and right" and tilts "the cabinet in a roll in whatever direction you push your joystick", concluding the game to be "great fun."Home conversionsReview scoresPublicationScoreComputer and Video Games70% (C64)68% (ZX)40% (CPC)[3]CRASH77% (ZX)Famitsu34/40 (3DS)Sinclair User (ZX)Your Sinclair9/10 (ZX)The Milwaukee Journal9/10 (SMS)AwardsEntityAwardGolden Joystick AwardsGame of the Year (Runner&#8209;Up)The home conversions were also well received. The game was runner-up in the category of Game of the Year at the 1986 Golden Joystick Awards.The Milwaukee Journal in May 1987 gave the Master System version a positive review, rating it a score of 9 out of 10. The reviewer Edward J. Semrad described the Master System version of Space Harrier as "the latest innovation" and "the most powerful cartridge ever made for any computer or game system." He concluded it "sets new standards in audio, graphic detail, memory and price ($40 list)."The September 1988 issue of Computer Gaming World (page 50) called Space Harrier "the best arcade shoot-'em-up of the year ... as exciting a game as this reviewer has ever played".[CR][B]Trivia:[/B][CR]The flying furry creature in the bonus stages is very similar to Falkor, the flying dog-dragon from the 1984 film, The NeverEnding Story.The game was originally supposed to be set in a real world military setting as players controlled a Harrier jet fighter. Due to the technical limitation at the offset of development of not having enough memory for all the intended graphics the decision was made to switch the game to a science fiction setting. The game however did retain the "Harrier" portion of its name though. [CR]</plot>
		<releasedate>13/8/1994</releasedate>
		<year>1994</year>
		<genre>Action</genre>
		<studio>Sega</studio>
		<nplayers>1</nplayers>
		<perspective>3rd-Person</perspective>
		<rating>3.5</rating>
		<ESRB>E10+ - Everyone 10+</ESRB>
		<videoid>Hzgrb-mjLaM</videoid>
		<thegamesdb_id>117</thegamesdb_id>
		<mobygames_url>https://www.mobygames.com/game/sega-32x/space-harrier</mobygames_url>
		<giantbomb_url>https://www.giantbomb.com/space-harrier/3030-6036/</giantbomb_url>
		<consolegrid_url>http://consolegrid.com/games/11449</consolegrid_url>
		<boxart1>yU3ZXgU.jpg</boxart1>
		<boxart2>U5zqbTc.jpg</boxart2>
		<boxart3>U0n9B3p.jpg</boxart3>
		<snapshot1>ZfKQhvK.jpg</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>reonvfq.gif</snapshot2>
		<snapshot3>Md3f2QA.gif</snapshot3>
		<snapshot4>lOqoBUQ.gif</snapshot4>
		<snapshot5>SFerM7i.gif</snapshot5>
		<snapshot6>eVfOSjm.gif</snapshot6>
		<snapshot7>y45ZFAT.gif</snapshot7>
		<snapshot8>AMJi9Vk.gif</snapshot8>
		<snapshot9>THuUehW.gif</snapshot9>
		<snapshot10>FUNihu0.gif</snapshot10>
		<fanart1>z4RGMJI.jpg</fanart1>
		<clearlogo1>beYgMIi.png</clearlogo1>
	</game>
	<game name="Space Harrier (Japan, USA)">
		<description>Space Harrier (Japan, USA)</description>
		<rom crc="86E7F989" name="Sega_32X/Space%20Harrier%20%28Japan%2C%20USA%29.32x" sha1="F32A52A7082761982024E40291DBD962A835B231" size="868254" />
		<title_clean>Space Harrier</title_clean>
		<plot>[CR][B]Overview:[/B][CR]"Welcome to the Fantasy Zone, get ready!"Space Harrier (&#12473;&#12506;&#12540;&#12473;&#12495;&#12522;&#12450;&#12540; Sup&#275;su Hari&#257;) is a third-person rail shooter game. It was developed by Sega AM2 and created by legendary developer, Yu Suzuki, responsible for many popular Sega games. The game was published by Sega and originally released in the arcades in October 1985. Since then, the game has been released on a number of platforms and spawned many sequels.Using Sega's Super Scaler 16-bit graphics technology, the game produced pseudo-3D sprite-scaling at high frame rates, with the ability to scale as many as 32,000 sprites and fill a moving landscape with them, along with 6144 colors on screen out of a 98,304 color palette (15-bit RGB high color depth with shadow &amp; highlight).It also introduced a true analog flight stick for movement, with the ability to register movement in any direction as well as measure the degree of push, which could move the player character at different speeds depending on how far the stick is pushed in a certain direction. It also introduced a motion-based, hydraulic cockpit arcade cabinet, which moved in the direction the player moved the joystick. The game was also an early example of a third-person shooter; it was influenced by the earlier 1982 Sega game Buck Rogers: Planet of Zoom, and Space Harrier in turn influenced later 3D shooters such as Nintendo's Star Fox (Starwing) in 1993.Running on the Sega Space Harrier arcade system board previously used by Hang-On, the pseudo-3D sprite/tile scaling in the game was handled in a similar manner to textures in later texture-mapped polygonal 3D games of the 1990s. Yu Suzuki stated that his "designs were always 3D from the beginning. All the calculations in the system were 3D, even from Hang-On. I calculated the position, scale, and zoom rate in 3D and converted it backwards to 2D. So I was always thinking in 3D."[1] The game's success established Suzuki as the leading arcade game designer at the time.[2]Space Harrier later saw ports to many home game systems.Space Harrier's release on the Sega Master System home console is particularly notable, as there were two versions: one was a port of the arcade game, while the other, entitled Space Harrier 3-D (1988), supported the SegaScope stereoscopic 3D glasses. The game also spawned the sequel Space Harrier II (1988) and the spin-off Planet Harriers (2000).[CR][B]Gameplay:[/B][CR]The bonus stage.The game takes place in a unique place called the "Fantasy Zone" (no deeper plot is associated with Space Harrier). The Fantasy zone is a place filled with many strange creatures like one-eyed mammoths, alien pods, strange looking dragons, robots and flying mushrooms etc. The main character is a man with a giant gun/rocket that allows him to fly around. He runs along in a pseudo 3D level blasting anything that comes at him.The game has the player moving forward at all times and many enemies will get in the player's way, blasting projectiles and moving along in a certain pattern. The player must also do his or her best to move out of harm's way while shooting at anything that's presented on screen. Most objects are destructible, but some are not. If the player gets hit once, he or she will lose a life. The player starts off with two lives, and an extra life can be gained if the player racks up 5,000,000 points.The arcade version.The points will gradually increase as the player keeps moving. More points will be given for every thing that is destroyed by the player.There are eighteen stages in the game and a boss fight is presented in the end of sixteen of the stages. Two of the stages, stage 5 and stage 12, are bonus levels. The main character will jump on a dragon-like creature and destroy as many objects - trees, stone poles and bushes - as he or she can.StagesThe third stage, Amar.Stage 1: MootStage 2: GeezaStage 3: AmarStage 4: CiecielStage 5: Bonus StageStage 6: OlisisStage 7: LucasiaStage 8: IdaStage 9: ReviStage 10: MiniaStage 11: ParmsStage 12: Bonus StageStage 13: DrailStage 14: AsuteStage 15: VicelStage 16: NaturaStage 17: NarkStage 18: Absymbel[CR]Arcade cabinets[CR]There were several different arcade cabinets. The first two were the standard upright and sit-down cabinets, which introduced the use of an analog flight stick that, for the first time, detected movement in 360 directions as well as the degree of push. The first port to feature similar analog stick controls was the version that appeared in Shenmue for the Dreamcast in 1999.The third was a new type of deluxe cabinet: the "rolling" cabinet. The "rolling" type moved the entire cabinet in the direction the player moved the analog flight stick, left/right and forward/backward, simulating flight movement for the first time in an arcade cabinet. The first port to simulate the rolling type deluxe arcade cabinet was Space Harrier 3D, which utilized the Nintendo 3DS's gyroscope motion sensor, in 2012.[CR]Sega Space Harrier arcade hardware[CR]The arcade hardware used to run the game is widely known as the Sega Space Harrier system, or less commonly known as the Sega Hang-On system. It utilized two boards: the CPU (Central Processing Unit) mother board, and the Super Scaler graphics board which handled the game's complex sprite-scaling. The game displayed 128 sprites per frame, at 60 frames per second, scaling 7680 sprites per second. The graphics board itself is capable of scaling up to 32,000 sprites per second with more memory, as was the case with later Super Scaler titles.Technical specificationsCPU (Central Processing Unit) mother boardMain CPU processors: 2x Motorola MC 68000 (16/32-bit) @ 10 MHz each Performance: 3.5 MIPS (Million Instructions Per Second)Additional CPU: Intel 8751 (8-bit) @ 8 MHzSound CPU: Zilog Z80 (8-bit) @ 4 MHz Performance: 580,000 IPS (Instructions Per Second)Stereo sound chips FM (Frequency Modulation) synthesis chip: Yamaha YM2203 @ 4 MHz Channels: 3 FM channels, 3 SSG (Software-controlled Sound Generator) channelsPCM (Pulse-Code Modulation) chip: SegaPCM @ 8 MHz Channels: 16 PCM 8-bit channels @ 31.25 KHz sampling rateRAM (Random Access Memory) Program RAM: 32 KBAudio RAM: 2 KBROM (Read-Only Memory) Program EPROM (Erasable Programmable ROM) memory: 448 KBAudio EPROM: 192 KBAudio ROM for PCM audio samples: Up to 16 MBSuper Scaler GPU (Graphics Processing Unit) boardGPU: Sega Super Scaler 171-5320 graphics card Sega 315-5011 sprite line comparitorSega 315-5012 sprite generator2x Sega 315-5049 tilemap chipsSega PAL chipset: 2x Sega 315-5107 horizontal timing controlSega 315-5108 vertical timing controlSega 315-5122 timing chipDisplay resolution: 320 x 224 pixelsColours on screen: 6,144Colour palette: 32,768 (15-bit colour)Frame rate: 60 frames per secondSprites displayed per frame: 128Sprites displayed per second: 7680Sprites scaled per second: Up to 32,000Hardware layers: 2 tile layers1 text layer1 sprite layer with hardware sprite zooming1 road layerTranslucent shadowsVRAM (Video RAM) memory: 192 KB high-speed SRAM (Static RAM)Graphics EPROM: 1152 KB[CR]Console ports[CR]The game was ported to several Sega consoles, such as the Sega 32X, and Sega Saturn. It also found its way to numerous computers and consoles of its era, often with various compromises in quality. The 32X version is one of the earliest ports to match quality with the arcade game, though even it cuts a couple of corners here and there. The Saturn version, released in Japan as "Sega Ages: Space Harrier" is also a pretty faithful version of the game. This version of the game also appeared in the US with two other games on a compilation disc simply called Sega Ages.The two Master System versions, including Space Harrier 3-D, reduced the graphical quality and speed quite a bit, but still managed to be a recognizable port of the original game. The first Master System version, released in 1986, was the first home video game cartridge to feature 2 Megabits (256 Kilobytes) of memory. The second Master System version, Space Harrier 3-D, featured the use of stereoscopic 3D graphics. The Master System versions also contain a new final boss fight against two glowing dragon creatures known as "Haya Oh." This new boss fight also appears in the X68000 version of the game. The Game Gear version of the game shares some of the basic quality issues as the Master System release, but contains different levels, an adjusted resolution, and a password system for continuing from later levels.Space Harrier, featured in Shenmue.The game was also featured in the game Shenmue. Space Harrier was located in the "You Arcade" building in the Dobuita area of the game; the player has to pay one-hundred yen to play the game. The "Sega Saturn" version of Space Harrier was also featured as a prize in the raffle in some of the convenience stores. The Sega Saturn version can be played on Ryo's Sega Saturn that is located in his living room.A polygonal remake of the game was made as part of Sega's Sega Ages series in Japan. The polygonal version of Space Harrier was released outside of Japan in the form of Sega Classics Collection.[CR][B]Reception:[/B][CR]Arcade versionThe arcade game was well received upon release. It became one of 1986's chart hits in the arcades. Computer and Video Games magazine reviewed the arcade game in its March 1986 issue, after reviewer Clare Edgeley played it at the 1986 ATEI (Amusement Trades Exhibition International) show in London, along with the arcade version of Super Mario Bros. She stated, "Perhaps the games to steal the show were" Space Harrier along with Shrike Avenger (1986), praising their hydraulic cockpit cabinets that "twist, turn and move" in the same direction as the joystick, making them "the most realistic" simulators "to date". She praised Space Harrier's "excellent graphics" for being "all in 3D with amazing technicolour landscapes" and a "multitude of objects" on screen, as well as "the sounds of the battle" output by "large speakers" where "you could almost lose touch with reality". She also praised the gameplay for being "exciting" and "very fast" paced, as well as the continue feature, but stated the game can be "very difficult."Clare Edgeley gave the arcade game a retrospective review in the February 1987 issue of Sinclair User, where she noted it had one of the first hydraulic arcade cabinets she had seen, along with 1986's Shrike Avenger. She stated that Space Harrier's "fabulously colourful 3D graphics" and "the movement of the sit-in cabinet were, and still are, breathtaking", noting "the seat-belt" and "turbulent" ride which "hurls you up, down, left and right" and tilts "the cabinet in a roll in whatever direction you push your joystick", concluding the game to be "great fun."Home conversionsReview scoresPublicationScoreComputer and Video Games70% (C64)68% (ZX)40% (CPC)[3]CRASH77% (ZX)Famitsu34/40 (3DS)Sinclair User (ZX)Your Sinclair9/10 (ZX)The Milwaukee Journal9/10 (SMS)AwardsEntityAwardGolden Joystick AwardsGame of the Year (Runner&#8209;Up)The home conversions were also well received. The game was runner-up in the category of Game of the Year at the 1986 Golden Joystick Awards.The Milwaukee Journal in May 1987 gave the Master System version a positive review, rating it a score of 9 out of 10. The reviewer Edward J. Semrad described the Master System version of Space Harrier as "the latest innovation" and "the most powerful cartridge ever made for any computer or game system." He concluded it "sets new standards in audio, graphic detail, memory and price ($40 list)."The September 1988 issue of Computer Gaming World (page 50) called Space Harrier "the best arcade shoot-'em-up of the year ... as exciting a game as this reviewer has ever played".[CR][B]Trivia:[/B][CR]The flying furry creature in the bonus stages is very similar to Falkor, the flying dog-dragon from the 1984 film, The NeverEnding Story.The game was originally supposed to be set in a real world military setting as players controlled a Harrier jet fighter. Due to the technical limitation at the offset of development of not having enough memory for all the intended graphics the decision was made to switch the game to a science fiction setting. The game however did retain the "Harrier" portion of its name though. [CR]</plot>
		<releasedate>13/8/1994</releasedate>
		<year>1994</year>
		<genre>Action</genre>
		<studio>Sega</studio>
		<nplayers>1</nplayers>
		<perspective>3rd-Person</perspective>
		<rating>3.5</rating>
		<ESRB>E10+ - Everyone 10+</ESRB>
		<videoid>Hzgrb-mjLaM</videoid>
		<thegamesdb_id>117</thegamesdb_id>
		<mobygames_url>https://www.mobygames.com/game/sega-32x/space-harrier</mobygames_url>
		<giantbomb_url>https://www.giantbomb.com/space-harrier/3030-6036/</giantbomb_url>
		<consolegrid_url>http://consolegrid.com/games/11449</consolegrid_url>
		<boxart1>CIMwTQ4.jpg</boxart1>
		<boxart2>U5zqbTc.jpg</boxart2>
		<boxart3>U0n9B3p.jpg</boxart3>
		<snapshot1>ZfKQhvK.jpg</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>reonvfq.gif</snapshot2>
		<snapshot3>Md3f2QA.gif</snapshot3>
		<snapshot4>lOqoBUQ.gif</snapshot4>
		<snapshot5>SFerM7i.gif</snapshot5>
		<snapshot6>eVfOSjm.gif</snapshot6>
		<snapshot7>y45ZFAT.gif</snapshot7>
		<snapshot8>AMJi9Vk.gif</snapshot8>
		<snapshot9>THuUehW.gif</snapshot9>
		<snapshot10>FUNihu0.gif</snapshot10>
		<fanart1>z4RGMJI.jpg</fanart1>
		<clearlogo1>beYgMIi.png</clearlogo1>
	</game>
	<game name="Star Trek Starfleet Academy - Starship Bridge Simulator (USA)">
		<description>Star Trek Starfleet Academy - Starship Bridge Simulator (USA)</description>
		<rom crc="DD9708B9" name="Sega_32X/Star%20Trek%20Starfleet%20Academy%20-%20Starship%20Bridge%20Simulator%20%28USA%29.32x" sha1="E5248328B64A1EC4F1079C88EE53EF8D48E99E58" size="1435630" />
		<title_clean>Star Trek Starfleet Academy - Starship Bridge Simulator</title_clean>
		<plot>Two years before the better-known computer game came this title, in which the aim is to successfully complete the space combat element of Starfleet training. You will fight Klingons, deal with repairs, and find yourself in all manner of dangerous situations, but try to stay within Starfleet directives.[CR]The game is viewed from the bridge of your vessel (there are 5 different ones in total), with polygons used to display the action. Information on the world situation at the time of the game is supplied within the game. There are quick missions bringing scenes from Star Trek movies to life.</plot>
		<releasedate>13/8/1995</releasedate>
		<year>1995</year>
		<genre>Simulation</genre>
		<studio>Interplay Productions</studio>
		<nplayers>1-2 VS</nplayers>
		<perspective>1st-Person</perspective>
		<ESRB>E - Everyone</ESRB>
		<thegamesdb_id>5970</thegamesdb_id>
		<mobygames_url>https://www.mobygames.com/game/sega-32x/star-trek-starfleet-academy-starship-bridge-simulator</mobygames_url>
		<giantbomb_url>https://www.giantbomb.com/star-trek-starfleet-academy-starship-bridge-simula/3030-19745/</giantbomb_url>
		<consolegrid_url>http://consolegrid.com/games/9621</consolegrid_url>
		<boxart1>LcWRTVC.jpg</boxart1>
		<boxart2>3zjiKg6.jpg</boxart2>
		<snapshot1>mw2T8q8.jpg</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>4eNxZGx.jpg</snapshot2>
		<snapshot3>qrGHjqW.jpg</snapshot3>
		<snapshot4>hAK4i80.jpg</snapshot4>
		<snapshot5>5a5uOlQ.jpg</snapshot5>
		<snapshot6>q4yJ8fc.jpg</snapshot6>
		<snapshot7>XzXV77r.jpg</snapshot7>
		<snapshot8>7yRgUZE.jpg</snapshot8>
		<snapshot9>uUyeEAm.jpg</snapshot9>
		<snapshot10>4xfCEMb.jpg</snapshot10>
		<fanart1>nPS1cVS.jpg</fanart1>
		<banner1>ZHLJ5q0.png</banner1>
	</game>
	<game name="Star Wars Arcade (USA)">
		<description>Star Wars Arcade (USA)</description>
		<rom crc="2F16B44A" name="Sega_32X/Star%20Wars%20Arcade%20%28USA%29.32x" sha1="F4FFAAF1D8330EA971643021BE3F3203E1EA065D" size="1573739" />
		<title_clean>Star Wars Arcade</title_clean>
		<plot>Star Wars Arcade is a 3D shoot 'em-up set in Episodes 4, 5, and 6 of the Star Wars saga.  You take control of either an X-Wing or Y-Wing, and are put right in the middle of the space combat.  In some levels, you have to shoot down a specific number of TIE fighters before time runs out. In other levels, your goal is to simply to make it to the end without getting blasted out of the sky.[CR]Some of the missions take place in deep space, around asteroids, or near Star Destroyers.  Other missions take place on the surface of the Death Star and re-create the Luke Skywalker's famous trench run to destroy it.</plot>
		<releasedate>13/8/1994</releasedate>
		<year>1994</year>
		<genre>Action</genre>
		<studio>LucasArts, Sega</studio>
		<nplayers>1-2 Co-Op</nplayers>
		<perspective>1st-Person</perspective>
		<rating>3.5</rating>
		<ESRB>E - Everyone</ESRB>
		<videoid>MUyTGmzKCN0</videoid>
		<thegamesdb_id>4926</thegamesdb_id>
		<mobygames_url>https://www.mobygames.com/game/sega-32x/star-wars-arcade</mobygames_url>
		<giantbomb_url>https://www.giantbomb.com/star-wars-arcade/3030-10715/</giantbomb_url>
		<boxart1>IhBqlVD.jpg</boxart1>
		<boxart2>ZLo0eeq.jpg</boxart2>
		<boxart3>7E3QkLT.jpg</boxart3>
		<boxart4>OYf4FFL.jpg</boxart4>
		<boxart5>DJE1Lzy.jpg</boxart5>
		<snapshot1>7oj1fnQ.jpg</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>BxDZQix.gif</snapshot2>
		<snapshot3>tkS767n.gif</snapshot3>
		<snapshot4>c1Uw5s0.gif</snapshot4>
		<snapshot5>0h4PF9n.gif</snapshot5>
		<snapshot6>ESjCNlw.gif</snapshot6>
		<snapshot7>hBYbDHs.gif</snapshot7>
		<snapshot8>HImKiYP.gif</snapshot8>
		<snapshot9>7VRLhs2.gif</snapshot9>
		<snapshot10>nrxHAZJ.gif</snapshot10>
	</game>
	<game name="Star Wars Arcade (Japan)">
		<description>Star Wars Arcade (Japan)</description>
		<rom crc="F4E9B846" name="Sega_32X/Star%20Wars%20Arcade%20%28Japan%29.32x" sha1="282767A07E453E868DE52B46BF11DEF3D071BDA6" size="1612583" />
		<title_clean>Star Wars Arcade</title_clean>
		<plot>Star Wars Arcade is a 3D shoot 'em-up set in Episodes 4, 5, and 6 of the Star Wars saga.  You take control of either an X-Wing or Y-Wing, and are put right in the middle of the space combat.  In some levels, you have to shoot down a specific number of TIE fighters before time runs out. In other levels, your goal is to simply to make it to the end without getting blasted out of the sky.[CR]Some of the missions take place in deep space, around asteroids, or near Star Destroyers.  Other missions take place on the surface of the Death Star and re-create the Luke Skywalker's famous trench run to destroy it.</plot>
		<releasedate>13/8/1994</releasedate>
		<year>1994</year>
		<genre>Action</genre>
		<studio>LucasArts, Sega</studio>
		<nplayers>1-2 Co-Op</nplayers>
		<perspective>1st-Person</perspective>
		<rating>3.5</rating>
		<ESRB>E - Everyone</ESRB>
		<videoid>MUyTGmzKCN0</videoid>
		<thegamesdb_id>4926</thegamesdb_id>
		<mobygames_url>https://www.mobygames.com/game/sega-32x/star-wars-arcade</mobygames_url>
		<giantbomb_url>https://www.giantbomb.com/star-wars-arcade/3030-10715/</giantbomb_url>
		<boxart1>laq2fii.png</boxart1>
		<boxart2>ZLo0eeq.jpg</boxart2>
		<boxart3>7E3QkLT.jpg</boxart3>
		<boxart4>OYf4FFL.jpg</boxart4>
		<boxart5>DJE1Lzy.jpg</boxart5>
		<snapshot1>7oj1fnQ.jpg</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>BxDZQix.gif</snapshot2>
		<snapshot3>tkS767n.gif</snapshot3>
		<snapshot4>c1Uw5s0.gif</snapshot4>
		<snapshot5>0h4PF9n.gif</snapshot5>
		<snapshot6>ESjCNlw.gif</snapshot6>
		<snapshot7>hBYbDHs.gif</snapshot7>
		<snapshot8>HImKiYP.gif</snapshot8>
		<snapshot9>7VRLhs2.gif</snapshot9>
		<snapshot10>nrxHAZJ.gif</snapshot10>
	</game>
	<game name="Star Wars Arcade (Europe)">
		<description>Star Wars Arcade (Europe)</description>
		<rom crc="82E82660" name="Sega_32X/Star%20Wars%20Arcade%20%28Europe%29.32x" sha1="A877CBF704FE7480966FD88A3C39EFB6A39392AC" size="1573753" />
		<title_clean>Star Wars Arcade</title_clean>
		<plot>Star Wars Arcade is a 3D shoot 'em-up set in Episodes 4, 5, and 6 of the Star Wars saga.  You take control of either an X-Wing or Y-Wing, and are put right in the middle of the space combat.  In some levels, you have to shoot down a specific number of TIE fighters before time runs out. In other levels, your goal is to simply to make it to the end without getting blasted out of the sky.[CR]Some of the missions take place in deep space, around asteroids, or near Star Destroyers.  Other missions take place on the surface of the Death Star and re-create the Luke Skywalker's famous trench run to destroy it.</plot>
		<releasedate>13/8/1994</releasedate>
		<year>1994</year>
		<genre>Action</genre>
		<studio>LucasArts, Sega</studio>
		<nplayers>1-2 Co-Op</nplayers>
		<perspective>1st-Person</perspective>
		<rating>3.5</rating>
		<ESRB>E - Everyone</ESRB>
		<videoid>MUyTGmzKCN0</videoid>
		<thegamesdb_id>4926</thegamesdb_id>
		<mobygames_url>https://www.mobygames.com/game/sega-32x/star-wars-arcade</mobygames_url>
		<giantbomb_url>https://www.giantbomb.com/star-wars-arcade/3030-10715/</giantbomb_url>
		<boxart1>laq2fii.png</boxart1>
		<boxart2>ZLo0eeq.jpg</boxart2>
		<boxart3>7E3QkLT.jpg</boxart3>
		<boxart4>OYf4FFL.jpg</boxart4>
		<boxart5>DJE1Lzy.jpg</boxart5>
		<snapshot1>7oj1fnQ.jpg</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>BxDZQix.gif</snapshot2>
		<snapshot3>tkS767n.gif</snapshot3>
		<snapshot4>c1Uw5s0.gif</snapshot4>
		<snapshot5>0h4PF9n.gif</snapshot5>
		<snapshot6>ESjCNlw.gif</snapshot6>
		<snapshot7>hBYbDHs.gif</snapshot7>
		<snapshot8>HImKiYP.gif</snapshot8>
		<snapshot9>7VRLhs2.gif</snapshot9>
		<snapshot10>nrxHAZJ.gif</snapshot10>
	</game>
	<game name="Stellar Assault (Japan)">
		<description>Stellar Assault (Japan)</description>
		<rom crc="FCE4C8C7" name="Sega_32X/Stellar%20Assault%20%28Japan%29.32x" sha1="FF4F1A2DDED85F3AD43BF28A85C46AD8595D5614" size="470532" />
		<title_clean>Stellar Assault</title_clean>
		<plot>Chaose has broken out on the edge of the Galaxy. A diabolical power has begun construction of a powerful sun laser. You are the Shadow Squadron's newest fighter jock and the fate and hope of the federation rests in your hands. Destroy the Sun Laser of face the FIRE!!![CR]https://www.gamefaqs.com/console/32x/home/584369.html[CR]</plot>
		<releasedate>13/8/1995</releasedate>
		<year>1995</year>
		<genre>Shooter</genre>
		<studio>Sega</studio>
		<nplayers>1</nplayers>
	</game>
	<game name="T-Mek (USA, Europe)">
		<description>T-Mek (USA, Europe)</description>
		<rom crc="66D2C48F" name="Sega_32X/T-Mek%20%28USA%2C%20Europe%29.32x" sha1="173C8425921D83DB3E8D181158E7599364F4C0F6" size="1441904" />
		<title_clean>T-Mek</title_clean>
		<plot>T-Mek is essentially an updated Battlezone. You are a warrior battling in the T-Mek competition, a hugely popular event in the future. You control a hovercraft and try to blow up everyone else.[CR]The action is viewed from your perspective as you travel around the arena. You also have an overall view of where your opponents are. Terrain surfaces and characteristics vary in each battle. In most levels you need to reach a certain score to progress, however there are out-and-out one-off Deathmatch duels to deal with periodically.</plot>
		<releasedate>13/8/1995</releasedate>
		<year>1995</year>
		<genre>Action</genre>
		<studio>Time Warner Interactive</studio>
		<nplayers>1-2 VS</nplayers>
		<perspective>1st-Person</perspective>
		<rating>3.4</rating>
		<ESRB>E - Everyone</ESRB>
		<thegamesdb_id>9081</thegamesdb_id>
		<mobygames_url>https://www.mobygames.com/game/sega-32x/t-mek</mobygames_url>
		<giantbomb_url>https://www.giantbomb.com/t-mek/3030-18557/</giantbomb_url>
		<boxart1>OFqQq86.jpg</boxart1>
		<boxart2>7uhy3Vk.jpg</boxart2>
		<boxart3>ZFbcNxH.jpg</boxart3>
		<snapshot1>DmmN60j.gif</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>QeXJfOY.gif</snapshot2>
		<snapshot3>5vfRUtH.gif</snapshot3>
		<snapshot4>S9iNQGK.gif</snapshot4>
		<snapshot5>k3NTqPn.gif</snapshot5>
		<snapshot6>hHVQAOo.gif</snapshot6>
	</game>
	<game name="Tempo (Japan, USA)">
		<description>Tempo (Japan, USA)</description>
		<rom crc="14E5C575" name="Sega_32X/Tempo%20%28Japan%2C%20USA%29.32x" sha1="6673BA83570B4F2C1B4A22415A56594C3CC6C6A9" size="1808035" />
		<title_clean>Tempo</title_clean>
		<plot>Tempo is a grasshopper who lives on Planet Rythmia, the world of music.  Unfortunately, the malevolent King Dirge is trying to steal all the rhythm from the planet.  It's unclear as to how a creature with no appreciation for music became King, but it's up to Tempo to stop him![CR]Tempo's game is a side scrolling platformer with 7 levels.  It's a single player game, although you can collect "dance" power-ups that allow you to call your friend, a butterfly, to help you defeat your enemies using killer dance moves.</plot>
		<releasedate>13/8/1995</releasedate>
		<year>1995</year>
		<genre>Action</genre>
		<studio>Sega</studio>
		<nplayers>1</nplayers>
		<perspective>Platform</perspective>
		<rating>3.8</rating>
		<ESRB>E - Everyone</ESRB>
		<thegamesdb_id>4927</thegamesdb_id>
		<mobygames_url>https://www.mobygames.com/game/sega-32x/tempo</mobygames_url>
		<giantbomb_url>https://www.giantbomb.com/tempo/3030-3595/</giantbomb_url>
		<boxart1>CtZY3Pm.jpg</boxart1>
		<boxart2>cFmSpmE.jpg</boxart2>
		<snapshot1>yLPSDm2.jpg</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>s4LInm0.gif</snapshot2>
		<snapshot3>v0L5s6v.gif</snapshot3>
		<snapshot4>2HCz1C5.gif</snapshot4>
		<snapshot5>JR51RWy.gif</snapshot5>
		<snapshot6>ETb9F56.gif</snapshot6>
		<snapshot7>HrGUX3S.gif</snapshot7>
		<snapshot8>tsbbGjz.gif</snapshot8>
		<snapshot9>o55ffCj.gif</snapshot9>
		<snapshot10>p0YYWZH.png</snapshot10>
	</game>
	<game name="Toughman Contest (USA, Europe)">
		<description>Toughman Contest (USA, Europe)</description>
		<rom crc="14EAC7A6" name="Sega_32X/Toughman%20Contest%20%28USA%2C%20Europe%29.32x" sha1="7588B0B8F4E93D5FDC920D3AB7E464154E423DA9" size="2949615" />
		<title_clean>Toughman Contest</title_clean>
		<plot>Toughman Contest is a game based on the world famous boxing competition of the same name.  You pick one of 24 fighters, compete in one of 5 locations from around the world, and re-create the Toughman tournament as seen on TV.  [CR]The boxing action is viewed from behind the back of fighter you control.  Your fighter is rendered as an outline, so you can see what your opponent is up to and react accordingly.  Toughman matches consist of three one minute rounds.  Your goal is to KO your opponent by causing their stamina meter to decrease to the point where they fall down, or beating on them enough that you are scored the winner at end of the third round.</plot>
		<releasedate>13/8/1995</releasedate>
		<year>1995</year>
		<genre>Sports</genre>
		<studio>Electronic Arts</studio>
		<nplayers>1-2 VS</nplayers>
		<perspective>3rd-Person</perspective>
		<rating>2.6</rating>
		<ESRB>T - Teen</ESRB>
		<thegamesdb_id>9082</thegamesdb_id>
		<mobygames_url>https://www.mobygames.com/game/sega-32x/toughman-contest</mobygames_url>
		<giantbomb_url>https://www.giantbomb.com/toughman-contest/3030-14857/</giantbomb_url>
		<consolegrid_url>http://consolegrid.com/games/4921</consolegrid_url>
		<boxart1>954UhdO.jpg</boxart1>
		<boxart2>KdvvAMk.jpg</boxart2>
		<boxart3>8I81Wff.jpg</boxart3>
		<snapshot1>Rcw6MZF.gif</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>YOYaXnA.gif</snapshot2>
		<snapshot3>EiTUdkJ.gif</snapshot3>
		<snapshot4>CHUugyk.gif</snapshot4>
		<snapshot5>PIvBuCa.gif</snapshot5>
		<snapshot6>SKuPXxA.jpg</snapshot6>
		<snapshot7>E9mtbUP.jpg</snapshot7>
		<snapshot8>uDD7vaQ.jpg</snapshot8>
		<snapshot9>ZJ3DE6s.png</snapshot9>
		<snapshot10>kvNEDgy.png</snapshot10>
	</game>
	<game name="Virtua Fighter (Europe)">
		<description>Virtua Fighter (Europe)</description>
		<rom crc="25AEA73C" name="Sega_32X/Virtua%20Fighter%20%28Europe%29.32x" sha1="24B3063284A914C76D8D1F681E3ED6323B0D7D0B" size="2658124" />
		<title_clean>Virtua Fighter</title_clean>
		<plot>[CR][B]Overview:[/B][CR]The first in the Virtua Fighter series, the game plays in a 3D format. Both the arcade original's Sega Model 1 hardware and the Saturn port's NV1 architecture relied on quadratic polygons instead of the triangular polygons that are used in modern 3D graphics. The images were created by using wire frames and flat-shaded quads. The game retains it's staple of multiple characters, who all have their own distinctive moves.It differed from other fighting games from the same era as the game relied on only the control stick and three buttons, punch, kick and guard. The game is highly regarded for the real world fighting techniques and it's in-depth fighting engine, and it was as a result viewed as revolutionary when it first came out.Developed by Sega AM2 team, with Yu Suzuki as director and Seiichi Ishii as main designer, the game was hugely influential in popularizing 3D polygon graphics across the video game industry. It inspired a new generation of 3D fighting games, ranging from Tekken and Toshinden to Soul and Dead or Alive. Some of the Sony staff involved in the creation of the PlayStation credit Virtua Fighter as inspiration for the PlayStation's 3D graphical capabilities (see here). More generally, it set a template for early 3D games in general. For example, it was cited as an influence on Tomb Raider.In 1998, Virtua Fighter was recognized by the Smithsonian Institution for contributions in the field of Art and Entertainment, and became a part of the Smithsonian Institution's Permanent Research Collection on Information Technology Innovation.[CR][B]Characters:[/B][CR]Akira YukiSarah BryantWolf HawkfieldDuralJacky BryantKage-MaruJeffry McWildLau ChanPai ChanAn Arabian character named Siba was originally scheduled to be featured in the game. His character model did in fact appear on some Virtua Fighter arcade cabinets. He was eventually dropped, but he makes an appearance in Sega Saturn Fighters MegaMix.[CR]Launch Game:[CR]Virtua Fighter was a North American launch game for the Sega Saturn (SS) on May 11, 1995. The game launched alongside other Saturn launch titles that included:* Panzer Dragoon* Daytona USAThat's right, the Saturn launched with only three games in North America.Rushed to meet the Saturn launch, the Saturn version is considered inferior to the Arcade and 32X versions. The game featured lesser graphics and more sluggish gameplay.Sega later released Virtua Fighter Remix, an improved version of the original that came free by mail with registration of a Saturn.[CR]</plot>
		<releasedate>13/8/1995</releasedate>
		<year>1995</year>
		<genre>Action</genre>
		<studio>Sega</studio>
		<nplayers>1-2 VS</nplayers>
		<perspective>3rd-Person</perspective>
		<rating>3.6</rating>
		<ESRB>T - Teen</ESRB>
		<thegamesdb_id>4928</thegamesdb_id>
		<mobygames_url>https://www.mobygames.com/game/sega-32x/virtua-fighter</mobygames_url>
		<giantbomb_url>https://www.giantbomb.com/virtua-fighter/3030-15584/</giantbomb_url>
		<consolegrid_url>http://consolegrid.com/games/8960</consolegrid_url>
		<boxart1>hb2w2KO.jpg</boxart1>
		<boxart2>0qjNefy.jpg</boxart2>
		<boxart3>Lwl5WtX.jpg</boxart3>
		<snapshot1>e96lYBI.jpg</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>Kc3dYko.gif</snapshot2>
		<snapshot3>nOsz60Q.gif</snapshot3>
		<snapshot4>EhTVklQ.gif</snapshot4>
		<snapshot5>lIK3ELq.gif</snapshot5>
		<snapshot6>MQ96OWx.gif</snapshot6>
		<snapshot7>5wmNgV1.gif</snapshot7>
		<snapshot8>z1tAg5H.gif</snapshot8>
		<snapshot9>3UryNNR.gif</snapshot9>
		<snapshot10>SV1JsN9.jpg</snapshot10>
		<fanart1>58Ae0WT.jpg</fanart1>
		<banner1>8fsOPrW.png</banner1>
		<clearlogo1>SxEjI6L.png</clearlogo1>
	</game>
	<game name="Virtua Fighter (Japan, USA)">
		<description>Virtua Fighter (Japan, USA)</description>
		<rom crc="B5DE9626" name="Sega_32X/Virtua%20Fighter%20%28Japan%2C%20USA%29.32x" sha1="F35754F4BFE3A53722D7A799F88FACE0FD13C424" size="2940139" />
		<title_clean>Virtua Fighter</title_clean>
		<plot>[CR][B]Overview:[/B][CR]The first in the Virtua Fighter series, the game plays in a 3D format. Both the arcade original's Sega Model 1 hardware and the Saturn port's NV1 architecture relied on quadratic polygons instead of the triangular polygons that are used in modern 3D graphics. The images were created by using wire frames and flat-shaded quads. The game retains it's staple of multiple characters, who all have their own distinctive moves.It differed from other fighting games from the same era as the game relied on only the control stick and three buttons, punch, kick and guard. The game is highly regarded for the real world fighting techniques and it's in-depth fighting engine, and it was as a result viewed as revolutionary when it first came out.Developed by Sega AM2 team, with Yu Suzuki as director and Seiichi Ishii as main designer, the game was hugely influential in popularizing 3D polygon graphics across the video game industry. It inspired a new generation of 3D fighting games, ranging from Tekken and Toshinden to Soul and Dead or Alive. Some of the Sony staff involved in the creation of the PlayStation credit Virtua Fighter as inspiration for the PlayStation's 3D graphical capabilities (see here). More generally, it set a template for early 3D games in general. For example, it was cited as an influence on Tomb Raider.In 1998, Virtua Fighter was recognized by the Smithsonian Institution for contributions in the field of Art and Entertainment, and became a part of the Smithsonian Institution's Permanent Research Collection on Information Technology Innovation.[CR][B]Characters:[/B][CR]Akira YukiSarah BryantWolf HawkfieldDuralJacky BryantKage-MaruJeffry McWildLau ChanPai ChanAn Arabian character named Siba was originally scheduled to be featured in the game. His character model did in fact appear on some Virtua Fighter arcade cabinets. He was eventually dropped, but he makes an appearance in Sega Saturn Fighters MegaMix.[CR]Launch Game:[CR]Virtua Fighter was a North American launch game for the Sega Saturn (SS) on May 11, 1995. The game launched alongside other Saturn launch titles that included:* Panzer Dragoon* Daytona USAThat's right, the Saturn launched with only three games in North America.Rushed to meet the Saturn launch, the Saturn version is considered inferior to the Arcade and 32X versions. The game featured lesser graphics and more sluggish gameplay.Sega later released Virtua Fighter Remix, an improved version of the original that came free by mail with registration of a Saturn.[CR]</plot>
		<releasedate>13/8/1995</releasedate>
		<year>1995</year>
		<genre>Action</genre>
		<studio>Sega</studio>
		<nplayers>1-2 VS</nplayers>
		<perspective>3rd-Person</perspective>
		<rating>3.6</rating>
		<ESRB>T - Teen</ESRB>
		<thegamesdb_id>4928</thegamesdb_id>
		<mobygames_url>https://www.mobygames.com/game/sega-32x/virtua-fighter</mobygames_url>
		<giantbomb_url>https://www.giantbomb.com/virtua-fighter/3030-15584/</giantbomb_url>
		<consolegrid_url>http://consolegrid.com/games/8960</consolegrid_url>
		<boxart1>kTCfYyq.png</boxart1>
		<boxart2>0qjNefy.jpg</boxart2>
		<boxart3>Lwl5WtX.jpg</boxart3>
		<snapshot1>e96lYBI.jpg</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>Kc3dYko.gif</snapshot2>
		<snapshot3>nOsz60Q.gif</snapshot3>
		<snapshot4>EhTVklQ.gif</snapshot4>
		<snapshot5>lIK3ELq.gif</snapshot5>
		<snapshot6>MQ96OWx.gif</snapshot6>
		<snapshot7>5wmNgV1.gif</snapshot7>
		<snapshot8>z1tAg5H.gif</snapshot8>
		<snapshot9>3UryNNR.gif</snapshot9>
		<snapshot10>SV1JsN9.jpg</snapshot10>
		<fanart1>58Ae0WT.jpg</fanart1>
		<banner1>8fsOPrW.png</banner1>
		<clearlogo1>SxEjI6L.png</clearlogo1>
	</game>
	<game name="Virtua Hamster (USA) (Proto)">
		<description>Virtua Hamster (USA) (Proto)</description>
		<rom crc="CD54AC37" name="Sega_32X/Virtua%20Hamster%20%28USA%29%20%28Proto%29.32x" sha1="C10F98D9DB73AE90BE5E5D556B663A5AFF015CEF" size="683298" />
		<title_clean>Virtua Hamster</title_clean>
		<plot>Not to be confused with other virtual pet games that simulate the Hamster owning experience (e.g. Ubisoft's Hamsterz Life and Petz: Hamsterz 2), Virtua Hamster was a Sega Genesis 32X game that had players guiding rocket-powered hamster test pilots on mini skateboards around a maze of tubes, collecting stolen blueprints in a mad scientist's laboratory.[CR]According to pre-production design documents posted by former Sega game designer Eric Quakenbush, Virtua Hamster was meant to have "the look and fast paced action of Virtua Racing and Virtua Fighter combined with an amusing puzzle strategy game and an unlikely group of heroes and enemies."[CR]Unfortunately, the game was never released (planned for 1995), presumably due to the 32X add-on's unpopularity. Quakenbush said a British company picked up the title for a possible PC release after Sega cancelled the project, but that also never made it to market. [CR]Other intriguing Virtua Hamster characters that serve as opponents seeking to hinder test pilot:[CR]A Kangaroo Rat with an Australian 'out-back' style rocket[CR]A Mole or shrew that lurks around like Peter Lorrie[CR]An armored, Armadillo-like, rodent from Brazil that chants soccer crowd anthems and yells "Goooaaal!" when he makes a point against another player[CR]A Pack-Rat who will grab any object he comes across and stuff into one of his many pockets[CR]And a pack of alley rats with black leather and chrome rockets[CR]http://www.gamesetwatch.com/2009/07/countdown_to_virtua_hamster.php[CR]</plot>
		<releasedate>13/8/1995</releasedate>
		<year>1995</year>
		<genre>Driving, Racing</genre>
		<studio>Front Street Publishing</studio>
		<nplayers>1</nplayers>
		<thegamesdb_id>20518</thegamesdb_id>
		<giantbomb_url>https://www.giantbomb.com/virtua-hamster/3030-31025/</giantbomb_url>
		<boxart1>81jBVII.jpg</boxart1>
	</game>
	<game name="Virtua Racing Deluxe (USA)">
		<description>Virtua Racing Deluxe (USA)</description>
		<rom crc="7896B62E" name="Sega_32X/Virtua%20Racing%20Deluxe%20%28USA%29.32x" sha1="18DFDEB50780C2623E60A6587D7ED701A1CF81F1" size="1288341" />
		<title_clean>Virtua Racing Deluxe</title_clean>
		<plot>Virtua Racing Deluxe is an enhanced arcade-to-console conversion of Sega's 3D racing game. This game is primarily an arcade-style affair; Players compete in a 5 lap race with timed checkpoints. It's also possible to play with 2 players in a split-screen mode.[CR]The 32X version of Virtua Racing adds a couple of new features. There are now 3 different types of cars to drive, including a stock car and a prototype racer. Furthermore, there are two all-new tracks.</plot>
		<releasedate>13/8/1994</releasedate>
		<year>1994</year>
		<genre>Driving, Racing</genre>
		<studio>Sega</studio>
		<nplayers>1-2 Alt</nplayers>
		<perspective>1st-Person</perspective>
		<rating>3.8</rating>
		<ESRB>E - Everyone</ESRB>
		<thegamesdb_id>4929</thegamesdb_id>
		<mobygames_url>https://www.mobygames.com/game/sega-32x/virtua-racing-deluxe</mobygames_url>
		<giantbomb_url>https://www.giantbomb.com/virtua-racing-deluxe/3030-11455/</giantbomb_url>
		<consolegrid_url>http://consolegrid.com/games/12221</consolegrid_url>
		<boxart1>8o23tQl.jpg</boxart1>
		<boxart2>frliBJz.jpg</boxart2>
		<boxart3>oEGxcUs.jpg</boxart3>
		<boxart4>jgKM8sy.jpg</boxart4>
		<snapshot1>Blj8zmf.jpg</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>S5V0xwK.gif</snapshot2>
		<snapshot3>OQy83QV.gif</snapshot3>
		<snapshot4>brcz8rj.gif</snapshot4>
		<snapshot5>PFoJxHg.gif</snapshot5>
		<snapshot6>Nc5fE2B.gif</snapshot6>
		<snapshot7>IUl0jdC.png</snapshot7>
		<snapshot8>A2wS15E.gif</snapshot8>
		<snapshot9>7V5ikME.jpg</snapshot9>
		<snapshot10>I3Qlm2k.png</snapshot10>
		<banner1>1b4nLWR.jpg</banner1>
	</game>
	<game name="Virtua Racing Deluxe (Japan)">
		<description>Virtua Racing Deluxe (Japan)</description>
		<rom crc="0908E888" name="Sega_32X/Virtua%20Racing%20Deluxe%20%28Japan%29.32x" sha1="1C64E80EB164CA8D6C6587A55AD60385BA1DAF27" size="1372593" />
		<title_clean>Virtua Racing Deluxe</title_clean>
		<plot>Virtua Racing Deluxe is an enhanced arcade-to-console conversion of Sega's 3D racing game. This game is primarily an arcade-style affair; Players compete in a 5 lap race with timed checkpoints. It's also possible to play with 2 players in a split-screen mode.[CR]The 32X version of Virtua Racing adds a couple of new features. There are now 3 different types of cars to drive, including a stock car and a prototype racer. Furthermore, there are two all-new tracks.</plot>
		<releasedate>13/8/1994</releasedate>
		<year>1994</year>
		<genre>Driving, Racing</genre>
		<studio>Sega</studio>
		<nplayers>1-2 Alt</nplayers>
		<perspective>1st-Person</perspective>
		<rating>3.8</rating>
		<ESRB>E - Everyone</ESRB>
		<thegamesdb_id>4929</thegamesdb_id>
		<mobygames_url>https://www.mobygames.com/game/sega-32x/virtua-racing-deluxe</mobygames_url>
		<giantbomb_url>https://www.giantbomb.com/virtua-racing-deluxe/3030-11455/</giantbomb_url>
		<consolegrid_url>http://consolegrid.com/games/12221</consolegrid_url>
		<boxart1>SS1GULv.jpg</boxart1>
		<boxart2>frliBJz.jpg</boxart2>
		<boxart3>oEGxcUs.jpg</boxart3>
		<boxart4>jgKM8sy.jpg</boxart4>
		<snapshot1>Blj8zmf.jpg</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>S5V0xwK.gif</snapshot2>
		<snapshot3>OQy83QV.gif</snapshot3>
		<snapshot4>brcz8rj.gif</snapshot4>
		<snapshot5>PFoJxHg.gif</snapshot5>
		<snapshot6>Nc5fE2B.gif</snapshot6>
		<snapshot7>IUl0jdC.png</snapshot7>
		<snapshot8>A2wS15E.gif</snapshot8>
		<snapshot9>7V5ikME.jpg</snapshot9>
		<snapshot10>I3Qlm2k.png</snapshot10>
		<banner1>1b4nLWR.jpg</banner1>
	</game>
	<game name="Virtua Racing Deluxe (Europe)">
		<description>Virtua Racing Deluxe (Europe)</description>
		<rom crc="27F14B5F" name="Sega_32X/Virtua%20Racing%20Deluxe%20%28Europe%29.32x" sha1="BB26DDDE26CD07191D872E8A76A170CA3326F781" size="1287621" />
		<title_clean>Virtua Racing Deluxe</title_clean>
		<plot>Virtua Racing Deluxe is an enhanced arcade-to-console conversion of Sega's 3D racing game. This game is primarily an arcade-style affair; Players compete in a 5 lap race with timed checkpoints. It's also possible to play with 2 players in a split-screen mode.[CR]The 32X version of Virtua Racing adds a couple of new features. There are now 3 different types of cars to drive, including a stock car and a prototype racer. Furthermore, there are two all-new tracks.</plot>
		<releasedate>13/8/1994</releasedate>
		<year>1994</year>
		<genre>Driving, Racing</genre>
		<studio>Sega</studio>
		<nplayers>1-2 Alt</nplayers>
		<perspective>1st-Person</perspective>
		<rating>3.8</rating>
		<ESRB>E - Everyone</ESRB>
		<thegamesdb_id>4929</thegamesdb_id>
		<mobygames_url>https://www.mobygames.com/game/sega-32x/virtua-racing-deluxe</mobygames_url>
		<giantbomb_url>https://www.giantbomb.com/virtua-racing-deluxe/3030-11455/</giantbomb_url>
		<consolegrid_url>http://consolegrid.com/games/12221</consolegrid_url>
		<boxart1>SS1GULv.jpg</boxart1>
		<boxart2>frliBJz.jpg</boxart2>
		<boxart3>oEGxcUs.jpg</boxart3>
		<boxart4>jgKM8sy.jpg</boxart4>
		<snapshot1>Blj8zmf.jpg</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>S5V0xwK.gif</snapshot2>
		<snapshot3>OQy83QV.gif</snapshot3>
		<snapshot4>brcz8rj.gif</snapshot4>
		<snapshot5>PFoJxHg.gif</snapshot5>
		<snapshot6>Nc5fE2B.gif</snapshot6>
		<snapshot7>IUl0jdC.png</snapshot7>
		<snapshot8>A2wS15E.gif</snapshot8>
		<snapshot9>7V5ikME.jpg</snapshot9>
		<snapshot10>I3Qlm2k.png</snapshot10>
		<banner1>1b4nLWR.jpg</banner1>
	</game>
	<game name="World Series Baseball Starring Deion Sanders (USA)">
		<description>World Series Baseball Starring Deion Sanders (USA)</description>
		<rom crc="6DE1BC75" name="Sega_32X/World%20Series%20Baseball%20Starring%20Deion%20Sanders%20%28USA%29.32x" sha1="AB3026EAE46A775ADB7EAEBC13702699557DDC41" size="2124092" />
		<title_clean>World Series Baseball Starring Deion Sanders</title_clean>
		<plot>This game is the 32X entry in Sega's popular and long-running World Series Baseball line.  It features a full MLBPA license, which allows it to have all 28 teams and 700 real-life players. [CR]There are 3 main game modes: exhibition, full season, and playoff.  Exhibition is usefull for a quick game between any two teams of your choosing.  Full season allows you to play an entire Major League Baseball season.  And finally the playoff mode allows you to play the games leading up to the World Series.  Also included are two different home run derby modes, and a full draft and trade for creating your team.</plot>
		<releasedate>13/8/1995</releasedate>
		<year>1995</year>
		<genre>Sports</genre>
		<studio>Sega</studio>
		<nplayers>1-2 Sim</nplayers>
		<perspective>3rd-Person</perspective>
		<rating>3.8</rating>
		<thegamesdb_id>20521</thegamesdb_id>
		<mobygames_url>https://www.mobygames.com/game/sega-32x/world-series-baseball-starring-deion-sanders</mobygames_url>
		<giantbomb_url>https://www.giantbomb.com/world-series-baseball-starring-deion-sanders/3030-17117/</giantbomb_url>
		<consolegrid_url>http://consolegrid.com/games/4991</consolegrid_url>
		<boxart1>C5y3O0X.png</boxart1>
		<boxart2>MWbRAsk.jpg</boxart2>
		<snapshot1>nQEaAmB.gif</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>Y8WPXa4.gif</snapshot2>
		<snapshot3>XkxpPvi.gif</snapshot3>
		<snapshot4>LXXxpWT.gif</snapshot4>
		<snapshot5>5j2MDZK.gif</snapshot5>
		<banner1>zZ9XktI.png</banner1>
	</game>
	<game name="WWF Raw (World)">
		<description>WWF Raw (World)</description>
		<rom crc="8EB7CD2C" name="Sega_32X/WWF%20Raw%20%28World%29.32x" sha1="94B974F2F69F0C10BC18B349FA4FF95CA56FA47B" size="2954610" />
		<title_clean>WWF Raw</title_clean>
		<plot>[CR][B]Overview:[/B][CR]WWF Raw is a wrestling game developed by  Sculptured Software and published by  Acclaim or LJN for multiple platforms. It is named for the TV show WWF Raw which regularly aired matches between WWF (now WWE) wrestlers and wrote stories around those bouts.The game uses a horizontal perspective of the ring and has multiple different modes based on events from the TV show: One-on-One, Tag Team, Bedlam, Survivor Series, Royal Rumble and Raw Endurance. Depending on the system, the player has a roster of up to thirteen WWF wrestlers to choose from. As well as regular attacks and signature moves, wrestlers will frequently get locked into a grapple and the player must mash buttons to escape and use the advantage to throw their opponent.[CR]Featured Wrestlers[CR]SNES, Genesis &amp; 32X Versions 1-2-3 Kid Bam Bam Bigelow Bret Hart DieselDoink the ClownKwang (only 32X Version with a code) Lex LugerLuna Vachon Owen Hart Razor Ramon Shawn Michaels The Undertaker YokozunaGame Gear Version Bam Bam Bigelow Bret HartCrush Diesel Lex Luger Randy Savage Razor Ramon Shawn Michaels The Undertaker YokozunaGame Boy Version Bret Hart DieselDoink the Clown Lex Luger Razor Ramon Shawn Michaels The Undertaker Yokozuna[CR]</plot>
		<releasedate>13/8/1994</releasedate>
		<year>1994</year>
		<genre>Action, Sports</genre>
		<studio>Acclaim Entertainment</studio>
		<nplayers>1-2 VS</nplayers>
		<perspective>3rd-Person</perspective>
		<rating>3.5</rating>
		<thegamesdb_id>38401</thegamesdb_id>
		<mobygames_url>https://www.mobygames.com/game/sega-32x/wwf-raw-</mobygames_url>
		<giantbomb_url>https://www.giantbomb.com/wwf-raw/3030-4155/</giantbomb_url>
		<boxart1>XPWYJeu.png</boxart1>
		<boxart2>uWL40EC.jpg</boxart2>
		<boxart3>O7wgclv.jpg</boxart3>
		<snapshot1>j65zk5k.jpg</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>t5MOjMB.jpg</snapshot2>
		<snapshot3>vk2eV7k.jpg</snapshot3>
		<snapshot4>GUb6sUp.png</snapshot4>
		<snapshot5>shp6yWY.png</snapshot5>
		<snapshot6>OIciFwC.png</snapshot6>
		<snapshot7>6UaoWY7.png</snapshot7>
		<snapshot8>aLqBuW5.jpg</snapshot8>
		<snapshot9>HWgZuMr.jpg</snapshot9>
		<snapshot10>rvSEA7v.jpg</snapshot10>
	</game>
	<game name="WWF WrestleMania - The Arcade Game (USA)">
		<description>WWF WrestleMania - The Arcade Game (USA)</description>
		<rom crc="61833503" name="Sega_32X/WWF%20WrestleMania%20-%20The%20Arcade%20Game%20%28USA%29.32x" sha1="551EEDC963CBA0E1410B3D229B332EF9EA061469" size="3508615" />
		<title_clean>WWF WrestleMania - The Arcade Game</title_clean>
		<plot>[CR][B]Overview:[/B][CR]WWF WrestleMania: The Arcade Game is an exaggerated fighting game that uses digitized sprites of the featured professional wrestlers, similar to Mortal Kombat. Players battle through one-on-one, one-on-two, and one-on-three matches to claim either the Intercontinental Championship or WWF Heavyweight Championship. Vince McMahon and Jerry Lawler provided commentary and the game was later ported to home consoles by Acclaim Studios Salt Lake City, which would make the successor title, WWF in Your House.[CR]Playable Characters[CR]The UndertakerShawn MichaelsBret HartRazor RamonLex LugerBam Bam Bigelow (Not playable in the SNES version)Yokozuna (Not playable in the SNES version)Doink The Clown[CR][B]Gameplay:[/B][CR]Developed by Midway, WWF Wrestlemania plays similarly to Mortal Kombat, with a few exceptions. Characters can move in somewhat 3D space, in that they can walk up and down, as well as left and right. Combat features five buttons: Light Punch, Power Punch, Light Kick, Power Kick and Block. It is also possible to Run by pressing Light Punch and Light Kick together.The main game consists of the player choosing to go after the Intercontinental title or the World Wrestling Federation Title. In the Intercontinental Title challenge, the chosen wrestler will face four opponents via one-on-one matches, followed by two two-on-one matches, and finally a three-on-one match. In the WWF Title Challenge, the player will start out with four two-on-one matches, moving on to two three-on-one matches, and finally the "Wrestlemania Challenge", a gauntlet match against every wrestler in the game. In the final match, however, only four people (including the player character) will be in the ring at once. Once an opponent is eliminated, someone will replace them until all eight opponents have been beaten.Each character has a unique ending.The only known "finishing move", similar to a Fatality, is done by the Undertaker. Originally the game was scheduled to have finishing moves for each character, but the WWF shot down the plan.[CR]</plot>
		<releasedate>13/8/1995</releasedate>
		<year>1995</year>
		<genre>Action, Sports</genre>
		<studio>Acclaim Entertainment</studio>
		<nplayers>1-2 Alt</nplayers>
		<perspective>3rd-Person</perspective>
		<rating>2.8</rating>
		<ESRB>E - Everyone</ESRB>
		<thegamesdb_id>14263</thegamesdb_id>
		<mobygames_url>https://www.mobygames.com/game/sega-32x/wwf-wrestlemania-the-arcade-game</mobygames_url>
		<giantbomb_url>https://www.giantbomb.com/wwf-wrestlemania-the-arcade-game/3030-8027/</giantbomb_url>
		<consolegrid_url>http://consolegrid.com/games/4999</consolegrid_url>
		<boxart1>vgOpOlW.jpg</boxart1>
		<boxart2>CDxWsQD.jpg</boxart2>
		<snapshot1>CVqGV2d.jpg</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>QhJNZDd.jpg</snapshot2>
		<snapshot3>CiddOvt.jpg</snapshot3>
		<snapshot4>yLBM4wa.jpg</snapshot4>
		<snapshot5>uPKdumT.jpg</snapshot5>
		<snapshot6>OB0g1hp.jpg</snapshot6>
		<snapshot7>CALQ2SR.jpg</snapshot7>
		<snapshot8>qABOcrv.jpg</snapshot8>
		<snapshot9>JBWnPrC.jpg</snapshot9>
		<snapshot10>FtJRcnk.jpg</snapshot10>
		<banner1>QeU8drP.jpg</banner1>
		<clearlogo1>ySNJPI3.png</clearlogo1>
	</game>
	<game name="X-Men (USA) (Proto)">
		<description>X-Men (USA) (Proto)</description>
		<rom crc="D61FEBC0" name="Sega_32X/X-Men%20%28USA%29%20%28Proto%29.32x" sha1="CD3FA2ACE2FDBF4B6402CB52EEB208010BF31029" size="1804822" />
		<title_clean>X-Men</title_clean>
		<plot>Here you have our second release. Impressive, eh? It's X-Men for the 32X, also known in later stages as X-Men: Mind Games. Although this is quite an elusive game concerning unreleased titles for the 32X, we can say for sure it has a lot to offer.[CR]For starters, development of this game was assigned to Scavenger, who owned some studios (like Zyrinx and Lemon) featuring many former Amiga demoscene developers, known for their high-tech profile and their enthusiasm into pushing systems to their limits.[CR]This X-Men adventure with beat 'em up-esque gameplay is a 3D game with stunning visuals for its time, probably redefining a new age of titles for the Mega Drive add-on.[CR]This prototype is quite early, basically something of a tech-demo which allows selecting and playing a couple levels from a concept title screen. These levels feature several playable areas -some of them having no enemies at all- and a single playable character, Bishop.[CR]There's also a debug camera function in this build, switched by pressing the START button. Using this camera, you can explore the whole levels and even glitching the game if you do what you shouldn't.[CR]With this proto we have a great playable sketch of a game that could have probably surpassed our expectations, having been finished and released, that is. This is a great showcase for both the 32X and the Scavenger studios.[CR]Enjoy![CR]IMPORTANT NOTICE[CR]This prototype, at the moment of its public release, is only working on real hardware, specifically set up to American region (regional lockout is displayed in both Japanese and PAL regions). We couldn't find any emulator able to reproduce the particular 3D engine used by this game. It boots and shows its concept title screen, and when you choose a level you even listen its corresponding music, but absolutely nothing is displayed on screen, turning this to be unplayable on emulators.[CR]We hope there will be many people behind the emulation scene pushing their efforts into making this game compatible with their emulators in upcoming revisions, so the game can be finally emulated. Until them, we'll have to play it on our 32X systems.[CR][CR]SegaSaturno unreleased section staff: saturn_worship, Wesker and Ryo Suzuki.[CR]Donators list: Adol, blackwolf, dagore91, FacundoARG, Lord Kefka, realbrucest, Ryo Suzuki,[CR]saturn_worship, tatoon and Wesker[CR][CR]www.segasaturno.com[CR]...the game is never over...[CR]</plot>
		<releasedate>13/8/1994</releasedate>
		<year>1994</year>
		<genre>Action</genre>
		<studio>Unreleased</studio>
		<nplayers>1</nplayers>
		<ESRB>RP - Rating Pending</ESRB>
		<thegamesdb_id>20520</thegamesdb_id>
		<consolegrid_url>http://consolegrid.com/games/5000</consolegrid_url>
		<boxart1>57poTFo.jpg</boxart1>
		<banner1>bI4lvwh.png</banner1>
	</game>
</datafile>