<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<datafile>
	<header>
		<emu_name>Amiga CDTV</emu_name>
		<emu_description>Amiga CDTV</emu_description>
		<emu_category>Amiga, 1990s, 16 Bit, PC</emu_category>
		<emu_version>052822</emu_version>
		<emu_date>09/18/2021</emu_date>
		<emu_author>Zach Morris</emu_author>
		<emu_visibility>visible</emu_visibility>
		<emu_homepage>http://www.redump.org/</emu_homepage>
		<emu_baseurl>http://archive.org/download/</emu_baseurl>
		<emu_launcher>retroplayer</emu_launcher>
		<emu_default_addon>none</emu_default_addon>
		<emu_ext_launch_cmd>none</emu_ext_launch_cmd>
		<emu_downloadpath>default</emu_downloadpath>
		<emu_postdlaction>unarchive_game_launch_cue</emu_postdlaction>
		<emu_comment>The Amiga The CDTV (from Commodore Dynamic Total Vision, later treated as a backronym for Compact Disc Television) is a home multimedia entertainment and video game console – convertible into a full-fledged personal computer by the addition of optional peripherals – developed by Commodore International and launched in April 1991.[CR]The CDTV is essentially a Commodore Amiga 500 home computer with a CD-ROM drive and remote control. With the optional keyboard, mouse, and floppy disk drive, it gained the functionality of the regular Amiga.[CR]Commodore marketed the machine as an all-in-one multimedia appliance. As such, it targeted the same market as the Philips CD-i. The expected market for multimedia appliances did not materialize, and neither machine met with any real commercial success. Though the CDTV was based entirely on Amiga hardware, it was marketed strictly as a CDTV, with the Amiga name omitted from product branding.[CR]Developer:  Commodore[CR]Manufacturer:  Commodore[CR]CPU:  Motorola 68EC020[CR]Memory:  2 MB[CR]Graphics:  Advanced Graphics Architecture[CR]Sound:  4 × 8-bit PCM channels (2 stereo channels)[CR]Display:  320×256[CR]Media:  CD[CR]Max Controllers:  2</emu_comment>
		<emu_thumb>6ncencl.jpg</emu_thumb>
		<emu_banner>IJMMCmG.jpg</emu_banner>
		<emu_fanart>623Lelh.jpg</emu_fanart>
		<emu_logo>hoJU12n.png</emu_logo>
		<emu_trailer>dlBIUTXHOiI</emu_trailer>
	</header>
	<game name="17 Bit - Collection for Amiga CDTV (Europe) (Disc A) (The Early Classics)">
		<description>17 Bit - Collection for Amiga CDTV (Europe) (Disc A) (The Early Classics)</description>
		<rom name="commodore_amiga_cdtv/17%20Bit%20-%20Collection%20for%20Amiga%20CDTV%20%28Europe%29%20%28Disc%20A%29%20%28The%20Early%20Classics%29.zip" size="488901716"/>
		<plot>These CDs give you a wide rage of Games, Animations, Demos, Graphics, IFF Artwork, Music Modules, Sound Samples, Clip-Art Games, Utilities, Home Finance, Applications and Utilities. Also included are demos from top grous worldwide such as LSD, Anarchy, Phenomena, Red Sector, Silents, Alcatraz, Crusaders, rebes, Melon Designs - and many others.</plot>
		<boxart1>DkZJPgZ.jpg</boxart1>
	</game>
	<game name="17 Bit - Collection for Amiga CDTV (Europe) (Disc B) (The Latest Batch)">
		<description>17 Bit - Collection for Amiga CDTV (Europe) (Disc B) (The Latest Batch)</description>
		<rom name="commodore_amiga_cdtv/17%20Bit%20-%20Collection%20for%20Amiga%20CDTV%20%28Europe%29%20%28Disc%20B%29%20%28The%20Latest%20Batch%29.zip" size="463298429"/>
		<plot>Games, Demos, Education, Word Processors, Utilities, Applications, Graphics, Music, in fact, everything you could ever want for your Amiga CDTV!</plot>
		<boxart1>mwWTHil.jpg</boxart1>
	</game>
	<game name="17 Bit - Continuation Disc (Europe)">
		<description>17 Bit - Continuation Disc (Europe)</description>
		<rom name="commodore_amiga_cdtv/17%20Bit%20-%20Continuation%20Disc%20%28Europe%29.zip" size="470391731"/>
		<plot>Another outstanding 17 Bit Disc collection for CDTV, packed full with Games, Graphics, Fonts, Utilities, Applications, Demos, Word Processors, Music and much, much more!</plot>
		<boxart1>7seguMU.jpg</boxart1>
	</game>
	<game name="Advanced Military Systems (Europe)">
		<description>Advanced Military Systems (Europe)</description>
		<rom name="commodore_amiga_cdtv/Advanced%20Military%20Systems%20%28Europe%29.zip" size="449169653"/>
		<boxart1>https://images.launchbox-app.com/8452b5ef-928d-4db8-afc9-9993dc2b3a6f.jpg</boxart1>
		<plot>Multimedia CD-ROM for Amiga CDTV featuring images, music and narration covering many kinds of military hardware, from the agile grace of the US Air Forces F-15 Eagle, to the awesome power of the Soviet submarine fleet, to the sleek and dangerous lines of the German leopard tank.</plot>
	</game>
	<game name="American Heritage - Illustrated Encyclopedic Dictionary - 1991a Edition (USA)">
		<description>American Heritage - Illustrated Encyclopedic Dictionary - 1991a Edition (USA)</description>
		<rom name="commodore_amiga_cdtv/American%20Heritage%20-%20Illustrated%20Encyclopedic%20Dictionary%20-%201991a%20Edition%20%28USA%29.zip" size="435301759"/>
		<plot>Over 80,000 Definitions, and thousands of full-color illustrations![CR]Definitions for over 80,000 words, with thousands of full-color graphics. Every word in every definition is hot-linked to all other definitions with the same word. Just click on the word and go![CR]Unique search capability allows you to find other terms related to the current word! Special features include audio spelling and pronunciation for each defined word.</plot>
		<boxart1>http://static.cd32-allianz.de/images/software/scans/American%20Heritage%20-%20Illustrated%20Encyclopedic%20Dictionary_Cover.jpg</boxart1>
	</game>
	<game name="Barney Bear Goes to School (USA)">
		<description>Barney Bear Goes to School (USA)</description>
		<rom name="commodore_amiga_cdtv/Barney%20Bear%20Goes%20to%20School%20%28USA%29.zip" size="74427491"/>
		<plot>Barney Bear Goes to School is an educational game for children aged two to six. It consists of two parts: the first one is a story book where the player has to help Barney Bear to wake up and get ready for school. The story is told through narrated pictures and for each one the player can interact with the scene by clicking on various objects. To continue the story a specific object has to be clicked on. The second part takes place in the school which contains various activities. This include three games:[CR]Spell It! - A picture along with the right spelling will be displayed and the player has to type it in by clicking on the right letters.[CR]How Many? - An object is drawn a certain number of times and the player has to count them and click on the correct number.[CR]Coloring Book - The player can fill the areas of several colourless pictures.</plot>
		<genre>Educational</genre>
		<groups>Barney Bear series</groups>
	</game>
	<game name="Bun for Barney, A (USA)">
		<description>Bun for Barney, A (USA)</description>
		<rom name="commodore_amiga_cdtv/Bun%20for%20Barney%2C%20A%20%28USA%29.zip" size="303960509"/>
		<plot>A Bun for Barney" is an animated story aimed at three-to-eight-year-olds in which a small bear discovers that the world is full of bounders ready to rip the cherries from his iced bun. The pop-up world contains animations, surprise word and number games and hidden nursery rhymes which children can explore by clicking on different parts of the screen. The game features the voice of Tom Baker.</plot>
		<boxart1>szi0qr9.jpg</boxart1>
		<clearlogo1>8XGbjNJ.png</clearlogo1>
		<genre>Educational</genre>
	</game>
	<game name="CD Remix Version II (Europe)">
		<description>CD Remix Version II (Europe)</description>
		<rom name="commodore_amiga_cdtv/CD%20Remix%20Version%20II%20%28Europe%29.zip" size="14661116"/>
		<boxart1>uzXP8lG.jpg</boxart1>
		<plot>CD Remix V2 is a DJ in your CDTV!</plot>
	</game>
	<game name="CDPD 1 (Europe)">
		<description>CDPD 1 (Europe)</description>
		<rom name="commodore_amiga_cdtv/CDPD%201%20%28Europe%29.zip" size="378659991"/>
		<boxart1>QUNLik4.jpg</boxart1>
		<plot>The CDPD series was basically targeted at CDTV and CD32 users, some of whom didnt have a disk drive or keyboard at all. The CDs are bootable and come with preinstalled PatNet and SerNet software allowing easy linkage with Amiga computers.</plot>
	</game>
	<game name="CDPD 2 (Europe)">
		<description>CDPD 2 (Europe)</description>
		<rom name="commodore_amiga_cdtv/CDPD%202%20%28Europe%29.zip" size="361346069"/>
		<boxart1>GrwheUA.jpg</boxart1>
		<plot>The CDPD series was basically targeted at CDTV and CD32 users, some of whom didnt have a disk drive or keyboard at all. The CDs are bootable and come with preinstalled PatNet and SerNet software allowing easy linkage with Amiga computers.</plot>
	</game>
	<game name="CDTV Demo Disc (Europe) (Disc 1) (Amiga CD Psygnosis Demo)">
		<description>CDTV Demo Disc (Europe) (Disc 1) (Amiga CD Psygnosis Demo)</description>
		<rom name="commodore_amiga_cdtv/CDTV%20Demo%20Disc%20%28Europe%29%20%28Disc%201%29%20%28Amiga%20CD%20Psygnosis%20Demo%29.zip" size="26954352"/>
	</game>
	<game name="CDTV Demo Disc (Europe) (Disc 2) (Amiga CDTV - Amiga 600 - Amiga 600 HD)">
		<description>CDTV Demo Disc (Europe) (Disc 2) (Amiga CDTV - Amiga 600 - Amiga 600 HD)</description>
		<rom name="commodore_amiga_cdtv/CDTV%20Demo%20Disc%20%28Europe%29%20%28Disc%202%29%20%28Amiga%20CDTV%20-%20Amiga%20600%20-%20Amiga%20600%20HD%29.zip" size="45222742"/>
		<boxart1>VCixCLp.jpg</boxart1>
	</game>
	<game name="Case of the Cautious Condor, The (Europe)">
		<description>Case of the Cautious Condor, The (Europe)</description>
		<rom name="commodore_amiga_cdtv/Case%20of%20the%20Cautious%20Condor%2C%20The%20%28Europe%29.zip" size="89944454"/>
		<plot>The Case of the Cautious Condor is an adventure game in an interactive comic book style developed by Tiger Media, Inc.. It was one of the first CD-ROM-only games that was furthermore a complete new development for that media and not only a port of another version such as an already existing floppy disc game or a laserdisc arcade machine.</plot>
		<studio>Tiger Media</studio>
		<boxart1>http://www.mobygames.com/images/covers/l/8249-the-case-of-the-cautious-condor-dos-front-cover.jpg</boxart1>
		<boxart2>https://images.launchbox-app.com/06058214-28db-4f7f-947a-5f37ac4c45c7.png</boxart2>
		<snapshot1>hJVhQaG.png</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>fxP7lXb.png</snapshot2>
		<clearlogo1>J5AEdnv.png</clearlogo1>
		<genre>Adventure</genre>
	</game>
	<game name="Cinderella - The Original Fairy Tale (USA) (En,Fr,De,Es,It)">
		<description>Cinderella - The Original Fairy Tale (USA) (En,Fr,De,Es,It)</description>
		<rom name="commodore_amiga_cdtv/Cinderella%20-%20The%20Original%20Fairy%20Tale%20%28USA%29%20%28En%2CFr%2CDe%2CEs%2CIt%29.zip" size="387368056"/>
		<plot>Cinderella - The Original Fairy Tale is an interactive storybook for the CDTV</plot>
		<snapshot1>https://i.ytimg.com/vi/yHY4UWFNXtk/maxresdefault.jpg</snapshot1>
	</game>
	<game name="Classic Board Games (Europe) (En,Ja,Fr,De,Es,It)">
		<description>Classic Board Games (Europe) (En,Ja,Fr,De,Es,It)</description>
		<rom name="commodore_amiga_cdtv/Classic%20Board%20Games%20%28Europe%29%20%28En%2CJa%2CFr%2CDe%2CEs%2CIt%29.zip" size="59109905"/>
		<plot>Classic Board Games is a collection of three classic board games, chess, checkers and backgammon, to be played against a remote opponent via modem. It can also be played taking turns at the same computer.</plot>
		<boxart1>https://images.launchbox-app.com/aac061d9-217e-4bfc-b0db-0350d38ec200.png</boxart1>
		<snapshot1>7TXjDbU.png</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>https://images.launchbox-app.com/cbf4e556-ad00-4806-942e-ba236984cea7.png</snapshot2>
		<clearlogo1>cLsSH9E.png</clearlogo1>
		<genre>Puzzle</genre>
	</game>
	<game name="Curse of RA, The (Germany)">
		<description>Curse of RA, The (Germany)</description>
		<rom name="commodore_amiga_cdtv/Curse%20of%20RA%2C%20The%20%28Germany%29.zip" size="1524834"/>
		<plot>The Curse of Ra is a Puzzle game, developed by Cybestyle and published by Rainbow Arts, which was released in Europe in 1990.[CR]Player (Scarab) has to escape a pyramid by solving the riddles. The player needs to remove all stones on a board by finding a counterpart. Only two stones with the same symbol can be removed at a time and they have to be on a straight line, horizontally or vertically. The game starts with Scarab on an ankh and that item has to be returned upon completion. Moving a stone is done by sitting on one and moving it towards the counterpart. Not all stones can be moved however and there are teleporters, obstructions and diversions to make it more difficult. There are also traps and for instance ice that forces Scarab to move in a single direction. When the stones are aligned, pressing fire matches them and they disappear.[CR]The game can be played in a Logic or in an Arcade mode. Logic mode offers 100 levels with no time limit. Special stones can make the player’s life easier or harder. In Arcade mode the player has to complete a level within a certain amount of time. Special coins can be used to buy extras after each level, such as ability to fly for 30 seconds, more time, extra lives and others. Levels are generated at random. The Arcade mode has a high score table. Demo mode shows the usage of all the different stones found in the game. This is a sort of non-playable tutorial. The game also provides a level editor.</plot>
		<studio>Cyberstyle</studio>
		<nplayers>1</nplayers>
		<boxart1>http://www.mobygames.com/images/covers/l/211698-the-curse-of-ra-dos-front-cover.jpg</boxart1>
		<boxart2>https://images.launchbox-app.com/3d2f3068-e40e-4779-bccb-1e0d8030b680.png</boxart2>
		<snapshot1>5SchZxU.jpg</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>https://images.launchbox-app.com/e9e452de-6be4-4ec7-802f-84d2a362c04e.jpg</snapshot2>
		<snapshot3>https://images.launchbox-app.com/ea0f8ff2-0dee-4855-855b-bbef158d9431.png</snapshot3>
		<snapshot4>Zn0rJGa.jpg</snapshot4>
		<clearlogo1>z3w6LoU.png</clearlogo1>
		<genre>Puzzle</genre>
	</game>
	<game name="Defender of the Crown (Europe)">
		<description>Defender of the Crown (Europe)</description>
		<rom name="commodore_amiga_cdtv/Defender%20of%20the%20Crown%20%28Europe%29.zip" size="206627318"/>
		<plot>Defender of the Crown is a strategy computer game designed by Kellyn Beck. It was Cinemaware's first game, and was originally released for the Commodore Amiga in 1986, setting a new standard for graphic quality in home computer games.</plot>
		<studio>Master Designer Software</studio>
		<nplayers>1</nplayers>
		<boxart1>http://www.mobygames.com/images/covers/l/189492-defender-of-the-crown-amiga-front-cover.jpg</boxart1>
		<boxart2>https://images.launchbox-app.com/d67f3ff3-4157-41b9-a121-f3fc8f02baab.png</boxart2>
		<snapshot1>UsOmEQP.png</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>fgKEwx4.png</snapshot2>
		<clearlogo1>tVR6f6J.png</clearlogo1>
		<genre>Action</genre>
		<groups>Cinemaware-style games,Defender of the Crown series,Fictional character: Robin Hood</groups>
	</game>
	<game name="Demo 1 (Europe)">
		<description>Demo 1 (Europe)</description>
		<rom name="commodore_amiga_cdtv/Demo%201%20%28Europe%29.zip" size="479618008"/>
	</game>
	<game name="Demo Collection for Amiga CDTV, The (Europe) (Black Disc)">
		<description>Demo Collection for Amiga CDTV, The (Europe) (Black Disc)</description>
		<rom name="commodore_amiga_cdtv/Demo%20Collection%20for%20Amiga%20CDTV%2C%20The%20%28Europe%29%20%28Black%20Disc%29.zip" size="476687818"/>
		<boxart1>VCixCLp.jpg</boxart1>
	</game>
	<game name="Fantastic Voyage (USA)">
		<description>Fantastic Voyage (USA)</description>
		<rom name="commodore_amiga_cdtv/Fantastic%20Voyage%20%28USA%29.zip" size="1780981"/>
		<plot>[I]Fantastic Voyage[/I] is a side-scrolling shooter based on the 1966 movie of the same name. The scientist Jan Benes is near death because of a clot of blood in his brain. A submarine, controlled by the player, is shrunk and needs to reach the brain through three levels. The enemies, which lower the energy bar when touched, are the human defense systems like antibody cells. [CR]Besides shooting enemies, there are also various passages in which the player needs to guide the submarine through narrow corridors without touching the environment. On the way the player needs to collect nine circuit boards required to destroy the blood cot; those may be hidden in dead ends or alternate ways. This means the player can move back and forth to try other routes at forks. It is important to pick up oxygen and fuel canisters in order to keep the submarine functional. Shield energy can be refilled by killing three enemies without missing a shot.</plot>
		<boxart1>WofcZqX.png</boxart1>
		<boxart2>0SxfaOR.jpg</boxart2>
		<snapshot1>https://images.launchbox-app.com/dfcc5b90-3991-4dc5-b5b9-c58564b28f98.png</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>Utr26MD.png</snapshot2>
		<clearlogo1>A4DMHQN.png</clearlogo1>
		<groups>Fantastic Voyage licensees,Setting: Inside a giant creature</groups>
	</game>
	<game name="Garden Fax - Fruits, Vegetables &amp; Herbs (USA)">
		<description>Garden Fax - Fruits, Vegetables &amp; Herbs (USA)</description>
		<rom name="commodore_amiga_cdtv/Garden%20Fax%20-%20Fruits%2C%20Vegetables%20%26%20Herbs%20%28USA%29.zip" size="35887816"/>
		<plot>Garden Fax Fruits, Vegetables and Herbs takes the guesswork out of choosing and caring for edible plants. This exciting new program features over 170 common and exotic plant species, providing horticultural information such as propagation and planting. Full color pictures, audio-visual presentations and text descriptions make Garden Fax a fun, easy and accurate way to answer your horticultural questions, whether you're a novice gardener or an experienced plant enthusiast</plot>
		<boxart1>https://elisoftware.org/w/images/8/8e/43467-51004.png</boxart1>
	</game>
	<game name="Garden Fax - Garden Plants (USA)">
		<description>Garden Fax - Garden Plants (USA)</description>
		<rom name="commodore_amiga_cdtv/Garden%20Fax%20-%20Garden%20Plants%20%28USA%29.zip" size="49402456"/>
		<plot>Garden Fax Garden Plants takes the guesswork out of choosing and caring for Bedding and Border plants. It features over 400 kinds of common and exotic plant species, providing individual horticultural information and techniques such as propagation and pruning. Full color pictures, audio-visual presentations and text descriptions make Garden Fax a fun, easy and accurate way to answer your horticultural questions, whether you're a novice gardener or an experienced plant enthusiast.</plot>
		<boxart1>https://elisoftware.org/w/images/9/9a/43467-51002.png</boxart1>
	</game>
	<game name="Garden Fax - Indoor Plants (USA)">
		<description>Garden Fax - Indoor Plants (USA)</description>
		<rom name="commodore_amiga_cdtv/Garden%20Fax%20-%20Indoor%20Plants%20%28USA%29.zip" size="36934715"/>
		<plot>Garden Fax Indoor Plants takes the guesswork out of choosing and caring for houseplants. It features over 200 common and exotic plant species, providing individual horticultural information and techniques such as propagation and pruning. Full color pictures, audio-visual presentations and text descriptions make Garden Fax a fun, easy and accurate way to answer your horticultural questions, whether you're a novice gardener or an experienced plant enthusiast.</plot>
	</game>
	<game name="Garden Fax - Trees, Shrubs, Roses &amp; Conifers (USA)">
		<description>Garden Fax - Trees, Shrubs, Roses &amp; Conifers (USA)</description>
		<rom name="commodore_amiga_cdtv/Garden%20Fax%20-%20Trees%2C%20Shrubs%2C%20Roses%20%26%20Conifers%20%28USA%29.zip" size="72931820"/>
		<plot>Garden Fax Trees, Shrubs, Roses and Conifers takes the guesswork out of choosing and caring for woody outdoor plants. This exciting new program features over 300 common and exotic plant species, providing individual horticultural information and techniques such as propagation and pruning. Full color pictures, audio-visual presentations and text descriptions make Garden Fax a fun, easy and accurate way to answer your horticultural questions, whether you're a novice gardener or an experienced plant enthusiast.</plot>
		<boxart1>https://elisoftware.org/w/images/c/c1/43467-51003.png</boxart1>
	</game>
	<game name="Hutchinson Encyclopedia, The (Europe)">
		<description>Hutchinson Encyclopedia, The (Europe)</description>
		<rom name="commodore_amiga_cdtv/Hutchinson%20Encyclopedia%2C%20The%20%28Europe%29.zip" size="173866271"/>
		<boxart1>2IWiT5h.jpg</boxart1>
		<plot>Choose from over 25,000 entries in the Hutchinson Encyclopedia</plot>
	</game>
	<game name="Illustrated Works of Shakespeare (Europe)">
		<description>Illustrated Works of Shakespeare (Europe)</description>
		<rom name="commodore_amiga_cdtv/Illustrated%20Works%20of%20Shakespeare%20%28Europe%29.zip" size="22607369"/>
		<boxart1>http://www.computinghistory.org.uk/userdata/images/large/95/49/product-79549.jpg</boxart1>
	</game>
	<game name="Language TV - English (France)">
		<description>Language TV - English (France)</description>
		<rom name="commodore_amiga_cdtv/Language%20TV%20-%20English%20%28France%29.zip" size="265194290"/>
		<plot>A CDTV course to teach you English through facts about the culture, and its language</plot>
		<snapshot1>https://i.ytimg.com/vi/cXHsadV6nPw/maxresdefault.jpg</snapshot1>
	</game>
	<game name="Lemmings (Europe)">
		<description>Lemmings (Europe)</description>
		<rom name="commodore_amiga_cdtv/Lemmings%20%28Europe%29.zip" size="25122169"/>
		<plot>Your task is to rescue the Lemmings across 120 levels of fast-paced puzzling. These creatures simply walk blindly through the world in the hope of reaching safety at the end of the level - unfortunately these levels include steep drops, gaps in the ground, barriers and rivers amongst other hazards.[CR]You are in control not of any individual Lemming, but of a cross-hair, which can be moved over any of the Lemmings. Along the bottom are a selection of functions which can be assigned to a Lemming, including climbing, floating and bashing. You must click to select the appropriate function, then click on the Lemming to activate it. Each level has a different range of skills on offer, a different amount of Lemmings, and a different percentage target in order to progress.</plot>
		<studio>DMA Design Limited</studio>
		<nplayers>1</nplayers>
		<videoid>aeAfeAQRwwE</videoid>
		<boxart1>http://www.mobygames.com/images/covers/l/954-lemmings-dos-front-cover.jpg</boxart1>
		<boxart2>https://images.launchbox-app.com/d3719c27-cf12-423c-9455-f934e206b161.png</boxart2>
		<snapshot2>https://images.launchbox-app.com/570a0b7d-ceda-4292-996a-67a4b73827ff.png</snapshot2>
		<clearlogo1>https://images.launchbox-app.com/e7f9a2dd-eba0-4436-a4a2-3f7f7e0b8ac2.png</clearlogo1>
		<genre>Puzzle</genre>
		<groups>Game Center CX challenge games,Gameplay feature: Herding,Games made into books,Lemmings series</groups>
	</game>
	<game name="Log!cal (Europe)">
		<description>Log!cal (Europe)</description>
		<rom name="commodore_amiga_cdtv/Log%21cal%20%28Europe%29.zip" size="1223699"/>
		<plot> _Log!cal_ is a bizarre puzzle game in which you have to arrange colored balls (green, purple, blue or yellow) to form quartets in any of several locations on the game board. These locations are, in fact, balls you can spin, then send any of the balls in them through the connection path.</plot>
		<releasedate>01/01/1992</releasedate>
		<year>1992</year>
		<nplayers>1</nplayers>
		<boxart1>http://www.mobygames.com/images/covers/l/22611-log-cal-commodore-64-front-cover.jpg</boxart1>
		<boxart2>https://images.launchbox-app.com/0b63ef5c-5657-4858-a7b0-5e19da29e3c1.png</boxart2>
		<snapshot1>https://images.launchbox-app.com/d9174b44-ff7e-4e2d-94f5-7a41619c2ef6.jpg</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>https://images.launchbox-app.com/033ad064-41ab-487b-bb01-1e8592ec9e2f.jpg</snapshot2>
		<snapshot3>https://images.launchbox-app.com/da94154f-742f-4f72-8b8e-cc5351fb40cb.jpg</snapshot3>
		<clearlogo1>4k2Z8ZA.png</clearlogo1>
		<genre>Puzzle</genre>
	</game>
	<game name="Mud Puddle (USA) (En,Fr,De,Es,It)">
		<description>Mud Puddle (USA) (En,Fr,De,Es,It)</description>
		<rom name="commodore_amiga_cdtv/Mud%20Puddle%20%28USA%29%20%28En%2CFr%2CDe%2CEs%2CIt%29.zip" size="202118587"/>
		<plot>Meet a walking mud puddle and see how it continually ambushes one little girl. You can ask the CDTV to read your favorite passages, to explain or pronounce unfamiliar words, and even to identify objects in the accompanying pictures. Primary text is in English. Optional audio background in French, German, Spanish, and Italian. Story by Robert N. Munsch. Artwork by Sami Suomalainen.</plot>
		<boxart1>https://elisoftware.org/w/images/b/bc/30122-97484.jpg</boxart1>
	</game>
	<game name="New Basics Electronic Cookbook, The - 1991a Edition (USA)">
		<description>New Basics Electronic Cookbook, The - 1991a Edition (USA)</description>
		<rom name="commodore_amiga_cdtv/New%20Basics%20Electronic%20Cookbook%2C%20The%20-%201991a%20Edition%20%28USA%29.zip" size="69386050"/>
		<plot>With recipes from the acclaimed Silver Palate series by Julee Rosso and Sheila Lukins. Choose from the complete collection of Silver Palate recipes by selecting from hundreds of ingredients. Design your menus according to what you have on hand, or by special occasions or meal types. Extensive information on buying, preparing and serving delicious Silver Palate dishes. Includes exciting custom menu ideas, with a special feature that compiles your shopping list for you!</plot>
	</game>
	<game name="Pandora's CD (Europe)">
		<description>Pandora's CD (Europe)</description>
		<rom name="commodore_amiga_cdtv/Pandora%27s%20CD%20%28Europe%29.zip" size="361663807"/>
		<plot>A sampler with something for everyone- CDTV and A570 CD drive compatible.[CR]A staggering 2,000 full color Amiga clipart library, textures library, photo library and sound effects for you to use in your productions.[CR]See demonstrations showing the uses of multimedia and CDTV in POI, POS, education, training and the home.[CR]Includes a sampler from Commodores prestigious Insight: Technology, a new CDTV title produced by Optonica Ltd.[CR]Text, graphics, animations, video, music and much, much more!</plot>
		<boxart1>https://elisoftware.org/w/images/b/b3/025465-130012.jpg</boxart1>
	</game>
	<game name="Prehistorik (Europe)">
		<description>Prehistorik (Europe)</description>
		<rom name="commodore_amiga_cdtv/Prehistorik%20%28Europe%29.zip" size="202508387"/>
		<plot>Prehistorik is a platform game developed by Titus Interactive for the Amiga, Atari ST, Amstrad CPC and MS-DOS. Titus Interactive also published it in 1991.</plot>
		<studio>Titus Interactive</studio>
		<boxart1>rvl6KXr.jpg</boxart1>
		<boxart3>Tno1tCi.jpg</boxart3>
		<snapshot1>MvUrES0.png</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>UUnuqWi.png</snapshot2>
		<clearlogo1>ecymG71.png</clearlogo1>
		<genre>Platform</genre>
		<groups>Animals: Dinosaurs,Prehistorik series,Protagonist: Caveman,Titus the Fox versions</groups>
	</game>
	<game name="Psycho Killer (Europe)">
		<description>Psycho Killer (Europe)</description>
		<rom name="commodore_amiga_cdtv/Psycho%20Killer%20%28Europe%29.zip" size="46826341"/>
		<plot>Psycho Killer is a graphic action-adventure game released by On-Line Entertainment in 1992 for the Commodore CDTV. [CR]The game involves an unnamed protagonist going on a quest in order to save a woman from a murderer, and to save himself. The graphics for the game were created using digitised still photographs that were taken in the suburbs of London.[CR]Gameplay of Psycho Killer is restricted to a point-and-click interface, such as clicking certain arrows to go their respective direction. There are multiple times in the game where the player must respond promptly to a quick time event in order to proceed to the next scene. Failure to do so can result in the game ending with the protagonist's death.</plot>
		<studio>Delta 4 Interactive</studio>
		<videoid>HYd7quRbu0Q</videoid>
		<boxart1>http://www.mobygames.com/images/covers/l/180438-psycho-killer-dos-front-cover.jpg</boxart1>
		<boxart2>https://images.launchbox-app.com/cef271bb-962a-4b99-80bd-15ba27c535fa.png</boxart2>
		<snapshot1>Ssj4an9.png</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>t4QwE48.png</snapshot2>
		<clearlogo1>EPRACWn.png</clearlogo1>
		<genre>Action,Adventure,Horror</genre>
	</game>
	<game name="Raffles (Sweden)">
		<description>Raffles (Sweden)</description>
		<rom name="commodore_amiga_cdtv/Raffles%20%28Sweden%29.zip" size="9199710"/>
		<plot>You play RAFFLES, the world's greatest cat burglar. You have broken in to the old Brooker Mansion only to find that Old Lady Brooker has locked you in and is demanding that you find all the jewels in the house her late husband hid there! You decide to humour her, but are having second thoughts when you realise that Old Man Brooker was somewhat of a mad scientist who has genetically engineered the plants and pets in the house to be abnormally large and dangerous! But its too late now to back down on your promise to the Mrs Brooker! To get out you must play the game, find the hidden jewels and take each of them to Old Lady Brooker up him her bedroom before she will allow you access to the key which will unlock the front door of the house and let you out again!</plot>
		<boxart1>https://images.launchbox-app.com/2dd31e30-e4c3-4b3b-8a72-1f384c0febf1.png</boxart1>
		<snapshot1>Yak7t63.png</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>NtSuW1K.png</snapshot2>
		<clearlogo1>ODHH09a.png</clearlogo1>
	</game>
	<game name="SimCity (Europe) (En,Fr,De,Es,It)">
		<description>SimCity (Europe) (En,Fr,De,Es,It)</description>
		<rom name="commodore_amiga_cdtv/SimCity%20%28Europe%29%20%28En%2CFr%2CDe%2CEs%2CIt%29.zip" size="211977335"/>
		<plot>SimCity, later renamed SimCity Classic, is a city-building simulation video game, first released on February 2, 1989, and designed by Will Wright for the Macintosh computer. SimCity was Maxis's second product, which has since been ported into various personal computers and game consoles, and spawned several sequels including SimCity 2000 in 1993, SimCity 3000 in 1999, SimCity 4 in 2003, SimCity DS, SimCity Societies in 2007, and SimCity in 2013. Until the release of The Sims in 2000, the SimCity series was the best-selling line of computer games made by Maxis. SimCity spawned a series of Sim games.</plot>
		<studio>Maxis</studio>
		<boxart1>miEni6y.jpg</boxart1>
		<boxart2>https://images.launchbox-app.com/f2350915-591b-4ba2-879e-35abf1333533.jpg</boxart2>
		<snapshot1>kvAqDYY.png</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>mF5l048.png</snapshot2>
		<snapshot3>N38LidG.png</snapshot3>
		<clearlogo1>2lTC5vv.png</clearlogo1>
		<genre>Construction,Management,Simulation</genre>
		<groups>Games with extra content copy protection,Games with randomly generated environments,Maxis Sim series,Setting: City - Boston,Setting: City - Rio de Janeiro,Setting: City - San Francisco,Setting: City - Tokyo,SimCity series,Video games turned into board / card games</groups>
	</game>
	<game name="Snoopy - The Case of the Missing Blanket (Sweden)">
		<description>Snoopy - The Case of the Missing Blanket (Sweden)</description>
		<rom name="commodore_amiga_cdtv/Snoopy%20-%20The%20Case%20of%20the%20Missing%20Blanket%20%28Sweden%29.zip" size="48381549"/>
		<plot>A simple adventure game for young players where you play Snoopy as the main character solving various puzzles in the area.[CR]The basic idea is manipulating objects by picking them up and dropping them at certain areas, which will result in a new sequence to the plot.[CR]You can use either a keyboard or joystick to play the game and there are only 5 actions you can perform: Move left, Move right, Jump, Pickup/Drop and Object Information.</plot>
		<boxart1>https://images.launchbox-app.com/e8dd4ae0-4f00-498c-8e3f-988d85dec63c.png</boxart1>
		<snapshot1>6bbKAm2.png</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>eZKCRw3.png</snapshot2>
		<clearlogo1>NjvjsEO.png</clearlogo1>
	</game>
	<game name="Team Yankee (Europe) (Ten on Ten)">
		<description>Team Yankee (Europe) (Ten on Ten)</description>
		<rom name="commodore_amiga_cdtv/Team%20Yankee%20%28Europe%29%20%28Ten%20on%20Ten%29.zip" size="4571320"/>
		<plot>Team Yankee is a video game adaptation of the 1987 Harold Coyle's World War III novel Team Yankee that was developed by Oxford Digital Enterprises for the Amiga, Atari ST and MS-DOS systems.</plot>
		<studio>Oxford Digital Enterprises</studio>
		<boxart1>6tMeL7z.jpg</boxart1>
		<boxart2>https://images.launchbox-app.com/d454d01b-450f-4b80-aeeb-a193529f4a64.png</boxart2>
		<clearlogo1>https://images.launchbox-app.com/f4da7db8-4b5d-4cf1-8265-e45c2e56a5df.png</clearlogo1>
		<genre>Driving,Strategy</genre>
		<groups>Inspiration: Literature,Tank: M1 Abrams,Team Yankee legacy</groups>
	</game>
	<game name="Team Yankee (Europe)">
		<description>Team Yankee (Europe)</description>
		<rom name="commodore_amiga_cdtv/Team%20Yankee%20%28Europe%29.zip" size="591144"/>
		<plot>Team Yankee is a video game adaptation of the 1987 Harold Coyle's World War III novel Team Yankee that was developed by Oxford Digital Enterprises for the Amiga, Atari ST and MS-DOS systems.</plot>
		<studio>Oxford Digital Enterprises</studio>
		<boxart1>6tMeL7z.jpg</boxart1>
		<boxart2>https://images.launchbox-app.com/d454d01b-450f-4b80-aeeb-a193529f4a64.png</boxart2>
		<clearlogo1>https://images.launchbox-app.com/f4da7db8-4b5d-4cf1-8265-e45c2e56a5df.png</clearlogo1>
		<genre>Driving,Strategy</genre>
		<groups>Inspiration: Literature,Tank: M1 Abrams,Team Yankee legacy</groups>
	</game>
	<game name="Time Table of History - Business, Politics &amp; Media - 1991a Edition (USA)">
		<description>Time Table of History - Business, Politics &amp; Media - 1991a Edition (USA)</description>
		<rom name="commodore_amiga_cdtv/Time%20Table%20of%20History%20-%20Business%2C%20Politics%20%26%20Media%20-%201991a%20Edition%20%28USA%29.zip" size="129368972"/>
		<plot>Over 6,000 Key events in Business, Politics and media, including Desert Storm![CR]This original time table includes over 6,000 stories covering key events in business, politics and media, from the Trojan Horse to Desert Storm.[CR]Stories are linked to exciting multimedia effects, including hundreds of graphics, sounds, maps and charts.[CR]All stories are linked together for advanced searching, thanks to Xiphias' unique Xearch system.[CR]Every word in every story is hot- linked to all other stories with the same word. Just click the word and go!</plot>
		<boxart1>http://static.cd32-allianz.de/images/software/scans/Time%20Table%20of%20History%20-%20Business,%20Politics%20%26%20Media_Cover.jpg</boxart1>
	</game>
	<game name="Trivial Pursuit - The CDTV Edition (Europe) (Disc 1)">
		<description>Trivial Pursuit - The CDTV Edition (Europe) (Disc 1)</description>
		<rom name="commodore_amiga_cdtv/Trivial%20Pursuit%20-%20The%20CDTV%20Edition%20%28Europe%29%20%28Disc%201%29.zip" size="201849702"/>
		<plot>This is the earliest home computer incarnation of Horn Abbot International Ltd's classic board game, [I]Trivial Pursuit[/I]. The game involves answering questions on one of six subject categories to gain moves, and answering questions on special squares to gain one of the six 'Wedges' you need to gain the right to take on the final winning question. Questions are aimed at British players - many entertainment questions are based on British TV, and sport questions relate to popular British sports.[CR]Two game modes are available: Single Player (which involves answering questions against the clock) and Multiplayer (where you can take on up to five human-controlled players). The computer reveals the answer, and you select 'yes' or 'no' to tell it whether you got it right.[CR]The question categories are exactly the same as the board game: Art and Literature, Science and Nature, Geography, History, Sports and Leisure, and Entertainment. However two different question styles are added to take advantage of computer technology - some questions relate to a picture or diagram and some relate to a piece of music. [CR]One additional feature not available in the board game is a statistical analysis of the number and type of questions answered correctly. This can be split into the performances of all the players, or the performance of an individual player within the six categories. It is especially useful at the end of the game, when choosing which category a player must answer to win the game.</plot>
		<boxart1>http://www.mobygames.com/images/covers/l/121639-trivial-pursuit-zx-spectrum-front-cover.jpg</boxart1>
		<boxart2>https://images.launchbox-app.com/f8bc443e-63f0-447f-a12d-0e891fd20c7c.png</boxart2>
		<snapshot1>DkWNRVf.png</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>BVZPMXC.png</snapshot2>
		<clearlogo1>gjK3ZQP.png</clearlogo1>
		<groups>Board game translations,Trivial Pursuit licensees</groups>
	</game>
	<game name="Trivial Pursuit - The CDTV Edition (Europe) (Disc 2)">
		<description>Trivial Pursuit - The CDTV Edition (Europe) (Disc 2)</description>
		<rom name="commodore_amiga_cdtv/Trivial%20Pursuit%20-%20The%20CDTV%20Edition%20%28Europe%29%20%28Disc%202%29.zip" size="201753129"/>
		<plot>This is the earliest home computer incarnation of Horn Abbot International Ltd's classic board game, [I]Trivial Pursuit[/I]. The game involves answering questions on one of six subject categories to gain moves, and answering questions on special squares to gain one of the six 'Wedges' you need to gain the right to take on the final winning question. Questions are aimed at British players - many entertainment questions are based on British TV, and sport questions relate to popular British sports.[CR]Two game modes are available: Single Player (which involves answering questions against the clock) and Multiplayer (where you can take on up to five human-controlled players). The computer reveals the answer, and you select 'yes' or 'no' to tell it whether you got it right.[CR]The question categories are exactly the same as the board game: Art and Literature, Science and Nature, Geography, History, Sports and Leisure, and Entertainment. However two different question styles are added to take advantage of computer technology - some questions relate to a picture or diagram and some relate to a piece of music. [CR]One additional feature not available in the board game is a statistical analysis of the number and type of questions answered correctly. This can be split into the performances of all the players, or the performance of an individual player within the six categories. It is especially useful at the end of the game, when choosing which category a player must answer to win the game.</plot>
		<boxart1>http://www.mobygames.com/images/covers/l/121639-trivial-pursuit-zx-spectrum-front-cover.jpg</boxart1>
		<boxart2>https://images.launchbox-app.com/f8bc443e-63f0-447f-a12d-0e891fd20c7c.png</boxart2>
		<snapshot1>DkWNRVf.png</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>BVZPMXC.png</snapshot2>
		<clearlogo1>gjK3ZQP.png</clearlogo1>
		<groups>Board game translations,Trivial Pursuit licensees</groups>
	</game>
	<game name="Turrican (Germany)">
		<description>Turrican (Germany)</description>
		<rom name="commodore_amiga_cdtv/Turrican%20%28Germany%29.zip" size="1650511"/>
		<plot>Turrican is a 1990 video game programmed and designed by Manfred Trenz. It was first developed for the Commodore 64 by Rainbow Arts, but was ported to other systems later. In addition to concept design and character creation, Trenz personally programmed Turrican on the Commodore 64. A sequel, Turrican II, followed 1991 for the Commodore 64 and other platforms.</plot>
		<studio>Rainbow Arts</studio>
		<boxart1>http://www.mobygames.com/images/covers/l/22600-turrican-commodore-64-front-cover.jpg</boxart1>
		<boxart2>https://images.launchbox-app.com/d8710fb0-d7b8-46c7-b26e-fc15d52281dc.png</boxart2>
		<snapshot1>XoVQTh6.png</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>MMjpFmF.png</snapshot2>
		<clearlogo1>https://images.launchbox-app.com/de72c38d-5a61-4008-8a14-4fbcb85cabe2.png</clearlogo1>
		<fanart1>https://images.launchbox-app.com/98a327f8-4668-43a2-b9d2-1ce028e8b963.png</fanart1>
		<genre>Action</genre>
		<groups>Turrican series</groups>
	</game>
	<game name="Turrican II - The Final Fight (Germany)">
		<description>Turrican II - The Final Fight (Germany)</description>
		<rom name="commodore_amiga_cdtv/Turrican%20II%20-%20The%20Final%20Fight%20%28Germany%29.zip" size="2064971"/>
		<plot>Turrican II: The Final Fight is the second game of the Turrican series. The game by Factor 5 was released in 1991 for the Commodore Amiga. This version was finished before the C64 version, but Manfred Trenz cites the C64 version as the original design. Turrican 2 was also released for the CDTV, Atari ST, Amstrad CPC and ZX Spectrum, and later for DOS, and also for the Mega Drive/Genesis and Game Boy rebranded as Universal Soldier.</plot>
		<studio>Rainbow Arts</studio>
		<boxart1>http://www.mobygames.com/images/covers/l/22602-turrican-ii-the-final-fight-commodore-64-front-cover.jpg</boxart1>
		<boxart2>https://images.launchbox-app.com/b9603b39-0202-46d7-b55d-1816ce784ca2.jpg</boxart2>
		<snapshot1>https://images.launchbox-app.com/c2724ef0-ab5e-429e-b4b7-38d59feda044.jpg</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>https://images.launchbox-app.com/baf62d6e-b529-4d19-a67e-1485194d0c73.jpg</snapshot2>
		<snapshot3>https://images.launchbox-app.com/3dde0f32-3acd-4b0d-bb36-a2d99f33cd40.jpg</snapshot3>
		<clearlogo1>https://images.launchbox-app.com/aaea67b7-fd50-4e3f-8bc9-8ac2b3309dcf.png</clearlogo1>
		<genre>Action</genre>
		<groups>Compilation: Play the Games Vol. 1: Der 10 Spiele Super-Pack,Turrican series</groups>
	</game>
	<game name="Welcome to CDTV Multimedia (USA)">
		<description>Welcome to CDTV Multimedia (USA)</description>
		<rom name="commodore_amiga_cdtv/Welcome%20to%20CDTV%20Multimedia%20%28USA%29.zip" size="44120073"/>
		<snapshot1>https://i.ytimg.com/vi/1yWkNKK9vQQ/hqdefault.jpg</snapshot1>
	</game>
	<game name="Will Bridge Vol. 1 - Initiation aux Encheres - Practice (France)">
		<description>Will Bridge Vol. 1 - Initiation aux Encheres - Practice (France)</description>
		<rom name="commodore_amiga_cdtv/Will%20Bridge%20Vol.%201%20-%20Initiation%20aux%20Encheres%20-%20Practice%20%28France%29.zip" size="16927005"/>
		<boxart1>https://images.launchbox-app.com/62ce2682-10f1-4441-bfea-060920f6754c.png</boxart1>
		<snapshot1>smp6RKz.png</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>ydQ8qTM.png</snapshot2>
		<clearlogo1>jhBWvfK.png</clearlogo1>
	</game>
	<game name="World Vista (Europe)">
		<description>World Vista (Europe)</description>
		<rom name="commodore_amiga_cdtv/World%20Vista%20%28Europe%29.zip" size="355517410"/>
		<boxart1>PhVbONn.jpg</boxart1>
		<plot>World Vista Atlas has maps and details taken from Rand McNally's World Facts and Maps.  It contains over 1,000 photos, and music from around the world</plot>
	</game>
	<game name="Wrath of the Demon (USA)">
		<description>Wrath of the Demon (USA)</description>
		<rom name="commodore_amiga_cdtv/Wrath%20of%20the%20Demon%20%28USA%29.zip" size="3434926"/>
		<plot>The mighty wizard Anthrax, in an attempt to usurp authority over the kingdom, has summoned a horrifying Demon. The Demon makes good on his chartered task by summoning a horde of monsters to lay waste to the kingdom at large. Fortuitously, a random stranger is strolling nearby the kingdom and realizes that only he can beat back the foul creatures. After some encouragement from the king, the adventurer begins the game on horseback, jumping over obstacles, beating flying creatures, and collecting potions on the ground. Afterward, the hero must proceed on foot through side-scrolling platforming levels, destroying creatures with his blade as well as collecting potions and additional weapons he will find on his deadly quest.</plot>
		<boxart1>jYQ0ZUA.jpg</boxart1>
		<boxart2>https://images.launchbox-app.com/0ce47d0e-6270-4d36-9cbe-5ee83aaf6a86.png</boxart2>
		<snapshot1>kkEZ1x6.png</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>https://images.launchbox-app.com/e36612c6-e159-445a-a10a-4e7b17e585fd.png</snapshot2>
		<clearlogo1>cMbxCGU.png</clearlogo1>
	</game>
	<game name="Xenon 2 - Megablast (Europe) (En,Fr,De,It)">
		<description>Xenon 2 - Megablast (Europe) (En,Fr,De,It)</description>
		<rom name="commodore_amiga_cdtv/Xenon%202%20-%20Megablast%20%28Europe%29%20%28En%2CFr%2CDe%2CIt%29.zip" size="659138049"/>
		<plot>Xenon 2: Megablast is a video game originally produced for the Amiga and Atari ST, and later converted to the PC, Sega Master System, Sega Mega Drive, Commodore CDTV, Acorn Archimedes, and Game Boy platforms. The game is a sequel to Xenon and was designed by The Bitmap Brothers (although coded by The Assembly Line). It became one of their most well-known titles. In 2016 it was ported to the Atari Jaguar.</plot>
		<studio>Bitmap Brothers</studio>
		<nplayers>2</nplayers>
		<boxart1>http://www.mobygames.com/images/covers/l/20031-xenon-2-megablast-amiga-front-cover.jpg</boxart1>
		<snapshot1>https://images.launchbox-app.com/72e69f55-c869-4591-9a46-cd43e3084fcc.jpg</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>https://images.launchbox-app.com/2a7d2405-3d64-4aba-9e0e-854c9cb81735.jpg</snapshot2>
		<snapshot3>https://images.launchbox-app.com/d9b244f7-4a71-4473-b736-b0ed2b8e5e60.jpg</snapshot3>
		<snapshot4>https://images.launchbox-app.com/1ea627f9-9498-4765-8ea7-db091c201e4c.jpg</snapshot4>
		<clearlogo1>https://images.launchbox-app.com/f6d7c45c-046a-498c-a6a1-29ee71ab712d.png</clearlogo1>
		<genre>Action,Driving,Shooter</genre>
		<groups>Genre: Scrolling shoot 'em up,Xenon series</groups>
	</game>
</datafile>