<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
	<datafile>
		<header>
			<emu_name>Internet Archive Best Of - Amiga</emu_name>
			<emu_description>Amiga</emu_description>
			<emu_category>Amiga, 1980s, 16 Bit, PC, Best of</emu_category>
			<emu_version>04012018</emu_version>
			<emu_date>05/01/2017</emu_date>
			<emu_author>Zach Morris</emu_author>
			<emu_visibility>visible</emu_visibility>
			<emu_homepage>http://www.no-intro.org</emu_homepage>
			<emu_baseurl>https://archive.org/download/</emu_baseurl>
			<emu_launcher>retroplayer</emu_launcher>
			<emu_default_addon>none</emu_default_addon>
			<emu_ext_launch_cmd>none</emu_ext_launch_cmd>
			<emu_downloadpath>default</emu_downloadpath>
			<emu_postdlaction>save_adf_to_folder_and_launch_m3u_file</emu_postdlaction>
			<emu_comment>For those who owned one, the Commodore Amiga home computer will always hold a special place in their heart. During the late eighties and early nineties, the various Amiga models that were realised during this time became the kings of the home computer market.[CR]Amiga fans will fondly remember the incredible gameplay of the titles released on the platform. It may have been an era when a computer's memory was measured in megabytes instead of gigabytes - graphics look positively antiquated by today's standards - and games could be spread across as many as fifteen floppy disks, but at the time, Commodore's machine was the best gaming computer you could own.[CR]Although it may be gone it's far from forgotten, with numerous releases today able to trace their lineage back to the Amiga's heyday. But out of all the classics that were released back then, here are the games considered the best.</emu_comment>
			<emu_thumb>yZpFsIK.jpg</emu_thumb>
			<emu_banner>ZwCuodA.jpg</emu_banner>
			<emu_fanart>DbOStGs.jpg</emu_fanart>
			<emu_logo>WxZIEbj.png</emu_logo>
			<emu_trailer>uXkYFqHyV98</emu_trailer>
		</header>
			<game name="Lionheart">
				<description>50.  Lionheart</description>
				<rom name="AmigaROMsCoverArtGHIJKL/Amiga_ROMs_%26_CoverArt_G-H-I-J-K-L.zip/Lionheart%2FLionheart.Disk1.adf" size="901120" />
				<rom name="AmigaROMsCoverArtGHIJKL/Amiga_ROMs_%26_CoverArt_G-H-I-J-K-L.zip/Lionheart%2FLionheart.Disk2.adf" size="901120" />
				<rom name="AmigaROMsCoverArtGHIJKL/Amiga_ROMs_%26_CoverArt_G-H-I-J-K-L.zip/Lionheart%2FLionheart.Disk3.adf" size="901120" />
				<rom name="AmigaROMsCoverArtGHIJKL/Amiga_ROMs_%26_CoverArt_G-H-I-J-K-L.zip/Lionheart%2FLionheart.Disk4.adf" size="901120" />
				<title_clean>Lionheart</title_clean>
				<plot>As Valdyn aka "Lionheart", you will have to travel deep into the territory of your king's enemy to retrieve a stolen holy relic which happens to be named "Lionheart" as well.[CR]The game itself is a platform/hack'n'slay affair, similar to Rastan. You proceed through the world that is scrolling in all directions and cut everything to pieces with your trusty sword that is cocky enough to come close to you.</plot>
				<releasedate>30/3/1992</releasedate>
				<year>1992</year>
				<genre>Action</genre>
				<studio>Thalion Software</studio>
				<nplayers>1</nplayers>
				<perspective>Platform</perspective>
				<rating>4.4</rating>
				<thegamesdb_id>29487</thegamesdb_id>
				<mobygames_url>https://www.mobygames.com/game/amiga/lionheart</mobygames_url>
				<giantbomb_url>https://www.giantbomb.com/lionheart/3030-17450/</giantbomb_url>
				<boxart1>xaJALr4.jpg</boxart1>
				<boxart2>ARk4r6P.jpg</boxart2>
				<boxart3>1RC180g.jpg</boxart3>
				<boxart4>rBRcEIl.jpg</boxart4>
				<snapshot1>Twcwwu2.jpg</snapshot1>
				<snapshot2>cBfwRE3.png</snapshot2>
				<snapshot3>vH5xMk9.png</snapshot3>
				<snapshot4>QtesyaY.png</snapshot4>
				<snapshot5>RlcpWwp.png</snapshot5>
				<snapshot6>3xNBdqI.png</snapshot6>
				<snapshot7>WK9HImL.png</snapshot7>
				<snapshot8>2be672q.png</snapshot8>
				<snapshot9>Uu6noim.png</snapshot9>
				<snapshot10>7RacFlq.png</snapshot10>
				<emu_command>A4000</emu_command>
			</game>
			<game name="Ishar 2 - Messengers of Doom (AGA)">
				<description>49.  Ishar 2 - Messengers of Doom (AGA)</description>
				<rom name="AmigaROMsCoverArtGHIJKL/Amiga_ROMs_%26_CoverArt_G-H-I-J-K-L.zip/Ishar%202%20-%20Messengers%20of%20Doom%2FIshar%202%20-%20Messengers%20of%20Doom%20%28AGA%29.Disk1.adf" size="901120" />
				<rom name="AmigaROMsCoverArtGHIJKL/Amiga_ROMs_%26_CoverArt_G-H-I-J-K-L.zip/Ishar%202%20-%20Messengers%20of%20Doom%2FIshar%202%20-%20Messengers%20of%20Doom%20%28AGA%29.Disk2.adf" size="901120" />
				<rom name="AmigaROMsCoverArtGHIJKL/Amiga_ROMs_%26_CoverArt_G-H-I-J-K-L.zip/Ishar%202%20-%20Messengers%20of%20Doom%2FIshar%202%20-%20Messengers%20of%20Doom%20%28AGA%29.Disk3.adf" size="901120" />
				<rom name="AmigaROMsCoverArtGHIJKL/Amiga_ROMs_%26_CoverArt_G-H-I-J-K-L.zip/Ishar%202%20-%20Messengers%20of%20Doom%2FIshar%202%20-%20Messengers%20of%20Doom%20%28AGA%29.Disk4.adf" size="901120" />
				<title_clean>Ishar 2 - Messengers of Doom</title_clean>
				<plot>Ishar 2: Messengers of Doom is the sequel to Ishar: Legend of the Fortress.[CR]Following the defeat of Krogh and the banishment of the powers of chaos, Ishar became a cultural and intellectual centre in Kendoria. Over time people came to the island and settled there and a city, named "Zach's Island" developed. Shandar, a monk of chaos, entered the city along with settlers from the northern lands. His trading in hallucinogens soon made him rich and powerful. Eventually Shandar controlled "Zach's Island" and had many followers and worshippers. He built a strong fortress, a second Ishar, to challenge the empire.[CR]In the sequel you can import saved characters from Ishar, or create your own team.[CR]In the game you have to explore the magic land (dungeons, tree-cities, mountain paths with real graded height effect), fight the enemies, join the allies and relax in towns, which even have medieval nightclubs. [CR]Now the area is 3 times bigger, and innovation is your ability  to use pet animals as allies in battles, and create magic potions. There are day and night cycles.</plot>
				<releasedate>30/3/1993</releasedate>
				<year>1993</year>
				<genre>Action, RPG</genre>
				<studio>Silmarils</studio>
				<nplayers>1</nplayers>
				<perspective>1st-Person</perspective>
				<rating>4.1</rating>
				<mobygames_url>https://www.mobygames.com/game/amiga/ishar-2-messengers-of-doom</mobygames_url>
				<giantbomb_url>https://www.giantbomb.com/ishar-2-messengers-of-doom/3030-20068/</giantbomb_url>
				<boxart1>g1wG8Ol.jpg</boxart1>
				<boxart2>FsX10a1.jpg</boxart2>
				<snapshot1>T0Edp9k.png</snapshot1>
				<snapshot2>tPkMMzO.png</snapshot2>
				<snapshot3>zEUT4Zx.png</snapshot3>
				<snapshot4>G4aBnCt.png</snapshot4>
				<snapshot5>2Bg4JYS.png</snapshot5>
				<snapshot6>TJjTXK6.png</snapshot6>
				<snapshot7>OHmfK8U.png</snapshot7>
				<snapshot8>kSxRLRG.png</snapshot8>
				<snapshot9>dhf47if.png</snapshot9>
				<snapshot10>tKloxm6.png</snapshot10>
				<emu_command>A4000</emu_command>
			</game>
			<game name="Dungeon Quest">
				<description>48.  Dungeon Quest</description>
				<rom name="AmigaROMsCoverArtCDEF/Amiga_ROMs_%26_CoverArt_C-D-E-F.zip/Dungeon%20Quest%2FDungeon%20Quest.Disk1.adf" size="901120" />
				<rom name="AmigaROMsCoverArtCDEF/Amiga_ROMs_%26_CoverArt_C-D-E-F.zip/Dungeon%20Quest%2FDungeon%20Quest.Disk2.adf" size="901120" />
				<title_clean>Dungeon Quest</title_clean>
				<plot>In a far-off land, an evil force is in charge, and you set off with the intention of putting things right. Immediately you see signs of desolation and environmental failure, with lifeless and malnourished people all round. Still, you must not give up; your friend who lives amidst this needs your help. With full graphical depiction of events and places, this interactive fiction can be played purely using the keyboard, but the bottom half of the screen contains some mouse interaction for direction entry. You can move in four directions, examine and take objects, talk to people and solve puzzles.</plot>
				<releasedate>30/3/1989</releasedate>
				<year>1989</year>
				<genre>Adventure</genre>
				<studio>Image Tech</studio>
				<nplayers>1</nplayers>
				<perspective>1st-Person</perspective>
				<mobygames_url>https://www.mobygames.com/game/amiga/dungeon-quest</mobygames_url>
				<giantbomb_url>https://www.giantbomb.com/dungeon-quest/3030-11919/</giantbomb_url>
				<boxart1>8338qtB.jpg</boxart1>
				<snapshot1>x1pS1i9.png</snapshot1>
				<snapshot2>yKVwWGX.png</snapshot2>
				<snapshot3>rUCTxl3.png</snapshot3>
				<snapshot4>qG6qnmF.png</snapshot4>
				<snapshot5>JdywX3Y.png</snapshot5>
				<snapshot6>DCOgXe0.png</snapshot6>
				<snapshot7>sf2lZkB.png</snapshot7>
				<snapshot8>jJP1UXs.png</snapshot8>
				<snapshot9>GQtJstF.png</snapshot9>
				<snapshot10>9b1rfVc.png</snapshot10>
				<emu_command>A4000</emu_command>
			</game>
			<game name="Snow Bros.">
				<description>47.  Snow Bros.</description>
				<rom name="AmigaROMsCoverArtRS/Amiga_ROMs_%26_CoverArt_R-S.zip/Snow%20Bros%2FSnow%20Bros..Disk1.adf" size="901120" />
				<rom name="AmigaROMsCoverArtRS/Amiga_ROMs_%26_CoverArt_R-S.zip/Snow%20Bros%2FSnow%20Bros..Disk2.adf" size="901120" />
				<title_clean>Snow Bros.</title_clean>
				<plot>[CR][B]Overview:[/B][CR]Snow Bros. is an action game developed by Toaplan and published by Capcom for multiple platforms.[CR][B]Gameplay:[/B][CR]Much like Bubble Bobble, Snow Bros takes place on single screens where the objective is to "trap" enemies and then destroy them via chain reactions. In this game, the enemies are trapped by shooting snow at them: when enough snow has been thrown at an enemy, they become a snowball that can be pushed around and/or kicked. If a snowball is left idle for too long, the enemy will break free. Kicking the snowball causes it to ricochet around the stage, taking out any foes in its path. The snowball (and the enemy within it) is destroyed upon hitting the bottom walls of the screen. Other snowballs can be launched when a moving snowball hits it. This creates the ability to setup chain reactions. The best way to rack up points is to create a chain reaction that kills every enemy on screen with a single kick of a snowball.[CR]When enemies are destroyed, they leave behind a food item (often sushi or ice cream) worth points upon collecting. If you manage to do a 100% chain reaction, large tickets appear from the top of the screen, worth 10000 points each. You can move on to the next stage/screen after killing all enemies. Time is limited in each screen- taking too long results in an invincible monster appearing to chase and kill you (another similarity to Bubble Bobble).[CR]There are several power ups (resembling potions) available to the player, which spawn at random from a dead enemy. Red potions increase the speed of your character; Blue potions increase the strength of your snow (meaning you can make enemies into snowballs faster), and Yellow increases your range. Green potions engage a bonus stage that fills the screen with new enemies, each representing a letter of the word "BONUS". Each one you kill results in you earing the corresponding letter- getting all of them results in a 1-UP. The final power up inflates your character into a baloon, which makes you invincible and able to move throughout the stage quickly- any contact with enemies kills them.[CR]Every 10 stages ends in a boss encounter.[CR]The NES version of the game introduces cut scenes and a more fleshed out story. However, this version has many of the stages and enemy layouts altered from the arcade version. A Mega Drive version came out in Japan and Europe and is something of a collectiors item- garnering high prices on Auctions. An official sequel called Snow Bros 2: With New Elves came out shortly after. A homebrew Snow Bros 3 was made and distributed in South America.[CR]</plot>
				<releasedate>30/3/2006</releasedate>
				<year>2006</year>
				<genre>Action</genre>
				<perspective>Platform</perspective>
				<mobygames_url>https://www.mobygames.com/game/amiga/snow-bros-nick-tom</mobygames_url>
				<giantbomb_url>https://www.giantbomb.com/snow-bros-nick-tom/3030-19781/</giantbomb_url>
				<boxart1>DwiMhCd.jpg</boxart1>
				<snapshot1>oJS9C4z.png</snapshot1>
				<snapshot2>J0mJzi6.png</snapshot2>
				<snapshot3>TS7P8TJ.png</snapshot3>
				<snapshot4>M84Htt4.png</snapshot4>
				<snapshot5>VgXRkjQ.png</snapshot5>
				<snapshot6>7KGPfAx.png</snapshot6>
				<snapshot7>93mnqZ6.png</snapshot7>
				<snapshot8>8ZYzKQi.png</snapshot8>
				<snapshot9>33Kl6TW.png</snapshot9>
				<snapshot10>GGvgSp0.png</snapshot10>
				<emu_command>A4000</emu_command>
			</game>
			<game name="Benefactor">
				<description>46.  Benefactor</description>
				<rom name="AmigaROMs_A-B/Amiga_ROMs_%26_CoverArt_A-B.zip/Benefactor%2FBenefactor.Disk1.adf" size="901120" />
				<rom name="AmigaROMs_A-B/Amiga_ROMs_%26_CoverArt_A-B.zip/Benefactor%2FBenefactor.Disk2.adf" size="901120" />
				<rom name="AmigaROMs_A-B/Amiga_ROMs_%26_CoverArt_A-B.zip/Benefactor%2FBenefactor.Disk3.adf" size="901120" />
				<title_clean>Benefactor</title_clean>
				<plot>[CR]A Superb puzzle game in which you have to rescue small little folks of Lullyat who have been kidnapped! As a hero you are, you are willing going to risk your life running around various dungeons with some gritty puzzles to keep you well occupied into the blissful darkness of night that you will surely be by the time you finish this game. Its a wonderfull world of puzzles which will keep you busy for hours and hours with game more addictive then any coke products you might have tasted in years past! The people from Lullyat may look like lemmings but BEWARE! not all of the nice friendly little people are nice! some have been turned into evil creatures just like the creature that kidnaped them. -Sigh-ALL is not lost, as you have the ability in amongst all the puzzles your heart can take to change these evil Lullyat people back into their former self by usually solving several puzzles to have them walk past this special painting machine which will magicly turn your new fluffy friends back into good law abinding citizens!! well, citizens of Lullyat that is. As you play through the numerous levels you'll quickly figure out that in order to save the people of Lullyat you have solve puzzles to get the keys that will unlock the once cute and free minions of Lullyat and while some have been stricken slightly mad by their capture, once healed will help you solve puzzles that you simply cannot do by yourself. The animations are you'd expect are cute and very well done along with some superb! and interesting puzzles this game really is puzzle games with your standard platform gameplay at is absolute best. You'll notice going through the numerous levels that there are a lot of Indiana Jones type scenario's which just make this gaming experience one to remember. Definitely worthy of a 5 Star rating in my book.[CR]</plot>
				<releasedate>30/7/1994</releasedate>
				<year>1994</year>
				<genre>Action, Strategy</genre>
				<studio>Psygnosis Limited</studio>
				<nplayers>1</nplayers>
				<perspective>3rd-Person</perspective>
				<rating>4.0</rating>
				<thegamesdb_id>9046</thegamesdb_id>
				<mobygames_url>https://www.mobygames.com/game/amiga/benefactor</mobygames_url>
				<giantbomb_url>https://www.giantbomb.com/benefactor/3030-11446/</giantbomb_url>
				<boxart1>3ONl4ql.jpg</boxart1>
				<boxart2>LUuQij5.jpg</boxart2>
				<boxart3>AIn2JI9.jpg</boxart3>
				<boxart4>j5gGUOl.jpg</boxart4>
				<boxart5>Swm2p9V.jpg</boxart5>
				<boxart6>AIn2JI9.jpg</boxart6>
				<boxart7>j5gGUOl.jpg</boxart7>
				<boxart8>Swm2p9V.jpg</boxart8>
				<snapshot1>WUntdGB.png</snapshot1>
				<snapshot2>dwOFlc1.png</snapshot2>
				<snapshot3>RMfIFjY.png</snapshot3>
				<snapshot4>ip11mqz.png</snapshot4>
				<snapshot5>m47kIcC.png</snapshot5>
				<snapshot6>60dEybR.png</snapshot6>
				<snapshot7>cGedrjc.png</snapshot7>
				<snapshot8>Ln68Tdd.png</snapshot8>
				<snapshot9>jC00Vo4.png</snapshot9>
				<snapshot10>W0vATli.png</snapshot10>
				<clearlogo1>q0yt3uU.png</clearlogo1>
				<emu_command>A4000</emu_command>
			</game>
			<game name="Alien Breed - Tower Assault (OCS &amp; AGA)">
				<description>45.  Alien Breed - Tower Assault</description>
				<rom name="AmigaROMs_A-B/Amiga_ROMs_%26_CoverArt_A-B.zip/Alien%20Breed%20-%20Tower%20Assault%2FAlien%20Breed%20-%20Tower%20Assault%20%28OCS%20%26%20AGA%29.Disk1.adf" size="901120" />
				<rom name="AmigaROMs_A-B/Amiga_ROMs_%26_CoverArt_A-B.zip/Alien%20Breed%20-%20Tower%20Assault%2FAlien%20Breed%20-%20Tower%20Assault%20%28OCS%20%26%20AGA%29.Disk2.adf" size="901120" />
				<rom name="AmigaROMs_A-B/Amiga_ROMs_%26_CoverArt_A-B.zip/Alien%20Breed%20-%20Tower%20Assault%2FAlien%20Breed%20-%20Tower%20Assault%20%28OCS%20%26%20AGA%29.Disk3.adf" size="901120" />
				<rom name="AmigaROMs_A-B/Amiga_ROMs_%26_CoverArt_A-B.zip/Alien%20Breed%20-%20Tower%20Assault%2FAlien%20Breed%20-%20Tower%20Assault%20%28OCS%20%26%20AGA%29.Disk4.adf" size="901120" />
				<title_clean>Alien Breed - Tower Assault</title_clean>
				<plot>A scientific outpost on a far off planet has been attacked. Nothing is known about the attackers, since all communications have been destroyed. A team of marines is dispatched to investigate and destroy the unknown invaders. As their dropships enter the atmosphere and approach the base, the defence lasers, damaged in the onslaught, move into action. They launch wild bursts of laser fire at the approaching marines, who are not prepared and take heavy losses. Rookies Nash and Jordan crash-land, and must fight off the alien force.[CR]As with the previous Alien Breed, the gameplay is viewed from above. Your soldier shoots his way through the levels, collecting keys, ammunition and credits along the way. Computers can be logged into to buy new weapons. A new 'retreat' mode allows you to fire while moving backwards.[CR]The game is largely non-linear, as most levels have multiple exits, and the game can be moved through in different ways. There is a variety of indoor and outdoor levels, although you spend most time inside some of the multi-level towers. After activating a self-destruct mechanism, you must escape the building quickly.</plot>
				<releasedate>30/3/1994</releasedate>
				<year>1994</year>
				<genre>Action</genre>
				<studio>Team17 Software Limited</studio>
				<nplayers>1-2 Sim</nplayers>
				<perspective>3rd-Person</perspective>
				<rating>3.8</rating>
				<thegamesdb_id>20261</thegamesdb_id>
				<mobygames_url>https://www.mobygames.com/game/amiga/alien-breed-tower-assault</mobygames_url>
				<giantbomb_url>https://www.giantbomb.com/alien-breed-tower-assault/3030-15149/</giantbomb_url>
				<boxart1>4EnCfQI.jpg</boxart1>
				<boxart2>aKRKJXo.jpg</boxart2>
				<snapshot1>kZqA1hQ.jpg</snapshot1>
				<snapshot2>Yzly25N.jpg</snapshot2>
				<snapshot3>BYwRBZC.png</snapshot3>
				<snapshot4>fD3nuRr.png</snapshot4>
				<snapshot5>BYwRBZC.png</snapshot5>
				<snapshot6>fD3nuRr.png</snapshot6>
				<emu_command>A4000</emu_command>
			</game>
			<game name="Zak McKracken and the Alien Mindbenders">
				<description>44.  Zak McKracken and the Alien Mindbenders</description>
				<rom name="AmigaROMsCoverArtTUVWXYZ/Amiga_ROMs_%26_CoverArt_T-U-V-W-X-Y-Z.zip/Zak%20McKracken%20and%20the%20Alien%20Mindbenders%2FZak%20McKracken%20and%20the%20Alien%20Mindbenders.Disk1.adf" size="901120" />
				<rom name="AmigaROMsCoverArtTUVWXYZ/Amiga_ROMs_%26_CoverArt_T-U-V-W-X-Y-Z.zip/Zak%20McKracken%20and%20the%20Alien%20Mindbenders%2FZak%20McKracken%20and%20the%20Alien%20Mindbenders.Disk2.adf" size="901120" />
				<title_clean>Zak McKracken and the Alien Mindbenders</title_clean>
				<plot>[CR][B]Plot:[/B][CR]Zak McKracken is a tabloid reporter who discovers a plot by aliens to decrease the intelligence of the people of Earth. He embarks on a globe-trotting adventure to stop the aliens plans, teaming up with scientist Annie Larris and the first human astronauts to land on the surface of Mars, Melissa China &amp; Leslie Bennett.[CR]Zak discovers a number of special crystals in his adventure that give him powers including teleportation &amp; the ability to jump into the body of animals.[CR]Playable Characters[CR]The player is able to control 4 characters:Zak McKrackenAnnie LarrisMelissa ChinaLeslie Bennett[CR]Unlike the First SCUMM game Maniac Mansion you are not able to control &amp; switch between all characters from the start of the game. Only as the plot progresses and the characters are introduced are you able to control them.[CR][B]Trivia:[/B][CR]Unlike most other LucasArts games (with the exception of Maniac Mansion) you were able to die in Zak McKracken.The original box came with a fake newspaper with several humorous articles in it.There is a can of chainsaw fuel on Mars, if you try to pick it up characters will say it's for a different game, in Maniac Mansion there was a chainsaw in the kitchen that was out of fuel, but there was no fuel for it in that game.[CR]Cameo[CR]Lou's Pawn Shop (AST)[CR]In Maniac Mansion, another game by Lucasarts, a poster with Zak McKracken on it can be found in the arcade hall. And vice versa, in Lou's pawn shop a Maniac Mansion advertisement poster can be found on the wall.[CR]</plot>
				<releasedate>30/3/1988</releasedate>
				<year>1988</year>
				<genre>Adventure</genre>
				<studio>Lucasfilm Games LLC</studio>
				<nplayers>1</nplayers>
				<perspective>3rd-Person</perspective>
				<rating>3.7</rating>
				<mobygames_url>https://www.mobygames.com/game/amiga/zak-mckracken-and-the-alien-mindbenders</mobygames_url>
				<giantbomb_url>https://www.giantbomb.com/zak-mckracken-and-the-alien-mindbenders/3030-6728/</giantbomb_url>
				<boxart1>FWflrGk.jpg</boxart1>
				<boxart2>dUQDPkQ.jpg</boxart2>
				<boxart3>BPH46Ou.jpg</boxart3>
				<snapshot1>LJcMxDP.gif</snapshot1>
				<snapshot2>JJRGqtI.gif</snapshot2>
				<snapshot3>tCOrFcb.gif</snapshot3>
				<snapshot4>3nerbXp.gif</snapshot4>
				<snapshot5>5Bb9Gdi.gif</snapshot5>
				<snapshot6>Nu7PKIE.gif</snapshot6>
				<snapshot7>Fd6aYng.gif</snapshot7>
				<snapshot8>uEQaVSJ.png</snapshot8>
				<snapshot9>IaxS5Tg.png</snapshot9>
				<snapshot10>tm1W2R4.png</snapshot10>
				<emu_command>A4000</emu_command>
			</game>
			<game name="Ultima V - Warriors of Destiny">
				<description>43.  Ultima V - Warriors of Destiny</description>
				<rom name="AmigaROMsCoverArtTUVWXYZ/Amiga_ROMs_%26_CoverArt_T-U-V-W-X-Y-Z.zip/Ultima%20V%20-%20Warriors%20of%20Destiny%2FUltima%20V%20-%20Warriors%20of%20Destiny.Disk1.adf" size="901120" />
				<rom name="AmigaROMsCoverArtTUVWXYZ/Amiga_ROMs_%26_CoverArt_T-U-V-W-X-Y-Z.zip/Ultima%20V%20-%20Warriors%20of%20Destiny%2FUltima%20V%20-%20Warriors%20of%20Destiny.Disk2.adf" size="901120" />
				<title_clean>Ultima V - Warriors of Destiny</title_clean>
				<plot>Boxart showing an artpiece of the avatar.[CR]Ultima V, on the heels of the moral and technological breakthrough Ultima IV, has that King Arthur quality to it. It's been 2 years in your world(20 in Britannia) and someone named Blackthorn has usurped the throne after Lord British has disappeared. LB has been spotted at marshes some times although Blackthorn has persecuted any who say so as sacreligious. While LB was ruling the Avatar's eight virtues were expounded and practiced to make Britannia more wealthy, but now there are high taxes and martial law and Blackthorn has twisted the eight laws to form a police state. He even wants to figure out the mantras and the secrets to the Codex and the now sealed-off dungeons. Your object is to rid Britannia of the menace he and possible accomplices pose to Britannia.[CR]Iolo and Shamino realize the kingdom is trouble and call on the Avatar of legend to come back. He does, but as he is summoned through the magic moongate three Shadowlords appear and one throws a bolt into Shamino, who is left on the edge of death. The three heroes retreat to Iolo's hut deep in the woods, where they hope to let Shamino recuperate.Title screen[CR]You'll need to get Lord British's artifacts, the Sandalwood Box, visit eight shrines and solve their quests (need to get the mantras too), get eight words of power to open the dungeon, and find Lord British. You begin as an avatar, but can lose the status by harming virtues. In the game this loss of Avatar status is shown by important clues being withheld. For example, in Britain, you won&#8217;t receive the password for opening the dungeon Despise if you haven't followed the path of the Avatar. The game now also has day and night cycles. In the night, the gates to most towns are closed and the people living there mostly lay in their beds although guards still patrol.OverworldUnderworld[CR]One of the new improvements is the magic and combat system. In a combat situation you have a cursor which you can use to attack in any direction. That cursor will remain on the selected monster as long as you wish. That doesn&#8217;t mean combat is easy since you only get 30 hit-points, more when a new character level has been achieved, while monster magic capabilities and sheer numbers have increased. Magical spells are now (and in further Ultimas too) divided into 8 cycles. The higher the level of the spell caster, the more magic they can use.Great graphics for that time[CR]Availability[CR]The game is available at gog.com and is part of the "Ultima 4+5+6" package.[CR]</plot>
				<releasedate>30/3/1990</releasedate>
				<year>1990</year>
				<genre>RPG</genre>
				<studio>ORIGIN Systems, Inc.</studio>
				<nplayers>1</nplayers>
				<perspective>Top-Down</perspective>
				<rating>4.4</rating>
				<thegamesdb_id>9555</thegamesdb_id>
				<mobygames_url>https://www.mobygames.com/game/amiga/ultima-v-warriors-of-destiny</mobygames_url>
				<giantbomb_url>https://www.giantbomb.com/ultima-v-warriors-of-destiny/3030-16762/</giantbomb_url>
				<boxart1>slRDhJl.jpg</boxart1>
				<boxart2>RcCz2A4.jpg</boxart2>
				<boxart3>fUdbTFs.jpg</boxart3>
				<boxart4>tizqDTc.jpg</boxart4>
				<boxart5>Fi5cwI7.jpg</boxart5>
				<snapshot1>LUECnYo.png</snapshot1>
				<snapshot2>7Iz7hOH.png</snapshot2>
				<snapshot3>d9cfd01.png</snapshot3>
				<snapshot4>Ciq8fnE.png</snapshot4>
				<snapshot5>rMt0dEm.png</snapshot5>
				<snapshot6>5tu4qBF.png</snapshot6>
				<snapshot7>pCGSmKo.png</snapshot7>
				<snapshot8>z9sezB4.png</snapshot8>
				<snapshot9>bo2exNK.png</snapshot9>
				<snapshot10>0cpZYvC.png</snapshot10>
				<emu_command>A4000</emu_command>
			</game>
			<game name="Space Quest III - The Pirates of Pestulon">
				<description>42.  Space Quest III - The Pirates of Pestulon</description>
				<rom name="AmigaROMsCoverArtRS/Amiga_ROMs_%26_CoverArt_R-S.zip/Space%20Quest%20III%20-%20The%20Pirates%20of%20Pestulon%2FSpace%20Quest%20III%20-%20The%20Pirates%20of%20Pestulon.Disk1.adf" size="901120" />
				<rom name="AmigaROMsCoverArtRS/Amiga_ROMs_%26_CoverArt_R-S.zip/Space%20Quest%20III%20-%20The%20Pirates%20of%20Pestulon%2FSpace%20Quest%20III%20-%20The%20Pirates%20of%20Pestulon.Disk2.adf" size="901120" />
				<rom name="AmigaROMsCoverArtRS/Amiga_ROMs_%26_CoverArt_R-S.zip/Space%20Quest%20III%20-%20The%20Pirates%20of%20Pestulon%2FSpace%20Quest%20III%20-%20The%20Pirates%20of%20Pestulon.Disk3.adf" size="901120" />
				<rom name="AmigaROMsCoverArtRS/Amiga_ROMs_%26_CoverArt_R-S.zip/Space%20Quest%20III%20-%20The%20Pirates%20of%20Pestulon%2FSpace%20Quest%20III%20-%20The%20Pirates%20of%20Pestulon.Disk4.adf" size="901120" />
				<title_clean>Space Quest III - The Pirates of Pestulon</title_clean>
				<plot>[CR]Space Quest III: The Pirates of Pestulon is a 1989 adventure game developed and published by Sierra On-Line. It is widely regarded as the best game in the Space Quest series, and was selected as the 1989 Adventure Game of the Year by the Software Publishers of America.[CR][B]Story:[/B][CR] This time, Roger *is* the trash.[CR]When we last left Roger, he was floating through space in a cryogenic sleep chamber, hoping to get rescued. Rescue does come, but unfortunately in the form of a interstellar garbage hauler. Seen as just a piece of space debris, Roger and his ship are sucked up to be disposed of. Fortunately for Roger, this manages to activate his chamber's awakening function and he is able to make his escape.[CR]  Pay me if you want to live.[CR]Through Roger's weird luck, his escape finds him at the helm of a new ship, the Aluminum Mallard, which he decides to take on a tour of his current star system. Stopping at a nearby planet, Phleebhut, Roger makes his way to a local tourist destination. After perusing the knick knacks and while on his way back to his ship, Roger encounters the Annihilator droid, Arnoid the Terminator. Arnoid is there to collect an unpaid debt in Roger's name from the Labion Terror Beast Whistle he purchased from the Gippazoid Novelty Company's mail order catalogue back in SQ2. Unfortunately Roger doesn't have the money so Arnoid is forced to terminate him.[CR]  Monolith Burger[CR]Through his sheer prowess, or perhaps dumb luck, Roger manages to defeat the droid and quickly leaves the planet. Shaken, and a bit hungry, Roger stops off at a Monolith Burger for a quick bite. After ordering the fun meal and obtaining a nifty decoder ring as the prize, Roger decides to play the new Astro Chicken Arcade Game from ScumSoft. Being pretty good at video games, Roger manages to obtain the high score and also unlocks a mysteriously coded message. Using his new decoder ring Roger discovers that the makers of the game, and the Space Quest series, are being held captive by ScumSoft and forced to write computer games.[CR]   Preparing for a robot duel [CR]Being the noble hero that he is, Roger sets off to free the Two Guys from Andromeda. Again, through his incredible skill, or perhaps just even more blind dumb luck, Roger sneaks his way into ScumSoft and frees the two guys. Unfortunately he finds himself trapped by the evil CEO who forces Roger to face him in a life size Rock 'Em Sock 'Em duel.[CR]   Wilco, Two Guys, and Williams[CR]Yet again, Roger manages to prevail and escapes with the guys onto his ship. After a fierce but quick space battle, Roger escapes with the two guys and it looks like they're home free. Unfortunately Roger's luck catches up with him and they all get sucked into a black hole. Fortunately, instead of being annihilated, they are instead transported to some far off and strange galaxy. Landing on the only planet that can sustain life, they touch down and happen across a strange guy named Ken Williams who happens to own a software company himself. He immediately hires the two guys to make a game about their adventures with offers of riches and glory. Unfortunately they already have a janitor, so Roger gets back in his ship and sets off for sights unknown.[CR][B]Gameplay:[/B][CR]Space Quest 3 utilized Sierra's new SCI engine which brought an entirely new parser and updated graphics and sound card support. This game brought something new to the adventure game world: mouse support. Though you still interacted primarily through the arrow keys and a text parser, it was also possible to utilize the mouse for movement and inventory interaction.[CR]Unfortunately, or perhaps fortunately for those hardcore gamers, this game still allowed many irreversible deaths and dead end puzzles.[CR]Astro Chicken [CR] Astro Chicken Title Screen[CR]Astro Chicken was a minigame included within Space Quest 3, that featured a hidden message randomly displayed when the player received a high score. The goal of the game was to land a chicken on a trampoline. Upon doing so the chicken would let out a resounding "Bacock!", and then you would repeat. The game has similarities to Lunar Lander but the chicken rebounds from the trampoline if it lands too hard.[CR]The name of the game is considered a possible parody of the identically named thought experiment by theoretical physicist Freeman Dyson. A sequel to Astro Chicken (Ms. Astro Chicken) was included as a playable minigame in Space Quest IV. The Astro Chicken developer, Scum Soft, is almost certainly a reference to Sierra's adventure game arch rival, LucasArts, and their ScummVM engine.[CR][B]Reception:[/B][CR]The game received very good critical reviews from the various media at the time generally getting 4 out of 5 or around 80% mark reviews.[CR]Requirements[CR]8088/8086 CPU512KB RAM CGA, EGA, Hercules, MCGA, Tandy/PCjr, or VGA graphicsAdlib, Game Blaster, IBM Music Feature Card, PC speaker, PS/1 Audio Card, Roland MT-32, Sound Blaster, Tandy DAC, or Tandy/PCjr sound cardKeyboard, optional Mouse[CR]</plot>
				<releasedate>30/3/1989</releasedate>
				<year>1989</year>
				<genre>Adventure</genre>
				<studio>Sierra On-Line, Inc.</studio>
				<nplayers>1</nplayers>
				<perspective>3rd-Person</perspective>
				<rating>3.6</rating>
				<mobygames_url>https://www.mobygames.com/game/amiga/space-quest-iii-the-pirates-of-pestulon</mobygames_url>
				<giantbomb_url>https://www.giantbomb.com/space-quest-iii-the-pirates-of-pestulon/3030-2228/</giantbomb_url>
				<boxart1>LYr6dCw.jpg</boxart1>
				<boxart2>0gkZSK9.jpg</boxart2>
				<boxart3>9fNsCAC.jpg</boxart3>
				<boxart4>U1ixw45.jpg</boxart4>
				<snapshot1>qi50wU1.png</snapshot1>
				<snapshot2>TAcMl0u.png</snapshot2>
				<snapshot3>jJYE6YF.png</snapshot3>
				<snapshot4>vtoljsZ.png</snapshot4>
				<snapshot5>eW4mCBM.png</snapshot5>
				<snapshot6>Sob6Wpf.png</snapshot6>
				<snapshot7>S9oErjI.png</snapshot7>
				<snapshot8>ZznGv7i.png</snapshot8>
				<snapshot9>eWTC6sz.png</snapshot9>
				<snapshot10>KgI4x0O.png</snapshot10>
				<emu_command>A4000</emu_command>
			</game>
			<game name="F-15 Strike Eagle II">
				<description>41.  F-15 Strike Eagle II</description>
				<rom name="AmigaROMsCoverArtCDEF/Amiga_ROMs_%26_CoverArt_C-D-E-F.zip/F-15%20Strike%20Eagle%20II%2FF-15%20Strike%20Eagle%20II.Disk1.adf" size="901120" />
				<rom name="AmigaROMsCoverArtCDEF/Amiga_ROMs_%26_CoverArt_C-D-E-F.zip/F-15%20Strike%20Eagle%20II%2FF-15%20Strike%20Eagle%20II.Disk2.adf" size="901120" />
				<title_clean>F-15 Strike Eagle II</title_clean>
				<plot>The second in the series features campaigns in Lybia, the Persian Gulf, The Middle East and Vietnam, making for a total of 250,000 miles of potential action and danger. Primary and secondary aerial and ground-based targets must be destroyed on each of these. You are armed with a cannon, AMRAAM long-range air-to-air missile, Sidewinder short-range air-to-air missile, and the Maverick air-to-ground missile.[CR]11 camera angles including internal and external views of the plane exist. To help new players there is a training mode, with options to disable crashes and automate take-off and landing. Enemy AI is responsive, but a targeting computer helps you take them out before they can do it to you. The game incorporates two "Director's Modes" which cuts away from your cockpit to highlight special events occurring elsewhere in the game world, like enemy base launching fighters, SAM sites launching SAMs, and your missiles hitting the target.</plot>
				<releasedate>30/3/1991</releasedate>
				<year>1991</year>
				<genre>Action, Simulation</genre>
				<studio>MicroProse Software, Inc.</studio>
				<nplayers>1</nplayers>
				<perspective>1st-Person</perspective>
				<rating>3.8</rating>
				<mobygames_url>https://www.mobygames.com/game/amiga/f-15-strike-eagle-ii</mobygames_url>
				<giantbomb_url>https://www.giantbomb.com/f-15-strike-eagle-ii/3030-15144/</giantbomb_url>
				<boxart1>SOk5zFm.jpg</boxart1>
				<boxart2>ajKEiOR.jpg</boxart2>
				<boxart3>IPsdyGr.jpg</boxart3>
				<snapshot1>OwVQzFV.png</snapshot1>
				<snapshot2>ANnEtc1.png</snapshot2>
				<snapshot3>r9gwIHA.png</snapshot3>
				<snapshot4>ghg83qI.png</snapshot4>
				<snapshot5>Kk14h3m.png</snapshot5>
				<snapshot6>HTNNmpo.png</snapshot6>
				<snapshot7>cWwrjoG.png</snapshot7>
				<snapshot8>WpobvQl.png</snapshot8>
				<snapshot9>UPEGMSs.png</snapshot9>
				<snapshot10>Oa71zfk.png</snapshot10>
				<emu_command>A4000</emu_command>
			</game>
			<game name="Ultima VI - The False Prophet">
				<description>40.  Ultima VI - The False Prophet</description>
				<rom name="AmigaROMsCoverArtTUVWXYZ/Amiga_ROMs_%26_CoverArt_T-U-V-W-X-Y-Z.zip/Ultima%20VI%20-%20The%20False%20Prophet%2FUltima%20VI%20-%20The%20False%20Prophet.Disk1.adf" size="901120" />
				<rom name="AmigaROMsCoverArtTUVWXYZ/Amiga_ROMs_%26_CoverArt_T-U-V-W-X-Y-Z.zip/Ultima%20VI%20-%20The%20False%20Prophet%2FUltima%20VI%20-%20The%20False%20Prophet.Disk2.adf" size="901120" />
				<rom name="AmigaROMsCoverArtTUVWXYZ/Amiga_ROMs_%26_CoverArt_T-U-V-W-X-Y-Z.zip/Ultima%20VI%20-%20The%20False%20Prophet%2FUltima%20VI%20-%20The%20False%20Prophet.Disk3.adf" size="901120" />
				<rom name="AmigaROMsCoverArtTUVWXYZ/Amiga_ROMs_%26_CoverArt_T-U-V-W-X-Y-Z.zip/Ultima%20VI%20-%20The%20False%20Prophet%2FUltima%20VI%20-%20The%20False%20Prophet.Disk4.adf" size="901120" />
				<title_clean>Ultima VI - The False Prophet</title_clean>
				<plot>[CR][B]Overview:[/B][CR]Ultima VI: The False Prophet is the third game in the second trilogy of the Ultima series, and the sixth (or possibly seventh) title to be released in the series. Ultima VI is notable for its single-scale world, in which cities blend seamlessly into the overworld, its strong moral sense, and its unstructured, non-linear gameplay -- a harbinger of what would later be called sandbox games.[CR]The Ultima VI engine would see use in the Worlds of Ultima series, which took place outside the main Ultima universe.[CR]Ultima VI was the final Ultima to see release on a wide variety of personal computer platforms, ranging from the C64 to the Atari ST, to the Amiga, FM Towns, PC98, X68K, and the PC, and years later on the SNES. Ultima VI was the first Ultima game not available on the Apple II.[CR][B]Background:[/B][CR]In Ultima VI, as in the previous two Ultima games, the player assumes the role of the Avatar, the embodiment of virtue and hope for the lands of Britannia. The game begins with the Avatar on Earth, enjoying a computer game, when a moongate suddenly appears. They enter through it, only to find themselves in the middle of a ritual sacrifice conducted by the winged, demonic-looking race known as Gargoyles. Although the Avatar is bound to the altar, and all appears lost, their companions -- Iolo. Shamino, and Dupre -- appear and free him. They then find themselves back in Lord British's castle, where they discover that the shrines of the virtues are under attack by the Gargoyles. The Avatar is tasked with freeing the shrines and discovering the nature of the Gargoyle invasion.[CR][B]Gameplay:[/B][CR]Similarly to other Ultimas, they are free to build their character, via stat points, in any way they wish. The Avatar is capable of using all weapons and spells in the game; however by increasing either STR, DEX, or INT, either melee, ranged, or magic attacks will be increased in effectiveness.[CR]Like other games in the series, the Avatar gathers a party to fight alongside them. They start off with three members, Iolo the Bard, Shamino the Ranger, and Dupre the Knight, but they can take any number of different characters with them, each of which have their own stats and uses. While the Avatar is the main character of the game, it is possible to take control over individual characters at times (which can have strategic uses), although the player cannot talk to other NPCs unless they are controlling the Avatar.[CR]As a sandbox-style game, Ultima VI lets the player do things different ways. There is not set order to completing objectives or visiting dungeons. There are a number of optional areas to visit and weapons to obtain. It is easy to miss things unless they explore every area. There is no level gating -- the player can explore the entire world from the get go. Ultima VI has a handful of travel options -- in addition to running, the Avatar can buy a horse, a boat, or ride a raft.[CR]The Avatar can rob stores, steal from the bank, and kill NPCS. They can kill a farmer's cow for meat, or milk it for milk to churn into butter. Take flour, and bake bread with it. Buy a ship and explore, or kill the shipwright and steal all his deeds. Ultima VI had a large number of what would now be called crafting opportunities, in which the player can take items gathered from the world and combine them to create something new.[CR]Although the player has a great deal of freedom, Ultima VI has, in the background and hidden from the player, something called Karma. Stealing or unprovoked killing decrease karma, while doing certain missions increases it. It is not possible to complete the game if the player's karma is too low.[CR][B]Characters:[/B][CR]NameLocationSTRDEXINTMagicNotesBeh Lembefore Hythloth dunegon232426GargoyleBlainwith Gypsy band162118Gypsy jugglerGornunder Sutek's isleFighterGwennoMinoc1821179Bard, scholar and Iolo's wifeJaanaYewDruid and healerJuliaMinoc211817TinkererKatrinaNew Magincia191616ShepherdLeonnaMoonglow151518FighterLeodonMoonglow1519157FighterSeggallionSerpent's Hold282120Fighter. From another dimensionSentriSerpent's Hold261816Lord of Serpent's HoldSherryLord British's CastleA mouse. Can get into small spaces.[CR]Mantras[CR]NameMantraCompassionmuControlunDiligenceusHonestyahmHonorsummHumilitylumJusticebehPassionorPridemulSacrificecahSingularityunorusSpiritualityomValorra[CR]Spells[CR]Spells are organized in eight circles of increasing difficulty. The magic cost of each spell corresponds to its circle; so a fourth circle spell will cost four magic points.[CR]Reagents[CR]Using magic in Ultima 6 requires that the spell caster has the proper reagents on hand. Reagents may be found in certain areas, or purchased from vendors.[CR]The table below lists the areas where reagents may be gathered, as well as their price from various shops.NameHarvesting LocationHoranceNicodemusRudyomXiaoZoltanBlack Pearl34Blood Moss3233Garlic1132Ginseng1231Mandrake526Nightshade231Spider Silk11232Sulpherous Ash22131[CR]Cheats[CR]Ultima VI included a full cheat menu, allowing the Avatar to teleport anywhere in the game, spawn any item, and modify internal game state. To access it, the Avatar must talk to Iolo and speak the following words:[CR]spam[CR]spam[CR]spam[CR]humbug[CR]After doing this, the cheat/debug menu will appear. Using these cheats does not affect the outcome of the game (assuming of course that the player does not alter the game flags or karma).[CR]Availability[CR]The game is nowadays available at Good Old Games (Gog.com) in a package with Ultima 4 and 5, and has been made playable on modern computers.[CR]</plot>
				<releasedate>30/3/1992</releasedate>
				<year>1992</year>
				<genre>RPG</genre>
				<studio>ORIGIN Systems, Inc.</studio>
				<nplayers>1</nplayers>
				<perspective>3rd-Person</perspective>
				<rating>3.3</rating>
				<mobygames_url>https://www.mobygames.com/game/amiga/ultima-vi-the-false-prophet</mobygames_url>
				<giantbomb_url>https://www.giantbomb.com/ultima-vi-the-false-prophet/3030-10012/</giantbomb_url>
				<boxart1>ZjI7Y7D.jpg</boxart1>
				<boxart2>LzdWsKk.jpg</boxart2>
				<boxart3>IFrQJjE.jpg</boxart3>
				<boxart4>oxjIisC.jpg</boxart4>
				<boxart5>EPvEpQv.jpg</boxart5>
				<snapshot1>PUokXy0.png</snapshot1>
				<snapshot2>r2dq6HK.png</snapshot2>
				<snapshot3>1XA1cWi.png</snapshot3>
				<snapshot4>v8naOMl.png</snapshot4>
				<snapshot5>ckgbFft.png</snapshot5>
				<snapshot6>h9d3dO9.png</snapshot6>
				<snapshot7>RneuKYd.png</snapshot7>
				<snapshot8>80FvG7E.png</snapshot8>
				<snapshot9>51zzeKD.png</snapshot9>
				<snapshot10>CZXAkPu.png</snapshot10>
				<emu_command>A4000</emu_command>
			</game>
			<game name="Super Cars II">
				<description>39.  Super Cars II</description>
				<rom name="AmigaROMsCoverArtRS/Amiga_ROMs_%26_CoverArt_R-S.zip/Super%20Cars%20II%2FSuper%20Cars%20II.Disk1.adf" size="901120" />
				<rom name="AmigaROMsCoverArtRS/Amiga_ROMs_%26_CoverArt_R-S.zip/Super%20Cars%20II%2FSuper%20Cars%20II.Disk2.adf" size="901120" />
				<title_clean>Super Cars II</title_clean>
				<plot>The follow up to Magnetic Fields' earlier racing game develops the format in several ways. As before, the racing is overhead view and against a field of 9 computer cars, with championship points awarded for finishing positions. The computer drivers now take on the humourous names from Lotus 1, such as 'Ayrton Sendup' and 'T Hairy Bootson'. The most noticeable addition is a split screen 2 player mode. [CR]The power ups have been changed around from the original, with the handling improvements gone, so as to put more of an emphasis on learning to control the slippery cars. These have been replaced by further weapons and more engine upgrades.[CR]The questions from the original have been replaced by mock driving test questions about stopping distances and the like - as before, money and points are won and lost depending on your answers.</plot>
				<releasedate>30/3/1991</releasedate>
				<year>1991</year>
				<genre>Action, Driving, Racing</genre>
				<studio>Gremlin Graphics Software Ltd.</studio>
				<nplayers>1-2 Alt</nplayers>
				<perspective>Top-Down</perspective>
				<rating>3.7</rating>
				<thegamesdb_id>24649</thegamesdb_id>
				<mobygames_url>https://www.mobygames.com/game/amiga/supercars-ii</mobygames_url>
				<giantbomb_url>https://www.giantbomb.com/super-cars-ii/3030-4263/</giantbomb_url>
				<boxart1>mlUQ6yO.jpg</boxart1>
				<boxart2>Cow9kph.jpg</boxart2>
				<boxart3>myzD2aW.jpg</boxart3>
				<snapshot1>lTP8VGL.png</snapshot1>
				<snapshot2>Q0RACJI.png</snapshot2>
				<snapshot3>g6CZk8w.png</snapshot3>
				<snapshot4>k4i6Dna.png</snapshot4>
				<snapshot5>Fo0xa6D.png</snapshot5>
				<snapshot6>1ukrhrB.png</snapshot6>
				<snapshot7>JvjGD96.jpg</snapshot7>
				<snapshot8>Ocr5Aug.jpg</snapshot8>
				<snapshot9>PBakFTZ.jpg</snapshot9>
				<snapshot10>jLbxrJF.jpg</snapshot10>
				<emu_command>A4000</emu_command>
			</game>
			<game name="Super Stardust (AGA)">
				<description>38.  Super Stardust</description>
				<rom name="AmigaROMsCoverArtRS/Amiga_ROMs_%26_CoverArt_R-S.zip/Super%20Stardust%2FSuper%20Stardust%20%28AGA%29.Disk1.adf" size="901120" />
				<rom name="AmigaROMsCoverArtRS/Amiga_ROMs_%26_CoverArt_R-S.zip/Super%20Stardust%2FSuper%20Stardust%20%28AGA%29.Disk2.adf" size="901120" />
				<rom name="AmigaROMsCoverArtRS/Amiga_ROMs_%26_CoverArt_R-S.zip/Super%20Stardust%2FSuper%20Stardust%20%28AGA%29.Disk3.adf" size="901120" />
				<rom name="AmigaROMsCoverArtRS/Amiga_ROMs_%26_CoverArt_R-S.zip/Super%20Stardust%2FSuper%20Stardust%20%28AGA%29.Disk4.adf" size="901120" />
				<rom name="AmigaROMsCoverArtRS/Amiga_ROMs_%26_CoverArt_R-S.zip/Super%20Stardust%2FSuper%20Stardust%20%28AGA%29.Disk5.adf" size="901120" />
				<rom name="AmigaROMsCoverArtRS/Amiga_ROMs_%26_CoverArt_R-S.zip/Super%20Stardust%2FSuper%20Stardust%20%28AGA%29.Disk6.adf" size="901120" />
				<title_clean>Super Stardust</title_clean>
				<plot>Like Stardust, in this Asteroids clone you control your Panther PX-2 ship through successive waves of asteroids and other enemies, which are drawn using ray-tracing techniques.[CR]The game features both overhead and 3D sections. In the overhead part, you must eliminate enemy ships and asteroids across several zones in each world. The 3D sections consist of underwater tunnels that link one world to another and they are each defended by a guardian you must defeat.</plot>
				<releasedate>30/10/1994</releasedate>
				<year>1994</year>
				<genre>Action</genre>
				<studio>Team17 Software Limited</studio>
				<nplayers>1</nplayers>
				<perspective>3rd-Person</perspective>
				<rating>4.5</rating>
				<mobygames_url>https://www.mobygames.com/game/amiga/super-stardust</mobygames_url>
				<giantbomb_url>https://www.giantbomb.com/super-stardust/3030-2707/</giantbomb_url>
				<boxart1>QTuoj5E.jpg</boxart1>
				<boxart2>0dXvaS5.jpg</boxart2>
				<boxart3>VQhRjNG.jpg</boxart3>
				<snapshot1>Vk4ozgE.png</snapshot1>
				<snapshot2>DExgov2.png</snapshot2>
				<snapshot3>fHdTtJj.png</snapshot3>
				<snapshot4>S1NpWf1.png</snapshot4>
				<snapshot5>glCxotK.png</snapshot5>
				<snapshot6>eIKGP9e.png</snapshot6>
				<snapshot7>9flg2HP.png</snapshot7>
				<snapshot8>orA5OwD.png</snapshot8>
				<snapshot9>h0SxnoU.png</snapshot9>
				<snapshot10>rcCbaac.png</snapshot10>
				<emu_command>A4000</emu_command>
			</game>
			<game name="Lightforce">
				<description>37.  Lightforce</description>
				<rom name="AmigaROMsCoverArtGHIJKL/Amiga_ROMs_%26_CoverArt_G-H-I-J-K-L.zip/Lightforce%2FLightforce.Disk1.adf" size="901120" />
				<rom name="AmigaROMsCoverArtGHIJKL/Amiga_ROMs_%26_CoverArt_G-H-I-J-K-L.zip/Lightforce%2FLightforce.Disk2.adf" size="901120" />
				<title_clean>Lightforce</title_clean>
				<plot>This compilation contains four games.[CR]1. Bio Challenge[CR]2. IK+[CR]3. R-Type[CR]4. Voyager</plot>
				<releasedate>30/3/1990</releasedate>
				<year>1990</year>
				<genre>Action</genre>
				<studio>Ocean Software Ltd.</studio>
				<perspective>Side-Scrolling</perspective>
				<mobygames_url>https://www.mobygames.com/game/amiga/light-force</mobygames_url>
				<giantbomb_url>https://www.giantbomb.com/light-force/3030-19827/</giantbomb_url>
				<boxart1>L8wkrlb.jpg</boxart1>
				<boxart2>Ame0qNC.jpg</boxart2>
				<boxart3>4gFtahq.jpg</boxart3>
				<boxart4>VI8USDB.jpg</boxart4>
				<boxart5>04KAVBT.jpg</boxart5>
				<boxart6>I4BGMwx.jpg</boxart6>
				<emu_command>A4000</emu_command>
			</game>
			<game name="Eye of the Beholder">
				<description>36.  Eye of the Beholder</description>
				<rom name="AmigaROMsCoverArtCDEF/Amiga_ROMs_%26_CoverArt_C-D-E-F.zip/Eye%20of%20the%20Beholder%2FEye%20of%20the%20Beholder.Disk1.adf" size="901120" />
				<rom name="AmigaROMsCoverArtCDEF/Amiga_ROMs_%26_CoverArt_C-D-E-F.zip/Eye%20of%20the%20Beholder%2FEye%20of%20the%20Beholder.Disk2.adf" size="901120" />
				<rom name="AmigaROMsCoverArtCDEF/Amiga_ROMs_%26_CoverArt_C-D-E-F.zip/Eye%20of%20the%20Beholder%2FEye%20of%20the%20Beholder.Disk3.adf" size="901120" />
				<title_clean>Eye of the Beholder</title_clean>
				<plot>[CR][B]Overview:[/B][CR]Eye of the Beholder (EotB) is the first game in the  AD&amp;D-based  Eye of the Beholder trilogy published by SSI as a part of their "Legend Series." It was developed by Westwood Associates, the same developers that would go on to become Westwood Studios, and published by SSI. It was notable at the time for its use of lush 3D graphics, extensive puzzles, and animated monster encounters along with the degree of interactivity that players had within its dungeons such as flipping levers, weighing down pressure plates with stones, and its real-time interface. The game pits a party of adventurers against the machinations of a beholder known as Xanathar: a ruthless criminal hiding deep beneath the port city of Waterdeep.[CR]The game is a licensed TSR product, and implements the  2nd Edition AD&amp;D ruleset and features the  Forgotten Realms campaign setting that had been used in previous SSI AD&amp;D games such as the Gold Box series. In the Forgotten Realms setting, Waterdeep is one of the greatest cities of the era, the so-called "Crown of the North," a vital trading hub whose wealth has seen its environs and its influence expand rapidly throughout the Sword Coast region. The secretive Lords of Waterdeep, the unseen council that both watches and protects the city from fell schemes discovered outside and within its own walls, maintain the tenuous balance of power between the factions there in order to ensure its survival. Only one of these Lords is ever shown as the "public" face in order to act as a liaison between the people and themselves.[CR]Copy protection takes the form of challenge questions that the player will occasionally be asked during the course of the game that would refer to a specific word within the game manual. Copies were encouraged in order to preserve the original disks. The console versions did not include this aspect.[CR]The manual is also notable for including a great deal of information concerning the monsters, classes, and weapons that could be encountered within the game, all adhering to the 2nd Edition AD&amp;D ruleset. Experience tables and other pieces of information are located in the back of the manual. The following manuals would be similar in design, although the monsters described would be changed from one title to the next. The manual for Eye of the Beholder also contains a rough map of Waterdeep as well as a historical primer on its significance.[CR]The game was ported to consoles in 1994, including a  SNES version by  Capcom and a  Sega CD version by  Sega. While Capcom's version is a more faithful reproduction of the original, the Sega CD version was an enhanced  remake famous for its CD soundtrack composed by  Yuzo Koshiro. Departing from the  chiptune medieval music of the the original PC version, Koshiro's Sega CD soundtrack was one of the first  ambient  electronica soundtracks.[CR][B]Story:[/B][CR]Eye of the Beholder's story begins with a meeting called by Piergeiron, the current Lord of Waterdeep, with the party. He hands them a letter describing a threat that his friend, the Archmage, Khelben "Blackstaff" Arunsun, has detected witin the city and requests that the party investigate the disturbances and, if necessary, deal with them in whatever method they see fit. They are given an official commission from the city and are quickly ushered to the sewers where they believe the threat to be located. However, their unseen nemesis has been waiting for them and the only way out is suddenly blocked by a thundering avalanche of rocks and stone, forcing the player to delve deeper below the streets of Waterdeep and to a confrontation with their foe.[CR]After a series of traps and challenges that the party encounters during the adventure, they come face to face with Xanathar, a beholder who is also acting as the major crime lord of Waterdeep who has been plotting his ascension to power. After a climactic battle in which Xanatar is defeated, the party is celebrated as heroes of the city.[CR][B]Gameplay:[/B][CR]The game uses a  grid-based, 3D system wherein the world is viewed from a first-person perspective with 90&#176; turns and movement spaces. Within the ever-present interface, a small window on the upper left quadrant of the screen displayed the world as in the first with the party listed on the right. A text box on the bottom part of the screen displays various messages while a compass is also shown when outside of combat. Random enemy encounters provide combat opportunities within the game against mixed groups of foes. Everything in the interface is mouse-driven.[CR]Party setup and character selection are left entirely up to the player and many of the mechanisms and options available would remain unchanged through the next two iterations of the series. The party would always remain limited to six characters.Races[CR]Six races are available for players to choose from and would be the first step in creating a new batch of characters. Gender has no bearing on a character's performance aside from making available the appropriate portraits during character creation. Many of the steps utilized in this part of the game would continue to act as the standard setup throughout the series.[CR]In keeping with the 2nd Edition AD&amp;D ruleset, each race has its own set of restrictions concerning both what classes are available to them such as how far they can advance in certain ones. Racial modifiers can also affect their efficiency in certain professions. Human: As in most RPGs, their statistics and abilities are fairly average across the board with no distinctive bonuses.Elf: Fair haired, fair skinned, and more agile than humans, their specialties are focused on both magic and war although they tend to do better as spellcasters. They have a bonus to dexterity and the use of bows along with long or short swords. They are highly resistant to charm or sleep spells. Dwarf: Short, gruff, and strong, they are renowned for their smithing skills as well as their combat abilities. Being a somewhat non-magical race, they have good resistances against many spells and even poisons. Halflings: Short in stature, friendly to a fault, and generally good natured, halflings are also innately resistant to spells. They're also dexterous making them decent fighters and sticky fingered rogues.Half Elves: They have no racial modifiers but are somewhat resistant to sleep and charm spells. However, because of their longer lifespans, they are able to multi-class with a greater number of combinations than other races and are decent fighters. Gnome: Good as clerics, thieves, and even fighters, they are also fairly magic resistant as their distant cousins, the dwarves, are.Classes[CR]As with many RPGs, the game offers a choice to the player to select from a variety of classes that they could use to first create their characters and, ultimately, their parties with.[CR]Throughout the entire  Eye of the Beholder series, six  classes would be made available to players to choose from, each with its own set of restrictions, although certain races have the ability to multi-class meaning that they can become a combination of classes. Each classes require certain prime requisites, or ability scores, to be at certain values before that character can become part of that class.Fighter: The consummate fighter, they can use nearly every weapon that they find. They can use magical weapons, rings, but can cast no spells. As they gain levels, they also gain speed which enables them to attack more often in combat. The prime requisite for this class is strength and any race and alignment can be a member.Paladin: These are elite fighters dedicated to smiting evil wherever it may be and will not join a party that has evil members. They are immune to disease, have increased resistances to spell effects and poison, and can heal other characters with their "laying on of hands" ability. At higher levels, they are also able to turn undead and can cast certain clerical spells. They also have a persistent aura around them that acts as a negative affect on evil creatures that come too close. Only humans with good scores in both Strength and Charisma can become this class.Thieves: A high dexterity is a prime requisite for this class and they are restricted in wearing only leather-type armor and in using a limited number of weapons. Any race can be this class and it is considered an important one to have in the game to avoid getting the party killed whenever a trap is found.Rangers: They can use any weapon as a fighter can and can even dual wield melee weapons without any penalty, but only if they are not wearing heavy armor. Humans, elves, and half-elves are the only races that are allowed in the game that can be a part of this class.Cleric: They are holy warriors that can fight with a number of weapons and wear armor while casting divine spells against their enemies. Ideal for dealing with the undead as well as healing the party. Wisdom is the prime requisite for this class and any race can be a part of it.Mages: The spellcasters of the Realm, what they lack in armor and weapons expertise are made up for in the spells that they can weave. Unlike several other RPG systems of the time that utilized spell points, mages in AD&amp;D have to memorize a set number of spells in order to store and use them at a later time. Once those memorized spells are used up, the mage must take time to memorize another batch. Intelligence is the prime requisite for this class and as they gain in level, they also gain extra slots that can be used to store memorized spells. Humans, Elves, and Half-Elves can become mages in the game.Alignment[CR]AD&amp;D along with many other PnP RPGs at the time makes extensive use of an  alignment system to determine a character's worldview and how they conduct themselves within society which would also be reflected in EotB's mechanics as well as that of its following sequels.[CR]World View:Lawful: A character will work within the lawsNeutral: A character will move between valuing a society and valuing an individual.Chaotic: A character will choose the good of the individual above that of everything else.[CR]Ethics:Good: The character tries to act in a moral and upstanding manner.Neutral: A character leans towards evaluating 'situational ethics' depending on the circumstances.Evil: A character acts without regard for others or in an overly malignant manner.[CR]For example, a Lawful Good character would be by-the-book when it came to upholding the good in society while a Chaotic Good character would be more willing to bend the rules in order to provide the same. A Lawful Evil character might hold their word as their bond and be loathe to break it for anyone, but would only give it if confronted by someone whose power they respect or as a part of one of their fell schemes. As interesting as this was, the game did not make an extensive use of the potential that this system could bring to an RPG.Attributes[CR]Character  attributes would help determine what classes were available for certain characters and how well they would perform in them. In 2nd Edition AD&amp;D, attribute scores of 18 were considered the highest possible in a natural sense, although racial bonuses and magical effects/enhancements in the form of spells or items would be able to raise them higher either temporarily or permanently in more rare cases. These are set as far as the game was concerned. Leveling improved a character's HP (hit points) and general abilities, but their base statistics would almost never change.[CR]EotB and its  following sequels would also allow the player to modify statistics during character creation with any number of changes that were limited only by the maximum level a particular attribute could be as determined by race.Strength: This determines the amount of physical damage that a character can inflict. With a strength statistic of 18, an additional variable is added to indicate exceptional strength as a percentage shown as 18/23.Constitution: A character's health and toughness is determined by this. In AD&amp;D, this has other effects outside of simply determining the HP amount gained after every level, such as a character's resistance to certain physical effects.Intelligence: A vital attribute for mages as they learn spells.Dexterity: Characters with a high dexterity tend to be nimble and agile improving their AC (armor class) which measures how hard they are to hit in combat. Important for every class, but more so with others such as fighters and thieves. With a score of 16 or higher, fighters can negate some of the penalties levied against them for using dual weapons.Charisma: This determines how attractive or repulsive a character is to everyone around them, whether it is in how they carry themselves in conversation or appear in public. Important for paladins.Wisdom: A character's innate ability to judge situations and make the best choices. It is also important in spell resistance and particularly key for clerics. Higher wisdom scores above 13 also translate into extra spells that clerics can utilize.[CR]Combat[CR]Fighting in the game is handled through random encounters wherein experience, items, and gold are earned. The front ranks, determined by the two characters at the top of the party list, can engage in melee combat. All other characters must resort to ranged weapons or spells in order to join in the fight. An onscreen menu guides their actions and right clicking with the mouse on the appropriate icon, such as a warrior's sword, would cause them to act.[CR]Camping is available for the player to rest and heal the party, memorize spells, and save the game when necessary.[CR]NPC Companions[CR]As well as creating a party of player characters, during the adventure beneath the city of Waterdeep it is possible to find other adventurers who will offer their services to help the player characters in defeating Xanathar.TOD UPHILLTod is a Halfling Thief who accidentally fell down a sewer grate in the city of Waterdeep. His bones are located at the very entrance to the sewers and can be taken to the Dwarven Cleric on Level 5 in order to be resurrected.Location - Level 1, SewersClass - ThiefAlignment - Chaotic-NeutralLEVELHPACSTRCONINTDEXCHAWIS532?171811191614ANYAAnya is a Human Fighter. Once her bones are found they can be taken to the Dwarven Cleric on Level 5 in order to be resurrected.Location - Level 3, Lower SewersClass - FighterAlignment - Chaotic-GoodLEVELHPACSTRCONINTDEXCHAWIS445?1816514911TAGHORTaghor is a Dwarven Fighter who can be found injured on Level 4 of the Upper Dwarven Ruins. If the party tends to his wounds then he will offer his services. Taghor was separated from his clan of Dwarves during a skirmish with a group of Drow Elves. He is looking to find his clan.Location - Level 4, Upper Dwarven RuinsClass - FighterAlignment - Chaotic-GoodLEVELHPACSTRCONINTDEXCHAWIS545?171911?9?DORHUMDorhum is a Dwarven Fighter. When the players first encounter the Dwarf encampment on the Level 5 Dwarven Ruins, Armun, the current Dwarf Chieftan will state that the young Dwarf Dorhum would like to travel with the party while he searches for their lost Prince, Keirgar.Location - Level 5, Dwarf EncampmentClass- FighterAlignment - Lawful-GoodLEVELHPACSTRCONINTDEXCHAWIS328?181713161411ILERIAIleria is a Half Elf Cleric. Her bones can be found on the Level 7, Reach of the Drow and taken to the Dwarven Cleric on Level 5 in order to be resurrected.Location - Level 7, Upper Reach of the DrowClass - ClericAlignment - Lawful-GoodLEVELHPACSTRCONINTDEXCHAWIS652?10171215?9BEOHRAMBeohram is a Human Paladin. He is a member of the Waterdeep City Watch who overheard rumors of Xanathar's plot and died while investigating the Lower Reach of the Drow, alone. His bones can be found immediately after a particularly deadly trap, giving hint of how he died, and if collected they can be taken back to the Dwarven Cleric on Level 5 to be resurrected.Location - Level 9, Lower Reach of the DrowClass - PaladinAlignment - Lawful-GoodLEVELHPACSTRCONINTDEXCHAWIS755?17189131715KEIRGARKeirgar is a Dwarven Fighter. He is prince of the Dwarves, recently taken prisoner during a battle with the Drow. He can be found shackled on Level 10, The Mantis Hive, just after an encounter with the Drow spy of Xanathar. After rescuing him, he will ask the party to escort him back to the Dwarven encampment. After doing so, he will offer to stay with the party in order to help them defeat Xanathar. Keirgar is part of the requirement for the Dwarves to relinquish the Wand of Silvias (an item required to defeat Xanathar).Location - Level 10, The Mantis HiveClass - FighterAlignment - Lawful GoodLEVELHPACSTRCONINTDEXCHAWIS545?181915121715TYRRATyrra is an Elven Ranger. Her bones can be found on Level 10, The Mantis Hive and returned to the Dwarven Cleric in Level 5 in order to be resurrected. After being resurrected Tyrra explains that she was escorting another group of adventurers and blames their incompetence on her death. She is reluctant to join the player character's party but offers her services nonetheless.Location - Level 10, The Mantis HiveClass - FighterAlignment - Lawful GoodLEVELHPACSTRCONINTDEXCHAWIS645?16171418716KIRATHKirath is a Half Elf Magician. His bones can be found on Level 11, Xanathar's Outer Sanctum, along with a number of powerful magic items in a heap. These can be returned to the Dwarven Cleric on Level 5 in order to be resurrected.Location - Level 11, Xanathar's Outer SanctumClass - MageAlignment - NeutralLEVELHPACSTRCONINTDEXCHAWIS721?11817181213[CR]</plot>
				<releasedate>30/3/1991</releasedate>
				<year>1991</year>
				<genre>Action, RPG</genre>
				<studio>Strategic Simulations, Inc.</studio>
				<nplayers>1</nplayers>
				<perspective>1st-Person</perspective>
				<rating>4.0</rating>
				<videoid>esb5j-yv6uw</videoid>
				<thegamesdb_id>24589</thegamesdb_id>
				<mobygames_url>https://www.mobygames.com/game/amiga/eye-of-the-beholder</mobygames_url>
				<giantbomb_url>https://www.giantbomb.com/eye-of-the-beholder/3030-11234/</giantbomb_url>
				<boxart1>VtGnX1i.jpg</boxart1>
				<boxart2>q9d6VMp.jpg</boxart2>
				<boxart3>QLmWex3.jpg</boxart3>
				<boxart4>p3w7sfm.jpg</boxart4>
				<boxart5>1uDSxFb.jpg</boxart5>
				<boxart6>7UNgVnX.jpg</boxart6>
				<boxart7>UII7ehS.jpg</boxart7>
				<boxart8>LXDDVWA.jpg</boxart8>
				<boxart9>4I6Zn4C.jpg</boxart9>
				<snapshot1>v2xQzBu.gif</snapshot1>
				<snapshot2>ayCGA4m.gif</snapshot2>
				<snapshot3>KiyJzPu.gif</snapshot3>
				<snapshot4>xCT2oDi.gif</snapshot4>
				<snapshot5>ImmZIrA.gif</snapshot5>
				<snapshot6>fBVk5Vz.gif</snapshot6>
				<snapshot7>yGc1qTf.gif</snapshot7>
				<snapshot8>4Z1DYqi.gif</snapshot8>
				<snapshot9>TSSDRvo.gif</snapshot9>
				<snapshot10>5EupEmx.gif</snapshot10>
				<emu_command>A4000</emu_command>
			</game>
			<game name="Banshee (AGA)">
				<description>35.  Banshee</description>
				<rom name="AmigaROMs_A-B/Amiga_ROMs_%26_CoverArt_A-B.zip/Banshee%2FBanshee%20%28AGA%29.Disk1.adf" size="901120" />
				<rom name="AmigaROMs_A-B/Amiga_ROMs_%26_CoverArt_A-B.zip/Banshee%2FBanshee%20%28AGA%29.Disk2.adf" size="901120" />
				<rom name="AmigaROMs_A-B/Amiga_ROMs_%26_CoverArt_A-B.zip/Banshee%2FBanshee%20%28AGA%29.Disk3.adf" size="901120" />
				<rom name="AmigaROMs_A-B/Amiga_ROMs_%26_CoverArt_A-B.zip/Banshee%2FBanshee%20%28AGA%29.Disk4.adf" size="901120" />
				<title_clean>Banshee</title_clean>
				<plot>A vertically-scrolling shoot 'em up from the old school, with similarities to games like 1942 and SWIV. There are lots of big, brash enemy vehicles to take on, plus individual soldiers (these often lie in a pool of blood afterwards, a gruesome sight making full use of AGA graphics) and civilians. Many of the enemies have good hiding places and can emerge surprisingly, Commando-style.[CR]There are four large levels, which also scroll a small amount horizontally, the idea being that you can evade some opposition. There's a special loop-the-loop type feature available, which can double as an attack or an evasive move.</plot>
				<releasedate>30/3/1994</releasedate>
				<year>1994</year>
				<genre>Action</genre>
				<studio>Core Design Ltd.</studio>
				<nplayers>1-2 Sim</nplayers>
				<perspective>Top-Down</perspective>
				<rating>4.2</rating>
				<thegamesdb_id>10165</thegamesdb_id>
				<mobygames_url>https://www.mobygames.com/game/amiga/banshee</mobygames_url>
				<giantbomb_url>https://www.giantbomb.com/banshee/3030-7970/</giantbomb_url>
				<boxart1>kW4qlDi.jpg</boxart1>
				<boxart2>AAQZbnW.jpg</boxart2>
				<boxart3>kxjUZEQ.jpg</boxart3>
				<boxart4>kxjUZEQ.jpg</boxart4>
				<snapshot1>gNDMSGj.png</snapshot1>
				<snapshot2>bA0D8c3.png</snapshot2>
				<snapshot3>dMtx5QG.png</snapshot3>
				<snapshot4>PRb1cDV.png</snapshot4>
				<snapshot5>1qae7mN.png</snapshot5>
				<snapshot6>gNDMSGj.png</snapshot6>
				<snapshot7>bA0D8c3.png</snapshot7>
				<snapshot8>dMtx5QG.png</snapshot8>
				<snapshot9>PRb1cDV.png</snapshot9>
				<snapshot10>1qae7mN.png</snapshot10>
				<clearlogo1>r1yNQrJ.png</clearlogo1>
				<emu_command>A4000</emu_command>
			</game>
			<game name="Superfrog">
				<description>34.  Superfrog</description>
				<rom name="AmigaROMsCoverArtRS/Amiga_ROMs_%26_CoverArt_R-S.zip/Superfrog%2FSuperfrog.Disk1.adf" size="901120" />
				<rom name="AmigaROMsCoverArtRS/Amiga_ROMs_%26_CoverArt_R-S.zip/Superfrog%2FSuperfrog.Disk2.adf" size="901120" />
				<rom name="AmigaROMsCoverArtRS/Amiga_ROMs_%26_CoverArt_R-S.zip/Superfrog%2FSuperfrog.Disk3.adf" size="901120" />
				<rom name="AmigaROMsCoverArtRS/Amiga_ROMs_%26_CoverArt_R-S.zip/Superfrog%2FSuperfrog.Disk4.adf" size="901120" />
				<title_clean>Superfrog</title_clean>
				<plot>[CR][B]Overview:[/B][CR]Hoped to be a rival to Mario and Sonic, Superfrog was the Amiga's very own icon. The game was a side-scrolling platformer with 24 levels across six different environments, developed by Team17 before their success with the Worms franchise.[CR]Plot &amp; Setting[CR]The game takes after typical fantasy cliches, with a prince and bride-to-be despised by an evil witch, who kidnaps the bride and transforms the prince into a (sentient, but physically normal) frog. At first hopeless, he is sitting by a river when a magic potion floats by and, upon drinking it, he is transformed into the SuperFrog of the title.The first five worlds of SuperFrog.[CR]In the first world, Enchanted Forest, SuperFrog hunts for the golden key required to unlock the witch's castle. After searching the Spooky Castle in the second world, he is "captured by Colin the Troll", caged and sent to a circus. His escape from the circus fills the third world, Fun Land, with the frog-prince leaving via a time machine he discovers. This takes him to the fourth world, Ancient Pyramid, but he is unable to reverse the time machine and freezes himself in suspended animation until the present day. He awakes in the fifth world, Ice Caverns, eventually arriving at a rocket which he uses to travel to the final world, the witch's Space Station. After travelling through the station he arrives at the witch's lair and rescues his bride.[CR]In the end cutscene, the two share a kiss once again, but instead of restoring the prince it transforms the bride into a frog as well.In-Game AdvertisingLucozade shown in detail in the intro.[CR]The drink Lucozade is what gives SuperFrog his powers, and a detailed bottle is shown during the intro sequence. Cans are also available as pickups throughout levels (providing substantial point bonuses among other effects), and the jackpot on the gambling machine requires three Lucozade cans.[CR]The game was one of the earliest to feature product placement, particularly a brand with little impact on the game (instead of games about brands, or sports games with real teams), but not the first.[CR]In a reversed scenario, adverts for SuperFrog are also present in the earlier Team17 game Alien Breed.[CR][B]Gameplay:[/B][CR]The game is similar to other platformers of the time, particularly Sonic and Mario, with large 2D levels, enemies, hidden areas, high speeds, and plenty of collectibles and pickups.[CR]The game is broken into six themed worlds of four levels each - forest, castle, circus, history, ice and space - which must be played in order (though level codes can be used to start at any particular level). Levels have time limits (explained as your superpower energy expiring, with small extensions by collecting Lucozade) and can't be exited until a certain number of coins are collected. At the end of each world, SuperFrog must fight the witch in a simple boss battle.[CR]Worlds and levels often include unique features or enemies. Water is occasionally present but (as the player is a frog) harmless and only causes a small slowdown - with the exception of water in the Ice Caverns, which is filled with frozen ice spikes, and some dripping boiling water in the Fun Land, which burns SuperFrog.Pickups &amp; Collectibles[CR]All levels include a number of coins, fruit and gems, along with rarer high-scoring items and bottles of Lucozade. All add points to the player's score, with bonuses awarded for collecting large amounts of fruit/coins/Lucozade (items in hidden areas are included in these totals). Of these, only coins are required to be collected for the level's exit to open, but the number of coins on a level is always far more than the 'toll' required. An extra life is provided at every 200,000 points scored.[CR]SuperFrog starts with a number of lives (three by default, though options also allow 1 or 5), each with five health bars. Attacks from or contact with most enemies take off one piece of health, stun SuperFrog, and knock him out of the air if jumping, but also provide a short period of invulnerability to recover. Other environmental hazards such as spikes and fire will kill Superfrog immediately regardless of health or temporary invulnerability. Although some are immortal and must be avoided, SuperFrog can kill some enemies with the Destructo-Spud pickup or by jumping on them.[CR]There are also several pickups which affect SuperFrog directly:Pills, which are used immediately when picked upRestart Pills - SuperFrog spawns at the most recently-collected Restart Pill upon death (otherwise at the level start)Speedup/slowdown pills - change the speed that SuperFrog moves for a short time, and usually placed in helpful rather than dangerous placesInvisibility - SuperFrog becomes temporarily invisible (except for his eyes, to assist the player) and invulnerable to most enemiesAbilities, which last until SuperFrog dies or the level ends. Levels usually have duplicates of each; collecting extras adds score but doesn't increase the effect.Destructo-Spud - a short-range weapon that can be thrown at some enemies or objects to destroy them. It returns automatically after being thrown, can't be killed, and can be used repeatedly.Frog Wings - allow higher jumps, limited flight, and can be used to slow falls (although the game does not include fall damage, spikes and other dangers are often hidden in pits).Frog Dolls, which award an extra life immediately.Completed Level MinigameEnd of level slot machine.[CR]At the end of each level the player is awarded credits based on the time remaining, amount of fruit collected and the number of coins collected. These can be convertered directly to points to increase the player's score, or used in a slot machine for potentially bigger or better rewards. Prizes range from 10,000-75,000 point bonuses, extra lives, or a code to skip to the just-completed level (the only way to acquire them in-game). The slot machine is fairly complex, with several ways to win - gambling winnings for higher rewards, a simpler "Hi-Lo" feature, or getting three Lucozade cans which awards the Jackpot prize of points, credits and the level code.Platform-exclusive Features[CR]The Amiga versions include a bonus level between worlds 5 and 6 (i.e. approaching the Space Station), based upon the previous Team17 game Project X, named 'Project F'. The game plays like a basic side-scrolling shoot-'em-up, with the original spaceship replaced with SuperFrog in a space helmet.[CR]The PC game is the only version that includes gambling after completing the final level, including a prize of a (non-functional) level code.Other FeaturesEnd of Game Rankings[CR]Superfrog included a rating system that awarded the player a title when they finished the game, with the rank determined by overall score (and level scores determined by time, pickups, and luck/skill at the gambling machine).Mr PloppyFrog SpawnTadpole Grade 3Tadpole Grade 2Tadpole Grade 1Rookie Frog Grade 3Rookie Frog Grade 2Rookie Frog Grade 1Frog with a PurposeFrog with a MissionChuffed FrogFrog VeteranMean Green MachineSuper Frog Grade 3Super Frog Grade 2Super Frog Grade 1Frog God[CR]The game allowed high scores to be saved to a disk for 'a permanent record of your achievement', although it recommended against using the disks that SuperFrog was played from for obvious reasons.[CR]</plot>
				<releasedate>30/3/1993</releasedate>
				<year>1993</year>
				<genre>Action</genre>
				<studio>Team17 Software Limited</studio>
				<nplayers>1</nplayers>
				<perspective>Platform</perspective>
				<rating>4.0</rating>
				<videoid>LZfX-EvDeNc</videoid>
				<thegamesdb_id>10305</thegamesdb_id>
				<mobygames_url>https://www.mobygames.com/game/amiga/superfrog</mobygames_url>
				<giantbomb_url>https://www.giantbomb.com/superfrog/3030-12022/</giantbomb_url>
				<boxart1>KhUvXmZ.jpg</boxart1>
				<boxart2>OSERk3G.jpg</boxart2>
				<boxart3>dVEYOqs.jpg</boxart3>
				<snapshot1>KxlKZDm.png</snapshot1>
				<snapshot2>1G0kujn.gif</snapshot2>
				<snapshot3>mdERMjU.gif</snapshot3>
				<snapshot4>uEBRSPZ.gif</snapshot4>
				<snapshot5>mPqIJmH.gif</snapshot5>
				<snapshot6>yn7W8Zr.gif</snapshot6>
				<snapshot7>vlMKmGT.gif</snapshot7>
				<snapshot8>y3Tl24r.gif</snapshot8>
				<snapshot9>ukoQDB6.gif</snapshot9>
				<snapshot10>tZidsMo.gif</snapshot10>
				<clearlogo1>9cs7sF7.png</clearlogo1>
				<emu_command>A4000</emu_command>
			</game>
			<game name="Indiana Jones and the Last Crusade - The Graphic Adventure">
				<description>33.  Indiana Jones and the Last Crusade</description>
				<rom name="AmigaROMsCoverArtGHIJKL/Amiga_ROMs_%26_CoverArt_G-H-I-J-K-L.zip/Indiana%20Jones%20and%20the%20Last%20Crusade%20-%20The%20Graphic%20Adventure%2FIndiana%20Jones%20and%20the%20Last%20Crusade%20-%20The%20Graphic%20Adventure.Disk1.adf" size="901120" />
				<rom name="AmigaROMsCoverArtGHIJKL/Amiga_ROMs_%26_CoverArt_G-H-I-J-K-L.zip/Indiana%20Jones%20and%20the%20Last%20Crusade%20-%20The%20Graphic%20Adventure%2FIndiana%20Jones%20and%20the%20Last%20Crusade%20-%20The%20Graphic%20Adventure.Disk2.adf" size="901120" />
				<rom name="AmigaROMsCoverArtGHIJKL/Amiga_ROMs_%26_CoverArt_G-H-I-J-K-L.zip/Indiana%20Jones%20and%20the%20Last%20Crusade%20-%20The%20Graphic%20Adventure%2FIndiana%20Jones%20and%20the%20Last%20Crusade%20-%20The%20Graphic%20Adventure.Disk3.adf" size="901120" />
				<title_clean>Indiana Jones and the Last Crusade - The Graphic Adventure</title_clean>
				<plot>It is 1938 and adventurer Indiana Jones is joined by his father on this quest, preventing Adolf Hitler from capturing the Holy Grail. He will have to deal with Nazi guards, the Luftwaffe and enemy spies as he tries to stop the tyrannical Nazi leader.[CR]The Graphic Adventure uses the same SCUMM gameplay system as the previous Maniac Mansion. Most of the screen is used for a visual rendition of the current scene. At the bottom of the screen are words, which can be clicked on using the mouse to activate their functions. For example, objects can be picked up, used, pushed or pulled, and turned on and off. Most locations are from the movie, but some further scenes are added.[CR]In keeping with Indiana's action-man persona, the game also features pure action scenes. Unlike most Lucasfilm adventures, you can die.[CR]Two PC versions of the game were released, one with 16 color EGA graphics, and one with 256 color VGA graphics.</plot>
				<releasedate>30/3/1989</releasedate>
				<year>1989</year>
				<genre>Adventure</genre>
				<studio>Lucasfilm Games LLC</studio>
				<nplayers>1</nplayers>
				<perspective>3rd-Person</perspective>
				<rating>3.9</rating>
				<videoid>qKfd4sv2xz4</videoid>
				<thegamesdb_id>18892</thegamesdb_id>
				<mobygames_url>https://www.mobygames.com/game/amiga/indiana-jones-and-the-last-crusade-the-graphic-adventure</mobygames_url>
				<giantbomb_url>https://www.giantbomb.com/indiana-jones-and-the-last-crusade-the-graphic-adv/3030-14748/</giantbomb_url>
				<boxart1>iImfxba.jpg</boxart1>
				<boxart2>yQvO7SK.jpg</boxart2>
				<boxart3>L9QZixO.jpg</boxart3>
				<boxart4>KaM1ZgR.jpg</boxart4>
				<boxart5>b4UP7HJ.jpg</boxart5>
				<boxart6>wxCQ63w.jpg</boxart6>
				<boxart7>CIKf4vY.jpg</boxart7>
				<snapshot1>Niqcrm1.png</snapshot1>
				<snapshot2>JPvYCTp.png</snapshot2>
				<snapshot3>3iSVgys.png</snapshot3>
				<snapshot4>r74V17D.png</snapshot4>
				<snapshot5>JzH6R5N.png</snapshot5>
				<snapshot6>bkTtzk8.png</snapshot6>
				<snapshot7>w3pgSrA.png</snapshot7>
				<snapshot8>XgzvNUC.png</snapshot8>
				<snapshot9>ANv6akb.png</snapshot9>
				<snapshot10>Pbn2BP5.png</snapshot10>
				<emu_command>A4000</emu_command>
			</game>
			<game name="DreamWeb">
				<description>32.  DreamWeb</description>
				<rom name="AmigaROMsCoverArtCDEF/Amiga_ROMs_%26_CoverArt_C-D-E-F.zip/DreamWeb%2FDreamWeb.Disk1.adf" size="901120" />
				<rom name="AmigaROMsCoverArtCDEF/Amiga_ROMs_%26_CoverArt_C-D-E-F.zip/DreamWeb%2FDreamWeb.Disk2.adf" size="901120" />
				<rom name="AmigaROMsCoverArtCDEF/Amiga_ROMs_%26_CoverArt_C-D-E-F.zip/DreamWeb%2FDreamWeb.Disk3.adf" size="901120" />
				<rom name="AmigaROMsCoverArtCDEF/Amiga_ROMs_%26_CoverArt_C-D-E-F.zip/DreamWeb%2FDreamWeb.Disk4.adf" size="901120" />
				<title_clean>DreamWeb</title_clean>
				<plot>[CR][B]Overview:[/B][CR]Dreamweb is a point-and-click adventure game, Cyberpunk adventure game that drew influence from the Science Fiction film, Blade Runner. Though Dreamweb was not a massive commercial success, it was noted for several things. It featured a very unique top-down view, portrayed quite brutal violence, its exceptional soundtrack by Matt Seldon that helped give the game an incredibly gritty atmosphere and most infamously; Dreamweb contained, which was incredible controversy at the time, graphical portrayal of a sex scene.[CR]In 2012, the DOS version of the game was released as freeware, it is currently available through ScummVM's website.[CR][B]Story:[/B][CR]Dreamweb takes place in an unspecified dystopian American city. The player assumes control of the protagonist Ryan, who works as a bartender and has become increasingly plagued with dreams and visions. Before the start of the game, Ryan is visited in his dreams by the Keepers of the Dreamweb; which they claim to control the balance of the world. The Master Keeper tells Ryan that Seven Evils are uniting to destroy the Dreamweb and sends Ryan on a mission to stop them. As the game begins, Ryan awakes with the words 'I know now what I must do'.[CR]One of the unique aspects of Dreamweb was the way in which the writer handles the story. There is a certain ambiguity within the story's premise that leaves the player unsure whether the Dreamweb actually exists or whether Ryan has become mentally unstable and is losing his grip on reality. It is backed up by the seven targets all being high ranking and famous, yet at the same time, unconnected people in his own city and also by a booklet that was released with the game entitled 'Diary of a Madman' which was written to provide back story on Ryan's dreams.[CR][B]Gameplay:[/B][CR]The game features a top down view which is deemed uncommon in point-and-click adventure games. This interface, despite being unique, was met with mixed reviews from critics. Another unique feature is the way in which Ryan is able to pick up almost every object in the world, though this again was met with mixed criticism as some reviewers believed it confused puzzles. Ryan also acquires a gun early on and makes frequent use of it, almost always with gory results.[CR]</plot>
				<releasedate>30/3/1995</releasedate>
				<year>1994</year>
				<genre>Adventure</genre>
				<studio>Empire Interactive Entertainment</studio>
				<nplayers>1</nplayers>
				<perspective>Top-Down</perspective>
				<rating>3.1</rating>
				<mobygames_url>https://www.mobygames.com/game/amiga/dreamweb</mobygames_url>
				<giantbomb_url>https://www.giantbomb.com/dreamweb/3030-13950/</giantbomb_url>
				<boxart1>K8fnRay.jpg</boxart1>
				<snapshot1>36I4sGC.jpg</snapshot1>
				<snapshot2>4TmP04I.jpg</snapshot2>
				<snapshot3>NTAxsLC.jpg</snapshot3>
				<snapshot4>BAhEHqz.jpg</snapshot4>
				<snapshot5>wPrrxHo.jpg</snapshot5>
				<snapshot6>9l0DCr1.jpg</snapshot6>
				<snapshot7>ziIumYM.jpg</snapshot7>
				<snapshot8>3ZsyUam.jpg</snapshot8>
				<emu_command>A4000</emu_command>
			</game>
			<game name="Frontier - Elite II">
				<description>31.  Frontier - Elite II</description>
				<rom name="AmigaROMsCoverArtCDEF/Amiga_ROMs_%26_CoverArt_C-D-E-F.zip/Frontier%20-%20Elite%20II%2FFrontier%20-%20Elite%20II.Disk1.adf" size="901120" />
				<rom name="AmigaROMsCoverArtCDEF/Amiga_ROMs_%26_CoverArt_C-D-E-F.zip/Frontier%20-%20Elite%20II%2FFrontier%20-%20Elite%20II.Disk2.adf" size="901120" />
				<title_clean>Frontier - Elite II</title_clean>
				<plot>[CR][B]Overview:[/B][CR]Frontier: Elite II was the sequel to the seminal Elite and furthered the ambition of an open ended space trading game. The sequel brought with it markedly improved physics and a realistically modelled galaxy. To augment the open-ended nature of the game the universe was procedurally generated and real sized planets despite there being little to explore on them.[CR][B]Plot:[/B][CR]Whilst no plot emerges during gameplay there is a plot present in the manual which sets the premise of the game. Fresh from victory in the Thargoid War during the original game humanity finds itself in crisis. With the Thargoids retreated to their own territory humanity has fallen into a cold war between the militaristic Federation and the slave owners of the Imperial Fleet. After a short war a tense ceasefire is in effect made worse by new anarchic systems taking advantage of the fear of military action by operating without law. You enter the world as always with 100 credits and a ship as the original protagonists grandchild, with no alliances to the factions and a chance to carve your own path in the world.[CR][B]Gameplay:[/B][CR]Changes from Elite[CR]Whilst Elite restricted you to one ship, Frontier: Elite II encouraged purchase of new ships to suit your style of play. Military vessels ranged from light fighter crafts to mammoth naval style crafts with trading crafts offering larger cargo space and mining crafts coming with specific mining lasers. Graphics are understandably improved with texture mapping and curved polygons moving the series from the simplistic wireframe style of the original.[CR] Factions[CR]The game has two primary factions which players may join. The Federation based on Earth and The Empire based in the Achenar system. Progress through both involved completing missions given at bases which allowed for promotions. The reality was that there was little gameplay difference between the two aside from the location of the base and how that would affect trade routes. The Empire was more permissive of slavery allowing for new trading opportunities whilst slavery was an arrestable offence in Federation territories. Certain ships were also designated as being independent, Federation or Empire ensuring they were out of bounds to those in an opposing faction. Finally upon joining a faction it locked off the enemies portion of space due to enemies becoming hostile upon spotting you.[CR] Control[CR]Unlike Elite, whose controls were arcade style, Frontier opted for a rigid Newtonian physics model making flight control and dogfights highly difficult. In moving momentum had to be considered as did gravitational pull. Whilst difficult this did offer emergent gameplay such as using planets to slingshot great distances (not programmed in but emergent through the physics model). This put control closer to a flight simulator than the arcades. Making gameplay approachable despite these difficulties was done in two ways. Firstly long distance travel is done by use of the hyperdrive which makes long distance travel extremely quick and day to day such as docking and navigating to positions for using the hyperdrive can be handed to the autopilot.[CR] Earning Credits[CR]The game starts you with one hundred credits and an Eagle Long Range Fighter, setting you loose on an open ended universe. As with Elite the game concerns engaging in legal or illegal trading to earn credits and advance in whatever fashion the player desires. The game revolves around finding the most profitable trading routes and running them to earn maximum credits. Trading can be done by simply purchasing from ports or by mining asteroids however the cost of a mining vessel does restrict that aspect of the game until later levels. Certain items are deemed illegal in various ports and planets (such as narcotics) with the reward of lucrative black market trading being offset by the risk of police intervention. Again though black market trading involves a certain amount of investment (life support for cargo bay to transport slaves for example) which limits it to a more advanced player. Beyond trading bounty hunting and military missions can both be highly profitable but come with inherent risks. Bounty hunting taking you into anarchic systems and to highly dangerous ships with military missions raising your rank by allying you to a faction and to a set of solar systems whilst making you unwelcome in others.[CR] Bugs[CR]Rushed for release in the UK for Christmas 1993 the game was filled with bugs. These ranged from inconsistencies between the booklet and the game (with regards to ship details) to incorrect prices paid for gems in the Cemiess system making trading there almost game-breakingly lucrative. The only bug which required a patch however was the "mining glitch" where attempting to leave equipment in a system ended in a crash. The most famous of bugs however is the wormhole bug which exploited a maths overflow in calculating hyperspace distances. In essence is the jump distance was exactly 655.36 light years the game would allow a jump regardless of ship capabilities. This was removed for the versions released after 1993 however it has made the freeware UK version the most popular. Moving away from bugs large portions of the game seemingly suffers from it's ambition by showing a lack of polish. Ships such as "The Lion" cannot handle having turrets installed as it simply fires into it's own wing and missiles being largely unable to damage crafts. Whilst minor there are instances of this lack of polish impacting strongly on gameplay as can be seen by the police AI being astonishingly poor resulting in police chases being impossible due to the police crafts crashing into each other almost instantly.[CR] Ships[CR]Interplanetary Shuttle[CR]Lifter[CR]Osprey[CR]Falcon[CR]Hawk Airfighter[CR]Kestrel Airfighter[CR]Eagle Mk. I[CR]Eagle Mk. II[CR]Eagle Mk. III[CR]Sidewinder[CR]Krait[CR]Gecko[CR]Adder[CR]Viper[CR]Cobra Mk. I[CR]Moray Starboat[CR]Cobra Mk. III[CR]Constrictor[CR]Asp Explorer[CR]Transporter[CR]Lion Transport[CR]Tiger Trader[CR]Imperial Courier[CR]Imperial Trader[CR]Python Freighter[CR]Anaconda[CR]Puma Shuttle[CR]Boa[CR]Panther Clipper[CR]Easter Eggs[CR]As with Elite there are countless Easter eggs present in Frontier: Elite II.The developers have claimed there is a black hole in the game which can be found at the center of the universe.Around the planet "industry" there is a space station called "Ridley Scott" as an tribute to the Alien franchise.As a thank you for porting Frontier to the PC adverts for Chris Sawyer's "Transport Game" can be found in space stations.The planet "Scott" has a space station called "Amundsen" after the North Pole explorers.[CR][B]Sequels:[/B][CR]The only sequel received was Frontier: First Encounters which launched for the PC in 1995 to mixed reviews due to its premature release drawing criticism of it being half finished. A proposed modern iteration named Elite 4 was planned and down as being under development on the Frontier Developments website but was never shown. On November 5th 2012 Frontier Development launched a Kickstarter to help fund development of Elite: Dangerous, a sequel in the genre and spirit of the original games for release in 2014. The project achieved it's goal and raised over &#163;1.5 million in funding.[CR]</plot>
				<releasedate>30/3/1993</releasedate>
				<year>1993</year>
				<genre>Action, Simulation</genre>
				<nplayers>1</nplayers>
				<perspective>1st-Person</perspective>
				<rating>3.5</rating>
				<videoid>RaSnKWUgRfg</videoid>
				<thegamesdb_id>10202</thegamesdb_id>
				<mobygames_url>https://www.mobygames.com/game/amiga/frontier-elite-ii</mobygames_url>
				<giantbomb_url>https://www.giantbomb.com/frontier-elite-ii/3030-16330/</giantbomb_url>
				<boxart1>6oYQ8lv.jpg</boxart1>
				<snapshot1>99O6kLl.png</snapshot1>
				<snapshot2>pISEsbv.png</snapshot2>
				<snapshot3>VyVAQEH.png</snapshot3>
				<snapshot4>cNslI73.png</snapshot4>
				<snapshot5>2itjMET.png</snapshot5>
				<snapshot6>GBPuXiD.png</snapshot6>
				<snapshot7>YxHr2aw.png</snapshot7>
				<snapshot8>aExnPPp.png</snapshot8>
				<snapshot9>KnnGxrL.png</snapshot9>
				<snapshot10>bZBKZLk.png</snapshot10>
				<clearlogo1>4IwyFFh.png</clearlogo1>
				<emu_command>A4000</emu_command>
			</game>
			<game name="It Came from the Desert">
				<description>30.  It Came from the Desert</description>
				<rom name="AmigaROMsCoverArtGHIJKL/Amiga_ROMs_%26_CoverArt_G-H-I-J-K-L.zip/It%20Came%20from%20the%20Desert%2FIt%20Came%20from%20the%20Desert.Disk1.adf" size="901120" />
				<rom name="AmigaROMsCoverArtGHIJKL/Amiga_ROMs_%26_CoverArt_G-H-I-J-K-L.zip/It%20Came%20from%20the%20Desert%2FIt%20Came%20from%20the%20Desert.Disk2.adf" size="901120" />
				<rom name="AmigaROMsCoverArtGHIJKL/Amiga_ROMs_%26_CoverArt_G-H-I-J-K-L.zip/It%20Came%20from%20the%20Desert%2FIt%20Came%20from%20the%20Desert.Disk3.adf" size="901120" />
				<title_clean>It Came from the Desert</title_clean>
				<plot>[CR][B]Overview:[/B][CR]It Came From The Desert is an adventure/strategy game developed by Cinemaware and released in 1989 for the Amiga and later ported to various other platforms. Set in June of 1951, the game follows Greg Bradley, a geologist living in the remote town of Lizard Breath in the United States. After a meteorite falls in the outskirts of town, a large army of mutant-ants begin appearing across town and the player is the only one who can stop it.[CR][B]Gameplay:[/B][CR] Ants![CR]It Came From The Desert is a non-linear adventure game with elements of strategy, action and horror. The game is successful in creating a haunting atmosphere, where the player won't know what will happen next. There are multiple ways to play the game with many different endings, both good and bad. Each scene can branch off into an entirely different story path, depending on the player's actions and thus multiple playthroughs are required to see everything the game has to offer.[CR]The player moves from location via an overworld map, each trip taking a certain amount of time depending on the distance. The game plays out in real-time, with each second equating a minute in-game. In certain situations, the game allows the player to travel across the town of Lizard Breath in a top-down perspective, from flying planes to access the ant army or even driving a tank. The game features day/night cycles, with some locations and story triggers only available at certain parts of the day. For example, a player can choose to meet a reporter who will require him to be at the town's quarry at 10 AM, failure to arrive at the specified date will effectively end that sidestory. This requires the player to keep track of all their tasks, as no in-game journal exists.[CR]When the player encounters an ant, the game enters a first-person perspective shootout, where the player must shoot off the ant's antennae. This mode is very intense, and there is little room for error, as the player's gun has a limited amount of ammo and only several seconds to react. If the player is incapacitated, they will end up in the hospital. There are several other ways to end up in the hospital, from crashing their car, exposure to smoke, or sexual exhaustion (yep). The player can choose to accept treatment, which can be from one day to several, or escape. The player can attempt to escape the hospital by making their way down to the ground level, which involves a top-down mini-game where the player must use stealth, such as hiding in beds or in rooms as well as using wheelchairs to outrun doctors, nurses and guards. If the player is caught, they are strapped down and they have no choice but to accept recovery, losing precious days of gametime. Lizard's Breath is a lonely place.[CR]Throughout the game, the town will progressively succumb to the ant invasion if the player fails to act against the ants. Ants will start to appear throughout town, buildings will be deserted and some of the townsfolk will begin to transform into mutant ants. The player has just 15 days to repel the ant invasion. In order to do so, the player must first find sufficient evidence to convince the Mayor of the threat. The player can find clues from townsfolk, such as liquid trails or tissue samples. One piece of evidence requires the player to fly a cropduster with a built in sound recorder over the ants and record their sounds. The player can also get evidence from Ants themselves if they successfully disable them, but this is far riskier. When the player finds evidence, he must take it to the town's University Lab, where it can take several days to compile results. If the player has more than one sample of evidence, this time is significantly reduced.[CR]When enough evidence is found and the Mayor is convinced of the threat, the player is put in charge of mobilizing a defense at the town's police department. This brings up the Situation Map, where the player can allocate the army, police, construction and townsfolk to the town's various locations to aid in fending off the ants. Each unit has a special trait: Army units will deploy tanks to battle ants and construction workers can repair buildings destroyed by the ants. The Situation Map must be checked frequently to find out where ants are coming from, so the player can move units to that location. The player can also take the fight to the ants themselves, which can be far more effective and less resource-intense, but can still be far riskier. In order to drive them off, the player must first defeat an initial ant in a shootout then defeat ants in the area using grenades. When the army has been drawn back, the player must find the location of the ant's nest, enter and plant a bomb and escape, destroying the source of the ant army and saving Lizard Breath.[CR]Genesis version[CR]A version of It Came from the Desert was produced for the Genesis/Mega Drive but scrapped due to a game-breaking glitch. In 2014, Cinemaware announced that it was working with retro developer Watermelon to fix the glitch and finally release the Genesis version on cartridge.[CR]</plot>
				<releasedate>30/3/1989</releasedate>
				<year>1990</year>
				<genre>Action, Adventure</genre>
				<studio>Cinemaware Corporation</studio>
				<nplayers>1</nplayers>
				<perspective>1st-Person</perspective>
				<rating>4.0</rating>
				<thegamesdb_id>9492</thegamesdb_id>
				<mobygames_url>https://www.mobygames.com/game/amiga/it-came-from-the-desert</mobygames_url>
				<giantbomb_url>https://www.giantbomb.com/it-came-from-the-desert/3030-4180/</giantbomb_url>
				<boxart1>C37BQQO.jpg</boxart1>
				<boxart2>WEcs7Ig.jpg</boxart2>
				<boxart3>bZhCHUe.jpg</boxart3>
				<boxart4>ffyMUhg.jpg</boxart4>
				<snapshot1>Gt01k45.gif</snapshot1>
				<snapshot2>Ir6M2n9.gif</snapshot2>
				<snapshot3>bV9fSOt.gif</snapshot3>
				<snapshot4>Ldf6xzU.gif</snapshot4>
				<snapshot5>c9Moyql.gif</snapshot5>
				<snapshot6>d48KNRT.gif</snapshot6>
				<snapshot7>oDTRhUT.gif</snapshot7>
				<snapshot8>InYHoqP.gif</snapshot8>
				<snapshot9>kQuKtA1.gif</snapshot9>
				<snapshot10>JTAMS4B.gif</snapshot10>
				<clearlogo1>aBKmIe0.png</clearlogo1>
				<emu_command>A4000</emu_command>
			</game>
			<game name="Championship Manager '93">
				<description>29.  Championship Manager '93</description>
				<rom name="AmigaROMsCoverArtCDEF/Amiga_ROMs_%26_CoverArt_C-D-E-F.zip/Championship%20Manager%20%2793%2FChampionship%20Manager%20%2793.Disk1.adf" size="901120" />
				<rom name="AmigaROMsCoverArtCDEF/Amiga_ROMs_%26_CoverArt_C-D-E-F.zip/Championship%20Manager%20%2793%2FChampionship%20Manager%20%2793.Disk2.adf" size="901120" />
				<rom name="AmigaROMsCoverArtCDEF/Amiga_ROMs_%26_CoverArt_C-D-E-F.zip/Championship%20Manager%20%2793%2FChampionship%20Manager%20%2793.Disk3.adf" size="901120" />
				<title_clean>Championship Manager '93</title_clean>
				<plot>[CR]The videogame series responsible for more poor European college grades than any other got serious for the first time in Championship Manager '93.Outside of the Eastenders reject greasily pointing at you from the front cover,  '93 represented the series' most comprehensive title yet, combining much-needed improvements to the commentary system with the inaugural inclusion of real-world player data. The result was an English football simulation the likes of which had never been seen, with the expanded commentary managing to recreate that Saturday feeling with aplomb. The key ingredients were in place for the first time and Championship Manager took off from here.93/94 was an add-on disk that updated stats to reflect the end of season transfers, offering up precious little in the way of gameplay alterations and a couple of extra background images. Nevertheless, it was considered an essential purchase by fans at the time, kickstarting a yearly release tradition that follows the series to this day.[CR]</plot>
				<releasedate>17/9/1993</releasedate>
				<year>1993</year>
				<studio>Domark Software, Inc.</studio>
				<nplayers>1-4 Sim</nplayers>
				<thegamesdb_id>30523</thegamesdb_id>
				<mobygames_url>https://www.mobygames.com/game/amiga/championship-manager-9394</mobygames_url>
				<giantbomb_url>https://www.giantbomb.com/championship-manager-93/3030-16216/</giantbomb_url>
				<boxart1>a2s8BvT.png</boxart1>
				<boxart2>HjOJ7zz.jpg</boxart2>
				<boxart3>GvGr8uQ.jpg</boxart3>
				<snapshot1>aTps1dP.png</snapshot1>
				<snapshot2>PZiCc8a.png</snapshot2>
				<snapshot3>MuSeyrh.png</snapshot3>
				<snapshot4>u8VcK3c.png</snapshot4>
				<snapshot5>oiFR6XJ.png</snapshot5>
				<snapshot6>UT38tai.png</snapshot6>
				<snapshot7>hzZeTbn.png</snapshot7>
				<snapshot8>xlR21xG.png</snapshot8>
				<snapshot9>itWv73B.png</snapshot9>
				<snapshot10>Sjd87Vy.png</snapshot10>
				<emu_command>A4000</emu_command>
			</game>
			<game name="Beneath a Steel Sky">
				<description>28.  Beneath a Steel Sky</description>
				<rom name="AmigaROMs_A-B/Amiga_ROMs_%26_CoverArt_A-B.zip/Beneath%20a%20Steel%20Sky%2FBeneath%20a%20Steel%20Sky.Disk1.adf" size="901120" />
				<rom name="AmigaROMs_A-B/Amiga_ROMs_%26_CoverArt_A-B.zip/Beneath%20a%20Steel%20Sky%2FBeneath%20a%20Steel%20Sky.Disk2.adf" size="901120" />
				<rom name="AmigaROMs_A-B/Amiga_ROMs_%26_CoverArt_A-B.zip/Beneath%20a%20Steel%20Sky%2FBeneath%20a%20Steel%20Sky.Disk3.adf" size="901120" />
				<rom name="AmigaROMs_A-B/Amiga_ROMs_%26_CoverArt_A-B.zip/Beneath%20a%20Steel%20Sky%2FBeneath%20a%20Steel%20Sky.Disk4.adf" size="901120" />
				<rom name="AmigaROMs_A-B/Amiga_ROMs_%26_CoverArt_A-B.zip/Beneath%20a%20Steel%20Sky%2FBeneath%20a%20Steel%20Sky.Disk5.adf" size="901120" />
				<rom name="AmigaROMs_A-B/Amiga_ROMs_%26_CoverArt_A-B.zip/Beneath%20a%20Steel%20Sky%2FBeneath%20a%20Steel%20Sky.Disk6.adf" size="901120" />
				<rom name="AmigaROMs_A-B/Amiga_ROMs_%26_CoverArt_A-B.zip/Beneath%20a%20Steel%20Sky%2FBeneath%20a%20Steel%20Sky.Disk7.adf" size="901120" />
				<rom name="AmigaROMs_A-B/Amiga_ROMs_%26_CoverArt_A-B.zip/Beneath%20a%20Steel%20Sky%2FBeneath%20a%20Steel%20Sky.Disk8.adf" size="901120" />
				<rom name="AmigaROMs_A-B/Amiga_ROMs_%26_CoverArt_A-B.zip/Beneath%20a%20Steel%20Sky%2FBeneath%20a%20Steel%20Sky.Disk9.adf" size="901120" />
				<rom name="AmigaROMs_A-B/Amiga_ROMs_%26_CoverArt_A-B.zip/Beneath%20a%20Steel%20Sky%2FBeneath%20a%20Steel%20Sky.Disk10.adf" size="901120" />
				<rom name="AmigaROMs_A-B/Amiga_ROMs_%26_CoverArt_A-B.zip/Beneath%20a%20Steel%20Sky%2FBeneath%20a%20Steel%20Sky.Disk11.adf" size="901120" />
				<rom name="AmigaROMs_A-B/Amiga_ROMs_%26_CoverArt_A-B.zip/Beneath%20a%20Steel%20Sky%2FBeneath%20a%20Steel%20Sky.Disk12.adf" size="901120" />
				<rom name="AmigaROMs_A-B/Amiga_ROMs_%26_CoverArt_A-B.zip/Beneath%20a%20Steel%20Sky%2FBeneath%20a%20Steel%20Sky.Disk13.adf" size="901120" />
				<rom name="AmigaROMs_A-B/Amiga_ROMs_%26_CoverArt_A-B.zip/Beneath%20a%20Steel%20Sky%2FBeneath%20a%20Steel%20Sky.Disk14.adf" size="901120" />
				<rom name="AmigaROMs_A-B/Amiga_ROMs_%26_CoverArt_A-B.zip/Beneath%20a%20Steel%20Sky%2FBeneath%20a%20Steel%20Sky.Disk15.adf" size="901120" />
				<title_clean>Beneath a Steel Sky</title_clean>
				<plot>[CR][B]Overview:[/B][CR]Beneath a Steel Sky is a 1994 point-and-click adventure game developed by Revolution Software Ltd. and originally published by Virgin Interactive. It was a creative collaboration between Charles Cecil, a game designer who would later create the concept for the Broken Sword franchise, and Dave Gibbons, an acclaimed comic book artist best known for illustrating the seminal superhero graphic novel Watchmen. The game stars protagonist Robert Foster, a tribal survivalist and technological prodigy who was orphaned and raised in a post-World-War-III Australian Outback, and his sarcastic robotic companion Joey. The setting and concepts of Beneath a Steel Sky address concerns about heavily-urbanized society and the threats posed by humanity's over-reliance on technology, consumer capitalism, and government surveillance. Beneath a Steel Sky's introductory sequence was packed-in as a comic book with certain editions of the game.[CR][B]Gameplay:[/B][CR]As a traditional  point-and-click adventure game, Beneath a Steel Sky's gameplay is similar to LucasArts adventure games of the era, primarily consisting of navigating dialogue trees and solving inventory-based puzzles. However, there are certain sequences in which the protagonist may be killed or receive a "bad" ending, requiring players to load a saved game in order to continue. Players choose Foster's responses during conversations and may question NPCs about events related to the story and its characters, as well as Foster's own personal background. Foster's robotic pal Joey is also present throughout most of the game, providing color commentary and playing a key role in solving certain puzzles. The CD-ROM release of Beneath a Steel Sky includes full voice acting for all character dialogue.[CR]The game's world is largely non-linear and players must explore their surroundings thoroughly for key items and clues about their next destination. At one point in the game, the player gains access to an abstract cyberspace world that must be navigated to make progress.[CR][B]Story:[/B][CR]Beneath a Steel Sky is set in a future dystopic version of Australia where players assume the role of a plucky tribal-turned-fugitive named Robert Foster. As a young boy, Robert was the sole survivor of a helicopter crash that killed his mother and left him orphaned before being discovered by a tribe of scavengers, who raised Robert as one of their own in "The Gap", an area comprised of the modern-day Australian Outback. His adoptive tribe only knew Robert by his first name, but they eventually gave him his new surname of "Foster" in reference to an empty can of Foster's Lager found near his transport's crash site. Foster learns basic survival skills under the tribe's guidance and demonstrates an incredible affinity for engineering and electronics, which he uses to construct "Joey": an AI companion stored on a small circuit board that can be swapped between robotic shells.[CR]One night, the tribe elder prophecies about a terrible evil emanating from deep beneath Union City and headed for their tribe's makeshift village. A heavily-armed helicopter suddenly arrives in The Gap and summarily attacks Foster's defenseless tribe before landing to deploy a team of soldiers from Union City. Joey's chassis is also severely damaged during the attack, forcing Foster to eject and store Joey's main circuit board for safekeeping. The soldiers begin searching specifically for Foster, claiming to want to return him to his original home. When the team's Commander Reich threatens to massacre Robert's entire village unless he is found, Foster turns himself over to Reich's custody; however, as they depart The Gap, Reich's team detonates a large explosive that obliterates the scavengers' settlement as Foster watches in horror. Restrained by Reich's guards, a grieving Foster can only bide his time and wait for an opportunity to escape and exact his vengeance.[CR]While en route to Union City central command, the helicopter's pilot loses navigational control, forcing the transport down somewhere among the cityscape's dizzying skyscrapers. After crash-landing onto an elevated city street, Foster makes a narrow escape from Reich's soldiers and finds a new robotic chassis for Joey, but Reich soon corners Foster near an industrial furnace and calls him by the unfamiliar name "Overmann". When Reich threatens Foster with a pistol, he is instantly disarmed and killed by a security turret embedded in a nearby wall.[CR]Using Reich's ID card, Foster begins investigating the reasons behind his capture and the connection to the helicopter crash that left him an orphan. He quickly finds Union City to be an urban dystopia; the sprawling metropolis is completely controlled by a centralized computer known as LINC and a legion of secret police, as well as a nightmarish justice system mired in bureaucracy. Although offering modern comforts such as advanced medical technology and automated labor, Union City's government does not recognize basic human rights for many of its citizens, with harsh distinctions between the upper and lower classes. Citizens that have been stripped of any privileges due to inappropriate behavior are known as "D-LINCs", and are subject to terrible working conditions and restricted movement inside the city with little hope for a reprieve.[CR]Foster also meets Anita, a D-LINC citizen and resistance sympathizer working in a pipe factory. She informs Foster of a plan devised by agents of nearby Hobart City to disable the rampant growth of LINC's biological components with a virus. Unfortunately, Anita is killed before she can deploy the virus; Foster later discovers a message file left for him by Anita, imploring him to complete her mission. Foster eventually obtains the virus in LINC-SPACE and, after discovering a large complex of tunnels deep beneath the city, infects LINC's systems with the virus. Joey also gains an advanced android shell inside the complex, remarking on how vulnerable he feels in his new humanoid form. However, before Foster can reach LINC's core control interface, he is confronted by a pair of deadly security androids which he barely manages to dispatch with Joey's assistance.[CR]Foster and Joey finally reach LINC's core only to discover Foster's father, Dr. Richard Overmann, physically integrated into the computer by a mass of organic tendrils. Richard explains how he became the project leader responsible for developing and constructing LINC twenty years ago, willingly fusing himself with the system in order to achieve the perfect union of man and machine. However, LINC soon grew beyond Overmann's control; it murdered the remainder of Union City's administrative council and established itself as the city's supreme ruler. Robert's mother Maria fled from Union City with her child after she realized the threat posed by LINC's absolute power. Union City security forces learned of Maria's plans to return to her original home in Hobart City and sabotaged her transport, causing the fateful crash that led to Robert's upbringing in The Gap.[CR]LINC now requires a new biologically-compatible human to interface with, as Overmann is near death; this was the reason Foster was forcibly brought to Union City at the beginning of the game, as well as why Reich was killed after threatening Foster. A regretful Overmann dies in Foster's arms, claiming that Robert was the only reason he clung to life for twenty long years. In order to save Foster from a lifetime of torment as LINC's new host, Joey uses his new humanoid robotic shell to interface with LINC instead, thus providing an ideal synthetic host for LINC and restoring Union City's basic administrative functions. As the citizens begin to relearn their city's computer system and take responsibility for their own lives again, a grateful Foster and Joey say their goodbyes before Foster returns to The Gap to seek out his next adventure.[CR]Re-releases &amp; Remake[CR]Animated introductory sequence added for Beneath a Steel Sky: Remastered[CR]Beneath a Steel Sky is currently available for download from the ScummVM homepage or from GoG.com. The game also came free with the Broken Sword trilogy box set released in the United Kingdom on 14 December 2007.[CR]Released on 23 September 2009 for the price of $2.99, Beneath a Steel Sky: Remastered is an updated port of the original game for the iPhone and iPod Touch. The game remains almost entirely the same, except for improved sound and voice acting, all new animated sequences (which are drawn by the game's original artist, Dave Gibbons), and a help system that the player can take advantage of at any time. Naturally, the game supports touch control, allowing players to slide their fingers over objects to see whether or not it is interactive.[CR][B]Trivia:[/B][CR]One of the lockers in the security building has the name "Lovecraft" on it, in reference to early 20th century horror writer  H. P. Lovecraft.[CR]System Requirements (PC)[CR]MinimumOS : Windows XP / Vista / 7 / 8 / 10Processor : 1 GHz processorMemory : 256 MB RAMGraphics : 3D graphics card compatible with DirectX 9.0cHard Drive : 80 MB availableRecommendedOS : Windows XP / Vista / 7 / 8 / 10Processor : 1.4 GHz processorMemory : 512 MB RAMGraphics : 3D graphics card compatible with DirectX 9.0cHard Drive : 80 MB available[CR]System Requirements (Mac)[CR]MinimumOS : OS X 10.6.8 or newerProcessor : Intel Core Duo 2GHz+Memory : 1 GB RAMGraphics : Video card with at least 64 MB VRAMHard Drive : 80 MB available space[CR]System Requirements (Linux)[CR]MinimumOS :Ubuntu 14.04 / Mint 17Processor : 1 GHz processorMemory : 256 MB RAMGraphics : 3D graphics card with at least 128 MB VRAMHard Drive : 80 MB available spaceRecommendedOS : Ubuntu 14.04 / Mint 17Processor : 1.4 GHz processorMemory : 512 MB RAMGraphics : 3D graphics card with at least 128 MB VRAMHard Drive : 80 MB available space[CR]</plot>
				<releasedate>30/3/1994</releasedate>
				<year>1994</year>
				<genre>Adventure</genre>
				<studio>Virgin Interactive Entertainment (Europe) Ltd.</studio>
				<nplayers>1</nplayers>
				<perspective>3rd-Person</perspective>
				<rating>3.4</rating>
				<thegamesdb_id>10170</thegamesdb_id>
				<mobygames_url>https://www.mobygames.com/game/amiga/beneath-a-steel-sky</mobygames_url>
				<giantbomb_url>https://www.giantbomb.com/beneath-a-steel-sky/3030-10915/</giantbomb_url>
				<boxart1>qzU920D.jpg</boxart1>
				<boxart2>GUXdRql.jpg</boxart2>
				<boxart3>puyBmaT.jpg</boxart3>
				<boxart4>bl9iF6L.jpg</boxart4>
				<boxart5>puyBmaT.jpg</boxart5>
				<boxart6>bl9iF6L.jpg</boxart6>
				<snapshot1>Ihyff8H.jpg</snapshot1>
				<snapshot2>ElpdHzh.png</snapshot2>
				<snapshot3>YNatZJY.png</snapshot3>
				<snapshot4>mmLpgcC.png</snapshot4>
				<snapshot5>tPnyHOo.png</snapshot5>
				<snapshot6>BUEdREp.png</snapshot6>
				<snapshot7>B1xPxth.png</snapshot7>
				<snapshot8>OoRMhza.png</snapshot8>
				<snapshot9>v7mTRS0.png</snapshot9>
				<snapshot10>CLwgENV.png</snapshot10>
				<fanart1>9ntCiTe.jpg</fanart1>
				<clearlogo1>fRfU2GV.png</clearlogo1>
				<emu_command>A4000</emu_command>
			</game>
			<game name="Roadkill (AGA)">
				<description>27.  Roadkill</description>
				<rom name="AmigaROMsCoverArtRS/Amiga_ROMs_%26_CoverArt_R-S.zip/Roadkill%20%28AGA%29%2FRoadkill%20%28AGA%29.Disk1.adf" size="901120" />
				<rom name="AmigaROMsCoverArtRS/Amiga_ROMs_%26_CoverArt_R-S.zip/Roadkill%20%28AGA%29%2FRoadkill%20%28AGA%29.Disk2.adf" size="901120" />
				<rom name="AmigaROMsCoverArtRS/Amiga_ROMs_%26_CoverArt_R-S.zip/Roadkill%20%28AGA%29%2FRoadkill%20%28AGA%29.Disk3.adf" size="901120" />
				<title_clean>Roadkill</title_clean>
				<plot>Set in the future, Roadkill is a racing game featuring all manner of gruesome additions. There are 9 computer opponents in each race, and you must finish in the top 3 every time. Rockets and homing missiles can be collected so as to shoot the rival cars out. The tracks feature inbuilt hazards and treacherous shortcuts[CR]Money is a big factor in all of this - the higher you finish in a race, the more you get; it can be collected during the race; each car you destroy gives you more money than the previous one, as you go for the Jackpot and then the Super Jackpot.</plot>
				<releasedate>30/3/1994</releasedate>
				<year>1994</year>
				<genre>Action, Driving, Racing</genre>
				<studio>Acid Software</studio>
				<nplayers>1</nplayers>
				<perspective>Top-Down</perspective>
				<rating>4.4</rating>
				<thegamesdb_id>10317</thegamesdb_id>
				<mobygames_url>https://www.mobygames.com/game/amiga/roadkill-</mobygames_url>
				<giantbomb_url>https://www.giantbomb.com/roadkill/3030-37415/</giantbomb_url>
				<boxart1>QZOeJ4P.jpg</boxart1>
				<boxart2>iSdNbw2.jpg</boxart2>
				<snapshot1>h7El5rO.png</snapshot1>
				<clearlogo1>tU2FApi.png</clearlogo1>
				<emu_command>A4000</emu_command>
			</game>
			<game name="Lemmings 2 - The Tribes">
				<description>26.  Lemmings 2 - The Tribes</description>
				<rom name="AmigaROMsCoverArtGHIJKL/Amiga_ROMs_%26_CoverArt_G-H-I-J-K-L.zip/Lemmings%202%20-%20The%20Tribes%2FLemmings%202%20-%20The%20Tribes.Disk1.adf" size="901120" />
				<rom name="AmigaROMsCoverArtGHIJKL/Amiga_ROMs_%26_CoverArt_G-H-I-J-K-L.zip/Lemmings%202%20-%20The%20Tribes%2FLemmings%202%20-%20The%20Tribes.Disk2.adf" size="901120" />
				<rom name="AmigaROMsCoverArtGHIJKL/Amiga_ROMs_%26_CoverArt_G-H-I-J-K-L.zip/Lemmings%202%20-%20The%20Tribes%2FLemmings%202%20-%20The%20Tribes.Disk3.adf" size="901120" />
				<title_clean>Lemmings 2 - The Tribes</title_clean>
				<plot>[CR][B]Overview:[/B][CR]Lemmings 2: Tribes is the sequel to DMA Design's earlier puzzle hit Lemmings and takes its name from the 12 tribes of lemmings that inhabit the island on which the game takes place. The island is divided into twelve regions, one for each tribe. Some tribes differ in color, but all are controlled in the same way. Some abilities are specific to certain tribes, while others are reused several times.[CR]The land of each tribe has its own visual style and music, and some unique challenges.[CR]Psygnosis published the game in the US and Europe. SunSoft would produce the Japanese console versions, as they had with Lemmings.[CR][B]Gameplay:[/B][CR]Land of the Lemmings[CR]The game features 120 levels split equally between the 12 tribes. When the 10 levels of any tribe are complete, a segment of a talisman is awarded. When all 12 pieces of talisman are united, the island of the lemmings will be saved.[CR]Over 50 types of lemming are featured in Tribes, compared to just 8 of the original game.[CR]Each Tribe starts with 60 lemmings. In a significant departure from other Lemmings games, rather than have a 'fresh set' of lemmings for each level and a target number to save, only one lemming has to reach the exit to pass the level. However, only lemmings that survived could proceed to the next level, which might lead to the player having insufficient lemmings to complete a particular stage, requiring earlier levels to be replayed. Gold, silver and Bronze are awarded for each level, gold being required to unlock a finishing animated video.[CR][B]Gameplay:[/B] additions not related to the lemmings themselves include hazards and challenges specific to each environment, and the interface features an additional 'fan' icon, which allows drifting lemmings to be blown along.[CR]Levels are generally more interactive with elements such as rope swings, catapults and trampolines.[CR][B]Levels:[/B][CR]The Tribes of Lemmings 2:Polar bea... err LemmingA day at the beachPolarHighlandCircusClassicOutdoorEgyptianBeachMedievalSportsShadowPrehistoric (aka Cavelem)SpaceThe Lemmings of the Twelve TribesArcherAttractorBalloonerBasher*BazookaBlocker*Bomber*BooterBuilder*Climber*Club BasherDigger*DiverExploderFencerFillerFlamethrowerFloater*Glue PourerHang GliderHopperIcarus WingsJetpackJumperKayakerLaser BlasterMagic CarpetMiner*MortarParachuterPlanterPlatformerPole-vaulterRock ClimberRollerRoperRunnerSand PourerScooperShimmierSkaterSkierSliderSpearerStackerStomperSuper LemmingSurferSwimmerThrowerTwisterWalker[CR]*returning from the original Lemmings. When playing the Classic tribe area, lemmings are limited to these original 8 types.[CR][B]Trivia:[/B][CR]In a piece of cross-promotion, one of the hazards featured in the game is a robot that also featured in the Developers other title of the same year, Walker.[CR]When an Attractor Lemming is used to make lemmings dance, lemmings perform a different style of dance depending on their tribe.[CR]</plot>
				<releasedate>30/3/1993</releasedate>
				<year>1993</year>
				<genre>Strategy</genre>
				<studio>Psygnosis Limited</studio>
				<nplayers>1</nplayers>
				<perspective>3rd-Person</perspective>
				<rating>3.5</rating>
				<mobygames_url>https://www.mobygames.com/game/amiga/lemmings-2-the-tribes</mobygames_url>
				<giantbomb_url>https://www.giantbomb.com/lemmings-2-the-tribes/3030-18818/</giantbomb_url>
				<boxart1>eYzpTuY.jpg</boxart1>
				<boxart2>jPzRNIy.jpg</boxart2>
				<boxart3>KfrwQJB.jpg</boxart3>
				<boxart4>IxNLhLD.jpg</boxart4>
				<boxart5>PdImiCc.jpg</boxart5>
				<snapshot1>OnA3yR5.gif</snapshot1>
				<snapshot2>MHTIOq7.gif</snapshot2>
				<snapshot3>G0OgfZ4.gif</snapshot3>
				<snapshot4>oG87EMC.gif</snapshot4>
				<snapshot5>4GnKm1N.gif</snapshot5>
				<snapshot6>y7nN8BF.gif</snapshot6>
				<snapshot7>GHSuUbz.gif</snapshot7>
				<snapshot8>8dlnRCF.png</snapshot8>
				<snapshot9>xYwUQcl.png</snapshot9>
				<snapshot10>NFHDluC.png</snapshot10>
				<emu_command>A4000</emu_command>
			</game>
			<game name="Indiana Jones and the Fate of Atlantis - The Graphic Adventure">
				<description>25.  Indiana Jones and the Fate of Atlantis</description>
				<rom name="AmigaROMsCoverArtGHIJKL/Amiga_ROMs_%26_CoverArt_G-H-I-J-K-L.zip/Indiana%20Jones%20and%20the%20Fate%20of%20Atlantis%20-%20The%20Graphic%20Adventure%2FIndiana%20Jones%20and%20the%20Fate%20of%20Atlantis%20-%20The%20Graphic%20Adventure.Disk1.adf" size="901120" />
				<rom name="AmigaROMsCoverArtGHIJKL/Amiga_ROMs_%26_CoverArt_G-H-I-J-K-L.zip/Indiana%20Jones%20and%20the%20Fate%20of%20Atlantis%20-%20The%20Graphic%20Adventure%2FIndiana%20Jones%20and%20the%20Fate%20of%20Atlantis%20-%20The%20Graphic%20Adventure.Disk2.adf" size="901120" />
				<rom name="AmigaROMsCoverArtGHIJKL/Amiga_ROMs_%26_CoverArt_G-H-I-J-K-L.zip/Indiana%20Jones%20and%20the%20Fate%20of%20Atlantis%20-%20The%20Graphic%20Adventure%2FIndiana%20Jones%20and%20the%20Fate%20of%20Atlantis%20-%20The%20Graphic%20Adventure.Disk3.adf" size="901120" />
				<rom name="AmigaROMsCoverArtGHIJKL/Amiga_ROMs_%26_CoverArt_G-H-I-J-K-L.zip/Indiana%20Jones%20and%20the%20Fate%20of%20Atlantis%20-%20The%20Graphic%20Adventure%2FIndiana%20Jones%20and%20the%20Fate%20of%20Atlantis%20-%20The%20Graphic%20Adventure.Disk4.adf" size="901120" />
				<rom name="AmigaROMsCoverArtGHIJKL/Amiga_ROMs_%26_CoverArt_G-H-I-J-K-L.zip/Indiana%20Jones%20and%20the%20Fate%20of%20Atlantis%20-%20The%20Graphic%20Adventure%2FIndiana%20Jones%20and%20the%20Fate%20of%20Atlantis%20-%20The%20Graphic%20Adventure.Disk5.adf" size="901120" />
				<rom name="AmigaROMsCoverArtGHIJKL/Amiga_ROMs_%26_CoverArt_G-H-I-J-K-L.zip/Indiana%20Jones%20and%20the%20Fate%20of%20Atlantis%20-%20The%20Graphic%20Adventure%2FIndiana%20Jones%20and%20the%20Fate%20of%20Atlantis%20-%20The%20Graphic%20Adventure.Disk6.adf" size="901120" />
				<rom name="AmigaROMsCoverArtGHIJKL/Amiga_ROMs_%26_CoverArt_G-H-I-J-K-L.zip/Indiana%20Jones%20and%20the%20Fate%20of%20Atlantis%20-%20The%20Graphic%20Adventure%2FIndiana%20Jones%20and%20the%20Fate%20of%20Atlantis%20-%20The%20Graphic%20Adventure.Disk7.adf" size="901120" />
				<rom name="AmigaROMsCoverArtGHIJKL/Amiga_ROMs_%26_CoverArt_G-H-I-J-K-L.zip/Indiana%20Jones%20and%20the%20Fate%20of%20Atlantis%20-%20The%20Graphic%20Adventure%2FIndiana%20Jones%20and%20the%20Fate%20of%20Atlantis%20-%20The%20Graphic%20Adventure.Disk8.adf" size="901120" />
				<rom name="AmigaROMsCoverArtGHIJKL/Amiga_ROMs_%26_CoverArt_G-H-I-J-K-L.zip/Indiana%20Jones%20and%20the%20Fate%20of%20Atlantis%20-%20The%20Graphic%20Adventure%2FIndiana%20Jones%20and%20the%20Fate%20of%20Atlantis%20-%20The%20Graphic%20Adventure.Disk9.adf" size="901120" />
				<rom name="AmigaROMsCoverArtGHIJKL/Amiga_ROMs_%26_CoverArt_G-H-I-J-K-L.zip/Indiana%20Jones%20and%20the%20Fate%20of%20Atlantis%20-%20The%20Graphic%20Adventure%2FIndiana%20Jones%20and%20the%20Fate%20of%20Atlantis%20-%20The%20Graphic%20Adventure.Disk10.adf" size="901120" />
				<rom name="AmigaROMsCoverArtGHIJKL/Amiga_ROMs_%26_CoverArt_G-H-I-J-K-L.zip/Indiana%20Jones%20and%20the%20Fate%20of%20Atlantis%20-%20The%20Graphic%20Adventure%2FIndiana%20Jones%20and%20the%20Fate%20of%20Atlantis%20-%20The%20Graphic%20Adventure.Disk11.adf" size="901120" />
				<title_clean>Indiana Jones and the Fate of Atlantis - The Graphic Adventure</title_clean>
				<plot>[CR][B]Overview:[/B][CR]The game's title screen.[CR]Indiana Jones and the Fate of Atlantis is a point-and-click adventure game that was released by LucasArts in 1992.[CR]Set during the years leading up to World War II, players take the role of Indiana Jones as he is caught in a race to find Atlantis before the Nazis can harvest the power of orichalcum, a legendary and powerful metal.[CR]A significant aspect to the game is the different routes in which a player can take to complete the game. This marks the first time multiple paths were featured in a LucasArts adventure game. The three different routes each involve different gameplay and different endings.[CR]This game was an unlockable game mode in the 2009 Wii game Indiana Jones and the Staff of Kings. The game can be played on modern PCs using ScummVM.[CR]A sequel was in the works, but it was cancelled and the story was reworked into two separate comics published by Dark Horse.[CR][B]Story:[/B][CR]The interior of Barnett College.[CR]Indiana Jones is asked to retrieve a strange idol from Barnett College, where he teaches. The man who asked Indy to find the artifact turns out to be Klaus Kerner, a Nazi agent. Klaus steals the idol and draws Indy into an adventure to uncover what it is the Nazis are after.[CR]In his search, Indy teams up with Sophia Hapgood, an old colleague who is also a target of Kerner because of the necklace she wears: an artifact that will help them uncover the final resting place of Atlantis. It is after meeting with Sophia that Indy learns of what the Nazis want with Atlantis and the power they would obtain if they were ever to get hold of a mineral called orichalcum.[CR]Another key to finding Atlantis, Indy learns, is in the legendary Lost Dialogue, a book of disputed existence by Plato. The story continues to unfold depending on which path the player chooses to take.[CR][B]Gameplay:[/B][CR]The general gameplay is set out like a traditional point and click adventure game. There are many puzzles, but the game also includes optional combat. In many situations a problem can be solved using puzzle solving, but sometimes the player can optionally solve a dispute with a fist fight.Paths[CR]The game includes three distinct paths that the player can take. Each path includes different objects that the player can interact with, locations, and dialogue. The three paths are:Wits: A path with many puzzle solving elements.Fists: Fewer problems but with more fighting scenes.Team: The path that relies more heavily on Sophia Hapgood in some of the puzzles.Indy Quotient[CR]As the player progresses they are rewarded with Indy Quotient (IQ) points. To receive the maximum 1,000 points the player will have to play through every path and see every alternative ending. In order to achieve this, the player must play through the game a minimum of three times.[CR]Steam Re-Release[CR]In 2009, Lucasarts re-released the game for the price of $4.99 on Steam.[CR]</plot>
				<releasedate>30/3/1992</releasedate>
				<year>1992</year>
				<genre>Adventure</genre>
				<studio>Lucasfilm Games LLC</studio>
				<nplayers>1</nplayers>
				<perspective>3rd-Person</perspective>
				<rating>3.3</rating>
				<thegamesdb_id>9491</thegamesdb_id>
				<mobygames_url>https://www.mobygames.com/game/amiga/indiana-jones-and-the-fate-of-atlantis</mobygames_url>
				<giantbomb_url>https://www.giantbomb.com/indiana-jones-and-the-fate-of-atlantis/3030-3633/</giantbomb_url>
				<boxart1>B8eJRl9.jpg</boxart1>
				<boxart2>TXuMNPn.jpg</boxart2>
				<boxart3>awrGvab.jpg</boxart3>
				<boxart4>JXqFxQq.jpg</boxart4>
				<boxart5>LuZ6ZJW.jpg</boxart5>
				<boxart6>gYXG0H3.jpg</boxart6>
				<boxart7>RdGYaPl.jpg</boxart7>
				<snapshot1>TvfwCkf.gif</snapshot1>
				<snapshot2>HsQgNOZ.gif</snapshot2>
				<snapshot3>AuSz0AJ.gif</snapshot3>
				<snapshot4>ofyIbfg.gif</snapshot4>
				<snapshot5>psh0Nvj.png</snapshot5>
				<snapshot6>E1Ksmk9.png</snapshot6>
				<snapshot7>SiRfmaX.png</snapshot7>
				<snapshot8>lF7I1kj.png</snapshot8>
				<snapshot9>r5oUVHG.png</snapshot9>
				<snapshot10>eb9XarU.png</snapshot10>
				<fanart1>AGUoc5J.jpg</fanart1>
				<clearlogo1>FuO5CkC.png</clearlogo1>
				<emu_command>A4000</emu_command>
			</game>
			<game name="Chaos Engine, The">
				<description>24.  The Chaos Engine</description>
				<rom name="AmigaROMsCoverArtCDEF/Amiga_ROMs_%26_CoverArt_C-D-E-F.zip/Chaos%20Engine%2C%20The%2FChaos%20Engine%2C%20The.Disk1.adf" size="901120" />
				<rom name="AmigaROMsCoverArtCDEF/Amiga_ROMs_%26_CoverArt_C-D-E-F.zip/Chaos%20Engine%2C%20The%2FChaos%20Engine%2C%20The.Disk2.adf" size="901120" />
				<title_clean>Chaos Engine, The</title_clean>
				<plot>At the end of The Chaos Engine you managed to put a stop to Baron Fortesque's out of control machine, only to free the Baron himself from its clutches. Unfortunately not everything went to plan after that. During the confusion the Baron snuck away back into his own contraption and into another time period. Our two heroes decide the only way to stop him is follow him, but unfortunately luck isn't on their side...[CR]Both players (either two human or one human and one computer controlled) are trapped within the Chaos Engine and can only escape by helping the Baron rebuild the engine. He will reward the character who helps him the most by granting him freedom, thus pitching our two heroes against each other.[CR]Whereas The Chaos Engine was a two-player co-operative game, The Chaos Engine 2 is a two-player competitive game!</plot>
				<releasedate>30/3/1996</releasedate>
				<year>1996</year>
				<genre>Action</genre>
				<studio>Renegade Software</studio>
				<nplayers>1-2 Sim</nplayers>
				<perspective>Top-Down</perspective>
				<rating>3.7</rating>
				<thegamesdb_id>10181</thegamesdb_id>
				<mobygames_url>https://www.mobygames.com/game/amiga/chaos-engine-2</mobygames_url>
				<giantbomb_url>https://www.giantbomb.com/the-chaos-engine-2/3030-19058/</giantbomb_url>
				<boxart1>FkNQpvt.jpg</boxart1>
				<boxart2>3GpRtBX.jpg</boxart2>
				<snapshot1>MEFxbD5.png</snapshot1>
				<snapshot2>R7W5ZJE.png</snapshot2>
				<snapshot3>ZfPpeYB.png</snapshot3>
				<snapshot4>CmUwc6Q.png</snapshot4>
				<snapshot5>oximcze.png</snapshot5>
				<snapshot6>AjcIlye.png</snapshot6>
				<snapshot7>E3dMa6f.png</snapshot7>
				<snapshot8>hUSoF5V.png</snapshot8>
				<snapshot9>kGyG9QT.png</snapshot9>
				<clearlogo1>zDxnkXh.png</clearlogo1>
				<emu_command>A4000</emu_command>
			</game>
			<game name="Worms - The Director's Cut (AGA)">
				<description>23.  Worms - The Director's Cut</description>
				<rom name="AmigaROMsCoverArtTUVWXYZ/Amiga_ROMs_%26_CoverArt_T-U-V-W-X-Y-Z.zip/Worms%20-%20The%20Director%27s%20Cut%2FWorms%20-%20The%20Director%27s%20Cut%20%28AGA%29.Disk1.adf" size="901120" />
				<rom name="AmigaROMsCoverArtTUVWXYZ/Amiga_ROMs_%26_CoverArt_T-U-V-W-X-Y-Z.zip/Worms%20-%20The%20Director%27s%20Cut%2FWorms%20-%20The%20Director%27s%20Cut%20%28AGA%29.Disk2.adf" size="901120" />
				<rom name="AmigaROMsCoverArtTUVWXYZ/Amiga_ROMs_%26_CoverArt_T-U-V-W-X-Y-Z.zip/Worms%20-%20The%20Director%27s%20Cut%2FWorms%20-%20The%20Director%27s%20Cut%20%28AGA%29.Disk3.adf" size="901120" />
				<title_clean>Worms - The Director's Cut</title_clean>
				<plot>[CR][B]Overview:[/B][CR]Released in 1997 exclusively for Amiga AGA systems (A1200 and A4000), Worms: The Director's Cut (also known as Worms: DC) is a heavily modified version of Andy Davidson's turn-based strategic artillery game Worms, which was first put forth by developer Team17 and publisher Ocean Software in 1995. Like its forebear, it is a two-dimensional game in which a player-controlled team of worms uses a large arsenal of weapons in order to attack and defeat other teams of worms controlled either by humans or A.I. Design and programming of The Director's Cut was largely attributed to Davidson himself, and the focus on AGA systems allowed for a broader depth of colors than the initial Amiga version (sixteen colors rather than eight) as well as nine-layer parallax. Davidson also reportedly pushed for a CD32 version as well in order to offer enhanced sound, though this version never materialized. In addition to cosmetic upgrades, The Director's Cut features a number of new gameplay features, including fifteen new weapons, cavern maps with enclosed ceilings, and a Graffiti mode where players can "paint" custom maps.[CR]Development[CR]According to creator Andy Davidson, the goal for Worms: The Director's Cut was not only to make it "the best version of Worms available on any platform," but also "the best Amiga game ever." Since a proper sequel to Worms, Worms 2, was being developed concurrently by a separate team, Davidson was given carte blanche to create his ideal version of the original Worms. Many of the ideas generated for The Director's Cut would later be incorporated into Worms 2, and Davidson himself referred to it as something of a testbed for the sequel, though Team17 co-founder Martyn Brown stated that the development teams for Worms 2 and The Director's Cut "were quite separate" and did not really have "shared design goals." The Director's Cut would end up being one of the last Worms titles that Davidson would exert significant creative influence over before leaving Team17 in the late '90s; as Brown recounted in 2009, Davidson had "quite a bit of input into the sequel, Worms 2, but much less so in Armageddon."[CR][B]Gameplay:[/B][CR]See also: Worms[CR]The fundamental gameplay of Worms is not significantly overhauled with the release of The Director's Cut, however a number of new mechanics and weapons are introduced, many of which are carried forward into subsequent titles. In addition to the normal forward jump, for instance, worms are given the ability to perform a more vertical backwards hop. Certain weapons can now be placed while on a Ninja Rope or Bungee, and the Ninja Rope is further modified to allow for multiple swings without touching the ground (also known as Tarzaning). Cavern levels that severely restrict the effectiveness of certain weapon types are added into the mix with the normal "Open" levels, and a new Graffiti mode allows players the means to quickly create custom maps in-game. Fifteen new weapons are also added to the original complement, and many of them, including the Holy Hand Grenade and the Concrete Donkey, would go on to become staples of the series.[CR]New Weapons[CR]The Director's Cut includes nearly forty weapons and utilities in total, although more than half of these are carried over from the previous game. Only two previously-introduced weapons did not make the cut: the Prod of Worms and the Mole Bomb of Worms: Reinforcements. Most of the new weapons in The Director's Cut are considered "super weapons," and as a result they must be collected from weapon crates rather than being immediately granted to the player. Three "secret weapons" are among the new additions also; these armaments do not show up on the weapon panel by default, and are more rare in crates than other super weapons.Grenade LauncherGrenade LauncherDamage: Up to 30 HP per impactHotkey: F2 (3x)Unlike most propelled or thrown weapons in Worms, the Grenade Launcher does not give the player control over the strength of its release. Instead, it is always launched at full strength in whatever direction it is pointed when fired. Its payload explodes as soon as it touches a solid object, releasing a cluster of bomb fragments that also explode upon touching the ground. It can be somewhat challenging to ensure that these bombs fall in a predictable way, so deploying it against groups of worms is often preferable to individual worms.HandgunHandgunDamage: 5 HP per bulletHotkey: F3 (3x)The only addition to the firearm category in The Director's Cut, the Handgun is also, without a doubt, the least powerful weapon in its class. When a worm takes aim with the Handgun and fires upon a target, three bullets are released, each capable of dealing five hit points of damage. With the absence of the Prod in Worms: DC, the Handgun is most likely intended to take its place as a humiliation weapon. Even the manual admits that it is "not much use," suggesting it instead as a satisfying way of finishing off particularly troublesome worms.Petrol BombPetrol BombDamage: 15 HP per flameHotkey: F6 (2x)The Petrol Bomb is tossed just like a Grenade, and similarly is not affected by wind. From there, however, its similarities to other thrown weapons diminishes, as it explodes immediately upon impact with the ground and unleashes several gouts of flame that spread out horizontally from its impact point. These flames cause damage to any worm they come into contact with, which can be compounded depending on the level of exposure. It is perhaps most effective when used against multiple worms or worms in confined areas.Homing PigeonHoming PigeonDamage: Up to 75 HPHotkey: 6Essentially a Homing Missile with a brain (albeit a small one), the Homing Pigeon is mindful of its surroundings in a way that the Homing Missile is not. Once released, it will endeavor to seek out its preselected target while also avoiding terrain obstructions along the way. The bird's intelligence does have its limits, and furthermore it requires a small period to activate after being fired, so misfires are possible, but overall it is much easier to deploy successfully than a Homing Missile, and it causes a greater amount of damage as well.Mad CowsMad CowsDamage: Up to 75 HP per cowHotkey: 6 (2x)The first Worms weapon that can be released in herds, the Mad Cow armament consists of a number of ambulatory bovine bombs that explode with the power of Dynamite. Once unleashed, one or more Mad Cows will run forward and explode immediately upon encountering any obstruction. The exact number of Cows released by the player is adjustable, and depending on the player's current stock, between one and five can be sent out at once. Mad Cow weapon crates typically yield three, so a single crate can result in up to three uses.Holy Hand GrenadeHoly Hand GrenadeDamage: Up to 100 HPHotkey: 7Making the first of many appearances within the Worms franchise, the Holy Hand Grenade of The Director's Cut operates much like later iterations of the weapon, being thrown in the same manner as other Grenade-class weapons. Unlike its contemporaries, however, the Holy Hand Grenade (or HHG) is far more powerful, powerful enough to kill an uninjured worm, in fact. It does not possess a player-adjusted timer, but rather explodes three seconds after it comes to rest on the ground. Compared to other explosives, its radius is quite large.Baseball BatBaseball BatDamage: 30 HPHotkey: 8 (2x)The only new melee weapon introduced in Worms: DC, the Baseball Bat is used at close range to both damage a worm and send them flying. By aiming the targeting crosshair up or down the player is able to affect the trajectory in which the opposing worms is propelled. Aiming further toward the ground will send the worm a greater distance, while aiming upward will send them higher into the air. Since the weapon's base damage is not that spectacular in and of itself, the Baseball Bat is more commonly used to knock worms into the water.Super SheepSuper SheepDamage: Up to 75 HPHotkey: 9Being a remarkable specimen within the ovine genus, the Super Sheep is possessed of an ability that others of its kind can only dream of, that being the ability to take flight. Upon pressing the fire button once, the Super Sheep is set loose, and appears to be nothing more than a normal Sheep. When the fire button is pressed again, the fluffy beast shoots straight up into the air where his movements can be directly steered by the player. It is up to this player to direct the fast-moving Sheep missile into enemy worms, where it explodes.Sheep-on-a-RopeSheep-on-a-RopeDamage: Up to 75 HPHotkey: 9 (2x)A combination of the Sheep weapon and the Ninja Rope, the Sheep-on-a-Rope is a regular-strength Sheep that can be navigated around the environment in much the same way that worms can navigate while using the Ninja Rope. This includes the ability to swing, detach, and reattach before touching the ground. If at any time the Sheep touches the ground without being attached to the rope, it explodes. In Worms: DC's secret Monkey Mode, it is replaced with Kenny-p&#229;-ett-Rep (Kenny-on-a-Rope), which is functionally identical.Sheep StrikeSheep StrikeDamage: Up to 50 HP per impactHotkey: 9 (3x)Threatening to do in players in with "mutton from the skies," the Sheep Strike is a version of the Air Strike in which missiles have been replaced with volatile bouncing Sheep. Five Sheep in total are dropped over the targeted area, and each one explodes upon contact with the ground. The threat does not end there, though, as each one will then bound into the air and crash into the landscape a second time, causing another explosion. Each individual explosion is weaker than other Sheep weapons, but when combined they are devastating.Old LadyOld LadyDamage: Up to 75 HPHotkey: 0Possessed of innate combustible properties, the confused Old Lady is a powerful weapon not altogether unlike a walking stick of Dynamite. She is not so much launched as she is set loose to hobble bemusedly along the landscape in search of something only she is aware of. After about ten seconds of ambling and incoherent muttering, the Old Lady explodes, causing considerable damage to any worms nearby. Since the Old Lady cannot be manually detonated by the player, she requires a certain amount of prediction on the player's part.Priceless Ming VasePriceless Ming VaseDamage: Up to 75 HP (initial), up to 50 HP (fragments)Hotkey: 0 (2x)Proving that they have no regard even for fine art, worms have been known to utilize a Priceless Ming Vase or two as weapons of war. It is used, like Dynamite, by dropping it at the desired location, and it allows its user five seconds to retreat before it detonates. The initial explosion causes a great deal of injury, but also sends several shards into the atmosphere that explode upon hitting the ground, causing additional damage. Large gatherings of worms are natural targets for the Ming Vase, as are enclosed ares that can focus its payload.Postal StrikePostal StrikeDamage: Up to 50 HP per impactHotkey: 0 (3x)Invoking the Postal Strike releases a number of deadly letter bombs over a specified zone that drift lethargically to the ground. These epistolary explosives have somewhat larger damage potential than a normal Air Strike, though there is one major caveat: they are heavily affected by wind. This forces players to either use the Postal Strike in calm conditions or attempt to gauge the wind's effect on the weapon's payload in order to adjust its target area appropriately. Despite the extra consideration required, when used well it is very powerful.Nuclear BombNuclear BombDamage: NoneHotkey: 0 (4x)Though it causes no actual damage when activated, the Nuclear Bomb can nonetheless be one of the deadliest weapons in Worms: DC. Setting off a Nuke causes the entire level to sink (or the water level to rise, depending on how you look at it); while this causes no damage in and of itself, any worms near the waterline will be consumed and killed by whatever deadly substance resides at the bottom of that particular stage. This weapon is indiscriminate in who it kills, so it is best used when one's own worms are situated on higher ground.Concrete DonkeyConcrete DonkeyDamage: Up to 100 HP per impactHotkey: 0 (5x)The Concrete Donkey represents the ultimate in lethal force, and as such it is one of the rarest and most coveted weapons in the game. Calling down the Concrete Donkey causes the aforementioned garden ornament to fall vertically through the level at a point chosen by the player. Each time it makes contact with solid ground, it causes an explosion equal in strength to the Holy Hand Grenade, and it proceeds in this fashion until it has reached the bottom of the map. Worms targeted by the Concrete Donkey are very unlikely to survive.[CR][B]Reception:[/B][CR]The critical response to Worms: The Director's Cut from the Amiga gaming press was very positive, with Amiga Format and CU Amiga both giving the game a score within the ninetieth percentile. While these reviews acknowledged that the game was essentially an update to Worms rather than an entirely new game, a fact which even prompted Amiga Format to publish a second review score of 45% specifically for those that already own Worms, the cosmetic enhancements, new weapons, and gameplay tweaks were all seen as welcome additions. In spite of these recommendations, Worms: DC reportedly sold only 5,000 copies in total.[CR]</plot>
				<releasedate>30/3/1997</releasedate>
				<year>1997</year>
				<genre>Strategy</genre>
				<studio>Ocean Software Ltd.</studio>
				<perspective>Side-Scrolling</perspective>
				<rating>4.6</rating>
				<mobygames_url>https://www.mobygames.com/game/amiga/worms-the-directors-cut</mobygames_url>
				<giantbomb_url>https://www.giantbomb.com/worms-the-directors-cut/3030-18826/</giantbomb_url>
				<boxart1>tnyeASJ.jpg</boxart1>
				<boxart2>iXzR4vw.jpg</boxart2>
				<boxart3>LyhAyWl.jpg</boxart3>
				<boxart4>YGtrr0D.jpg</boxart4>
				<snapshot1>0MDvXR3.png</snapshot1>
				<snapshot2>9bSNpu4.png</snapshot2>
				<snapshot3>RmbNIdH.png</snapshot3>
				<snapshot4>idztM0h.png</snapshot4>
				<snapshot5>suzckCv.png</snapshot5>
				<snapshot6>FgNRbYn.png</snapshot6>
				<snapshot7>bSrcJKf.png</snapshot7>
				<snapshot8>ZZYoz6x.png</snapshot8>
				<snapshot9>tX6i9GA.png</snapshot9>
				<snapshot10>X829PML.png</snapshot10>
				<emu_command>A4000</emu_command>
			</game>
			<game name="Ruff 'n' Tumble">
				<description>22.  Ruff 'n' Tumble</description>
				<rom name="AmigaROMsCoverArtRS/Amiga_ROMs_%26_CoverArt_R-S.zip/Ruff%20%27n%27%20Tumble%2FRuff%20%27n%27%20Tumble.Disk1.adf" size="901120" />
				<rom name="AmigaROMsCoverArtRS/Amiga_ROMs_%26_CoverArt_R-S.zip/Ruff%20%27n%27%20Tumble%2FRuff%20%27n%27%20Tumble.Disk2.adf" size="901120" />
				<title_clean>Ruff 'n' Tumble</title_clean>
				<plot>Ruff Rogers has lost his marbles - in the literal sense of the small round balls used to play a game on drains. He's been armed with a gun to retrieve them from 16 levels of side-scrolling platform shooting.[CR]The gun you start with isn't especially powerful, but various machine guns and flamethrowers can be collected, which make much lighter work of the enemies. Your character can jump and duck responsively, and fire at all angles.[CR]There are 3 different colours of marbles, which a quota to recover from each level. Collecting enough of each particular colour sees all similar ones turned to coins, which can go towards extra lives and points bonuses. Switches are built into the levels; these act as restart points.</plot>
				<releasedate>30/3/1994</releasedate>
				<year>1994</year>
				<genre>Action</genre>
				<studio>Renegade Software</studio>
				<nplayers>1</nplayers>
				<perspective>Platform</perspective>
				<rating>4.4</rating>
				<mobygames_url>https://www.mobygames.com/game/amiga/ruff-n-tumble</mobygames_url>
				<giantbomb_url>https://www.giantbomb.com/ruff-n-tumble/3030-7496/</giantbomb_url>
				<boxart1>ZQ44gQS.jpg</boxart1>
				<boxart2>82A4o23.jpg</boxart2>
				<boxart3>wymBshH.jpg</boxart3>
				<snapshot1>Wsb4cE3.png</snapshot1>
				<snapshot2>CyyUXs0.png</snapshot2>
				<snapshot3>GOwQqKq.png</snapshot3>
				<snapshot4>HBMXld6.png</snapshot4>
				<snapshot5>EM5KlkT.png</snapshot5>
				<snapshot6>OYQH26T.png</snapshot6>
				<snapshot7>oRASAm2.png</snapshot7>
				<snapshot8>YpJUfU6.png</snapshot8>
				<snapshot9>a3pk42g.png</snapshot9>
				<snapshot10>id5GmPt.png</snapshot10>
				<emu_command>A4000</emu_command>
			</game>
			<game name="Colonization">
				<description>21.  Colonization</description>
				<rom name="AmigaROMsCoverArtCDEF/Amiga_ROMs_%26_CoverArt_C-D-E-F.zip/Colonization%2FColonization.Disk1.adf" size="901120" />
				<rom name="AmigaROMsCoverArtCDEF/Amiga_ROMs_%26_CoverArt_C-D-E-F.zip/Colonization%2FColonization.Disk2.adf" size="901120" />
				<rom name="AmigaROMsCoverArtCDEF/Amiga_ROMs_%26_CoverArt_C-D-E-F.zip/Colonization%2FColonization.Disk3.adf" size="901120" />
				<rom name="AmigaROMsCoverArtCDEF/Amiga_ROMs_%26_CoverArt_C-D-E-F.zip/Colonization%2FColonization.Disk4.adf" size="901120" />
				<title_clean>Colonization</title_clean>
				<plot>Sid Meier's Colonization is a strategy game which puts you in the role of Viceroy of the New World. You are sent by your King and country to establish colonies in the newly-discovered Americas that lie to the west. You face many of the same challenges that faced colonial organizers of the time-competition[CR]from other Old World powers, strange native cultures, the problems of establishing profitable trade programs, and the problems of organizing an army from a rag-tag band of colonists.[CR]The game begins with the European discovery of the Americas (1500) and continues until approximately the time of the American[CR]Revolution (1800). In the beginning of the game you are given a trading/exploration ship and a small group of colonists. You have no knowledge of what lies ahead of your ship, so you must explore until you find a suitable spot to lay down your first colony. As your[CR]colonies grow larger and larger, you inevitably encounter native populations and are confronted with competing imperial powers from the Old World.[CR]Each of your colonies is populated by a number of colonists, who you can assign to various tasks. Some chop wood, mine for ore and collect plants outside the colony, some others stay inside to turn those raw materials into more valuable cargo - such as rum (made from sugar), coats (made of furs) or hammers (made of lumber). Hammers which aren't a cargo you can sell, but represent the speed with which you construct new buildings in your colony. Some colonists are specialists, and thus are more effective at a certain job. [CR]The cargo you collect and produce is an important thing. You can take it to Europe to sell, and earn money to buy some other necessary things, hire colonists (though new, willing colonists appear in Europe by themselves) or buy ships and artillery. You can also trade it with the Indians or colonies of other nations. [CR]You'll construct various buildings in your colonies. They have a lot of different functions: some of them can improve the speed with which you produce valuable cargo, others allow you to defend yourself from attacks more easily or construct ships and artillery. Some buildings require you to spend a number of valuable Tools when constructed, though you can make new Tools out of ore. [CR]As you explore the land, you'll come across the Indian villages and some "places of interest" which can be investigated. A colonist that enters an Indian village can be welcomed with open hands, and the natives will reveal a map of nearby lands, or teach him a profession. Investigating places of interest has various consequences: sometimes you'll find nothing, sometimes you'll be killed for trespassing on ancient burial ground, but sometimes you'll find treasure! (Taking this treasure to Europe can be difficult though - if you don't have a sufficiently big ship, the King will agree to transport it for you... if you give him 50% of the gold). [CR]To defend yourself from enemies, you'll want to have some military units. Just give a colonist a musket and he'll turn into a Soldier, give him a horse, and he's a Scout or a Dragoon. However, such a warrior is typically inexperienced, though he might gain military experience in battle. Artillery is also good at defense, but don't try to leave your colonies with it - in the open field, it is useless. [CR]As you progress in the game, you'll feel that working for the King is getting more and more annoying, especially since he keeps raising your taxes, thus decreasing your income from sold goods. Your colonies produce "Liberty Bells", which increase rebel sentiment in the colonies. If the majority of colonists supports your yearning for freedom, you can declare independence. But when you do that, you'll have to deal with the King's expeditionary force arriving to teach you a lesson. If you manage to defeat all his incoming armies and emerge victorious from the American Revolutionary War, you've won!</plot>
				<releasedate>31/5/1995</releasedate>
				<year>1995</year>
				<genre>Simulation, Strategy</genre>
				<studio>MicroProse Software, Inc.</studio>
				<nplayers>1</nplayers>
				<perspective>Top-Down</perspective>
				<rating>3.7</rating>
				<mobygames_url>https://www.mobygames.com/game/amiga/sid-meiers-colonization</mobygames_url>
				<giantbomb_url>https://www.giantbomb.com/sid-meiers-colonization/3030-8876/</giantbomb_url>
				<boxart1>jE53EMF.jpg</boxart1>
				<boxart2>60JWiNy.jpg</boxart2>
				<boxart3>j7iL0F2.jpg</boxart3>
				<boxart4>qAHQbDj.jpg</boxart4>
				<snapshot1>ILuj1ER.png</snapshot1>
				<snapshot2>Na7PIQ6.png</snapshot2>
				<snapshot3>m2GdpAn.png</snapshot3>
				<snapshot4>WKCeim9.png</snapshot4>
				<snapshot5>HJgGd7C.png</snapshot5>
				<snapshot6>Vy8dEww.png</snapshot6>
				<snapshot7>GdwkkmK.png</snapshot7>
				<snapshot8>EU66JcX.png</snapshot8>
				<snapshot9>oTqDYAJ.png</snapshot9>
				<snapshot10>ugt4G5p.png</snapshot10>
				<emu_command>A4000</emu_command>
			</game>
			<game name="Eye of the Beholder II - The Legend of Darkmoon">
				<description>20.  Eye of the Beholder II - The Legend of Darkmoon</description>
				<rom name="AmigaROMsCoverArtCDEF/Amiga_ROMs_%26_CoverArt_C-D-E-F.zip/Eye%20of%20the%20Beholder%20II%20-%20The%20Legend%20of%20Darkmoon%2FEye%20of%20the%20Beholder%20II%20-%20The%20Legend%20of%20Darkmoon.Disk1.adf" size="901120" />
				<rom name="AmigaROMsCoverArtCDEF/Amiga_ROMs_%26_CoverArt_C-D-E-F.zip/Eye%20of%20the%20Beholder%20II%20-%20The%20Legend%20of%20Darkmoon%2FEye%20of%20the%20Beholder%20II%20-%20The%20Legend%20of%20Darkmoon.Disk2.adf" size="901120" />
				<rom name="AmigaROMsCoverArtCDEF/Amiga_ROMs_%26_CoverArt_C-D-E-F.zip/Eye%20of%20the%20Beholder%20II%20-%20The%20Legend%20of%20Darkmoon%2FEye%20of%20the%20Beholder%20II%20-%20The%20Legend%20of%20Darkmoon.Disk3.adf" size="901120" />
				<rom name="AmigaROMsCoverArtCDEF/Amiga_ROMs_%26_CoverArt_C-D-E-F.zip/Eye%20of%20the%20Beholder%20II%20-%20The%20Legend%20of%20Darkmoon%2FEye%20of%20the%20Beholder%20II%20-%20The%20Legend%20of%20Darkmoon.Disk4.adf" size="901120" />
				<title_clean>Eye of the Beholder II - The Legend of Darkmoon</title_clean>
				<plot>[CR][B]Story:[/B][CR]The sequel to  Eye of the Beholder takes place shortly after the success of the heroes from the first game, presumably the player's party, over the beholder, Xanathar, which had saved the city.[CR]However, frequent reports of missing travelers on the outskirts of Waterdeep have begun to filter into the hands of the Lords of Waterdeep and once again, the City's greatest Archmage, Khelben "Blackstaff" Arunsun, calls upon the party to investigate the matter. Villagers are disappearing and the city guard are wary of wandering too far into the woods to the north and west for fear of what might be waiting for the overly curious. With the discovery of several shallow graves and the journal of a self-styled archeologist hinting at even darker mysteries, the party has little to go on until they discover Temple Darkmoon. There, amidst three towers, they must uncover its mysteries and destroy the evil lurking within.[CR][B]Overview:[/B][CR]Eye of the Beholder II (EotB II) was the second game in the AD&amp;D based  Eye of the Beholder trilogy published by  SSI as a part of their "Legend Series". It would the last title developed for SSI by  Westwood Associates, the same developers that would go on to become Westwood Studios. As with its predecessor, it was notable at the time for its use of lush 3D graphics, extensive puzzles, and animated monster encounters along with the degree of interactivity that players had within its dungeons, but would include a variety of improvements such as deeper role-playing experience and a larger area to explore.[CR]The objective of the game was to explore the mysterious Temple of Darkmoon on the request of the archmage, Khelben "Blackstaff" Arunsun. It soon becomes clear that there is far more to the Temple than previously suspected and the party will need to unravel its secrets in order to survive.[CR]The game was a licensed product of TSR's  2nd Edition AD&amp;D rules and used the  Forgotten Realms campaign setting as did the previous games.[CR]Copy protection took the form of a verification question accompanied by an illustration. Matching the illustration with the correct one in the manual would produce the correct answer. Copies were also encouraged in order to preserve the original disks.[CR]The manual was also notable for including a great deal of information concerning the monsters, classes, and weapons that could be encountered within the game, all adhering to the 2nd Edition AD&amp;D ruleset. Experience tables and other pieces of information were located in the back of the manual.[CR][B]Gameplay:[/B][CR]As with the  rest of the series, tthe game uses a  grid-based, 3D system wherein the world is viewed from a first-person perspective with 90&#176; turns and movement spaces. Within the ever-present interface, a small window on the upper left quadrant of the screen displayed the world as in the first with the party listed on the right. A text box on the bottom part of the screen displayed various messages while a compass was also shown when outside of combat. Random enemy encounters would provide combat opportunities within the game against mixed groups of foes. Everything in the interface continued to be mouse driven.[CR]As with most RPGs, party setup and character selection were left entirely up to the player. If the player so chose to create a party of warriors, they could expect extreme difficulty ahead without a mage to help teleport them back home, out of a dungeon, or heal them adequately in combat. A party is limited to six characters.[CR]Veterans from the  first EotB game will be able to import their characters. A pre-built party is also available for play for those that do not want to go through the creation process. Races[CR]No new races were added to the sequel and many of the same restrictions and statistical rules remained unchanged. Six races are given to the player to choose from and build a party of characters with as before.[CR]As with the  first game, players can only generate four characters on their own to make up the initial party. Two slots are reserved for potential NPCs that may join later on in the game, creating a total of six adventurers that can make up the group.[CR]In keeping with the 2nd Edition AD&amp;D ruleset, each race has its own set of restrictions concerning both what classes are available to them such as how far they can advance in certain ones. Racial modifiers can also affect their efficiency in certain professions. Human: As in most RPGs, their statistics and abilities are fairly average across the board with no distinctive bonuses.Elf: Fair haired, fair skinned, and more agile than humans, their specialties are focused on both magic and war although they tend to do better as spellcasters. They have a bonus to dexterity and the use of bows along with long or short swords. They are highly resistant to charm or sleep spells. Dwarf: Short, gruff, and strong, they are renowned for their smithing skills as well as their combat abilities. Being a somewhat non-magical race, they have good resistances against many spells and even poisons. Halflings: Short in stature, friendly to a fault, and generally good natured, halflings are also innately resistant to spells. They're also dextrous making them decent fighters and sticky fingered rogues.Half Elves: They have no racial modifiers but are somewhat resistant to sleep and charm spells. However, because of their longer lifespans, they are able to multiclass with a greater number of combinations than other races and are decent fighters. Gnome: Good as clerics, thieves, and even fighters, they are also fairly magic resistant as their distant cousins, the dwarves, are. Classes[CR]As with  Eye of the Beholder, six  classes are made available to players to choose from, each with its own set of restrictions. Each classes require certain prime requisites, or ability scores, to be at certain values before that character can become part of that class. No major changes have been made to this system and it would continue to be used throughout the series in much of the same way.Fighter: The consummate fighter, they can use nearly every weapon that they find. They can use magical weapons, rings, but can cast no spells. As they gain levels, they also gain speed which enables them to attack more often in combat. The prime requisite for this class is strength and any race and alignment can be a member.Paladin: These are elite fighters dedicated to smiting evil wherever it may be and will not join a party that has evil members. They are immune to disease, have increased resistances to spell effects and poison, and can heal other characters with their "laying on of hands" ability. At higher levels, they are also able to turn undead and can cast certain clerical spells. They also have a persistent aura around them that acts as a negative affect on evil creatures that come too close. Only humans with good scores in both Strength and Charisma can become this class.Thieves: A high dexterity is a prime requisite for this class and they are restricted in wearing only leather-type armor and in using a limited number of weapons. Any race can be this class and it is considered an important one to have in the game to avoid getting the party killed whenever a trap is found.Rangers: They can use any weapon as a fighter can and can even dual wield melee weapons without any penalty, but only if they are not wearing heavy armor. Humans, elves, and half-elves are the only races that are allowed in the game that can be a part of this class.Cleric: They are holy warriors that can fight with a number of weapons and wear armor while casting divine spells against their enemies. Ideal for dealing with the undead as well as healing the party. Wisdom is the prime requisite for this class and any race can be a part of it.Mages: The spellcasters of the Realm, what they lack in armor and weapons expertise are made up for in the spells that they can weave. Unlike several other RPG systems of the time that utilized spell points, mages in AD&amp;D have to memorize a set number of spells in order to store and use them at a later time. Once those memorized spells are used up, the mage must take time to memorize another batch. Intelligence is the prime requisite for this class and as they gain in level, they also gain extra slots that can be used to store memorized spells. Humans, Elves, and Half-Elves can become mages in the game. Alignment[CR]AD&amp;D along with many other PnP RPGs at the time made extensive use of an alignment system to determine a character's worldview and how they conducted themselves within society which would also be reflected in EotB II's mechanics. The entire series used this system but it did not impact the main narrative in a meaningful way, other than in determining who or what could join the party.[CR]World View:Lawful: A character will work within the lawsNeutral: A character will move between valuing a society and valuing an individual.Chaotic: A character will choose the good of the individual above that of everything else.[CR]Ethics:Good: The character tries to act in a moral and upstanding manner.Neutral: A character leans towards evaluating 'situational ethics' depending on the circumstances.Evil: A character acts without regard for others or in an overly malignant manner.[CR]For example, a Lawful Good character would be by-the-book when it came to upholding the good in society while a Chaotic Good character would be more willing to bend the rules in order to provide the same. A Lawful Evil character might hold their word as their bond and be loathe to break it for anyone, but would only give it if confronted by someone whose power they respect or as a part of one of their fell schemes. As interesting as this was, the game did not make an extensive use of the potential that this system could bring to an RPG. Attributes[CR]None of the basic character  attributes used to determine what classes were available for certain characters and how well they would perform in them would significantly change from the first game and even into the third title,  Assault of Myth Drannor. They would continue to be based upon TSR's 2nd Edition AD&amp;D ruleset, however, with all of the set limits and restrictions.[CR]Attribute scores of 18 were still considered the highest possible in a natural sense, although racial bonuses and magical effects/enhancements in the form of spells or items would be able to raise them higher either temporarily or permanently in more rare cases. These are set as far as the game was concerned. Leveling improved a character's HP (hit points) and general abilities, but their base statistics would almost never change.Strength: This determines the amount of physical damage that a character can inflict. With a strength statistic of 18, an additional variable is added to indicate exceptional strength as a percentage shown as 18/23.Constitution: A character's health and toughness is determined by this. In AD&amp;D, this has other effects outside of simply determining the HP amount gained after every level, such as a character's resistance to certain physical effects.Intelligence: A vital attribute for mages as they learn spells.Dexterity: Characters with a high dexterity tend to be nimble and agile improving their AC (armor class) which measures how hard they are to hit in combat. Important for every class, but more so with others such as fighters and thieves. With a score of 16 or higher, fighters can negate some of the penalties levied against them for using dual weapons.Charisma: This determines how attractive or repulsive a character is to everyone around them, whether it is in how they carry themselves in conversation or appear in public. Important for paladins.Wisdom: A character's innate ability to judge situations and make the best choices. It is also important in spell resistance and particularly key for clerics. Higher wisdom scores above 13 also translate into extra spells that clerics can utilize.[CR]Combat[CR]The fighting system would also remain relatively unchanged from the  first game making it extremely accessible to veterans.[CR]Fighting in the game is handled through random encounters wherein experience, items, and gold are earned. The front ranks, determined by the two characters at the top of the party list, can engage in melee combat. All other characters must resort to ranged weapons or spells in order to join in the fight. An onscreen menu guided their actions and right clicking with the mouse on the appropriate icon, such as a warrior's sword, would cause them to act.[CR]Camping was available for the player to rest and heal the party, memorize spells, and save the game when necessary.[CR]NPC Companions[CR]As well as creating your own party of player characters, throughout the course of your adventure in the temple of Darkmoon it is possible to find and recruit other NPC characters to join your cause.INSAL Insal is a Halfling thief who can be found in the level 1 Underground. He has been captured by the priests of Darkmoon and if you free him from his shackles he will offer to join your party, or you are given the option of setting him free. If you allow him to join your party he will leave you the first time you camp and steal a number of your items in the process. Location - Underground, Level 1 Class - ThiefSHORN Shorn is a Dwarven cleric who can be found in the level 2 Underground. If you free him from his cell he will offer to join your party. Location - Underground, Level 2 Class - Cleric Alignment - Lawful NeutralLEVELHPACSTRCONINTDEXCHAWIS84010151314141613SAN-RAAL  San-Raal is a Drow magician whose bones can be found in the level 2 Underground. If you take his bones to the altar of revival you can use one of its charges to bring him back to life where he will automatically join in any empty party slot. Location - Underground, Level 2 Class - Mage Alignment - Chaotic NeutralLEVELHPACSTRCONINTDEXCHAWIS8281011161814913CALANDRA  Calandra is a Human Fighter who is imprisoned in the level 2 Underground. It is possible to have previously uncovered aspects of her back story before finding her, there is evidence of a struggle in the forest before reaching the temple of Darkmoon, and at the entrance to the temple you can find Calandra's sister who is searching for her. If you free her from her cell she will offer to join your party. Location - Underground, Level 2 Class - Fighter Alignment - Lawful GoodLEVELHPACSTRCONINTDEXCHAWIS976918161315148AMBER  Amber is an Elven Thief/Mage. She is the scout who was sent by Khelben to investigate Darkmoon and disappeared before Khelben recruited your party. Her bones can be found in the Priest's quarters and must be taken to the altar of revival where it is possible to bring her back to life by expending one of its charges. She will automatically join your party in any available character slot. Location - Priest's Quarters Class - Thief/Mage Alignment - Neutral GoodLEVELHPACSTRCONINTDEXCHAWIS7/736614917181712TANGLOR Tanglor is a Dwarven Fighter/Cleric. He can be found resting in the Mantis Corridor and if you speak with him, depending on your alignment he may offer to join your party. Location - Mantis Corridor Class - Fighter/Cleric Alignment - Neutral GoodLEVELHPACSTRCONINTDEXCHAWIS7/7539161113151216[CR]</plot>
				<releasedate>30/3/1992</releasedate>
				<year>1992</year>
				<genre>RPG</genre>
				<studio>Strategic Simulations, Inc.</studio>
				<nplayers>1</nplayers>
				<perspective>1st-Person</perspective>
				<rating>4.0</rating>
				<thegamesdb_id>24588</thegamesdb_id>
				<mobygames_url>https://www.mobygames.com/game/amiga/eye-of-the-beholder-ii-the-legend-of-darkmoon</mobygames_url>
				<giantbomb_url>https://www.giantbomb.com/eye-of-the-beholder-ii-the-legend-of-darkmoon/3030-1500/</giantbomb_url>
				<boxart1>dQQWbgU.jpg</boxart1>
				<boxart2>Z7yHka6.jpg</boxart2>
				<boxart3>uVfCrs4.jpg</boxart3>
				<boxart4>sw4sB3I.jpg</boxart4>
				<boxart5>U0Fybgj.jpg</boxart5>
				<boxart6>choLImK.jpg</boxart6>
				<boxart7>I2o9qec.jpg</boxart7>
				<boxart8>HsKidyY.jpg</boxart8>
				<snapshot1>dSUs1ON.gif</snapshot1>
				<snapshot2>jMJEysT.gif</snapshot2>
				<snapshot3>WMxFQH0.gif</snapshot3>
				<snapshot4>dnKAKf4.gif</snapshot4>
				<snapshot5>ryIKpKd.gif</snapshot5>
				<snapshot6>UjTfEmu.gif</snapshot6>
				<snapshot7>vg67flP.gif</snapshot7>
				<snapshot8>s3PxAH3.gif</snapshot8>
				<snapshot9>a1XoVlL.gif</snapshot9>
				<snapshot10>sGY3rsg.gif</snapshot10>
				<emu_command>A4000</emu_command>
			</game>
			<game name="Lotus III - The Ultimate Challenge">
				<description>19.  Lotus III - The Ultimate Challenge</description>
				<rom name="AmigaROMsCoverArtGHIJKL/Amiga_ROMs_%26_CoverArt_G-H-I-J-K-L.zip/Lotus%20III%20-%20The%20Ultimate%20Challenge%2FLotus%20III%20-%20The%20Ultimate%20Challenge.Disk1.adf" size="901120" />
				<rom name="AmigaROMsCoverArtGHIJKL/Amiga_ROMs_%26_CoverArt_G-H-I-J-K-L.zip/Lotus%20III%20-%20The%20Ultimate%20Challenge%2FLotus%20III%20-%20The%20Ultimate%20Challenge.Disk2.adf" size="901120" />
				<title_clean>Lotus III - The Ultimate Challenge</title_clean>
				<plot>Licensed by the classic British car company, this game featured 2 modes of play - one has you racing against 19 computer rivals (with witty names such as Alain Phosphate and Crash-Hard Banger), and the other pits you against the clock. [CR]There are 13 different types of races, ranging from Motorways to night-time to sections punctuated by roadworks, and some are lap-based with others being simple A-B. 2 players could play on a split screen mode.[CR]The game's crowning glory, however, was the RECS editor, which allowed you to create courses of your own, with theoretically millions possible.</plot>
				<releasedate>30/3/1992</releasedate>
				<year>1992</year>
				<genre>Driving, Racing</genre>
				<studio>Gremlin Graphics Software Ltd.</studio>
				<nplayers>1-2 Sim</nplayers>
				<perspective>3rd-Person</perspective>
				<rating>4.0</rating>
				<mobygames_url>https://www.mobygames.com/game/amiga/lotus-the-ultimate-challenge</mobygames_url>
				<giantbomb_url>https://www.giantbomb.com/lotus-the-ultimate-challenge/3030-3191/</giantbomb_url>
				<boxart1>BeLFdx3.jpg</boxart1>
				<boxart2>zjI6RN3.jpg</boxart2>
				<boxart3>CtNNAFW.jpg</boxart3>
				<boxart4>tBpRMrx.jpg</boxart4>
				<snapshot1>lzaCgqp.png</snapshot1>
				<snapshot2>azithky.png</snapshot2>
				<snapshot3>6cvUF2u.png</snapshot3>
				<snapshot4>z1rPFUz.png</snapshot4>
				<snapshot5>9N30xZt.png</snapshot5>
				<snapshot6>PZSIG8R.png</snapshot6>
				<snapshot7>NE1qE1N.png</snapshot7>
				<snapshot8>wTINgs3.png</snapshot8>
				<snapshot9>s1f8Em6.png</snapshot9>
				<snapshot10>rzfmAMS.png</snapshot10>
				<emu_command>A4000</emu_command>
			</game>
			<game name="Sensible World of Soccer">
				<description>18.  Sensible World of Soccer</description>
				<rom name="AmigaROMsCoverArtRS/Amiga_ROMs_%26_CoverArt_R-S.zip/Sensible%20World%20of%20Soccer%2FSensible%20World%20of%20Soccer.Disk1.adf" size="901120" />
				<rom name="AmigaROMsCoverArtRS/Amiga_ROMs_%26_CoverArt_R-S.zip/Sensible%20World%20of%20Soccer%2FSensible%20World%20of%20Soccer.Disk2.adf" size="901120" />
				<title_clean>Sensible World of Soccer</title_clean>
				<plot>[CR]Sensible World of Soccer (SWOS) is a 2D soccer game that combines direct control from a top-down perspective with a management component. Developed by Sensible Software, the game was the direct sequel to Sensible Soccer. It was critically acclaimed upon release due to its simple, fluid controls and huge database, which featured teams and players from every professional league in every country at the time. In all, the database contained 1600 teams and 22000 players.[CR]The large database was a result of the more lenient licensing laws from the period, which allowed the use of real player names without high expense. The only deliberate inaccuracy in the data was a deliberate misspelling of UEFA, the Union of European Football Associations, which was instead referred to as EUFA. Directional controls aside, only one context-sensitive button was required to control the game, allowing you to easily perform passes, shots, lobs, headers and diving headers. Much like the original Sensible Soccer, SWOS was praised for its ball physics and high camera position which showed more of the pitch. Both features allowed for easy passing and created a soccer game focused upon flow and speed.[CR][B]Legacy:[/B][CR]Although originally released in 1992, the game continues to enjoy a high degree of critical respect. In 2006, it was named as one of the ten most important games ever by a panel that included game designers Warren Spector and Steve Meretzky. The panel argued that those ten games, which also included beloved titles such as Zork, SimCity, Super Mario Bros. 3 and Doom, should be archived to protect them from being lost to time. The hope is that the Library of Congress, who archive movies, books and other media, would accept the submissions as the start of a similar game canon. The game was released on multiple platforms to varied success, and there were numerous successful updates to the original. However, the 3D sequels that followed failed to achieve similar acclaim. In December 2007, Sensible World of Soccer was re-released with updated graphics on XBOX Live Arcade with a new online mode.[CR]Title Music[CR]Similar to Sensible Software's previous releases, SWOS had an original song recorded as its title music. Called "Goalscoring Superstar Hero," the song was written by the late Richard Joseph and lead designer Jon Hare and performed by Jacky Read.[CR]</plot>
				<releasedate>30/3/1994</releasedate>
				<year>1994</year>
				<genre>Action, Sports</genre>
				<studio>Renegade Software</studio>
				<nplayers>1-4 Sim</nplayers>
				<perspective>Top-Down</perspective>
				<rating>4.0</rating>
				<thegamesdb_id>12959</thegamesdb_id>
				<mobygames_url>https://www.mobygames.com/game/amiga/sensible-world-of-soccer</mobygames_url>
				<giantbomb_url>https://www.giantbomb.com/sensible-world-of-soccer/3030-19165/</giantbomb_url>
				<boxart1>LCLlira.jpg</boxart1>
				<boxart2>RV80xvA.jpg</boxart2>
				<snapshot1>8tezTxW.gif</snapshot1>
				<snapshot2>y7hs6ly.gif</snapshot2>
				<snapshot3>M0FWTIo.gif</snapshot3>
				<snapshot4>JP9VuBc.gif</snapshot4>
				<snapshot5>mc5OvSE.gif</snapshot5>
				<snapshot6>0Jan5Rv.gif</snapshot6>
				<snapshot7>YZUhsDx.gif</snapshot7>
				<snapshot8>091gnuH.gif</snapshot8>
				<snapshot9>kEPUSJR.gif</snapshot9>
				<snapshot10>FfUAJO1.gif</snapshot10>
				<clearlogo1>HWKv8IL.png</clearlogo1>
				<emu_command>A4000</emu_command>
			</game>
			<game name="Gunship 2000">
				<description>17.  Gunship 2000</description>
				<rom name="AmigaROMsCoverArtGHIJKL/Amiga_ROMs_%26_CoverArt_G-H-I-J-K-L.zip/Gunship%202000%2FGunship%202000.Disk1.adf" size="901120" />
				<rom name="AmigaROMsCoverArtGHIJKL/Amiga_ROMs_%26_CoverArt_G-H-I-J-K-L.zip/Gunship%202000%2FGunship%202000.Disk2.adf" size="901120" />
				<rom name="AmigaROMsCoverArtGHIJKL/Amiga_ROMs_%26_CoverArt_G-H-I-J-K-L.zip/Gunship%202000%2FGunship%202000.Disk3.adf" size="901120" />
				<rom name="AmigaROMsCoverArtGHIJKL/Amiga_ROMs_%26_CoverArt_G-H-I-J-K-L.zip/Gunship%202000%2FGunship%202000.Disk4.adf" size="901120" />
				<title_clean>Gunship 2000</title_clean>
				<plot>[CR]Gunship 2000 puts players in the role of a    helicopter   pilot for the     US Army. Players can choose to fly single, one-off missions or take part in an ongoing campaign in a theater of their choice, either in Eastern  Europe in a hypothetical conflict between NATO and the Soviet Union, or in the Persian Gulf to take part in the historical Operation Desert Storm.  Players start their career as a warrant officer, flying a lone helicopter in missions against either fixed targets or vehicles, usually tanks, on the move. Missions feature a primary objective, a secondary objective, a home base, and occasionally a FARP (forward arming refuel point,) where they could land and stock up on ammo and fuel. Most missions were of a search and destroy nature, but occasionally pick up and deliver missions were ordered. If players did well enough on their first few missions, they were offered the chance to be promoted to the commissioned rank of 2nd lieutenant.   Once this happened, players were accompanied in missions by a flight of wingmen. The flight consisted of six helos, total. One heavy flight, which contained four helos, and an additional light flight of two. Players could select aircraft and loadout for their flight, as well as issue orders to them in-flight. However, they executed their orders with varying degrees of competence. Often, they would attack low-priority targets with their best weapons, or, unload a barrage of high-powered weapons upon a target which the player already attacked with a missile in-flight. Even so, swooping in with a mix of six well-armed helos was more effective than going it alone.  The game featured adjustable realism settings. They also had to deal with environmental effects such as ground cover, which is ideal for helicopters to attack from, wind effects, and temperature. Lower air temperatures allow aircraft to carry heavier loads, in general, so players flying campaigns in Europe could typically load heavier ordnance than players trying to fight it out in the desert. Further, European maps typically had more terrain features to hide behind, making the European campaigns generally easier than desert ones.  Players could chose from a wide array of helicopters and armaments, some of which were in use at the time, and some of which were under development. The list includes:  AH-1T Cobra AH-64A Apache  AH-64D Apache Longbow (in development at the time)OH-58 Kiowa MD 500 Defender UH-60 Blackhawk RAH-66 Comanche Warrior (in development at the time, later canceled)RAH-66 Comanche Scout (in development at the time, later canceled)[CR]</plot>
				<releasedate>30/3/1993</releasedate>
				<year>1993</year>
				<genre>Simulation</genre>
				<studio>MicroProse Software, Inc.</studio>
				<nplayers>1</nplayers>
				<perspective>1st-Person</perspective>
				<rating>4.0</rating>
				<thegamesdb_id>10205</thegamesdb_id>
				<mobygames_url>https://www.mobygames.com/game/amiga/gunship-2000</mobygames_url>
				<giantbomb_url>https://www.giantbomb.com/gunship-2000/3030-1003/</giantbomb_url>
				<boxart1>godOn1k.jpg</boxart1>
				<boxart2>zpSPEM3.jpg</boxart2>
				<boxart3>etIVMXO.jpg</boxart3>
				<boxart4>ICLj7DD.jpg</boxart4>
				<snapshot1>asN687R.png</snapshot1>
				<snapshot2>HXF7vNb.png</snapshot2>
				<snapshot3>835NWFw.png</snapshot3>
				<snapshot4>JERLylo.png</snapshot4>
				<snapshot5>Nz7OFCg.png</snapshot5>
				<snapshot6>9Gj95uC.png</snapshot6>
				<snapshot7>QTHpJ5Y.png</snapshot7>
				<snapshot8>zfaihQy.png</snapshot8>
				<snapshot9>5QnGjQk.png</snapshot9>
				<snapshot10>dA257mi.png</snapshot10>
				<clearlogo1>6wwrgLh.png</clearlogo1>
				<emu_command>A4000</emu_command>
			</game>
			<game name="Wings">
				<description>16.  Wings</description>
				<rom name="AmigaROMsCoverArtTUVWXYZ/Amiga_ROMs_%26_CoverArt_T-U-V-W-X-Y-Z.zip/Wings%2FWings.Disk1.adf" size="901120" />
				<rom name="AmigaROMsCoverArtTUVWXYZ/Amiga_ROMs_%26_CoverArt_T-U-V-W-X-Y-Z.zip/Wings%2FWings.Disk2.adf" size="901120" />
				<title_clean>Wings</title_clean>
				<plot>You are an allied fighter pilot in WW1, duking it out with the "Huns" up in the sky in over 200 missions.[CR]The missions usually come in three flavors: Top-down view bombing missions where you have to take out strategically important targets, isometric strafing runs where you get to blast anything that you fancy blasting with an unlimited supply of ammo, and of course the main part: Dogfights in the sky. Rendered in 3D, seems from behind your head.[CR]The game is set in the years 1916 through 1918, and to loosen things up a little, we get to read a page of our character's new entry for the diary-like journal in his company between every mission.</plot>
				<releasedate>30/3/1990</releasedate>
				<year>1990</year>
				<genre>Action, Simulation</genre>
				<studio>Cinemaware Corporation</studio>
				<nplayers>1</nplayers>
				<perspective>3rd-Person</perspective>
				<rating>4.0</rating>
				<mobygames_url>https://www.mobygames.com/game/amiga/wings</mobygames_url>
				<giantbomb_url>https://www.giantbomb.com/wings/3030-2568/</giantbomb_url>
				<boxart1>Wtx3gKZ.jpg</boxart1>
				<boxart2>7fwvfWA.jpg</boxart2>
				<boxart3>mPVUyfE.jpg</boxart3>
				<boxart4>wTJZndB.jpg</boxart4>
				<snapshot1>8LRZhgR.gif</snapshot1>
				<snapshot2>gaqCW3b.gif</snapshot2>
				<snapshot3>MrxaDm8.gif</snapshot3>
				<snapshot4>5OAAwRe.gif</snapshot4>
				<snapshot5>NEwcs97.gif</snapshot5>
				<snapshot6>EKJpTno.gif</snapshot6>
				<snapshot7>rLMnv5j.gif</snapshot7>
				<snapshot8>bltMGFV.gif</snapshot8>
				<snapshot9>9dlZ4Ps.gif</snapshot9>
				<snapshot10>wFXCZyZ.gif</snapshot10>
				<emu_command>A4000</emu_command>
			</game>
			<game name="Syndicate">
				<description>15.  Syndicate</description>
				<rom name="AmigaROMsCoverArtRS/Amiga_ROMs_%26_CoverArt_R-S.zip/Syndicate%2FSyndicate.Disk1.adf" size="901120" />
				<rom name="AmigaROMsCoverArtRS/Amiga_ROMs_%26_CoverArt_R-S.zip/Syndicate%2FSyndicate.Disk2.adf" size="901120" />
				<rom name="AmigaROMsCoverArtRS/Amiga_ROMs_%26_CoverArt_R-S.zip/Syndicate%2FSyndicate.Disk3.adf" size="901120" />
				<rom name="AmigaROMsCoverArtRS/Amiga_ROMs_%26_CoverArt_R-S.zip/Syndicate%2FSyndicate.Disk4.adf" size="901120" />
				<title_clean>Syndicate</title_clean>
				<plot>[CR][B]Overview:[/B][CR]Syndicate is a  cyberpunk  isometric  real-time tactical game developed by  Bullfrog Productions and released in 1993 to critical acclaim. An expansion pack,  Syndicate: American Revolt (1993) and a sequel,  Syndicate Wars (1996), have also been released. On February 22, 2012 a  remake was released by  EA Partners and developed by  Starbreeze Studios.[CR]Backstory[CR]As the world of today slipped into the future, multinational corporations grew in size and profit. They came into positions to own small countries and to exercise direct influence over the world's governments. They practically became the world's governments, undemocratically controlling the lives of people through commerce. These corporations became known as Megacorps.[CR]One of the Megacorps, a European one, invented the CHIP. A device that is inserted into the neck and stimulates the brain stem to alter a persons perception of the outside world. The CHIP numbs a person's senses to the misery and squalor around them better than any drug and sold millions around the world. It could convince a user that the sun shone when it was raining and that they were more beautiful than they really were.[CR]The CHIP, like some  drugs, also made the user open to  auto-suggestion, allowing them to be manipulated by the Megacorps. The CHIP became a perfect tool for the Megacorps to manipulating the populace and to gain power with. It didn't take long before the Megacorps were corrupted and became crime Syndicates, fighting amongst each other for monopoly over CHIP manufacturing and control over the world.[CR]And in the year of 2096, the Syndicates have not only upgraded the drug they push, but also the way they fight. Instead of using ordinary thugs, they now use teams of custom-built  cyborg  agents to do their dirty deeds.[CR][B]Gameplay:[/B][CR]The player takes on the role of a young executive in a small European Syndicate. The objective of the game is to spread the Syndicate's control globally.World view screen[CR]The world is divided up into 50 territories. To gain control over a territory, the player must complete a mission in that territory. Missions objectives include the assassination of an important person, the elimination of rival agents or kidnapping. Once a territory has been gained, the player can start to collect taxes within it. The taxed amount can be adjusted, but if raised too high, the population can become rebellious against the Syndicate.[CR]The player selects a mission from the World map and can then select and outfit agents with weapons and  cybernetic modifications. Between missions, the player can also research new weapons and modifications. This is necessary if the player is to achieve the ultimate goal of world domination.During a mission[CR]In the missions the player controls up to four agents from a fixed isometric view. This is to reflect the fact that the player's character is sitting in an airship high above the city map. The player tells the CHIP controlled agents where to move and where to fire. They will not react to any event unless the player activates Panic mode. During missions, the player can kill  civilians and destroy many things without consequence.[CR][B]Weapons:[/B][CR] Pistol: Very cheap, but basically worthless. Medium range. Shotgun: Short effective range, but does more damage than the hand gun. Uzi SMG: Fast rate of fire, medium range and comes with plenty of ammunition.Long Range Rifle: Very long range and extremely accurate.Flame Thrower: Devastating, but with a very short range.Mini Gun: Gatling gun with a devastating rate of fire and an incredible range. Laser Gun: Will cut through anyone or anything that gets in it way.Gauss Gun: Portable rocket launcher. Hell yeah.[CR]Special Equipment[CR]Persuadertron: A short range weapon that fires a small dose of chemicals, which will make the target lose all their free will and follow the agent who fired.Access Card: Plastic card that allows some security doors to restricted areas to be opened. Will also identify the agent carrying it as a Police officer to other Police units.Scanner: Scans for possible threats and items in the area.Time Bomb: High powered explosive that will, after a set time period, blow with devastating force.MediKit: Will restore a single agent&#8217;s health completely.Energy Shield: Will, during a very short time span, completely protect the agent against all projectile weapons.[CR]</plot>
				<releasedate>30/3/1993</releasedate>
				<year>1993</year>
				<genre>Action, Strategy</genre>
				<studio>Electronic Arts, Inc.</studio>
				<nplayers>1</nplayers>
				<perspective>Isometric</perspective>
				<rating>4.0</rating>
				<thegamesdb_id>9512</thegamesdb_id>
				<mobygames_url>https://www.mobygames.com/game/amiga/syndicate</mobygames_url>
				<giantbomb_url>https://www.giantbomb.com/syndicate/3030-10865/</giantbomb_url>
				<boxart1>Ys6EVvi.jpg</boxart1>
				<boxart2>zNfFRVO.jpg</boxart2>
				<boxart3>L2ox31q.jpg</boxart3>
				<boxart4>lfqDD4f.jpg</boxart4>
				<snapshot1>1f8aASX.png</snapshot1>
				<snapshot2>dxT5MGk.jpg</snapshot2>
				<snapshot3>oYazTQE.jpg</snapshot3>
				<snapshot4>wJ2bZys.jpg</snapshot4>
				<snapshot5>uJubJcm.jpg</snapshot5>
				<snapshot6>YMYB9W0.jpg</snapshot6>
				<snapshot7>hGixCAD.jpg</snapshot7>
				<snapshot8>8hdFLAY.jpg</snapshot8>
				<snapshot9>8G9yOeJ.jpg</snapshot9>
				<snapshot10>6m1diVn.png</snapshot10>
				<clearlogo1>7u5bYkM.png</clearlogo1>
				<emu_command>A4000</emu_command>
			</game>
			<game name="Another World">
				<description>14.  Another World</description>
				<rom name="AmigaROMs_A-B/Amiga_ROMs_%26_CoverArt_A-B.zip/Another%20World%2FAnother%20World.Disk1.adf" size="901120" />
				<rom name="AmigaROMs_A-B/Amiga_ROMs_%26_CoverArt_A-B.zip/Another%20World%2FAnother%20World.Disk2.adf" size="901120" />
				<title_clean>Another World</title_clean>
				<plot>[CR][B]Overview:[/B][CR]The second entry of the Might &amp; Magic RPG series, Gates to Another World would continue its predecessor's open, non-linear world design. Players would continue to seek out out quests, fight terrible creatures, and explore another vast world laid at their feet. As was popular at the time, many of its conventions appear based on concepts drawn up within the Dungeons and Dragons rule set by TSR.[CR]As with the first game, this game had also included a full color map of the world that the game was taking place on (in this case, Crom).[CR]Several enhancements were also made to the game over that of its predecessor:the number of spells increasedthe number of mini-quests were substantially increasedsecondary skills were now made available to characters, such as mountaineering (allowing the party to pass through mountain areas) in addition to several otherstwo new classes were added to the game: Barbarian and Ninja.[CR]The combat heavy nature of the series would continue with this entry although there were many puzzles and secrets to be discovered within the game. Characters from the first game can also be transferred into this one but with the following restrictions:Gold is set to 1000Food is set to 40Gems less than or equal to 100 remain the same while those numbering over 100 are reduced to 100Character levels less than 7 remain the same. Those 7 and above are reset to 7 if the first game was successfully completed, or to 6 if it was not.[CR]Special sub-quests for character classes were also included in the game to enhance their abilities.SNES Versions[CR]The Super Nintendo saw two separate adaptations of Might and Magic II:The European version was developed by Iguana Entertainment (later Acclaim Studios Austin) and published by Elite. This version was to be ported to the US by Sammy, but was canceled. This version is almost identical to the Genesis version.Japan saw a separate Super Famicom release named Might and Magic: Book II. It was developed by Starcraft and published by LOZC/G Amusements. This version never left Japan. It was rebuilt from scratch to be more like contemporary Japanese RPGs, such as Shin Megami Tensei and Dragon Quest.[CR][B]Story:[/B][CR]As revealed at the end of the first Might and Magic, there is a considerable degree of sci-fi technology working behind the scenes of the world of VARN. The series' use of this would continue on through each one of the party-based RPG titles in the series and would usually be revealed close to the endgame.[CR]In Gates to Another World, the game picks up almost immediately following the events of Secret of the Inner Sanctrum. The party had uncovered a plot in the last game by an evil, otherworldly villain, Sheltem, who had escaped at the end by entering a gate to the world of Cron. It was also discovered that another being, Corak, had been pursuing him in Varn before he had escaped and now it falls to the characters to stop him. After many adventures and quests that take the party to the elemental planes and back again to the world of Cron, they finally track Sheltem down after assisting Corak.[CR]They confront him and his guards, but he manages to escape but not before telling them that CRON and all of its VARNs are heading into the sun. CRON is actually a massive ship and VARN is apparently one of its nacelles, a self contained world that is connected. Together, they have been set on a collision course and only the party can save both CRON and its VARNs.[CR]Sheltem has locked the controls and taunts the party with a recorded message revealing that he is the ruler of a world called Terra. He tells them that CRON and its VARNs were programmed by the Ancients to populate Terra, but he will not tolerate whom he believes to be inferiors polluting his race. However, in his arrogance, he has provided a cryptogram that must be deciphered with the clues given in order to change the course of CRON and save it and themselves from a fiery death.[CR]After solving the puzzle, it is revealed that what Sheltem had told them was partly the truth. CRON was created to populate Terra. But Sheltem is still missing and Corak has continued his search to stop his nemesis. The story continues in the third Might and Magic, the Isles of Terra.[CR][B]Gameplay:[/B][CR]The open ended gameplay was centered around a six person party with the world seen from a first person perspective utilizing rudimentary 3D graphics for the outdoor locations and indoor dungeons. Monsters along with certain other encounters were displayed as 2D pictures. As was the norm at the time for several RPG titles, movement was centered aroud a grid based scheme which meant 90 degree turns and square-based movement forward or back.[CR]The game was also considered quite detailed as well as difficult. Players were required to maintain a stock of food in order to be able to rest outside of an in to regain hit and spell points. Bashing open locked doors would often set off traps if they were not disarmed. Leveling was not automatic.[CR]Once a character had earned the requisite experience, it must be spent at a training ground in order to improve their statistics and abilities. Gems were often required to cast higher level spells and characters could also die from old age (natural or not), although the proper spells could alleviate its effects. Characters could also be afflicted with a number of debilitating conditions which often proved incredibly fatal to starting parties. Sex and alignment would also restrict certain characters from entering specific areas or in equipping certain items.[CR]Saves are handled at Inns within each town making it particularly dangerous to get caught far from their walls in dangerous territory. They are the only places where players may save the game.[CR]Towns and dungeons were all divided into 16 by 16 squares and the game used a  grid-based movement system with 90 degree turns.Races[CR]The game allows the player to select among five different races in building their characters. As with most other RPGs, certain races have slightly better statistics in certain areas and others, but the emphasis appears to be more on how resistant each one is against certain conditions such as falling prey to sleep spells or being more resistant to poison.[CR]The five races are:Human - Strong resistance to fear and some resistance to sleep spells. Average statistics make this race a good choice without any glaring weaknesses.Elf - They have a strong resistance to fear and are generally excellent at spellcastingDwarf - Some resistance to poison, stronger and hardier than the other races. They make excellent fighters but poor spellcasters.Gnome - Nimble and quick, they make excellent thieves and decent spellcasters.Half-Orc - They have a moderate resistance to sleep spells, are decently strong, and can make great fighters.Statistics[CR]The maximum value for any one statistic is 18, although this can change depending on several factors based on spells or the effects of certain items. However, if any statistic drops to 0, it will result in immediate death for that character.[CR]The basic statistics used in the game seem derived from the Dungeons and Dragons model of statistics, although carry different names so as to differentiate themselves. They are:Intellect - General knowledge. Important to sorcerers as it can affect spell points. Important to archers later on at higher levels as they begin learning sorcerer spells.Might - Raw strength. Important to any fighting class such as Knights and Paladins. Affects the damage a character can inflict in melee combat.Personality - A character's general degree of appeal to others. Particularly important to clerics as it affects their pool of spell points. Important to paladins when, at higher levels, they begin learning cleric spells.Endurance - Stamina. Affects how many hit points a character initially has to start with and will gain every time they level. Particularly important to fighters.Speed - Agility and general quickness affecting initiative. A faster character improves (increases) their Armor Class rating making them harder to hit.Accuracy - A character's ability to land hits during combat. This is particularly important to archers.Luck - Measures the general chances of a character succeeding when all else seems to have failed. Random and unpredictable.Classes[CR]Several classes are available for players to choose from in building their party of adventurers.Knight - These are considered the warriors of the game in being able to use any item or armor aside from those exclusively designed for another class or have an opposite alignment. They are able to attack more than once every round at higher levels.Paladin - While not quite as good as a Knight in combat, they are able to wield and equip as many items as they can with the same restrictions. At higher levels, they are also able to cast Clerical spells.Archer - These are the missile experts of the party and are able to use any weapon. Unlike the Paladin, they are also able to use missile weapons even in hand-to-hand combat. At higher levels, they are also able to cast Sorceror spells. They are restricted in the kind of armor that they can wear, however, such as chain mail or any lighter armor being the only types available for them and they cannot use a shield.Cleric - The traditional healer class, they can only wear light armor but they can also carry a shield. Weapons are restricted to a club, mace, flail, a staff, or a hammer. They cannot use ranged weapons such as bows. At higher levels, their healing abilities come in extremely valuable much further into the game. They are also the travel experts of Varn with spells that can teleport a party out from a dungeon, to a town for a quick rest, or enable them to walk on water to reach special areas.Sorceror - They can only wear padded armor and their choice of weapons are extremely limited and it almost goes without saying that they can't carry a shield. However, their spells more than make up this lack of physical protection and offensive ability with some of the most devastating attacks in the game.Robber - The traditional thief of the game, what they lack in offensive and defensive ability are made up with their talent for disarming traps and locks. They can fight as well as a cleric, but are far better at keeping the party safe from poison gas or fireballs erupting from chests.Barbarian - This character can use most weapons and starts with the greatest number of hit points out of any other class. A true tank character.Ninja - This character acts much like a fighting Robber, but they cannot carry a shield. They can use most one handed weapons but only swords specific to their class. Two handed weapons are limited to staves and the naginata. However, they do have the "assassinate" ability which is automatically attempted with their first attack. If successful, additional damage will result.Character Status[CR]In addition to their class and race, characters have a number of other statistics that players will need to keep track of during the game.Level - This is a measure of how experienced a character is. Characters start out at level 1 and can only gain levels once enough experience is earned and the necessary training is purchased.Spell Points - A measure of how many points are available to any one character for use with spells. Certain spells have higher point requirements than others.Hit Points - The number of hit points a character has remaining. At zero hit points, a character does not necessarily die. Instead, they fall unconscious. However, if they suffer anymore damage after reaching zero, death is the only result.Armor Class - The higher this number, the more resistant a character is to damage. Armor, spells, shields, and speed are among the factors that can help determine it.Age - Characters start at 18 years of age and grow older as the game continues on. As they become older, their skills begin to deteriorate and vital statistics will begin to drop. After around an age of 80, the character can actually die from resting overnight. Age can be delayed or reversed using spells or in discovering special locations.Experience Points - These are earned from defeating monsters and quests. These determine whether a character is ready to advance to the next level through training. The point requirements for reaching the next level usually double.Gems - This measures the number of gems that a character is carrying. Gems are valuable as they are consumed in order to cast many higher level spells.Gold - The coin of the realm earned in a variety of ways whether it is from monsters or in discovering long lost treasures.Food - Characters start with ten food units (up to a maximum of 40). One food unit represents a day's rations and is consumed when camping to replenish hit points and spell points during rest.Condition - A character's current status, whether they are asleep, poisoned, dead, etc..[CR]Each character also has their own backpack which can carry a maximum of six items.Alignment[CR]There are no absolutes in Might &amp; Magic nor does this affect the story progression of the game. Instead, it largely determines certain restrictions such as whether a piece of equipment can be used or whether a particular character can enter specific areas.Locations[CR]Five towns are scattered throughout the land, each offering their own sets of challenges. The player was not implicitly told where to go, leaving it to their own inquisitive nature to discover where they should head off to next and who to speak to in order to find the next quest. In addition to the towns, many dungeons and secret locations are also scattered throughout the game.[CR]Towns share many of the same services.Shops - Where supplies, such as new armor and food, can be purchased.Temples - Where sick or injured characters can be healed.Training Grounds - Important for advancing character levels once enough experience has been earned.Inns - Where characters can safely rest and where saves can be made.[CR]Combat[CR]Generic encounters were randomly generated and would often give the player several choices. If monsters were surprised, the player had the option to ignore them or initiate combat. If the monsters surprised the player's party, combat would immediately begin. If both parties simply encountered each other, the player would also be able to decide what they should do next.[CR]Players could decide simply to attack the monsters, or they could try and bribe them which usually meant giving them gems or valuable food. Players could also attempt to surrender at which point they will be dropped off at a random, and more dangerous, location within the region with all of their food, gold, and gems confiscated. Failing at either of these actions will throw the party into combat.[CR]Massive battles consisting of 255 enemies were also a part of the gameplay.[CR]</plot>
				<releasedate>30/3/1990</releasedate>
				<year>1990</year>
				<genre>RPG</genre>
				<studio>New World Computing, Inc.</studio>
				<nplayers>1</nplayers>
				<perspective>1st-Person</perspective>
				<rating>3.1</rating>
				<videoid>Zgkf6wooDmw</videoid>
				<thegamesdb_id>20375</thegamesdb_id>
				<mobygames_url>https://www.mobygames.com/game/amiga/might-and-magic-ii-gates-to-another-world</mobygames_url>
				<giantbomb_url>https://www.giantbomb.com/might-and-magic-ii-gates-to-another-world/3030-19917/</giantbomb_url>
				<boxart1>H24wubg.jpg</boxart1>
				<boxart2>aFMr0l7.jpg</boxart2>
				<boxart3>kPEaxoS.jpg</boxart3>
				<boxart4>kPEaxoS.jpg</boxart4>
				<snapshot1>vVpFvNO.jpg</snapshot1>
				<snapshot2>QtGnhbH.jpg</snapshot2>
				<snapshot3>rfKs9Ez.jpg</snapshot3>
				<snapshot4>XDtg545.png</snapshot4>
				<snapshot5>n8NfJHv.png</snapshot5>
				<snapshot6>jc9X6LA.png</snapshot6>
				<snapshot7>WmJnTVP.png</snapshot7>
				<snapshot8>nfpJ0Ph.png</snapshot8>
				<snapshot9>nCL2oRw.png</snapshot9>
				<snapshot10>N37ntj0.png</snapshot10>
				<clearlogo1>Hens2og.png</clearlogo1>
				<emu_command>A4000</emu_command>
			</game>
			<game name="Flashback">
				<description>13.  Flashback</description>
				<rom name="AmigaROMsCoverArtCDEF/Amiga_ROMs_%26_CoverArt_C-D-E-F.zip/Flashback%2FFlashback.Disk1.adf" size="901120" />
				<rom name="AmigaROMsCoverArtCDEF/Amiga_ROMs_%26_CoverArt_C-D-E-F.zip/Flashback%2FFlashback.Disk2.adf" size="901120" />
				<rom name="AmigaROMsCoverArtCDEF/Amiga_ROMs_%26_CoverArt_C-D-E-F.zip/Flashback%2FFlashback.Disk3.adf" size="901120" />
				<rom name="AmigaROMsCoverArtCDEF/Amiga_ROMs_%26_CoverArt_C-D-E-F.zip/Flashback%2FFlashback.Disk4.adf" size="901120" />
				<title_clean>Flashback</title_clean>
				<plot>[CR][B]Overview:[/B][CR]Flashback: The Quest for Identity is a 2D action-adventure platform game originally developed by Delphine Software International and published by U.S. Gold for Commodore Amiga home computers in 1992. The game stars plucky protagonist Conrad B. Hart, a young man stricken with total amnesia who finds himself stranded deep in the jungles of an alien world. Similar to Delphine's earlier title Out of This World, Flashback is notable for its use of rotoscoped animation, allowing for a visually fluid representation of the characters' various movements.[CR]The game was first released on floppy diskette for the Amiga, a home computer popular in Delphine's native France; it was eventually ported to MS-DOS, Super NES, Genesis, Atari Jaguar and the Acorn Archimedes the following year. A CD-ROM version was later released for MS-DOS, Sega CD, CD-i, 3DO and FM Towns in 1994. Many of Flashback's ports were developed wholly or in part by Tiertex Design Studios.[CR]Flashback: The Quest for Identity was followed by its 1995 sequel Fade to Black. The original game was remade in 2013 with full 3D graphics and was released simply as Flashback with no subtitle.[CR][B]Story:[/B][CR]The game opens in medias res as protagonist Conrad B. Hart flees down a corridor from a pair of men armed with laser weapons. Conrad jumps onto a hoverbike and temporarily evades his assailants; however, a much larger transport soon gives chase and quickly blasts Conrad's vehicle out of the sky. After a brief search of the crash area, the armed transport flies off, leaving Conrad for dead in the depths of an unknown jungle.AmnesiaFlashback features rotoscoped cutscenes.[CR]Conrad awakens the next day in an alien jungle on a planet known as Titan. It becomes apparent he has no memory of events prior to the chase. Upon awakening he notices that he knocked a cube-shaped object off a ledge and sets out to retrieve it. The cube contains a message recorded by the protagonist before he lost his memory. He gives no clues as to what has happened but tells him to seek out his friend Ian who is located in New Washington. Conrad then proceeds to take on the dangers of this jungle to find Ian. After battling enemies in the form of robots and mutants with other obstacles such as turrets and strange fires Conrad eventually comes across a hole in the ground that acts as an entrance to New Washington. An old man who sits near this hole trades an Anti-G Belt that negates the effects of gravity to some extent, for some credits allowing Conrad access to his next location.[CR]A short while after arriving in New Washington Conrad discovers Ian being held by a couple of New Washington Police Officers. After battling these men off Ian places Conrad in a machine that recovers his memories. It is revealed that Conrad had discovered a race of aliens was blending in with the human population on Earth in large quantity implying an eventual take over of the planet. His revelation had caught the attention of this alien race who would try to assassinate him. After they failed the first time it prompted Conrad to record the Holo-Cube message found earlier in the game and to send a copy of his memories to Ian. The game's manual would also explain that the alien race is called Morphs and killed Conrad's girlfriend. One night the aliens finally captured Conrad and took him aboard their ship. On this night they erased his memory but failed to secure him as Conrad would awaken and flee his captures, leading to what was witnessed at the beginning of the game.Employment[CR]With his memories restored Conrad decides he needs to return to Earth. With little money however, this was never going to be as easy as it sounds. Ian suggests that Conrad should take part in a TV Show where he must fight Cyborgs for a chance to win a ticket to Earth. As it would be too dangerous to compete under his own name Conrad has to get false ID papers. Ian sends him to a contact named Jack, who demands 1,500 credits for the papers. Since he doesn't have that sort of cash on hand Conrad partakes in multiple odd jobs available in New Washington.[CR]First he is hired by Titan Spaces Lines for an apparently easy job of collecting and delivering a parcel. Just outsides the parcels destination he is attacked by a member of the NWPD but overcomes him and delivers the package.[CR]The second mission comes from Virtual Crop that requests Conrad escort a VIP to their research center. It is made clear that the mission will require a firearm ad the area traveled in will be dangerous. The warning is well advised since mutants infest the area in addition to malfunctioning Security Spheres. Like previously though Conrad succeeds.[CR]Titan TV hires Conrad for the third mission. They report that a Model Cy-Borg 2.1 has escaped with the possible assistance of an outsider. It carries a virus which could spread to all other functioning cyborgs. A police officer informs Conrad that the Cy-Borg wants to make a deal. This turns out to be a trap however and Conrad kills the Police Officer for access to 2.1&#8217;s lair. Once in his hideout Conrad eliminates 2.1.[CR]The penultimate New Washington mission is accomplished for Titan Senior Advisory Board. Sabotage to the generator that supplies power to New Washington means the city is on the verge of blowing up. Conrad has 90 seconds to locate the sabotaged area and repair it. With only seconds left Conrad repairs the generator and saves New Washington.[CR]With only one mission required to gain the necessary credits for the false papers, another party hires Conrad to eliminate the mutant threat that is lurking in all the Restricted Areas. After accomplishing this task Conrad meets Jack one more time who now hands over the papers allowing entry into the game show.[CR]The game show of requires participants to fight their way through eight different levels of deadly situations. Littered throughout every level are Cy-Borg 2.1s, Sentry Spheres and mines. Conrad manages to fight through all levels and win a ticket to Earth.Back on EarthEarth[CR]Conrad believes The Morphs have a hidden base within a night club on Earth but upon arrival is attacked by the local law enforcement and security measures. After some time he locates the nightclub. He breaks in through an upper level thus causing more security measures to become active making his job of finding the Morphs more complicated.[CR]After much tribulation Conrad finds himself in a vent shaft above a group of Morphs that are discussing their plans. They reveal that soon their invasion will begin since millions of their kind are ready to teleport in and destroy humanity. Conrad&#8217;s vent then proceeds to collapse under his weight and he is discovered. It is decided that he will be thrown into the dungeon with plans for interrogation.[CR]After he wakes up in his cell Conrad discovers he is unarmed and that Cy-Borgs have been sent to his cell to carry out the interrogation. Unexpectedly though Conrad makes a quick burst for the door and evades the Cy-Borgs. Luckily enough his gun was not too far away and he is able to destroy his would-be interrogators. Further into their lair Conrad finally confronts the Morphs in combat. With their ability to take and lose shape whenever they want Conrad has a difficult time but overcomes everyone he meets. With the realization that the Morph invasion is close with no time to report it, Conrad teleports to the Morph home planet with the intention of stopping their conquest.[CR]On the planet Conrad tries to assist a human prisoner who is in possession of explosives. Unfortunately the man is killed by a Morph upon his release but lives long enough to give Conrad the destructive device. Conrad discovers a diary on the planet that reveals a captive human scientist managed to enter the theory of molecular research into a Titan computer. This theory was taken up by Conrad who made glasses revealing the aliens living among the human population. It is also revealed that The Master Brain, positions at the center of the planet, controls all morphs, destroying him will end the race. The device Conrad holds was created by the scientist and is powerful enough to destroy the entire planet.[CR]With other options being non-existent, Conrad decides to put the scientist's plan into action. He travels all the way into the planet&#8217;s core. After battling more Morphs the Master Brain is killed. After dropping the Atomic Charge into the foundations of the planet Conrad races against time to escape the planet in a docked ship before the planet explodes.[CR]Conrad only just makes it, with the ship just out of reach from the destructive force of the Atomic Device. Conrad soon learns though that he is in a galaxy unrecognized by the ship&#8217;s systems. With the possibility of being lost in space forever Conrad places himself in cryogenic suspension to be awakened if he is ever discovered.[CR]Critical Reception[CR]When the Genesis version was released Electronic Gaming Monthly issued the scores of 9,9,9,8 in addition to the Editor's Choice Gold award. They added, "...one of the best games ever made for the Genesis. The action is non-stop, and it really feels like you're playing a movie!...get a joystick, because the generic Sega controllers aren't precise enough to handle the diagonal motions necessary for some of the specialized techniques".[CR]</plot>
				<releasedate>30/3/1992</releasedate>
				<year>1992</year>
				<genre>Action</genre>
				<studio>U.S. Gold Ltd.</studio>
				<nplayers>1</nplayers>
				<perspective>Platform</perspective>
				<rating>4.1</rating>
				<thegamesdb_id>9496</thegamesdb_id>
				<mobygames_url>https://www.mobygames.com/game/amiga/flashback-the-quest-for-identity</mobygames_url>
				<giantbomb_url>https://www.giantbomb.com/flashback-the-quest-for-identity/3030-1066/</giantbomb_url>
				<boxart1>3dihXYh.jpg</boxart1>
				<boxart2>REp271Y.jpg</boxart2>
				<snapshot1>9684WpS.png</snapshot1>
				<snapshot2>vUpUO7D.png</snapshot2>
				<snapshot3>nkIgdCI.png</snapshot3>
				<snapshot4>5cX4RHO.png</snapshot4>
				<snapshot5>JDWsfPh.png</snapshot5>
				<snapshot6>9q6n6eY.png</snapshot6>
				<snapshot7>d3QhP0R.png</snapshot7>
				<snapshot8>YWYjU9Z.png</snapshot8>
				<snapshot9>hL3ox4i.png</snapshot9>
				<snapshot10>lzVBtna.png</snapshot10>
				<fanart1>8JC3gco.jpg</fanart1>
				<clearlogo1>TVeG3qy.png</clearlogo1>
				<emu_command>A4000</emu_command>
			</game>
			<game name="Civilization (AGA)">
				<description>12.  Civilization</description>
				<rom name="AmigaROMsCoverArtCDEF/Amiga_ROMs_%26_CoverArt_C-D-E-F.zip/Civilization%20%28AGA%29%2FCivilization%20%28AGA%29.Disk1.adf" size="901120" />
				<rom name="AmigaROMsCoverArtCDEF/Amiga_ROMs_%26_CoverArt_C-D-E-F.zip/Civilization%20%28AGA%29%2FCivilization%20%28AGA%29.Disk2.adf" size="901120" />
				<rom name="AmigaROMsCoverArtCDEF/Amiga_ROMs_%26_CoverArt_C-D-E-F.zip/Civilization%20%28AGA%29%2FCivilization%20%28AGA%29.Disk3.adf" size="901120" />
				<rom name="AmigaROMsCoverArtCDEF/Amiga_ROMs_%26_CoverArt_C-D-E-F.zip/Civilization%20%28AGA%29%2FCivilization%20%28AGA%29.Disk4.adf" size="901120" />
				<title_clean>Civilization</title_clean>
				<plot>[CR][B]Overview:[/B][CR]Sid Meier's Civilization is a turn-based  4X strategy game developed and published by  MicroProse for  MS-DOS in 1991. Designed by  Sid Meier, it is the first game in the  long-running series of the same name and the first game to popularize the 4X (explore, expand, exploit, and exterminate) sub-genre of strategy games. Players take on the role of a ruler of a civilization (loosely based on real-life historical civilizations) and is challenged to build it up amongst other empires (from two to six), from the end of the prehistoric era to the technological future.[CR]Over the years, the game received ports to the  Mac,  Amiga,  Atari ST,  Super Nintendo Entertainment System (published by  Koei in the United States and by  Asmik Ace in Japan),  PlayStation (published in Japan only by  Asmik Ace), and  N-Gage. A special port for the  Windows, titled  Sid Meier's CivNet, was released in 1995, featuring online multiplayer.[CR][B]History:[/B][CR]Sid Meier, a founder of MicroProse and veteran game designer, had established his name in the industry with such titles as Pirates!, Railroad Tycoon, and a variety of flight simulators. Drawing inspiration from two board games, Civilization from Avalon Hill and Risk, and two recently released computer games,  Populous and  SimCity, Meier set to work with Bruce Shelley on Civilization.[CR]While the game would see release via MicroProse, and Meier was a co-founder of the company, at the time of Civilization's creation, Meier was not an employee of MicroProse. Meier's former MicroProse partner, Bill Stealey, had changed the direction of the company away from PC games and into the home console and arcade market. Meier jumped ship prior to MicroProse going public.[CR]Inspired by their work on Railroad Tycoon, a deviation from their normal flight combat and military strategy games, Meier and Shelley began programming Civilization on an IBM PC in 1990. This began soon after MicroProse cancelled the sequel to  Railroad Tycoon. Meier personally handled all the programming and coding and all of the art for early incarnations of the game. The game became an all-consuming project, and Meier kept a notepad near his bed in case of sudden inspiration.[CR]Development occurred in cycles. Meier would develop a functioning prototype, hand it over to Shelley and they would dissect it until Meier went back to programming. The partners were the only ones involved in the early design process, with Meier unwilling to involve any other people until he was ready.[CR]An early incarnation of the game drew heavily from the duo's work on Railroad Tycoon and was equally inspired by SimCity. It was originally real-time based on zoning: players would choose areas for specific purposes and watch as their civilization slowly grew.[CR]At this moment in time, development was halted. Stealey, a former pilot, had developed MicroProse on the strength of flight simulators, and had little interest in other games. He was not particularly happy with the release of Railroad Tycoon, and Civilization would never had gotten so far if it were not for the previous game's success. Meier's status as a contractor, as opposed to employee, allowed the development of Civilization to continue. However, Stealey stepped in and refused to back the game, unless Meier and Shelley finished Covert Action, a action spy game that was set aside in favor of Railroad Tycoon.[CR]After Covert Action was finished, the team went back to Civilization where it saw the addition of its most important elements. First, the team incorporated turn based play. Zoning was abandoned and military strategy was added. Individual units were added that could be manipulated to various tasks. Meier also included the technology progression tree. During this time, little historic research was used. Instead Meier used popular conventions in how the public understood history, and incorporated these elements into his technology tree. With these additions to Civilization, the game was ready to leave the hands of Meier and Shelley.[CR]Due to the low priority of Meier's games at MicroProse, they had trouble securing the help they needed. It was only grudgingly that the company allowed the art team and play testing team to work on it.[CR]During this phase of development, the map was halved in size, large portions of the technology tree were removed, and units were removed. Prior to shipping however, Shelley developed the in-game reference guide, the Civilopedia, as well as the massive user manual.[CR]In 1991, the game shipped. It was late and saw very little promotion. However, on the strength of critical acclaim and word-of-mouth excitement, the game took the imagination of gamers everywhere and spawning a million selling franchise.[CR][B]Gameplay:[/B][CR]The player takes on the role as a ruler of a civilization and is challenged to build an empire amongst up to six other civilizations. The game begins at the end of the prehistoric era, 4000 BC, in a world without cities. The player starts with one or two Settler units to build his empire with. The cities that the player builds and micromanage will determine the success of the empire.[CR]In order to win the player is forced to explore the world, wage war and participate in diplomacy. The player must also decide where to build new cities, which city improvements or units to build, and which new advances in knowledge to take.[CR]As new knowledge is acquired, new units and improvements will be available to the player. Getting ahead in the technology race is a great advantage to the player.[CR]There are special city improvement in the game called Wonders of the World. They can only be built once in the world and gives an advantage to the civilization that builds it.[CR]The game is won when the player has destroyed all other civilizations, reached the end of the modern era (2100 AD) with the highest score or won the space race by reaching the star system of Alpha Centauri first.Civilizations[CR]Players can select amongst 14 historical civilizations to play. The difference between them is mostly cosmetic. The choice will determine titles, city names, musical heralds and color.RomanBabylonianGermanEgyptianAmericanGreekIndianRussianZuluFrenchAztecChineseEnglishMongol[CR]</plot>
				<releasedate>30/3/1992</releasedate>
				<year>1992</year>
				<genre>Strategy</genre>
				<studio>MicroProse Software, Inc.</studio>
				<nplayers>1</nplayers>
				<perspective>Top-Down</perspective>
				<rating>3.8</rating>
				<mobygames_url>https://www.mobygames.com/game/amiga/sid-meiers-civilization</mobygames_url>
				<giantbomb_url>https://www.giantbomb.com/sid-meiers-civilization/3030-3750/</giantbomb_url>
				<boxart1>Z6rgtOJ.jpg</boxart1>
				<boxart2>fDAsNMg.jpg</boxart2>
				<boxart3>168QOnw.jpg</boxart3>
				<boxart4>ozNAMuG.jpg</boxart4>
				<boxart5>jiIIMms.jpg</boxart5>
				<boxart6>At61kKO.jpg</boxart6>
				<snapshot1>JtLJwo1.gif</snapshot1>
				<snapshot2>N0bPpQs.gif</snapshot2>
				<snapshot3>t1MB4OS.gif</snapshot3>
				<snapshot4>bxmUs36.gif</snapshot4>
				<snapshot5>OdG4CBY.gif</snapshot5>
				<snapshot6>38jvN3r.gif</snapshot6>
				<snapshot7>C19GpKe.gif</snapshot7>
				<snapshot8>he2wAkA.gif</snapshot8>
				<snapshot9>6v7zhWI.gif</snapshot9>
				<snapshot10>vnkgvB7.gif</snapshot10>
				<emu_command>A4000</emu_command>
			</game>
			<game name="Dune II - The Battle for Arrakis">
				<description>11.  Dune II - The Battle for Arrakis</description>
				<rom name="AmigaROMsCoverArtCDEF/Amiga_ROMs_%26_CoverArt_C-D-E-F.zip/Dune%20II%20-%20The%20Battle%20for%20Arrakis%2FDune%20II%20-%20The%20Battle%20for%20Arrakis.Disk1.adf" size="901120" />
				<rom name="AmigaROMsCoverArtCDEF/Amiga_ROMs_%26_CoverArt_C-D-E-F.zip/Dune%20II%20-%20The%20Battle%20for%20Arrakis%2FDune%20II%20-%20The%20Battle%20for%20Arrakis.Disk2.adf" size="901120" />
				<rom name="AmigaROMsCoverArtCDEF/Amiga_ROMs_%26_CoverArt_C-D-E-F.zip/Dune%20II%20-%20The%20Battle%20for%20Arrakis%2FDune%20II%20-%20The%20Battle%20for%20Arrakis.Disk3.adf" size="901120" />
				<rom name="AmigaROMsCoverArtCDEF/Amiga_ROMs_%26_CoverArt_C-D-E-F.zip/Dune%20II%20-%20The%20Battle%20for%20Arrakis%2FDune%20II%20-%20The%20Battle%20for%20Arrakis.Disk4.adf" size="901120" />
				<rom name="AmigaROMsCoverArtCDEF/Amiga_ROMs_%26_CoverArt_C-D-E-F.zip/Dune%20II%20-%20The%20Battle%20for%20Arrakis%2FDune%20II%20-%20The%20Battle%20for%20Arrakis.Disk5.adf" size="901120" />
				<rom name="AmigaROMsCoverArtCDEF/Amiga_ROMs_%26_CoverArt_C-D-E-F.zip/Dune%20II%20-%20The%20Battle%20for%20Arrakis%2FDune%20II%20-%20The%20Battle%20for%20Arrakis.Disk6.adf" size="901120" />
				<title_clean>Dune II - The Battle for Arrakis</title_clean>
				<plot>Dune II is often considered the first mainstream modern real-time strategy game and established many conventions of the genre. Even though set in Frank Herbert's famous Dune universe, the game is only loosely connected to the plot of any of the books or the films based from them. Controlling either of the three Houses, the player must fight a number of battles against the other Houses. In the early levels, the goal is simply to earn a certain number of credits, while in the later missions, all enemies must be destroyed.[CR]The single resource in the game is the Spice, which must be collected by harvesters. The spice is converted to credits in a refinery, which are then spent to construct additional buildings and units. There are two terrain types: buildings can only be constructed on stone, while the Spice is only found on sand. However, units moving on sand attract the large sandworms of Dune, who are virtually indestructible and can swallow even large units whole. As levels progress, new and more advanced buildings and units are made available, including structures like a radar station, a repair facility or defense turrets and, for units, various ground troops, light vehicles and tanks. Each House can construct one unique special unit, and, after building a palace improvement, can unleash a unique palace effect.</plot>
				<rating>6.75</rating>
				<thegamesdb_id>9576</thegamesdb_id>
				<boxart1>5sS5cvj.jpg</boxart1>
				<emu_command>A4000</emu_command>
			</game>
			<game name="Sensible World of Soccer '96-'97">
				<description>10.  Sensible World of Soccer '96-'97</description>
				<rom name="AmigaROMsCoverArtRS/Amiga_ROMs_%26_CoverArt_R-S.zip/Sensible%20World%20of%20Soccer%20%2796-%2797%2FSensible%20World%20of%20Soccer%20%2796-%2797.Disk1.adf" size="901120" />
				<rom name="AmigaROMsCoverArtRS/Amiga_ROMs_%26_CoverArt_R-S.zip/Sensible%20World%20of%20Soccer%20%2796-%2797%2FSensible%20World%20of%20Soccer%20%2796-%2797.Disk2.adf" size="901120" />
				<title_clean>Sensible World of Soccer '96-'97</title_clean>
				<plot>The updated Sensible World of Soccer, with more up-to-date-teams and less of the bugs from the previous version.[CR]SWOS is a top down football/management game, with either quick game or 20-year career player-manager options. The games are set to last 3 minutes, but the 20-year career can suck in your entire life for a few months. The graphics are kept very small so the player can orientate themselves on the pitch without need for a radar. The controls are simple, easy to get used to and very effective. In the full career mode you can jump from club-to-club buying any of the game's 29000+ players, as well as play around with team tactics.[CR]And you can choose from 1400 teams over the five continents.</plot>
				<releasedate>30/3/1996</releasedate>
				<year>1996</year>
				<genre>Sports</genre>
				<studio>Renegade Software</studio>
				<nplayers>1-4 Sim</nplayers>
				<perspective>Top-Down</perspective>
				<rating>3.9</rating>
				<videoid>tNFOyF9bVt4</videoid>
				<thegamesdb_id>24494</thegamesdb_id>
				<mobygames_url>https://www.mobygames.com/game/amiga/sensible-world-of-soccer-9697</mobygames_url>
				<giantbomb_url>https://www.giantbomb.com/sensible-world-of-soccer-9697/3030-10022/</giantbomb_url>
				<boxart1>HLiWNMM.jpg</boxart1>
				<boxart2>WvYzHxy.jpg</boxart2>
				<boxart3>0JR3O1B.jpg</boxart3>
				<emu_command>A4000</emu_command>
			</game>
			<game name="UFO - Enemy Unknown (AGA)">
				<description>9.  UFO - Enemy Unknown</description>
				<rom name="AmigaROMsCoverArtTUVWXYZ/Amiga_ROMs_%26_CoverArt_T-U-V-W-X-Y-Z.zip/UFO%20-%20Enemy%20Unknown%2FUFO%20-%20Enemy%20Unknown%20%28AGA%29.Disk1.adf" size="901120" />
				<rom name="AmigaROMsCoverArtTUVWXYZ/Amiga_ROMs_%26_CoverArt_T-U-V-W-X-Y-Z.zip/UFO%20-%20Enemy%20Unknown%2FUFO%20-%20Enemy%20Unknown%20%28AGA%29.Disk2.adf" size="901120" />
				<rom name="AmigaROMsCoverArtTUVWXYZ/Amiga_ROMs_%26_CoverArt_T-U-V-W-X-Y-Z.zip/UFO%20-%20Enemy%20Unknown%2FUFO%20-%20Enemy%20Unknown%20%28AGA%29.Disk3.adf" size="901120" />
				<rom name="AmigaROMsCoverArtTUVWXYZ/Amiga_ROMs_%26_CoverArt_T-U-V-W-X-Y-Z.zip/UFO%20-%20Enemy%20Unknown%2FUFO%20-%20Enemy%20Unknown%20%28AGA%29.Disk4.adf" size="901120" />
				<title_clean>UFO - Enemy Unknown</title_clean>
				<plot>In the year 1998, the amount of reports of UFO sightings has been drastically increased. Stories about abductions and alien attacks became more and more widespread. Finally, after various nations of the world have failed to intercept the UFOs, their representatives met in a conference of global importance in Geneva, Switzerland. It was eventually decided to organize a secret paramilitary group, dubbed Extraterrestrial Combat Unit (X-COM). Starting with one base, two fighters, one transport, and a few soldiers, X-COM must locate the aliens, learn about their origins and technology, find out where their base is, and destroy it.</plot>
				<thegamesdb_id>9554</thegamesdb_id>
				<boxart1>8NuShrw.jpg</boxart1>
				<clearlogo1>H2aw2fp.png</clearlogo1>
				<emu_command>A4000</emu_command>
			</game>
			<game name="Turrican II - The Final Fight">
				<description>8.  Turrican II - The Final Fight</description>
				<rom name="AmigaROMsCoverArtTUVWXYZ/Amiga_ROMs_%26_CoverArt_T-U-V-W-X-Y-Z.zip/Turrican%20II%20-%20The%20Final%20Fight%2FTurrican%20II%20-%20The%20Final%20Fight.Disk1.adf" size="901120" />
				<rom name="AmigaROMsCoverArtTUVWXYZ/Amiga_ROMs_%26_CoverArt_T-U-V-W-X-Y-Z.zip/Turrican%20II%20-%20The%20Final%20Fight%2FTurrican%20II%20-%20The%20Final%20Fight.Disk2.adf" size="901120" />
				<title_clean>Turrican II - The Final Fight</title_clean>
				<plot>Turrican II: The Final Fight is a platformer/shooter as typically seen on consoles, but designed for home computers from the ground up.[CR]Its plot is - naturally - very simple: an evil mega-robot called The Machine attacks the United Planets Ship Avalon 1, slaughtering all who resist. All - except Bren McGuire, who manages to escape and slips into the experimental Turrican bionic armor. As Turrican, he strives to show The Machine who's the boss.[CR]Unlike other games of its type, this game contains three levels of horizontal shooter action in the spirit of R-Type or the developers' own Katakis. Six large worlds are to be explored, where you are basically free to go everywhere you want, since there is no automatic scrolling and the levels are packed with hidden extra lives and weapons. All those levels are very different: the first one in the rock desert is pretty colorful with parallaxing rainbow background and happy music, while the following worlds get darker and darker.[CR]Turrican can get some different weapons for his arm cannon:[CR]1. The bounce weapon which rebounds from surfaces into smaller bouncing balls when powered up;[CR]The laser, which can shoots beams as large as Turrican himself when maxed out;[CR] the multiple shot beam, which can shoot up to five beams covering approximately a 90 degree angle.[CR]The Turrican suit weaponry is not limited to the arm cannon however:[CR]1. He also can fire a continuous beam, activated by holding the fire button. This beam can be rotated around Turrican, so it is possible to blast things below him in this way;[CR]Additionally, he can fire power lines by pressing the space bar, resulting in two energy bars as high as the screen going from the Turrican suit to the left and right of the screen, severely damaging enemies in the process;[CR]If the space bar is pressed when the hero is crouching, the Turrican will morph into a shuriken shape. In this state, it will roll to the left or the right, damaging enemies while being invincible and small bombs can be dropped by pressing the fire button;[CR]Finally, the most powerful attack, which can only be used one time per life, can be delivered by pressing the fire button and the space bar at the same time. The Turrican suit will morph into a shuriken shape and fly around the screen for several seconds, while firing shots of the different weapons in multiple directions.</plot>
				<releasedate>30/3/1991</releasedate>
				<year>1991</year>
				<genre>Action</genre>
				<studio>Rainbow Arts Software GmbH</studio>
				<nplayers>1</nplayers>
				<perspective>3rd-Person</perspective>
				<rating>4.1</rating>
				<thegamesdb_id>9516</thegamesdb_id>
				<mobygames_url>https://www.mobygames.com/game/amiga/turrican-ii-the-final-fight</mobygames_url>
				<giantbomb_url>https://www.giantbomb.com/turrican-ii-the-final-fight/3030-18041/</giantbomb_url>
				<boxart1>M7uovzJ.jpg</boxart1>
				<boxart2>V5hVa9p.jpg</boxart2>
				<boxart3>3MJ0bfx.jpg</boxart3>
				<boxart4>LCAWdzZ.jpg</boxart4>
				<snapshot1>BYnUZmw.jpg</snapshot1>
				<snapshot2>IOWS0bl.jpg</snapshot2>
				<snapshot3>MZA1IKG.jpg</snapshot3>
				<snapshot4>d24NBvM.jpg</snapshot4>
				<snapshot5>sllsTRv.jpg</snapshot5>
				<snapshot6>gMpxzvT.jpg</snapshot6>
				<snapshot7>3J1XurH.jpg</snapshot7>
				<snapshot8>whew6mq.png</snapshot8>
				<snapshot9>ZsLE78H.png</snapshot9>
				<snapshot10>Qe5KgOf.png</snapshot10>
				<clearlogo1>vPBTgzw.png</clearlogo1>
				<emu_command>A4000</emu_command>
			</game>
			<game name="Simon the Sorcerer (AGA)">
				<description>7.  Simon the Sorcerer</description>
				<rom name="AmigaROMsCoverArtRS/Amiga_ROMs_%26_CoverArt_R-S.zip/Simon%20the%20Sorcerer%20%28AGA%29%2FSimon%20the%20Sorcerer%20%28AGA%29.Disk1.adf" size="901120" />
				<rom name="AmigaROMsCoverArtRS/Amiga_ROMs_%26_CoverArt_R-S.zip/Simon%20the%20Sorcerer%20%28AGA%29%2FSimon%20the%20Sorcerer%20%28AGA%29.Disk2.adf" size="901120" />
				<rom name="AmigaROMsCoverArtRS/Amiga_ROMs_%26_CoverArt_R-S.zip/Simon%20the%20Sorcerer%20%28AGA%29%2FSimon%20the%20Sorcerer%20%28AGA%29.Disk3.adf" size="901120" />
				<rom name="AmigaROMsCoverArtRS/Amiga_ROMs_%26_CoverArt_R-S.zip/Simon%20the%20Sorcerer%20%28AGA%29%2FSimon%20the%20Sorcerer%20%28AGA%29.Disk4.adf" size="901120" />
				<rom name="AmigaROMsCoverArtRS/Amiga_ROMs_%26_CoverArt_R-S.zip/Simon%20the%20Sorcerer%20%28AGA%29%2FSimon%20the%20Sorcerer%20%28AGA%29.Disk5.adf" size="901120" />
				<rom name="AmigaROMsCoverArtRS/Amiga_ROMs_%26_CoverArt_R-S.zip/Simon%20the%20Sorcerer%20%28AGA%29%2FSimon%20the%20Sorcerer%20%28AGA%29.Disk6.adf" size="901120" />
				<rom name="AmigaROMsCoverArtRS/Amiga_ROMs_%26_CoverArt_R-S.zip/Simon%20the%20Sorcerer%20%28AGA%29%2FSimon%20the%20Sorcerer%20%28AGA%29.Disk7.adf" size="901120" />
				<rom name="AmigaROMsCoverArtRS/Amiga_ROMs_%26_CoverArt_R-S.zip/Simon%20the%20Sorcerer%20%28AGA%29%2FSimon%20the%20Sorcerer%20%28AGA%29.Disk8.adf" size="901120" />
				<rom name="AmigaROMsCoverArtRS/Amiga_ROMs_%26_CoverArt_R-S.zip/Simon%20the%20Sorcerer%20%28AGA%29%2FSimon%20the%20Sorcerer%20%28AGA%29.Disk9.adf" size="901120" />
				<title_clean>Simon the Sorcerer</title_clean>
				<plot>[CR]Simon[CR]The story begins when Simon's dog "Chippy" discovers a chest in the loft of his house. Inside the chest he finds a very old and dirty book, titled " Ye Olde Spellbooke". Not interested in dusty old books, Simon throws it onto the floor. Surprisingly a magical portal appears when the book hits the floor. Being a ordinary teenager, Simon does not know what to do. However, that changes when Chippy decides to enter. Not wanting to lose his faithful dog, Simon decides to follow. After entering the portal, Simon finds himself in another world - more precisely he finds himself in a cauldron. It appears that some goblins see him as their lunch! Regretting the fact that he entered the portal, he manages to escape. Simon finds that a wizard called Calypso has been kidnapped by another wizard who goes by the name of The Evil Sordid. The only person who will send Simon back is Calypso, and so his quest begins, armed with humour, rudeness and sarcasm.[CR]Simon is voiced by UK based comedian and actor Chris Barrie who is the star of the popular TV series Red Dwarf.[CR][B]Gameplay:[/B][CR]Simon the Sorcerer is a point-and-click adventure game. The magical world Simon finds himself features parodies of many known fantasy stories: Narnia, Lord of the Rings, Rapunzel and The Three Billy Goats Gruff. Simon can travel around the nearby village, the forest and the mountains at the start of the game.[CR]Digital Distribution[CR]Simon the Sorcerer was re-released by Good Old Games with compatibility &amp; support for Windows XP, Vista, and 7 for both 32 and 64-bit.[CR]</plot>
				<releasedate>30/3/1994</releasedate>
				<year>1994</year>
				<genre>Adventure</genre>
				<studio>Adventuresoft Ltd.</studio>
				<nplayers>1</nplayers>
				<perspective>3rd-Person</perspective>
				<rating>2.0</rating>
				<thegamesdb_id>10314</thegamesdb_id>
				<mobygames_url>https://www.mobygames.com/game/amiga/simon-the-sorcerer</mobygames_url>
				<giantbomb_url>https://www.giantbomb.com/simon-the-sorcerer/3030-12260/</giantbomb_url>
				<boxart1>8sxpzrc.jpg</boxart1>
				<boxart2>DuRXwGE.jpg</boxart2>
				<boxart3>AyjuHzD.jpg</boxart3>
				<boxart4>8ORFIkR.jpg</boxart4>
				<boxart5>4L7Zton.jpg</boxart5>
				<boxart6>YghLIX5.jpg</boxart6>
				<boxart7>hsTyDPW.jpg</boxart7>
				<boxart8>sqyUpUv.jpg</boxart8>
				<boxart9>P8XLiA7.jpg</boxart9>
				<boxart10>8u6kXyY.jpg</boxart10>
				<snapshot1>jcY0369.jpg</snapshot1>
				<snapshot2>G6vR9ki.jpg</snapshot2>
				<snapshot3>k54jAPz.jpg</snapshot3>
				<snapshot4>eL7vLib.jpg</snapshot4>
				<snapshot5>5YzJhbX.jpg</snapshot5>
				<snapshot6>8vOV1hw.jpg</snapshot6>
				<snapshot7>osyLk6M.jpg</snapshot7>
				<snapshot8>OWExlPZ.jpg</snapshot8>
				<snapshot9>dnYmJQR.jpg</snapshot9>
				<snapshot10>Xvptlo5.jpg</snapshot10>
				<clearlogo1>GyF3NIC.png</clearlogo1>
				<emu_command>A4000</emu_command>
			</game>
			<game name="Slam Tilt - The Pinball Game (AGA)">
				<description>6.  Slam Tilt - The Pinball Game</description>
				<rom name="AmigaROMsCoverArtRS/Amiga_ROMs_%26_CoverArt_R-S.zip/Slam%20Tilt%20-%20The%20Pinball%20Game%2FSlam%20Tilt%20-%20The%20Pinball%20Game%20%28AGA%29.Disk1.adf" size="901120" />
				<rom name="AmigaROMsCoverArtRS/Amiga_ROMs_%26_CoverArt_R-S.zip/Slam%20Tilt%20-%20The%20Pinball%20Game%2FSlam%20Tilt%20-%20The%20Pinball%20Game%20%28AGA%29.Disk2.adf" size="901120" />
				<rom name="AmigaROMsCoverArtRS/Amiga_ROMs_%26_CoverArt_R-S.zip/Slam%20Tilt%20-%20The%20Pinball%20Game%2FSlam%20Tilt%20-%20The%20Pinball%20Game%20%28AGA%29.Disk3.adf" size="901120" />
				<rom name="AmigaROMsCoverArtRS/Amiga_ROMs_%26_CoverArt_R-S.zip/Slam%20Tilt%20-%20The%20Pinball%20Game%2FSlam%20Tilt%20-%20The%20Pinball%20Game%20%28AGA%29.Disk4.adf" size="901120" />
				<rom name="AmigaROMsCoverArtRS/Amiga_ROMs_%26_CoverArt_R-S.zip/Slam%20Tilt%20-%20The%20Pinball%20Game%2FSlam%20Tilt%20-%20The%20Pinball%20Game%20%28AGA%29.Disk5.adf" size="901120" />
				<title_clean>Slam Tilt - The Pinball Game</title_clean>
				<plot>Liquid Dezign featured many of the Digital Illusions team who developed 21st Century's hit pinball games, and after the generally-disliked Pinball Mania from another team, they produced one last Amiga pinball game.[CR]The game features four different tables, each with different layouts and features. A large number of sub-games are included, as well as a variety of animations on the LCD panel at the top. Each table has multi-ball features, with the view automatically switching to full-screen when this is activated. in total there are six different viewpoints, and no less than 47 different game modes are promised.</plot>
				<releasedate>30/3/1996</releasedate>
				<year>1996</year>
				<genre>Simulation</genre>
				<studio>21st Century Entertainment Ltd.</studio>
				<nplayers>1-8 Sim</nplayers>
				<perspective>Top-Down</perspective>
				<rating>3.9</rating>
				<mobygames_url>https://www.mobygames.com/game/amiga/slam-tilt</mobygames_url>
				<giantbomb_url>https://www.giantbomb.com/slam-tilt/3030-1155/</giantbomb_url>
				<boxart1>Q3kC1xR.jpg</boxart1>
				<snapshot1>vLmWpcz.gif</snapshot1>
				<snapshot2>X8DPSOx.gif</snapshot2>
				<snapshot3>v3Ah9y0.gif</snapshot3>
				<snapshot4>fRxbXAW.gif</snapshot4>
				<snapshot5>5rmdipG.gif</snapshot5>
				<snapshot6>EITAGhl.gif</snapshot6>
				<snapshot7>SfaqHrA.gif</snapshot7>
				<snapshot8>noHengN.gif</snapshot8>
				<snapshot9>27yozxS.gif</snapshot9>
				<snapshot10>VYl4hz2.gif</snapshot10>
				<emu_command>A4000</emu_command>
			</game>
			<game name="Settlers, The">
				<description>5.  The Settlers</description>
				<rom name="AmigaROMsCoverArtRS/Amiga_ROMs_%26_CoverArt_R-S.zip/Settlers%2C%20The%2FSettlers%2C%20The.Disk1.adf" size="901120" />
				<rom name="AmigaROMsCoverArtRS/Amiga_ROMs_%26_CoverArt_R-S.zip/Settlers%2C%20The%2FSettlers%2C%20The.Disk2.adf" size="901120" />
				<rom name="AmigaROMsCoverArtRS/Amiga_ROMs_%26_CoverArt_R-S.zip/Settlers%2C%20The%2FSettlers%2C%20The.Disk3.adf" size="901120" />
				<title_clean>Settlers, The</title_clean>
				<plot>The Settlers (also known as Serf City: Life is Feudal, original German title Die Siedler) is a slow-paced strategy video game by Blue Byte Software, released in 1993 for Commodore Amiga and in 1994 for the PC. The player is tasked with building a medieval settlement populated by an army of workers, each of whom perform their own individual task. The player competes against computer controlled opponents or another human player for supremacy of the land and resources.</plot>
				<releasedate>1/12/1993</releasedate>
				<genre>Construction and Management Simulation, Life Simulation, Strategy</genre>
				<nplayers>1</nplayers>
				<thegamesdb_id>24591</thegamesdb_id>
				<boxart1>TJsMobu.jpg</boxart1>
				<clearlogo1>RetGX7p.png</clearlogo1>
				<emu_command>A4000</emu_command>
			</game>
			<game name="Cannon Fodder">
				<description>4.  Cannon Fodder</description>
				<rom name="AmigaROMsCoverArtCDEF/Amiga_ROMs_%26_CoverArt_C-D-E-F.zip/Cannon%20Fodder%2FCannon%20Fodder.Disk1.adf" size="901120" />
				<rom name="AmigaROMsCoverArtCDEF/Amiga_ROMs_%26_CoverArt_C-D-E-F.zip/Cannon%20Fodder%2FCannon%20Fodder.Disk2.adf" size="901120" />
				<rom name="AmigaROMsCoverArtCDEF/Amiga_ROMs_%26_CoverArt_C-D-E-F.zip/Cannon%20Fodder%2FCannon%20Fodder.Disk3.adf" size="901120" />
				<title_clean>Cannon Fodder</title_clean>
				<plot>After the success of Cannon Fodder, a sequel was inevitable. The basic gameplay remained the same  guide a team of soldiers through a succession of levels populated by trees, huts and lakes. [CR]The major change is that the plot involves time travel, rather than straightforward war situations, and this means levels taking place in different scenarios including a strange Alien Planet. [CR]The levels include a variety of vehicles such as jeeps, tanks and helicopters, which can be used to shoot or even run down enemy soldiers. Standard bullets are joined by collectible grenades  use these wisely, as nothing else can destroy huts or vehicles. Finding strategic defence positions can be vital as well.</plot>
				<releasedate>30/3/1994</releasedate>
				<year>1994</year>
				<genre>Action, Strategy</genre>
				<studio>Virgin Interactive Entertainment (Europe) Ltd.</studio>
				<nplayers>1</nplayers>
				<perspective>3rd-Person</perspective>
				<rating>4.1</rating>
				<ESRB>T - Teen</ESRB>
				<videoid>HqRag50MCek</videoid>
				<thegamesdb_id>20186</thegamesdb_id>
				<mobygames_url>https://www.mobygames.com/game/amiga/cannon-fodder-2</mobygames_url>
				<giantbomb_url>https://www.giantbomb.com/cannon-fodder-2/3030-16384/</giantbomb_url>
				<boxart1>CbQRdqx.jpg</boxart1>
				<boxart2>YqmbLmt.jpg</boxart2>
				<boxart3>ZstOP6U.jpg</boxart3>
				<boxart4>uFVidfs.jpg</boxart4>
				<boxart5>FZ6Zrf2.jpg</boxart5>
				<boxart6>GB9V17B.jpg</boxart6>
				<snapshot1>Mg77sPw.jpg</snapshot1>
				<snapshot2>MNChLCE.gif</snapshot2>
				<snapshot3>ckGZssr.gif</snapshot3>
				<snapshot4>2ApEdBV.gif</snapshot4>
				<snapshot5>kQysaXG.gif</snapshot5>
				<snapshot6>CP6Y9KW.gif</snapshot6>
				<snapshot7>4djsRBG.gif</snapshot7>
				<snapshot8>KGw7RrF.gif</snapshot8>
				<snapshot9>Xe3NAiG.gif</snapshot9>
				<snapshot10>u3fja2X.gif</snapshot10>
				<clearlogo1>do0mT6z.png</clearlogo1>
				<emu_command>A4000</emu_command>
			</game>
			<game name="Sensible World of Soccer '95-'96 - European Championship Edition">
				<description>3.  Sensible World of Soccer '95-'96 - European Championship Edition</description>
				<rom name="AmigaROMsCoverArtRS/Amiga_ROMs_%26_CoverArt_R-S.zip/Sensible%20World%20of%20Soccer%20%2795-%2796%20-%20European%20Championship%20Edition%2FSensible%20World%20of%20Soccer%20%2795-%2796%20-%20European%20Championship%20Edition.Disk1.adf" size="901120" />
				<rom name="AmigaROMsCoverArtRS/Amiga_ROMs_%26_CoverArt_R-S.zip/Sensible%20World%20of%20Soccer%20%2795-%2796%20-%20European%20Championship%20Edition%2FSensible%20World%20of%20Soccer%20%2795-%2796%20-%20European%20Championship%20Edition.Disk2.adf" size="901120" />
				<title_clean>Sensible World of Soccer '95-'96 - European Championship Edition</title_clean>
				<plot>A "sequel" of sorts to Sensible Software's 1996 Sensible World of Soccer, a great conversion of the company's famous Amiga football (soccer) game. Based on the teams that played in Euro '96 tournament, SWOS: European Championship Edition sports new features that make the game even more addictive than SWOS, including the ability to pull off looping headers and curved passes, trial players, international management, and more charming cartoony graphics such as animated crowd and goal celebrations. Like its spiritual predecessor SWOS, the PC version of SWOS: ECE features digitized match commentary and funny animation sequences</plot>
				<releasedate>14/4/1996</releasedate>
				<year>1996</year>
				<genre>Sports</genre>
				<studio>Renegade Software</studio>
				<perspective>Top-Down</perspective>
				<rating>4.5</rating>
				<mobygames_url>https://www.mobygames.com/game/amiga/sensible-world-of-soccer-european-championship-edition</mobygames_url>
				<giantbomb_url>https://www.giantbomb.com/sensible-world-of-soccer-european-championship-edi/3030-16986/</giantbomb_url>
				<boxart1>ucRm6gE.jpg</boxart1>
				<emu_command>A4000</emu_command>
			</game>
			<game name="Lemmings">
				<description>2.  Lemmings</description>
				<rom name="AmigaROMsCoverArtGHIJKL/Amiga_ROMs_%26_CoverArt_G-H-I-J-K-L.zip/Lemmings%2FLemmings.Disk1.adf" size="901120" />
				<rom name="AmigaROMsCoverArtGHIJKL/Amiga_ROMs_%26_CoverArt_G-H-I-J-K-L.zip/Lemmings%2FLemmings.Disk2.adf" size="901120" />
				<title_clean>Lemmings</title_clean>
				<plot>[CR][B]Overview:[/B][CR]The first level - 'Just Dig'.Originally an Amiga exclusive, developed by DMA design (later becoming Rockstar North) was met with an exceptional reception and was quickly ported to many different platforms. A puzzle game that requires players to direct a group of green haired, blue-shirted, lemmings from point A to point B. The game is based on the myth that lemmings migrate in large groups and follow a single leader, who would often lead them off a cliff to their demise. In the game, lemmings constantly march in one direction unless they run into an obstacle, at which point they turn around and walk the other way. Being fearless and unaware of their own mortality, the lemmings will blindly run into fire, jump off cliffs, become crushed and fall victim to numerous other pitfalls.The player must command the lemmings to do certain tasks in order to complete each stage and get a certain percentage of lemmings to safety. These actions include digging, using a pick axe to dig diagonally, using their arms (windmill style) to punch horizontally through terrain and building staircases to traverse large gaps.[CR][B]Levels:[/B][CR]All levels in Lemmings consist of at least one entrance, and at least one exit. The aim in each level is to safely get an allocated amount of lemmings towards an exit. Obstacles; such as water, deadly traps and great heights will hinder the lemmings' progress.There are 120 levels in total, split into four difficulty ratings - Fun, Tricky, Taxing, and Mayhem.[CR][B]Skills:[/B][CR]There are eight different skills available for the lemmings to carry out. Each level has a different selection and amount of abilities available. Different situations require the use of different skills.Several lemmings using the 'floater' skill.The skills are:Climbers - Climbers will climb a vertical surface until they reach the end of the surface.Diggers - Diggers will dig downward vertically through any soft surface until they reach empty space impenetrable surface.Miners - These will dig diagonally downward through any soft surface until they reach empty space impenetrable surface.Bashers - Will dig horizontally through a wall made of any soft surface until they reach empty space impenetrable surface.Builders - Will build a 12 step stairway diagonally upwards.Blockers - Will stop walking and block the advances of other lemmings, causing them to reverse their course.Bombers - A countdown will appear above their head, counting from 5 to 0. Upon reaching zero, they will explode.Floaters - Using an umbrella, these lemmings will float down a long drop.Lemmings being nuked.Three other types of commands can be used by the player, these are:Drop rate - The player may increase and decrease the rate in which lemmings fall from the entrance.Pause - The player may temporarily halt the game, this mode can be used to select skills without using any extra time on the clock.Nuke - If the player has reached a dead end and cannot finish the level then this button can be clicked in order to blow up every lemming on the screen.[CR]</plot>
				<releasedate>14/2/1991</releasedate>
				<year>1991</year>
				<genre>Strategy</genre>
				<studio>Psygnosis Limited</studio>
				<nplayers>1-2 Sim</nplayers>
				<perspective>3rd-Person</perspective>
				<rating>4.1</rating>
				<thegamesdb_id>9546</thegamesdb_id>
				<mobygames_url>https://www.mobygames.com/game/amiga/lemmings</mobygames_url>
				<giantbomb_url>https://www.giantbomb.com/lemmings/3030-1446/</giantbomb_url>
				<boxart1>muVamFa.jpg</boxart1>
				<boxart2>icCvAXD.jpg</boxart2>
				<boxart3>h8X2fUU.jpg</boxart3>
				<boxart4>JgnztMx.jpg</boxart4>
				<boxart5>81oLedE.jpg</boxart5>
				<boxart6>ZmmD0Rq.jpg</boxart6>
				<boxart7>ckxCn7D.jpg</boxart7>
				<boxart8>ktIvWMa.jpg</boxart8>
				<snapshot1>5LanQJ2.gif</snapshot1>
				<snapshot2>upcv0B4.gif</snapshot2>
				<snapshot3>7Inu3SM.gif</snapshot3>
				<snapshot4>VKU1m5X.gif</snapshot4>
				<snapshot5>2gWJIsr.gif</snapshot5>
				<snapshot6>IC5Kw7R.gif</snapshot6>
				<snapshot7>XwPy4jZ.gif</snapshot7>
				<snapshot8>AHsxglm.gif</snapshot8>
				<snapshot9>KlqYSPH.gif</snapshot9>
				<snapshot10>2pTakS7.gif</snapshot10>
				<clearlogo1>1jFdN2D.png</clearlogo1>
				<emu_command>A4000</emu_command>
			</game>
			<game name="Secret of Monkey Island, The">
				<description>1.  The Secret of Monkey Island</description>
				<rom name="AmigaROMsCoverArtRS/Amiga_ROMs_%26_CoverArt_R-S.zip/Secret%20of%20Monkey%20Island%2C%20The%2FSecret%20of%20Monkey%20Island%2C%20The.Disk1.adf" size="901120" />
				<rom name="AmigaROMsCoverArtRS/Amiga_ROMs_%26_CoverArt_R-S.zip/Secret%20of%20Monkey%20Island%2C%20The%2FSecret%20of%20Monkey%20Island%2C%20The.Disk2.adf" size="901120" />
				<rom name="AmigaROMsCoverArtRS/Amiga_ROMs_%26_CoverArt_R-S.zip/Secret%20of%20Monkey%20Island%2C%20The%2FSecret%20of%20Monkey%20Island%2C%20The.Disk3.adf" size="901120" />
				<rom name="AmigaROMsCoverArtRS/Amiga_ROMs_%26_CoverArt_R-S.zip/Secret%20of%20Monkey%20Island%2C%20The%2FSecret%20of%20Monkey%20Island%2C%20The.Disk4.adf" size="901120" />
				<title_clean>Secret of Monkey Island, The</title_clean>
				<plot>[CR][B]Story:[/B][CR]Guybrush Threepwood, a young man with desires to become a mighty pirate, travels to Melee Island, a pirate haven. Upon arrival he meets three " important looking pirates" in the SCUMM Bar who set him three challenges to test his worthiness. These entail defeating the legendary insult sword fighting master Carla, finding buried treasure and stealing a statue from the governors mansion. During a botched break-in to the mansion he meets and subsequently falls in love with the governor Elaine Marley. Elsewhere the ghost pirate LeChuck is seen pining after the love of his life, the same Elaine Marley, and hatches a plan to capture her. While Guybrush is busy finishing the trials LeChuck and his ghost pirate crew abduct her and take her to Monkey Island. Upon completing the trials Guybrush discovers this revelation, purchases a ship from Stan, a used ship salesman who informs him the ship requires a crew of four people. After gathering Carla, the sword fighting Master he had previously defeated, Meathook, a pirate with two hooks replacing his hands, and Otis a prisoner in Melee Island's Prison Guybrush and crew set sail in pursuit to rescue her.[CR]Upon setting sail Guybrush's crew mutinied against him, and decided to sunbathe instead. After following the instructions on his map to get to Monkey Island, he shoots himself onto the island.;[CR]Arriving at Monkey Island he discovers a strange band of cannibals and a hermit named Herman Toothrot. After helping the cannibals recover a lost voodoo ingredient they provide him with a recipe to destroy ghosts. When attempting to confront LeChuck however he finds only a single crewman who informs him of LeChuck's intention to marry Elaine on Melee Island. He sets sail once more.[CR]Returning to Melee Island he arrives at the church with intent to prevent the marriage but finds Elaine had her own plan of escape. LeChuck attacks Guybrush and after lengthy exchange the two arrive at the ship emporium whereupon Guybrush sprays LeChuck with root beer, the cannibals ghost fighting elixir being made from voodoo root. With LeChuck demise Guybrush and Elaine share a romantic moment, watching fireworks.[CR]Development[CR]Developed by Ron Gilbert, Dave Grossman and Tim Schafer, The Secret of Monkey Island began production shortly after Gilbert finished work on Indiana Jones and the Last Crusade. The pirate premise of the game was inspired by Gilbert's love of The Pirates of the Caribbean ride in Disneyland. His desire was to create a lush and fanciful world fill with swashbuckling pirates much like those seen in classic film and literature.[CR]The team's desire was to create a more accessible adventure game that anyone at any skill level could enjoy. Until then the genre had been known for being filled with difficult and often esoteric puzzles and full of trial and error gameplay. Gilbert and company hoped to avoid this by offering non linear puzzle sections such as The Three Trials where the player is free to work on a second puzzle if another becomes too difficult. The series also set the precedent in Lucasarts adventures of never allowing the player to die.[CR]Just before the game was set to ship, the company responsible for boxing the games and shipping to retailers told Lucasarts that they could not fill the order in time due to need to give their workers time off. This prompted nearly all of the Lucasarts staff to, themselves, box and ship all of the initial copies of The Secret of Monkey Island. Gilbert has said that during this time he, Grossman and Schafer each signed a one dollar bill and slipped it into one of the boxes. It's unknown if anyone ever found it.[CR]Insult Sword Fighting[CR]When sword fighting, it's not enough to have the right technique, you must also be able to parry an opponent's insults with appropriately witty responses. For example; the correct response to "You fight like a dairy farmer!" would be "How appropriate, you fight like a cow!". If the fighter responds with the correct come back, he earns the right to dish out the next insult. The first to three insults wins the fight.[CR]In-Jokes[CR]The Secret of Monkey Island is filled with references to Loom, another Lucasarts game released around the same time. Early in the game Guybrush encounters Cobb, a character from Loom who wears an "Ask me about Loom" button, who's only response to Guybush's attempts at conversation are "Aye". That is, however, until Guybrush asks him about Loom. Cobb then launches into full advertisement on the games excellent story and wonderful soundtrack. Other references to Loom include a seagull from them game and the line "I'm Bobbin, are you my mother?" after Guybrush is fired from a cannon.[CR]The game also takes a shot at fellow developer Sierra. At one point in the game the player can make Guybrush fall off a mountain resulting in a game over screen similar to those found in Sierra's adventure games that says "Oh, no! You've really screwed up this time! Guess you'll have to start over! Hope you saved the game!". After a few moments Guybrush flys back up the mountain and the game continues as normal.[CR]Easter Eggs[CR]When the ' Important Looking Pirates' in the Scumm Bar ask Guybrush if he has any special skills, one dialogue option is to tell them that he can hold his breath for 10 minutes. Later, when Fester Shinetop throws you into the water, if you wait 10 minutes you'll see Guybrush drown, bloat up, and a load is required.[CR]The Special Edition also includes a few references to past Lucas-Arts titles:In the cave where Le Chuck's vessel is anchored you'll see the face of Manny Calavera, the protogonist of Grim Fandango, hidden in one of the skull-filled speleothems.At the Giant Monkey Head there's an idol statue of The Purple Tentacle from Maniac Mansion: Day of the Tentacle.[CR]The Secret of Monkey Island: Special Edition[CR]Special Edition Box Art[CR]On July 15, 2009, an updated "Special Edition" version of The Secret of Monkey Island was released on Xbox Live Arcade, PC, and iPhone/iPod touch (the game was later released on the PlayStation Network on April 22, 2010). This re-imagining has remained completely faithful to the original game, featuring updated 1080i graphics, new music, hand drawn recreations of all the characters, items, &amp; backgrounds, as well as full voice overs using the voice cast from The Curse of Monkey Island.[CR]The game has been given a streamlined interface designed to work better with a console controller. Players also have the ability to switch between the original version of the game and the special edition at any time with one button so that those who prefer the old style can still enjoy the experience. Moreover this version includes a built-in hint system for those who need it, which has three varying levels, but is a completely optional feature to use.[CR]PC System Requirements[CR]OriginalMS-DOS 5.0 or higher1 Mb of EMS required (2 Mb recommended)386/33 DX (486 DX recommended)Sounblaster and 100% compatibles, Adlib, Roland MT 32Special EditionWindows XP or VistaProcessor: Intel Pentium 4 3GHz or AMD Athlon 64 3000Memory: 256 MB RAM, 512 MB for VistaGraphics: 128 MB with Shader Model 2.0 capabilityDirectX: 9.0c (March 2009)Hard Drive: 2.5GB free hard drive spaceSound: DirectX 9.0c compliant sound card[CR]</plot>
				<releasedate>30/3/1991</releasedate>
				<year>1991</year>
				<genre>Adventure</genre>
				<studio>Lucasfilm Games LLC</studio>
				<nplayers>1</nplayers>
				<perspective>3rd-Person</perspective>
				<videoid>KFPFFZs5m_w</videoid>
				<thegamesdb_id>20368</thegamesdb_id>
				<mobygames_url>https://www.mobygames.com/game/amiga/secret-of-monkey-island-demo-version</mobygames_url>
				<giantbomb_url>https://www.giantbomb.com/the-secret-of-monkey-island/3030-3019/</giantbomb_url>
				<boxart1>VHHUNjq.jpg</boxart1>
				<boxart2>O3nHy4J.jpg</boxart2>
				<snapshot1>5cTaxJ4.jpg</snapshot1>
				<snapshot2>EjSoTam.jpg</snapshot2>
				<snapshot3>kCJ6EvD.jpg</snapshot3>
				<snapshot4>SYLxARR.jpg</snapshot4>
				<clearlogo1>7rsGeQ7.png</clearlogo1>
				<emu_command>A4000</emu_command>
			</game>
</datafile>