<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<datafile>
    <header>
        <emu_name>Internet Archive Best Of - Amiga</emu_name>
        <emu_description>Amiga</emu_description>
        <emu_category>Amiga, 1980s, 16 Bit, PC, Best of</emu_category>
        <emu_version>02082020</emu_version>
        <emu_date>05.01.2017</emu_date>
        <emu_author>Zach Morris</emu_author>
        <emu_visibility>visible</emu_visibility>
        <emu_homepage>http://www.no-intro.org</emu_homepage>
        <emu_baseurl>https://archive.org/download/</emu_baseurl>
        <emu_launcher>retroplayer</emu_launcher>
        <emu_default_addon>none</emu_default_addon>
        <emu_ext_launch_cmd>none</emu_ext_launch_cmd>
        <emu_downloadpath>default</emu_downloadpath>
        <emu_postdlaction>none</emu_postdlaction>
        <emu_comment>For those who owned one, the Commodore Amiga home computer will always hold a special place in their heart. During the late eighties and early nineties, the various Amiga models that were realised during this time became the kings of the home computer market.[CR]Amiga fans will fondly remember the incredible gameplay of the titles released on the platform. It may have been an era when a computer's memory was measured in megabytes instead of gigabytes - graphics look positively antiquated by today's standards - and games could be spread across as many as fifteen floppy disks, but at the time, Commodore's machine was the best gaming computer you could own.[CR]Although it may be gone it's far from forgotten, with numerous releases today able to trace their lineage back to the Amiga's heyday. But out of all the classics that were released back then, here are the games considered the best.</emu_comment>
        <emu_thumb>yZpFsIK.jpg</emu_thumb>
        <emu_banner>ZwCuodA.jpg</emu_banner>
        <emu_fanart>DbOStGs.jpg</emu_fanart>
        <emu_logo>WxZIEbj.png</emu_logo>
        <emu_trailer>uXkYFqHyV98</emu_trailer>
    </header>
  <game name="Lionheart">
    <description>50.  Lionheart</description>
    <rom name="amigaromset/CommodoreAmigaRomset1.zip/Lionheart_v2.1b_0845.hdf" size="4358144"/>
    <rating>4.4</rating>
    <perspective>Platform</perspective>
    <studio>Thalion</studio>
    <releasedate>30/03/1992</releasedate>
    <year>1993</year>
    <plot>As Valdyn aka "Lionheart", you will have to travel deep into the territory of your king's enemy to retrieve a stolen holy relic which happens to be named "Lionheart" as well.[CR]The game itself is a platform/hack'n'slay affair, similar to Rastan. You proceed through the world that is scrolling in all directions and cut everything to pieces with your trusty sword that is cocky enough to come close to you.</plot>
    <genre>2D,Side Scroller</genre>
    <nplayers>1</nplayers>
    <boxart1>UZDHH0h.jpg</boxart1>
    <boxart2>ARk4r6P.jpg</boxart2>
    <boxart3>1RC180g.jpg</boxart3>
    <boxart4>rBRcEIl.jpg</boxart4>
    <snapshot1>kSDSAfT.png</snapshot1>
    <snapshot2>p3tl9aE.png</snapshot2>
    <snapshot3>e6CXMOn.png</snapshot3>
    <snapshot4>ngvdpWr.png</snapshot4>
    <snapshot5>7t80NG3.png</snapshot5>
    <snapshot6>dFxNAZX.png</snapshot6>
    <snapshot7>WK9HImL.png</snapshot7>
    <snapshot8>2be672q.png</snapshot8>
    <snapshot9>Uu6noim.png</snapshot9>
    <snapshot10>7RacFlq.png</snapshot10>
    <emu_command>A4000</emu_command>
  </game>
  <game name="Ishar 2: Messengers Of Doom (AGA)">
    <description>49.  Ishar 2 - Messengers of Doom (AGA)</description>
    <rom name="amigaromset/CommodoreAmigaRomset1.zip/Ishar2_v1.3a_AGA_0787.hdf" size="3850240"/>
    <rating>4.0</rating>
    <perspective>1st-Person</perspective>
    <studio>Silmarils</studio>
    <releasedate>30/03/1993</releasedate>
    <year>1993</year>
    <plot>_Ishar 2: Messengers of Doom_ is the sequel to Ishar: Legend of the Fortress.[CR]Following the defeat of Krogh and the banishment of the powers of chaos, Ishar became a cultural and intellectual centre in Kendoria. Over time people came to the island and settled there. A city named Zach's Island developed and flourished. Shandar, a monk of chaos, entered the city along with settlers from the northern lands. His trading in hallucinogens soon made him rich and powerful. Eventually Shandar controlled Zach's Island and had many followers and worshippers. He built a strong fortress, a second Ishar, to challenge the empire. The warrior Zubaran has a vision that sends him on the quest to defeat Shandar and save his homeland.[CR]The gameplay system is similar to that of the predecessor and includes exploration of 3D outdoor areas, towns, and dungeons, party management and real-time combat. In the sequel the player can import saved characters from _Ishar_ , or recruit characters to join Zubaran on the quest. The game world includes dungeons, tree-cities, mountain paths with real graded height effect. [CR]Unlike the first game, there is a day and night cycle in _Messengers of Doom_. Shops are closed during the day, and medieval nightclubs are open only at night. The game world is considerably larger than in the previous game. Other new features include the ability to use pet animals as allies in battles, and create magic potions.</plot>
    <genre>Fantasy</genre>
    <groups>Ishar series,Gameplay feature: Alchemy,Gameplay feature: Hunger / Thirst,Gameplay feature: Importable characters,Gameplay feature: Controllable pet companions,Gameplay feature: Day / Night cycle</groups>
    <nplayers>1</nplayers>
    <boxart1>jvwa68c.jpg</boxart1>
    <boxart2>FsX10a1.jpg</boxart2>
    <snapshot1>6B3kamI.png</snapshot1>
    <snapshot2>zBgNslF.png</snapshot2>
    <snapshot3>llh3BbB.png</snapshot3>
    <snapshot4>MIKBmjI.png</snapshot4>
    <snapshot5>SBTRc9T.png</snapshot5>
    <snapshot6>IuUFLVe.png</snapshot6>
    <snapshot7>OHmfK8U.png</snapshot7>
    <snapshot8>kSxRLRG.png</snapshot8>
    <snapshot9>dhf47if.png</snapshot9>
    <snapshot10>tKloxm6.png</snapshot10>
    <banner1>vfYZx4h.png</banner1>
    <emu_command>A4000</emu_command>
  </game>
  <game name="Dungeon Quest">
    <description>48.  Dungeon Quest</description>
    <rom name="amigaromset/CommodoreAmigaRomset1.zip/DungeonQuest_v1.0_0663.hdf" size="1949696"/>
    <rating>2.5</rating>
    <perspective>1st-Person</perspective>
    <studio>Gainstar</studio>
    <releasedate>30/03/1989</releasedate>
    <year>1989</year>
    <plot>In a far-off land, an evil force is in charge, and you set off with the intention of putting things right. Immediately you see signs of desolation and environmental failure, with lifeless and malnourished people all round. Still, you must not give up; your friend who lives amidst this needs your help. With full graphical depiction of events and places, this interactive fiction can be played purely using the keyboard, but the bottom half of the screen contains some mouse interaction for direction entry. You can move in four directions, examine and take objects, talk to people and solve puzzles.</plot>
    <genre>Fantasy</genre>
    <nplayers>1</nplayers>
    <boxart1>gmU1yHp.png</boxart1>
    <snapshot1>s8P7fYU.png</snapshot1>
    <snapshot2>v9T1bRX.png</snapshot2>
    <snapshot3>yYnRmow.png</snapshot3>
    <snapshot4>2Z6IVu5.png</snapshot4>
    <snapshot5>utQZRGV.png</snapshot5>
    <snapshot6>nmOjmg3.png</snapshot6>
    <snapshot7>sf2lZkB.png</snapshot7>
    <snapshot8>jJP1UXs.png</snapshot8>
    <snapshot9>GQtJstF.png</snapshot9>
    <snapshot10>9b1rfVc.png</snapshot10>
    <emu_command>A4000</emu_command>
  </game>
  <game name="Snow Bros. (Image)">
    <description>47.  Snow Bros.</description>
    <rom name="amigaromset/CommodoreAmigaRomset1.zip/SnowBros_v1.2_Image_2601.hdf" size="1261568"/>
    <rating>3.5</rating>
    <perspective>Platform</perspective>
    <studio>Ocean (unreleased)</studio>
    <releasedate>30/03/2006</releasedate>
    <plot>A conversion of the cult fave arcade rave. It's effectively Bubble Bobbie in a snowy clime but with a few appropriate twists and some neat cartoon visuals. It looks and plays identically to its arcade parent - well, save for the absence of the simultaneous two player option (it wasn't implemented because the action would have slowed down from the ideal running speed). Although scheduled for release in mid-1991 and completed, the Amiga conversion was never published. Later, the game was rediscovered and released for free.</plot>
    <genre>Fixed Screen</genre>
    <groups>Snow Bros. series</groups>
    <nplayers>1</nplayers>
    <boxart1>bvP4hTr.jpg</boxart1>
    <snapshot1>Tr8goLl.png</snapshot1>
    <snapshot2>rZevm8F.png</snapshot2>
    <snapshot3>Ra3IwmN.png</snapshot3>
    <snapshot4>PQcdDCT.png</snapshot4>
    <snapshot5>wuSmH81.png</snapshot5>
    <snapshot6>zNmQVMw.png</snapshot6>
    <snapshot7>93mnqZ6.png</snapshot7>
    <snapshot8>8ZYzKQi.png</snapshot8>
    <snapshot9>33Kl6TW.png</snapshot9>
    <snapshot10>GGvgSp0.png</snapshot10>
    <emu_command>A4000</emu_command>
  </game>
  <game name="Benefactor">
    <description>46.  Benefactor</description>
    <rom name="amigaromset/CommodoreAmigaRomset1.zip/Benefactor_v1.1_0636.hdf" size="3702784"/>
    <rating>4.2</rating>
    <perspective>3rd-Person</perspective>
    <studio>Psygnosis</studio>
    <releasedate>30/07/1994</releasedate>
    <year>1994</year>
    <plot>As Ben E. Factor himself, you must travel through the six moons of Minniat, on which the peaceful and good-natured people of Lullyat have been kidnapped. These Merry Men each have their own potential skill once rescued, so releasing them in the right order is often essential for completing a level. Some Merry Men have grey suits - this marks them out as joyless and awkward characters which must be guided through a coloring machine.[CR]The Miniation people have loaded the 60 levels with various nasties, ranging from slugs (slow, but must be jumped), Rock Men (those with sharp backs are more dangerous, but both are quite nippy), spiked teeth emerging from manholes, and so on. A large map is provided, and at any point you can pause the game and scroll around the map, which makes the forward planning easier.</plot>
    <genre>2D,Side Scroller</genre>
    <nplayers>1</nplayers>
    <boxart1>RVbEfCL.jpg</boxart1>
    <boxart2>LUuQij5.jpg</boxart2>
    <boxart3>AIn2JI9.jpg</boxart3>
    <boxart4>j5gGUOl.jpg</boxart4>
    <boxart5>Swm2p9V.jpg</boxart5>
    <boxart6>AIn2JI9.jpg</boxart6>
    <boxart7>j5gGUOl.jpg</boxart7>
    <boxart8>Swm2p9V.jpg</boxart8>
    <snapshot1>Yb2eaFX.png</snapshot1>
    <snapshot2>VD7JkFj.png</snapshot2>
    <snapshot3>uY4sooo.png</snapshot3>
    <snapshot4>dP07JSe.png</snapshot4>
    <snapshot5>I7Ty5nH.png</snapshot5>
    <snapshot6>yzbxrq2.png</snapshot6>
    <snapshot7>cGedrjc.png</snapshot7>
    <snapshot8>Ln68Tdd.png</snapshot8>
    <snapshot9>jC00Vo4.png</snapshot9>
    <snapshot10>W0vATli.png</snapshot10>
    <clearlogo1>q0yt3uU.png</clearlogo1>
    <emu_command>A4000</emu_command>
  </game>
  <game name="Alien Breed: Tower Assault (AGA)">
    <description>45.  Alien Breed - Tower Assault</description>
    <rom name="amigaromset/CommodoreAmigaRomset1.zip/AlienBreedTowerAssault11_v1.2_AGA_2331.hdf" size="3620864"/>
    <rating>4.0</rating>
    <perspective>3rd-Person</perspective>
    <studio>Team 17</studio>
    <releasedate>30/03/1994</releasedate>
    <year>1994</year>
    <plot>A scientific outpost on a far off planet has been attacked. Nothing is known about the attackers, since all communications have been destroyed. A team of marines is dispatched to investigate and destroy the unknown invaders. As their dropships enter the atmosphere and approach the base, the defence lasers, damaged in the onslaught, move into action. They launch wild bursts of laser fire at the approaching marines, who are not prepared and take heavy losses. Rookies Nash and Jordan crash-land, and must fight off the alien force.[CR]As with the previous Alien Breed, the gameplay is viewed from above. Your soldier shoots his way through the levels, collecting keys, ammunition and credits along the way. Computers can be logged into to buy new weapons. A new 'retreat' mode allows you to fire while moving backwards.[CR]The game is largely non-linear, as most levels have multiple exits, and the game can be moved through in different ways. There is a variety of indoor and outdoor levels, although you spend most time inside some of the multi-level towers. After activating a self-destruct mechanism, you must escape the building quickly.</plot>
    <genre>2D,Side Scroller</genre>
    <groups>Alien Breed series</groups>
    <nplayers>1-2 Sim</nplayers>
    <boxart1>JbpqoS0.jpg</boxart1>
    <boxart2>aKRKJXo.jpg</boxart2>
    <snapshot1>Qat0UZ9.png</snapshot1>
    <snapshot2>odmDTBI.png</snapshot2>
    <snapshot3>2uG02SO.png</snapshot3>
    <snapshot4>swK6wvc.png</snapshot4>
    <snapshot5>sP6MZCf.png</snapshot5>
    <snapshot6>93hAn2V.png</snapshot6>
    <banner1>9T8eyKS.png</banner1>
    <emu_command>A4000</emu_command>
  </game>
  <game name="Zak McKracken And The Alien Mindbenders">
    <description>44.  Zak McKracken and the Alien Mindbenders</description>
    <rom name="amigaromset/CommodoreAmigaRomset1.zip/ZakMcKracken_v1.2_0965.hdf" size="2064384"/>
    <rating>3.8</rating>
    <perspective>3rd-Person</perspective>
    <studio>LucasFilm</studio>
    <releasedate>30/03/1988</releasedate>
    <year>1988</year>
    <plot>Zak McKracken is a tabloid reporter (and not a very good one at that). After having a psychedelic dream one day, Zak realizes that something is wrong -- space aliens are dumbifying the general public through the telephone system. Zak must stop this, but he can't do it alone. After finding a strange crystal, Zak manages to get the help of the anthropologist Annie and her friends, Melissa and Leslie. The four unlikely heroes must now figure out a way to destroy the dumbifying devices and save the Earth.[CR]Zak McKracken and the Alien Mindbenders is a third-person puzzle-solving adventure similar in gameplay to Lucasfilm's breakthrough title Maniac Mansion. The player chooses verb commands (Open, Pick Up, Give, etc.; there are no Look or Talk commands) to interact with the game world. The game features up to four controllable protagonists; it is possible to switch between them at any time after they have been introduced, and also exchange inventory items if the characters are in the same location. The game can be described as a "globe-trotting" adventure, since the heroes are required to travel to different exotic countries and even leave the Earth for a while in order to complete it. Some of the puzzles are optional or can be solved in different ways.</plot>
    <genre>2D,Side Scroller</genre>
    <groups>Setting: Middle East,Game Engine: SCUMM,Setting: Mars,Setting: City - San Francisco,Setting: Passenger Plane,Setting: Future now Past,Games with game altering copy protection</groups>
    <nplayers>1</nplayers>
    <boxart1>POg1yWp.jpg</boxart1>
    <boxart2>dUQDPkQ.jpg</boxart2>
    <boxart3>BPH46Ou.jpg</boxart3>
    <snapshot1>cN7KJvg.png</snapshot1>
    <snapshot2>IIWbRBx.png</snapshot2>
    <snapshot3>K0HXwan.png</snapshot3>
    <snapshot4>sLfkHbZ.png</snapshot4>
    <snapshot5>EY8ymh8.png</snapshot5>
    <snapshot6>yQkAaHs.png</snapshot6>
    <snapshot7>Fd6aYng.gif</snapshot7>
    <snapshot8>uEQaVSJ.png</snapshot8>
    <snapshot9>IaxS5Tg.png</snapshot9>
    <snapshot10>tm1W2R4.png</snapshot10>
    <banner1>BQmUe1L.png</banner1>
    <emu_command>A4000</emu_command>
  </game>
  <game name="Ultima V: Warriors Of Destiny">
    <description>43.  Ultima V - Warriors of Destiny</description>
    <rom name="amigaromset/CommodoreAmigaRomset1.zip/Ultima5_v1.2_0785.hdf" size="1474560"/>
    <rating>4.0</rating>
    <perspective>Top-Down</perspective>
    <studio>Origin</studio>
    <releasedate>30/03/1990</releasedate>
    <year>1989</year>
    <plot>The Avatar, the embodiment of the Eight Virtues and the hero of Britannia, is called back to deal with a grave threat. Lord British, the country's benevolent monarch, has disappeared, and a man named Blackthorn has usurped his throne. The tyrant rules the land by enforcing the virtues upon the will of the people, corrupting their meaning in the process. His fundamentalist visions led him to create a police state, where failure to adhere to the virtues is punishable by death. Behind Blackthorn are the three Shadowlords, anti-thesis to the three principles of Truth, Love, and Courage. The Avatar must understand their meaning and origins, find a way to defeat them, rescue Lord British, and restore the former ethical principles of Britannia.[CR]Ultima V uses the basics of the Ultima IV engine, an overhead perspective for the map of Britannia and its towns, and a rosette-compass 3D view for the dungeons. The battle system also resembles that of the previous game, with separate battle screens and navigation of character icons in turn-based style. Many of the gameplay elements of the predecessor return, including the complex spell system (reagents must be bought in order to cast spells), recruitable party members, moongates that teleport the party between locations, various means of transportation (horses, ships, etc., with the notable addition of a magic carpet), and so on. Character creation based on morally ambiguous questions and basic leveling up system have been preserved as well. In comparison to the predecessor, the classes have been reduced to four.[CR]Additional challenges include navigating characters through the Underworld, a vast underground area containing many hazards; random presence of Shadowlords in the cities, which influences the behavior of their inhabitants, making them run away, steal from, or attack the Avatar; inscriptions in a runic alphabet that must be deciphered by the player, and others.[CR]The game has a noticeably more detailed world than any of its predecessors; the towns are much larger, with many unique buildings and objects represented graphically. Ultima V introduces physical interaction with the game world: many objects can be pushed or pulled, the main character can sit down on a chair (which is graphically shown), etc. It also incorporates a day/night cycle and schedules for non-playable characters: for example, it is impossible to shop at night because the shopkeepers are sleeping. Dialogues with NPCs have been enhanced, featuring more unique and detailed conversation topics.</plot>
    <genre>2D,Side Scroller</genre>
    <groups>Ultima series,Ultima universe,Gameplay feature: Hunger / Thirst,Gameplay feature: Importable characters,Gameplay feature: Character development - Automatic leveling,Gameplay feature: Day / Night cycle,Fantasy Creatures: Orcs,Physical Bonus Content: World Map,Fantasy Creatures: Trolls,Fantasy Creatures: Dragons</groups>
    <nplayers>1</nplayers>
    <boxart1>mLC9wXW.jpg</boxart1>
    <boxart2>RcCz2A4.jpg</boxart2>
    <boxart3>fUdbTFs.jpg</boxart3>
    <boxart4>tizqDTc.jpg</boxart4>
    <boxart5>Fi5cwI7.jpg</boxart5>
    <snapshot1>rFA9saY.png</snapshot1>
    <snapshot2>AMF3YBu.png</snapshot2>
    <snapshot3>cbueghU.png</snapshot3>
    <snapshot4>OuCP3pv.png</snapshot4>
    <snapshot5>ViPq47E.png</snapshot5>
    <snapshot6>Y3gcaoT.png</snapshot6>
    <snapshot7>pCGSmKo.png</snapshot7>
    <snapshot8>z9sezB4.png</snapshot8>
    <snapshot9>bo2exNK.png</snapshot9>
    <snapshot10>0cpZYvC.png</snapshot10>
    <emu_command>A4000</emu_command>
  </game>
  <game name="Space Quest III: The Pirates Of Pestulon">
    <description>42.  Space Quest III - The Pirates of Pestulon</description>
    <rom name="amigaromset/CommodoreAmigaRomset1.zip/SpaceQuest3_v1.2_0292.hdf" size="3538944"/>
    <rating>4.0</rating>
    <perspective>3rd-Person</perspective>
    <releasedate>30/03/1989</releasedate>
    <plot>Narrowly escaping the events of Space Quest II: Vohaul's Revenge, Roger Wilco's escape pod floats through space. As just another metallic item of junk, it's soon picked up by an interstellar garbage hauler. Waking up in a pile of trash, quite familiar for this janitor-turned-hero, Roger Wilco must somehow escape. Once given access to the rest of the galaxy, he'll soon find himself having to avoid a collections cyborg for payments overdue, dealing with the corporate prison of software company Scummsoft, and having to digest the greasy food from the galaxy's finest hamburger joint. [CR] _Space Quest 3_ is a graphical adventure. The mouse is functional for movement and inventory access, however the game primarily relies on a text parser for specific commands and manipulation of objects on screen. In addition to the regular gameplay, there are also various mini-games, such as a simple non-scrolling arcade game _Astro Chicken_ , as well as a radar screen representation for ship-to-ship space combat.</plot>
    <genre>Fixed Screen</genre>
    <groups>Space Quest series,Game Engine: Sierra's Creative Interpreter (SCI),Setting: Space station / Spaceship</groups>
    <boxart1>http://www.mobygames.com/images/covers/l/13919-space-quest-iii-the-pirates-of-pestulon-dos-front-cover.jpg</boxart1>
    <boxart2>0gkZSK9.jpg</boxart2>
    <boxart3>9fNsCAC.jpg</boxart3>
    <boxart4>U1ixw45.jpg</boxart4>
    <snapshot1>http://www.mobygames.com/images/shots/l/781-space-quest-iii-the-pirates-of-pestulon-dos-screenshot-title.gif</snapshot1>
    <snapshot2>http://www.mobygames.com/images/shots/l/782-space-quest-iii-the-pirates-of-pestulon-dos-screenshot-the-developers.gif</snapshot2>
    <snapshot3>http://www.mobygames.com/images/shots/l/783-space-quest-iii-the-pirates-of-pestulon-dos-screenshot-beam-me.gif</snapshot3>
    <snapshot4>http://www.mobygames.com/images/shots/l/784-space-quest-iii-the-pirates-of-pestulon-dos-screenshot-where.gif</snapshot4>
    <snapshot7>S9oErjI.png</snapshot7>
    <snapshot8>ZznGv7i.png</snapshot8>
    <snapshot9>eWTC6sz.png</snapshot9>
    <snapshot10>KgI4x0O.png</snapshot10>
    <emu_command>A4000</emu_command>
  </game>
  <game name="F-15 Strike Eagle II">
    <description>41.  F-15 Strike Eagle II</description>
    <rom name="amigaromset/CommodoreAmigaRomset1.zip/F15StrikeEagle2_v1.0_0479.hdf" size="1507328"/>
    <rating>3.4</rating>
    <perspective>1st-Person</perspective>
    <studio>Microprose / ERBE</studio>
    <releasedate>30/03/1991</releasedate>
    <year>1991</year>
    <plot>The second in the series features campaigns in Lybia, the Persian Gulf, The Middle East and Vietnam, making for a total of 250,000 miles of potential action and danger. Primary and secondary aerial and ground-based targets must be destroyed on each of these. You are armed with a cannon, AMRAAM long-range air-to-air missile, Sidewinder short-range air-to-air missile, and the Maverick air-to-ground missile.[CR]11 camera angles including internal and external views of the plane exist. To help new players there is a training mode, with options to disable crashes and automate take-off and landing. Enemy AI is responsive, but a targeting computer helps you take them out before they can do it to you. The game incorporates two "Director's Modes" which cuts away from your cockpit to highlight special events occurring elsewhere in the game world, like enemy base launching fighters, SAM sites launching SAMs, and your missiles hitting the target.</plot>
    <genre>Flying</genre>
    <groups>F-15 Strike Eagle series,Historical conflict: Vietnam War ,Aircraft: F-15 Eagle,Games with manual lookup copy protection</groups>
    <nplayers>1</nplayers>
    <boxart1>rTYe7F8.jpg</boxart1>
    <boxart2>ajKEiOR.jpg</boxart2>
    <boxart3>IPsdyGr.jpg</boxart3>
    <snapshot1>zOEFyGi.png</snapshot1>
    <snapshot2>1gERDc0.png</snapshot2>
    <snapshot3>gbhi2qq.png</snapshot3>
    <snapshot4>c7mkp6X.png</snapshot4>
    <snapshot5>xMZCXwc.png</snapshot5>
    <snapshot6>wa3t9y3.png</snapshot6>
    <snapshot7>cWwrjoG.png</snapshot7>
    <snapshot8>WpobvQl.png</snapshot8>
    <snapshot9>UPEGMSs.png</snapshot9>
    <snapshot10>Oa71zfk.png</snapshot10>
    <emu_command>A4000</emu_command>
  </game>
  <game name="Ultima VI: The False Prophet">
    <description>40.  Ultima VI - The False Prophet</description>
    <rom name="amigaromset/CommodoreAmigaRomset1.zip/Ultima6_v1.0_0294.hdf" size="3424256"/>
    <rating>3.9</rating>
    <perspective>3rd-Person</perspective>
    <studio>Origin</studio>
    <releasedate>30/03/1992</releasedate>
    <year>1992</year>
    <plot>Several years after having restored Lord British to his rightful position as the monarch of Britannia, the Avatar is captured by demon-like creatures and placed on a sacrificial altar. His friends Iolo, Shamino and Dupre appear just in time to save him. In the Britannia castle, the Avatar learns that his abductors were gargoyles, a race of enigmatic creatures who have recently invaded Britannia and occupied the shrines of Virtue. As the Avatar embarks on a quest to liberate Britannia, he begins to gain insight into the gargoyles' true motives, and realizes that it is his duty to achieve peace and understanding between the two races.[CR] _Ultima VI_ is notable for having a fully continuous world. There is no "world map" in the game; all the locations are seamlessly connected to each other, turning the game world into an open environment. Compared to the previous installments in the series, the game focuses more on quests and exploration rather than on combat. The latter no longer involves separate screens; battles occur during exploration, without any transitions. The turn-based system from the previous games has been preserved. [CR]The interface has been re-designed, the original key-bound commands co-existing with selectable command icons and mouse-based interaction. The game world is more detailed than in the previous games, with a large number of various objects that can be manipulated or added to the inventory. Conversations are more extended, with a wider selection of topics, including many personal ones unique to specific characters. The player is also able to conduct extensive conversations with the Avatar's companions, as well as split the party and control the characters separately. Some important topics may be highlighted during text display, to facilitate further dialogue, which requires the player to type the desired conversation topics.[CR]Like in the predecessors, the player is free to explore the game world from the beginning of the game, and visit locations in any order. Following the main quest and obtaining specific items and information is necessary to complete the story; however, the player can also opt to bypass a large part of it by using previous knowledge of the game or outside help. The FM Towns version has full voice acting for all the conversations, in English and in Japanese.</plot>
    <genre>2D,Side Scroller</genre>
    <groups>Ultima series,Ultima universe,Animals: Mice,Gameplay feature: Fishing,Gameplay feature: Hunger / Thirst,Gameplay feature: Mining,Gameplay feature: Importable characters,Gameplay feature: Gambling,Games with manual lookup copy protection,Gameplay feature: Character development - Automatic leveling,Gameplay feature: Day / Night cycle,Sound engine: MED,Gameplay feature: Character development - Training,Physical Bonus Content: World Map,Fantasy Creatures: Trolls,Fantasy Creatures: Dragons</groups>
    <nplayers>1</nplayers>
    <boxart1>nMVADHm.png</boxart1>
    <boxart2>LzdWsKk.jpg</boxart2>
    <boxart3>IFrQJjE.jpg</boxart3>
    <boxart4>oxjIisC.jpg</boxart4>
    <boxart5>EPvEpQv.jpg</boxart5>
    <snapshot1>wgR1LmD.png</snapshot1>
    <snapshot2>BkBxkzm.png</snapshot2>
    <snapshot3>ktBqc37.png</snapshot3>
    <snapshot4>Fw7WaAa.png</snapshot4>
    <snapshot5>EMUu5da.png</snapshot5>
    <snapshot6>osxjzTz.png</snapshot6>
    <snapshot7>RneuKYd.png</snapshot7>
    <snapshot8>80FvG7E.png</snapshot8>
    <snapshot9>51zzeKD.png</snapshot9>
    <snapshot10>CZXAkPu.png</snapshot10>
    <emu_command>A4000</emu_command>
  </game>
  <game name="Super Cars II">
    <description>39.  Super Cars II</description>
    <rom name="amigaromset/CommodoreAmigaRomset1.zip/SuperCars2_v1.0_0224.hdf" size="2359296"/>
    <perspective>Top-Down</perspective>
    <studio>Gremlin</studio>
    <releasedate>30/03/1991</releasedate>
    <year>1990</year>
    <plot>&gt;Power your way through 27 stages of highway horror engaging in [CR]&gt;mile after mile of motorised combat. Select your car and equip it [CR]&gt;with a range of extras including:- turbo chargers, anti skid braking, [CR]&gt;side armour and missles to help you reach the final Supercar Challenge.[CR]&gt; \\-- Game Box[CR]***Super Cars*** is a top-view racing game from Gremlin Interactive, [CR]who later produced the Lotus series of games. Stylistically, the game [CR]is influenced by Super Sprint.[CR]There are 9 tracks at each of the 4 difficulty levels, which can be [CR]raced in any order (although the last track you race is made harder [CR]than usual). In the races you win money, which can be spent on temporary [CR]handling and power upgrades, plus armour plating and front/rear shooting [CR]missiles that can knock out other racers. The player must finish in the [CR]top 3 of each race to progress - initially there are 4 computer [CR]opponents, but more are added as you progress through the game.[CR]The car can be upgraded throughout the game via the shop section. The [CR]player is given an initial price, but also a number of options of things [CR]to say to the salesman - with the right combination, the price will [CR]drop.[CR]An unusual easter egg was featured in the game, whereby typing in a [CR]certain swear word in the name screen will reset the game.</plot>
    <genre>Driving</genre>
    <nplayers>1</nplayers>
    <boxart1>ojrMGrM.png</boxart1>
    <boxart2>Cow9kph.jpg</boxart2>
    <boxart3>myzD2aW.jpg</boxart3>
    <snapshot1>fXHlQNB.png</snapshot1>
    <snapshot2>nOmrTHN.png</snapshot2>
    <snapshot3>OX6if3t.png</snapshot3>
    <snapshot4>VjnByDk.png</snapshot4>
    <snapshot5>Vy7nmmS.png</snapshot5>
    <snapshot6>ldilCUb.png</snapshot6>
    <snapshot7>JvjGD96.jpg</snapshot7>
    <snapshot8>Ocr5Aug.jpg</snapshot8>
    <snapshot9>PBakFTZ.jpg</snapshot9>
    <snapshot10>jLbxrJF.jpg</snapshot10>
    <emu_command>A4000</emu_command>
  </game>
  <game name="Super Stardust (AGA)">
    <description>38.  Super Stardust</description>
    <rom name="amigaromset/CommodoreAmigaRomset1.zip/SuperStardust_v1.0_AGA_0175.hdf" size="6078464"/>
    <rating>4.4</rating>
    <perspective>3rd-Person</perspective>
    <studio>Team 17</studio>
    <releasedate>30/10/1994</releasedate>
    <year>1994</year>
    <plot>Like Stardust, in this Asteroids clone you control your Panther PX-2 ship through successive waves of asteroids and other enemies, which are drawn using ray-tracing techniques.[CR]The game features both overhead and 3D sections. In the overhead part, you must eliminate enemy ships and asteroids across several zones in each world. The 3D sections consist of underwater tunnels that link one world to another and they are each defended by a guardian you must defeat.</plot>
    <genre>Fixed Screen</genre>
    <groups>Stardust series,Asteroids variants</groups>
    <nplayers>1</nplayers>
    <boxart1>4HLdvfN.jpg</boxart1>
    <boxart2>0dXvaS5.jpg</boxart2>
    <boxart3>VQhRjNG.jpg</boxart3>
    <snapshot1>nFLHpcA.png</snapshot1>
    <snapshot2>JninCLr.png</snapshot2>
    <snapshot3>ED2rv1o.png</snapshot3>
    <snapshot4>iMtHROG.png</snapshot4>
    <snapshot5>Ky5sNqa.png</snapshot5>
    <snapshot6>K664PNv.png</snapshot6>
    <snapshot7>9flg2HP.png</snapshot7>
    <snapshot8>orA5OwD.png</snapshot8>
    <snapshot9>h0SxnoU.png</snapshot9>
    <snapshot10>rcCbaac.png</snapshot10>
    <emu_command>A4000</emu_command>
  </game>
  <game name="R-Type">
    <description>37.  R-Type</description>
    <rom name="amigaromset/CommodoreAmigaRomset1.zip/RType_v1.4.1_0940.hdf" size="1294336"/>
    <rating>4.0</rating>
    <studio>Activision</studio>
    <year>1989</year>
    <plot> _R-Type_ is a side scrolling shoot 'em up best known for its extremely tough and strategic gameplay. You control the R-9 spaceship as it launches a last-ditch effort to repel the evil Bydo empire.[CR]The R-9 comes equipped as standard with a small gun which can only take down the smallest of enemies without firing several shots. By holding down the fire button, it can be loaded up so as to release a large burst of energy, eliminating all but the strongest enemies in its path. From time to time, pods will come flying in your direction. Upon being shot, they release an upgrade. The first one will invariably be the one called "The Force", which is a weapons pod that clings either to the front or the back of your ship, absorbing any enemy bullets or acting as a bumper with which you can fly head-on into them. You can also use it as an offensive weapon by firing it and pulling it back in. Mastering the Force is vital to surviving in _R-Type_ , since it must be used both as protection against bullet clusters, as a remote controlled cannon, and in order to clear the screen from obstacles. Other upgrades give you target-seeking missiles or a bigger main gun. Different gun types, differentiated by their colour, serve different purposes. The blue one sends laser beams bouncing across the screen (good for tunnels), the red one fires straight ahead, and the yellow one follows any walls it may encounter (good for artillery emplacements).[CR]The stages of _R-Type_ are made in an organic style, certainly inspired by H. R. Giger's artwork for the Alien movies. When it came out, it was considered trend-setting since it broke off from the stereotypical sci-fi mould of other shoot'em'ups. In part, the levels themselves are your enemy, which is exemplified by the fourth, where spider-like creatures weave webs that cover the screen and block your path, or levels with intricate tunnel systems. Still, the levels are best handled with a combination of strategy and reflexes, without the memorisation that is required of R-Type's contemporary rival, Gradius.</plot>
    <genre>2D,Side Scroller</genre>
    <groups>R-Type series,Genre: Scrolling shoot 'em up</groups>
    <nplayers>1</nplayers>
    <boxart1>VfE1XQi.png</boxart1>
    <snapshot1>Wp9SZES.png</snapshot1>
    <snapshot2>bnUsshE.png</snapshot2>
    <snapshot3>rIFkgmh.png</snapshot3>
    <snapshot4>nEn5iTb.png</snapshot4>
    <snapshot5>5NlgcvM.png</snapshot5>
    <snapshot6>eDliZeH.png</snapshot6>
    <banner1>tveoIn1.png</banner1>
  </game>
  <game name="Eye Of The Beholder">
    <description>36.  Eye of the Beholder</description>
    <rom name="amigaromset/CommodoreAmigaRomset1.zip/EyeOfTheBeholder_v1.5_0116.hdf" size="3244032"/>
    <rating>3.8</rating>
    <perspective>1st-Person</perspective>
    <studio>SSI</studio>
    <releasedate>30/03/1991</releasedate>
    <year>1991</year>
    <plot>Something evil is lurking below the city of Waterdeep. The Lords of Waterdeep summon a group of heroes to investigate, but someone or something has been watching the proceedings. After the heroes enter the sewers, the ceiling collapses behind them. The only way out is the way down, into a dungeon filled with monsters, traps and puzzles.[CR] _Eye of the Beholder_ is a dungeon crawler RPG with a first-person perspective based on the 2nd Edition AD&amp;D; rules. The starting party consists of four characters and up to two NPCs can join later. Combat and magic happen in real time, similarly to Dungeon Master. There is a variety of monsters to fight and spells to cast. The game features a point-and-click interface for fighting, spellcasting and handling objects.</plot>
    <genre>Fantasy</genre>
    <groups>Dungeons &amp; Dragons (D&amp;D / AD&amp;D) licensees,Eye of the Beholder series,Dungeons &amp; Dragons Campaign Setting: Forgotten Realms,Gameplay feature: Hunger / Thirst,Games with manual lookup copy protection,Gameplay feature: Character development - Automatic leveling,Fantasy Creatures: Elves,Fantasy Creatures: Dwarves,Genre: Dungeon Crawler</groups>
    <nplayers>1</nplayers>
    <boxart1>MJrRVjI.jpg</boxart1>
    <boxart2>q9d6VMp.jpg</boxart2>
    <boxart3>QLmWex3.jpg</boxart3>
    <boxart4>p3w7sfm.jpg</boxart4>
    <boxart5>1uDSxFb.jpg</boxart5>
    <boxart6>7UNgVnX.jpg</boxart6>
    <boxart7>UII7ehS.jpg</boxart7>
    <boxart8>LXDDVWA.jpg</boxart8>
    <boxart9>4I6Zn4C.jpg</boxart9>
    <snapshot1>ZNhgAhm.png</snapshot1>
    <snapshot2>maLLezb.png</snapshot2>
    <snapshot3>Mvby0kK.png</snapshot3>
    <snapshot4>l4KqOpg.png</snapshot4>
    <snapshot5>vKJRLHy.png</snapshot5>
    <snapshot6>zHznnuh.png</snapshot6>
    <snapshot7>yGc1qTf.gif</snapshot7>
    <snapshot8>4Z1DYqi.gif</snapshot8>
    <snapshot9>TSSDRvo.gif</snapshot9>
    <snapshot10>5EupEmx.gif</snapshot10>
    <banner1>6BHcfDg.png</banner1>
    <videoid>esb5j-yv6uw</videoid>
    <emu_command>A4000</emu_command>
  </game>
  <game name="Banshee (AGA)">
    <description>35.  Banshee</description>
    <rom name="amigaromset/CommodoreAmigaRomset1.zip/Banshee_v3.2_AGA_0633.hdf" size="3899392"/>
    <rating>4.1</rating>
    <perspective>Top-Down</perspective>
    <studio>Core</studio>
    <releasedate>30/03/1994</releasedate>
    <year>1994</year>
    <plot>Banshee is a vertically-scrolling shoot 'em up from the old school, with similarities to games like 1942 and SWIV. There are lots of big, brash enemy vehicles to take on, plus individual soldiers (these often lie in a pool of blood afterwards, a gruesome sight making full use of AGA graphics) and civilians. Many of the enemies have good hiding places and can emerge surprisingly, Commando-style.[CR]There are four large levels, which also scroll a small amount horizontally, the idea being that you can evade some opposition. There's a special loop-the-loop type feature available, which can double as an attack or an evasive move.</plot>
    <genre>Flying</genre>
    <groups>Setting: Future now Past</groups>
    <nplayers>1-2 Sim</nplayers>
    <boxart1>2ha4PeM.png</boxart1>
    <boxart2>AAQZbnW.jpg</boxart2>
    <boxart3>kxjUZEQ.jpg</boxart3>
    <boxart4>kxjUZEQ.jpg</boxart4>
    <snapshot1>UfgXrOD.png</snapshot1>
    <snapshot2>9aXZ4vf.png</snapshot2>
    <snapshot3>TzLM3In.png</snapshot3>
    <snapshot4>qdpYH0M.png</snapshot4>
    <snapshot5>mlwcZjB.png</snapshot5>
    <snapshot6>5KS8OCi.png</snapshot6>
    <snapshot7>bA0D8c3.png</snapshot7>
    <snapshot8>dMtx5QG.png</snapshot8>
    <snapshot9>PRb1cDV.png</snapshot9>
    <snapshot10>1qae7mN.png</snapshot10>
    <clearlogo1>r1yNQrJ.png</clearlogo1>
    <emu_command>A4000</emu_command>
  </game>
  <game name="Superfrog">
    <description>34.  Superfrog</description>
    <rom name="amigaromset/CommodoreAmigaRomset1.zip/Superfrog_v1.2_0035.hdf" size="3702784"/>
    <rating>3.7</rating>
    <perspective>Platform</perspective>
    <studio>Team 17</studio>
    <releasedate>30/03/1993</releasedate>
    <year>1993</year>
    <plot>Superfrog is a traditional jump and run platformer. You're - surprise - a frog. Your enemies are all animals - like bees, hedgehogs or snails. You have no weapons. The only way to kill the enemies is to jump on them. Every stage has a time limit. In this limit you have to collect a pre-determined number of coins. Each of the six worlds has four stages. Every stage has a password. After all you can type your name into a high score table.</plot>
    <genre>2D,Side Scroller</genre>
    <groups>Animals: Frogs,Gameplay feature: Gambling,Superfrog series</groups>
    <nplayers>1</nplayers>
    <boxart1>MAeKQ81.png</boxart1>
    <boxart2>OSERk3G.jpg</boxart2>
    <boxart3>dVEYOqs.jpg</boxart3>
    <snapshot1>s08ub07.png</snapshot1>
    <snapshot2>ljY2yMX.png</snapshot2>
    <snapshot3>U1vG9bd.png</snapshot3>
    <snapshot4>GO8FBKx.png</snapshot4>
    <snapshot5>97v44G0.png</snapshot5>
    <snapshot6>OConxTK.png</snapshot6>
    <snapshot7>vlMKmGT.gif</snapshot7>
    <snapshot8>y3Tl24r.gif</snapshot8>
    <snapshot9>ukoQDB6.gif</snapshot9>
    <snapshot10>tZidsMo.gif</snapshot10>
    <banner1>TCtc3Wq.png</banner1>
    <clearlogo1>9cs7sF7.png</clearlogo1>
    <videoid>LZfX-EvDeNc</videoid>
    <emu_command>A4000</emu_command>
  </game>
  <game name="Indiana Jones And The Last Crusade - The Graphic Adventure">
    <description>33.  Indiana Jones and the Last Crusade</description>
    <rom name="amigaromset/CommodoreAmigaRomset1.zip/IndianaJones%26TheLastCrusadeAdventure_v1.3_1990.hdf" size="2899968"/>
    <perspective>3rd-Person</perspective>
    <releasedate>30/03/1989</releasedate>
    <plot>It is 1938 and adventurer Indiana Jones is joined by his father on this quest, preventing Adolf Hitler from capturing the Holy Grail. He will have to deal with Nazi guards, the Luftwaffe and enemy spies as he tries to stop the tyrannical Nazi leader.[CR]The Graphic Adventure uses the same SCUMM gameplay system as the previous Maniac Mansion. Most of the screen is used for a visual rendition of the current scene. At the bottom of the screen are words, which can be clicked on using the mouse to activate their functions. For example, objects can be picked up, used, pushed or pulled, and turned on and off. Most locations are from the movie, but some further scenes are added.[CR]In keeping with Indiana's action-man persona, the game also features pure action scenes. Unlike most Lucasfilm adventures, you can die.[CR]Two PC versions of the game were released, one with 16 color EGA graphics, and one with 256 color VGA graphics.</plot>
    <boxart1>2MySDNx.jpg</boxart1>
    <boxart2>yQvO7SK.jpg</boxart2>
    <boxart3>L9QZixO.jpg</boxart3>
    <boxart4>KaM1ZgR.jpg</boxart4>
    <boxart5>b4UP7HJ.jpg</boxart5>
    <boxart6>wxCQ63w.jpg</boxart6>
    <boxart7>CIKf4vY.jpg</boxart7>
    <snapshot7>w3pgSrA.png</snapshot7>
    <snapshot8>XgzvNUC.png</snapshot8>
    <snapshot9>ANv6akb.png</snapshot9>
    <snapshot10>Pbn2BP5.png</snapshot10>
    <videoid>qKfd4sv2xz4</videoid>
    <emu_command>A4000</emu_command>
  </game>
  <game name="DreamWeb (AGA)">
    <description>32.  DreamWeb</description>
    <rom name="amigaromset/CommodoreAmigaRomset1.zip/DreamWeb_v1.1_AGA_1815.hdf" size="4440064"/>
    <rating>3.9</rating>
    <perspective>Top-Down</perspective>
    <studio>Empire</studio>
    <releasedate>30/03/1995</releasedate>
    <year>1994</year>
    <plot>Ryan, a bartender from a dystopian future can't sleep peacefully for months. His nights are sequences of nightmares and strange dreams, days with frequent black-outs with strange visions, until one night a figure in monk attire appears to him, and tells him the story of the seven evil ones, uniting to destroy to Dreamweb, the only barrier between the world and darkness. The monk makes a proposition: Ryan becomes the "deliverer": the one who would keep the Dreamweb safe by killing those who try to destroy it.[CR]Descending into paranoia and just wanting dreams to stop, Ryan accepts the mission, then wakes up in a puddle of cold sweat, next to his beloved girlfriend in her house, and late for work. Again.[CR] _DreamWeb_ is a top-down adventure game set in a gritty futuristic dystopian city. Each location takes only a small portion of the screen without panning (except an optional small zoom window in the corner that follows the cursor), with the player interacting with objects and people by simply clicking them. Ryan has a limited inventory space, and as a lot of objects can be picked up (many without any use), the player must rationalize what might be useful and what just serves as filler. [CR]Dialogue is straightforward, with no options, but still required to advance in the game (to find new locations, for instance). In situations where many adventure games usually feature an indirect approach to solve a problem, Ryan often faces himself with situations where it's "killed or be killed", which result in deaths (sometimes of innocents). The game also contains a few scenes with graphically explicit sexual situations.[CR]The original release of the game included _Diary Of a (Mad?) Man_ , a 40-page diary telling the descent of Ryan into madness, or his destiny, written by Stephen Marley, providing a complete background to the events leading to the start of the game.</plot>
    <genre>Cyberpunk,Sci-Fi</genre>
    <nplayers>1</nplayers>
    <boxart1>Ok1zEyE.png</boxart1>
    <snapshot1>FzKlJqK.png</snapshot1>
    <snapshot2>6TrzXCD.png</snapshot2>
    <snapshot3>emzWU9F.png</snapshot3>
    <snapshot4>C7OoVv9.png</snapshot4>
    <snapshot5>jfYewwc.png</snapshot5>
    <snapshot6>vd70hla.png</snapshot6>
    <snapshot7>ziIumYM.jpg</snapshot7>
    <snapshot8>3ZsyUam.jpg</snapshot8>
    <emu_command>A4000</emu_command>
  </game>
  <game name="Frontier: Elite II">
    <description>31.  Frontier - Elite II</description>
    <rom name="amigaromset/CommodoreAmigaRomset1.zip/Frontier_v1.0_1960.hdf" size="966656"/>
    <perspective>1st-Person</perspective>
    <studio>The One</studio>
    <releasedate>30/03/1993</releasedate>
    <year>1990</year>
    <genre>Side Scroller</genre>
    <nplayers>1</nplayers>
    <snapshot1>SZ0h6pu.png</snapshot1>
    <snapshot2>SKtsJJb.png</snapshot2>
    <snapshot3>tKFBIYT.png</snapshot3>
    <snapshot4>jVulyGP.png</snapshot4>
    <snapshot5>AOWj9Pc.png</snapshot5>
    <snapshot6>6xEM3Rm.png</snapshot6>
    <snapshot7>YxHr2aw.png</snapshot7>
    <snapshot8>aExnPPp.png</snapshot8>
    <snapshot9>KnnGxrL.png</snapshot9>
    <snapshot10>bZBKZLk.png</snapshot10>
    <clearlogo1>4IwyFFh.png</clearlogo1>
    <videoid>RaSnKWUgRfg</videoid>
    <emu_command>A4000</emu_command>
  </game>
  <game name="It Came From The Desert">
    <description>30.  It Came from the Desert</description>
    <rom name="amigaromset/CommodoreAmigaRomset1.zip/ItCameFromTheDesert_v1.1.hdf" size="3063808"/>
    <rating>4.3</rating>
    <perspective>1st-Person</perspective>
    <studio>Cinemaware / Mirrorsoft</studio>
    <releasedate>30/03/1989</releasedate>
    <year>1990</year>
    <plot>Antheads: It Came from the Desert II is an add-on for It Came From the Desert. The story takes place five years after the original game. You are Brick Nash, who has stolen plutonium and prevented nuclear tests in the desert, so the people are mad at you because they didn't get any money but some are friendly like Biff and Dusty. The police are after you and people in Lizard Breath are turning into antheads. The gameplay remains unchanged from the base game.</plot>
    <genre>Mission Based</genre>
    <groups>Cinemaware-style games,It Came from the Desert series</groups>
    <nplayers>1</nplayers>
    <boxart1>rhUdZz0.jpg</boxart1>
    <boxart2>WEcs7Ig.jpg</boxart2>
    <boxart3>bZhCHUe.jpg</boxart3>
    <boxart4>ffyMUhg.jpg</boxart4>
    <snapshot1>rcMx2R8.png</snapshot1>
    <snapshot2>kBJ4uu1.png</snapshot2>
    <snapshot3>NxK0Il0.png</snapshot3>
    <snapshot4>1Q3ZoOw.png</snapshot4>
    <snapshot5>o2SNips.png</snapshot5>
    <snapshot6>Frov1in.png</snapshot6>
    <snapshot7>oDTRhUT.gif</snapshot7>
    <snapshot8>InYHoqP.gif</snapshot8>
    <snapshot9>kQuKtA1.gif</snapshot9>
    <snapshot10>JTAMS4B.gif</snapshot10>
    <clearlogo1>aBKmIe0.png</clearlogo1>
    <emu_command>A4000</emu_command>
  </game>
  <game name="Football Manager: World Cup Edition">
    <description>29.  Football Manager: World Cup Edition</description>
    <rom name="amigaromset/CommodoreAmigaRomset1.zip/FootballManagerWorldCupEdition_v1.0_2272.hdf" size="1130496"/>
    <rating>1.1</rating>
    <studio>Addictive (Prism Leisure)</studio>
    <year>1990</year>
    <plot>Football Manager: World Cup Edition 1990 is the third game in the popular Football Manager series. This time your mission is not to coach an club team, but one of the national teams that started in the real World Cup 1990 qualifications. Master the qualification games to reach the final tournament and try to get the World Cup. You can fill up your team with 22 players, and can give each of them individual tactical game instructions. Before each game you give an interview that has influence of the morals of your players. In every half-time you can give new instructions to your team and make tactical corrections.</plot>
    <genre>Management,Simulation</genre>
    <groups>Football Manager series</groups>
    <nplayers>1</nplayers>
    <boxart1>7D8KGYC.jpg</boxart1>
    <snapshot1>MPnyziL.png</snapshot1>
    <snapshot2>Rcu7QNt.png</snapshot2>
    <snapshot3>q2TkaEZ.png</snapshot3>
    <snapshot4>Rcu7QNt.png</snapshot4>
    <snapshot5>P3UcUEB.png</snapshot5>
    <snapshot6>At0UGjq.png</snapshot6>
  </game>
  <game name="Beneath A Steel Sky">
    <description>28.  Beneath a Steel Sky</description>
    <rom name="amigaromset/CommodoreAmigaRomset1.zip/BeneathASteelSky_v2.0_0207.hdf" size="12795904"/>
    <rating>3.9</rating>
    <perspective>3rd-Person</perspective>
    <studio>Virgin</studio>
    <releasedate>30/03/1994</releasedate>
    <year>1994</year>
    <plot>In futuristic Australia, there are giant cities owned solely by corporations, separated by a giant wasteland known as The Gap. When Robert Foster's Gap-dwelling tribe is killed by soldiers from Union City who capture him, everything changes for him. After a narrow escape from the helicopter bringing him there as it inexplicably crashes, Robert and his droid Joey must search the decaying city, attempting to befriend both the snobby rich and the frustrated poor as the two attempt to get out of the city, but in the middle of everything they uncover the dark truth about LINC, the bizarre computer which makes the city tick.[CR]The game uses the Virtual Theatre engine from Lure of the Temptress, which allows its characters to move freely independent of the player's input, making the game world more dynamic than it is usually the case in comparable games. Otherwise, the engine provides traditional point-and-click adventure gameplay.[CR]The iPhone version introduces a touch-based interface, new animated movies by Dave Gibbons, a context-sensitive hint system and a remastered audio track.</plot>
    <genre>Cyberpunk,Sci-Fi</genre>
    <groups>Theme: Hacking / Pseudohacking ,Game Engine: Virtual Theatre,Games made into comics,Compilations: Beneath a Steel Sky,Setting: Australian / Oceanian,Game feature: Simulated Internet,Physical Bonus Content: Comic</groups>
    <nplayers>1</nplayers>
    <boxart1>BIVv2Cm.jpg</boxart1>
    <boxart2>GUXdRql.jpg</boxart2>
    <boxart3>puyBmaT.jpg</boxart3>
    <boxart4>bl9iF6L.jpg</boxart4>
    <boxart5>puyBmaT.jpg</boxart5>
    <boxart6>bl9iF6L.jpg</boxart6>
    <snapshot1>jYIexJX.png</snapshot1>
    <snapshot2>7jakV41.png</snapshot2>
    <snapshot3>W4kE4eG.png</snapshot3>
    <snapshot4>9jBv4rA.png</snapshot4>
    <snapshot5>5ZecBlJ.png</snapshot5>
    <snapshot6>XeoPvS3.png</snapshot6>
    <snapshot7>B1xPxth.png</snapshot7>
    <snapshot8>OoRMhza.png</snapshot8>
    <snapshot9>v7mTRS0.png</snapshot9>
    <snapshot10>CLwgENV.png</snapshot10>
    <banner1>YrKII9K.png</banner1>
    <fanart1>9ntCiTe.jpg</fanart1>
    <clearlogo1>fRfU2GV.png</clearlogo1>
    <emu_command>A4000</emu_command>
  </game>
  <game name="Roadkill (AGA)">
    <description>27.  Roadkill</description>
    <rom name="amigaromset/CommodoreAmigaRomset1.zip/Roadkill_v2.1b_AGA_1108.hdf" size="3571712"/>
    <rating>4.4</rating>
    <perspective>Top-Down</perspective>
    <studio>Acid (Guildhall)</studio>
    <releasedate>30/03/1994</releasedate>
    <year>1994</year>
    <plot>Set in the future, _Roadkill_ is a racing game featuring all manner of gruesome additions. There are 9 computer opponents in each race, and you must finish in the top 3 every time. Rockets and homing missiles can be collected so as to shoot the rival cars out. The tracks feature inbuilt hazards and treacherous shortcuts.[CR]Money is a big factor in all of this - the higher you finish in a race, the more you get; it can be collected during the race; each car you destroy gives you more money than the previous one, as you go for the Jackpot and then the Super Jackpot.</plot>
    <genre>Sci-Fi,Sci-Fi</genre>
    <groups>Genre: Car / motorcycle combat,Sound engine: MED</groups>
    <nplayers>1</nplayers>
    <boxart1>L0vS1tG.jpg</boxart1>
    <boxart2>iSdNbw2.jpg</boxart2>
    <snapshot1>CJgQ6XH.png</snapshot1>
    <snapshot2>c04b4rf.png</snapshot2>
    <snapshot3>Cy8LUCQ.png</snapshot3>
    <snapshot4>BP0OVtC.png</snapshot4>
    <snapshot5>FBdPvb6.png</snapshot5>
    <snapshot6>tEofh9B.png</snapshot6>
    <banner1>n42MCXU.png</banner1>
    <clearlogo1>tU2FApi.png</clearlogo1>
    <emu_command>A4000</emu_command>
  </game>
  <game name="Lemmings 2: The Tribes (1 MB)">
    <description>26.  Lemmings 2 - The Tribes</description>
    <rom name="amigaromset/CommodoreAmigaRomset1.zip/Lemmings2_v1.4_1MB_0351.hdf" size="3096576"/>
    <rating>3.8</rating>
    <perspective>3rd-Person</perspective>
    <studio>Psygnosis</studio>
    <releasedate>30/03/1993</releasedate>
    <year>1991</year>
    <plot>The basic objective of the game is to guide a group of humanoid lemmings through a number of obstacles to a designated exit. In order to save the required number of lemmings to win, one must determine how to assign a limited number of eight different skills to specific lemmings that allow the selected lemming to alter the landscape, to affect the behavior of other lemmings, or to clear obstacles in order to create a safe passage for the rest of the lemmings.[CR]Lemmings was one of the best received video games of the early 1990s era. The popularity of the game led to development of its numerous ports to other systems and the creation of several sequels, remakes and spin-offs, as well as inspiring similar games.</plot>
    <genre>2D,Side Scroller</genre>
    <groups>Lemmings series,Games made into books,Game Center CX challenge games,Gameplay feature: Herding</groups>
    <nplayers>1-2 Sim</nplayers>
    <boxart1>hAOLbtd.jpg</boxart1>
    <boxart2>jPzRNIy.jpg</boxart2>
    <boxart3>KfrwQJB.jpg</boxart3>
    <boxart4>IxNLhLD.jpg</boxart4>
    <boxart5>PdImiCc.jpg</boxart5>
    <snapshot1>0RI1MX6.png</snapshot1>
    <snapshot2>esf4DB4.png</snapshot2>
    <snapshot3>H0UDH3V.png</snapshot3>
    <snapshot4>aTUaPAi.png</snapshot4>
    <snapshot5>LfZNJJE.png</snapshot5>
    <snapshot6>aoE8l6c.png</snapshot6>
    <snapshot7>GHSuUbz.gif</snapshot7>
    <snapshot8>8dlnRCF.png</snapshot8>
    <snapshot9>xYwUQcl.png</snapshot9>
    <snapshot10>NFHDluC.png</snapshot10>
    <banner1>YwBnYNv.png</banner1>
    <emu_command>A4000</emu_command>
  </game>
  <game name="Indiana Jones And The Fate Of Atlantis - The Graphic Adventure">
    <description>25.  Indiana Jones and the Fate of Atlantis</description>
    <rom name="amigaromset/CommodoreAmigaRomset1.zip/IndianaJones%26TheFateOfAtlantisAdventure_v1.3_0851.hdf" size="11157504"/>
    <perspective>3rd-Person</perspective>
    <releasedate>30/03/1992</releasedate>
    <plot>Indiana Jones is back! The great archaeologist and adventurer has to solve a grand mystery once again, aided by his trusty whip, his sharp wit, and his courage. A man who calls himself Mr. Smith is interested in a certain ancient statue. When the unsuspecting Indy hands it over to the client, he finds out that Mr. Smith is in fact a colonel in the Nazi army! Why was he so interested in that statue? A young woman who had once worked together with Indy, the pretty red-haired (and a bit troublesome) Sophia, tells him the whole thing must have a connection with the legendary lost continent Atlantis. Gathering clues from all over the world, Indy and Sophia embark on a grand journey across the globe.[CR]Indiana Jones and the Fate of Atlantis is a puzzle-solving adventure game conceived in the spirit of Indiana Jones movies; however, it is not based on a specific movie, introducing a new, independent story. The game utilizes LucasArts' SCUMM system, with action verbs the player chooses from a menu; objects that can be interacted with are highlighted. The game contains many puzzles of various kinds (mostly inventory-based) and dialogues with multiple choices. There are also a few simple hand-to-hand fights against the Nazis, some of which can be avoided.[CR]The middle part of the game can be played in three "modes": co-operation (Indy and Sophia), adventure (Indy alone), and action (Indy alone, with less puzzles and more action). In each mode there are different locations to visit, different puzzles to solve, and different characters to meet. The CD version of the game adds voice-overs to all the conversations.</plot>
    <boxart1>YJG0U6r.jpg</boxart1>
    <boxart2>TXuMNPn.jpg</boxart2>
    <boxart3>awrGvab.jpg</boxart3>
    <boxart4>JXqFxQq.jpg</boxart4>
    <boxart5>LuZ6ZJW.jpg</boxart5>
    <boxart6>gYXG0H3.jpg</boxart6>
    <boxart7>RdGYaPl.jpg</boxart7>
    <snapshot7>SiRfmaX.png</snapshot7>
    <snapshot8>lF7I1kj.png</snapshot8>
    <snapshot9>r5oUVHG.png</snapshot9>
    <snapshot10>eb9XarU.png</snapshot10>
    <fanart1>AGUoc5J.jpg</fanart1>
    <clearlogo1>FuO5CkC.png</clearlogo1>
    <emu_command>A4000</emu_command>
  </game>
  <game name="Chaos Engine 2, The (AGA)">
    <description>24.  The Chaos Engine</description>
    <rom name="amigaromset/CommodoreAmigaRomset1.zip/ChaosEngine2_v1.0_AGA_0173.hdf" size="3325952"/>
    <rating>4.1</rating>
    <perspective>Top-Down</perspective>
    <studio>Renegade, Time Warner Interactive</studio>
    <releasedate>30/03/1996</releasedate>
    <year>1996</year>
    <plot>At the end of The Chaos Engine you managed to put a stop to Baron Fortesque's out of control machine, only to free the Baron himself from its clutches. Unfortunately not everything went to plan after that. During the confusion the Baron snuck away back into his own contraption and into another time period. Our two heroes decide the only way to stop him is follow him, but unfortunately luck isn't on their side...[CR]Both players (either two human or one human and one computer controlled) are trapped within the Chaos Engine and can only escape by helping the Baron rebuild the engine. He will reward the character who helps him the most by granting him freedom, thus pitching our two heroes against each other.[CR]Whereas The Chaos Engine was a two-player co-operative game, The Chaos Engine 2 is a two-player competitive game!</plot>
    <genre>Sci-Fi,Sci-Fi</genre>
    <groups>The Chaos Engine series</groups>
    <nplayers>1-2 Sim</nplayers>
    <boxart1>Ysv1Xp5.jpg</boxart1>
    <boxart2>3GpRtBX.jpg</boxart2>
    <snapshot1>PXGqxmH.png</snapshot1>
    <snapshot2>wOixBGI.png</snapshot2>
    <snapshot3>Vy2Ec92.png</snapshot3>
    <snapshot4>cjq7GsP.png</snapshot4>
    <snapshot5>OXKDMUG.png</snapshot5>
    <snapshot6>eZrWgC7.png</snapshot6>
    <snapshot7>E3dMa6f.png</snapshot7>
    <snapshot8>hUSoF5V.png</snapshot8>
    <snapshot9>kGyG9QT.png</snapshot9>
    <clearlogo1>zDxnkXh.png</clearlogo1>
    <emu_command>A4000</emu_command>
  </game>
  <game name="Worms: The Director's Cut (AGA)">
    <description>23.  Worms - The Director's Cut</description>
    <rom name="amigaromset/CommodoreAmigaRomset1.zip/WormsDirectorsCut_v1.1_AGA_0605.hdf" size="3473408"/>
    <rating>4.6</rating>
    <perspective>Side-Scrolling</perspective>
    <studio>Team 17</studio>
    <releasedate>30/03/1997</releasedate>
    <year>1997</year>
    <plot>_Worms: The Director's Cut_ is a sequel to Worms. Like its predecessor, it is a turn-based artillery game. The game format remains the same: players control small armies of four Worms (whose names can be altered) with the sole purpose of blowing up all the other Worms on the map. Players can compete either against computer-controlled Worms or against each other. [CR]The weapons are more extensive (and destructive) than in the previous game, including the first appearances of the Kenny-on-a-Rope, Concrete Donkey, Priceless Ming Vase, Old Woman and Holy Hand Grenade. Also included is a level editor that allows players to create their own battlefields.</plot>
    <genre>2D,Side Scroller</genre>
    <groups>Worms series,Games with randomly generated environments,Animals: Worms,Gameplay feature: Jetpack,Gameplay feature: Freely destructible terrain,Games made in Blitz Basic,Games that include map/level editor</groups>
    <nplayers>1-8</nplayers>
    <boxart1>Ci4Fkkj.jpg</boxart1>
    <boxart2>iXzR4vw.jpg</boxart2>
    <boxart3>LyhAyWl.jpg</boxart3>
    <boxart4>YGtrr0D.jpg</boxart4>
    <snapshot1>UI0CfNZ.png</snapshot1>
    <snapshot2>ZjBQK3I.png</snapshot2>
    <snapshot3>asMompO.png</snapshot3>
    <snapshot4>TlZevxj.png</snapshot4>
    <snapshot5>Fh9Ef4D.png</snapshot5>
    <snapshot6>HfgaQCX.png</snapshot6>
    <snapshot7>bSrcJKf.png</snapshot7>
    <snapshot8>ZZYoz6x.png</snapshot8>
    <snapshot9>tX6i9GA.png</snapshot9>
    <snapshot10>X829PML.png</snapshot10>
    <banner1>eaweURJ.png</banner1>
    <emu_command>A4000</emu_command>
  </game>
  <game name="Ruff 'n' Tumble">
    <description>22.  Ruff 'n' Tumble</description>
    <rom name="amigaromset/CommodoreAmigaRomset1.zip/RuffNTumble_v1.4_0199.hdf" size="2244608"/>
    <rating>4.0</rating>
    <perspective>Platform</perspective>
    <studio>Renegade</studio>
    <releasedate>30/03/1994</releasedate>
    <year>1994</year>
    <plot>Ruff Rogers has lost his marbles - in the literal sense of the small round balls used to play a game on drains. He's been armed with a gun to retrieve them from 16 levels of side-scrolling platform shooting.[CR]The gun you start with isn't especially powerful, but various machine guns and flamethrowers can be collected, which make much lighter work of the enemies. Your character can jump and duck responsively, and fire at all angles.[CR]There are 3 different colours of marbles, which a quota to recover from each level. Collecting enough of each particular colour sees all similar ones turned to coins, which can go towards extra lives and points bonuses. Switches are built into the levels; these act as restart points.</plot>
    <genre>Platform</genre>
    <nplayers>1</nplayers>
    <boxart1>iH9tofT.jpg</boxart1>
    <boxart2>82A4o23.jpg</boxart2>
    <boxart3>wymBshH.jpg</boxart3>
    <snapshot1>YX50i0x.png</snapshot1>
    <snapshot2>V1hD9dE.png</snapshot2>
    <snapshot3>lhSKTGE.png</snapshot3>
    <snapshot4>xvfJBaE.png</snapshot4>
    <snapshot5>Wvl2f5M.png</snapshot5>
    <snapshot6>sXtfJIQ.png</snapshot6>
    <snapshot7>oRASAm2.png</snapshot7>
    <snapshot8>YpJUfU6.png</snapshot8>
    <snapshot9>a3pk42g.png</snapshot9>
    <snapshot10>id5GmPt.png</snapshot10>
    <banner1>DBF38b7.png</banner1>
    <emu_command>A4000</emu_command>
  </game>
  <game name="Colonization (AGA)">
    <description>21.  Colonization</description>
    <rom name="amigaromset/CommodoreAmigaRomset1.zip/Colonization_v1.0_AGA_0452.hdf" size="3358720"/>
    <rating>3.9</rating>
    <perspective>Top-Down</perspective>
    <studio>MicroProse</studio>
    <releasedate>31/05/1995</releasedate>
    <year>1995</year>
    <plot>_Sid Meier's Colonization_ is a strategy game which puts you in the role of Viceroy of the New World. You are sent by your King and country to establish colonies in the newly-discovered Americas that lie to the west. You face many of the same challenges that faced colonial organizers of the time-competition[CR]from other Old World powers, strange native cultures, the problems of establishing profitable trade programs, and the problems of organizing an army from a rag-tag band of colonists.[CR]The game begins with the European discovery of the Americas (1500) and continues until approximately the time of the American[CR]Revolution (1800). In the beginning of the game you are given a trading/exploration ship and a small group of colonists. You have no knowledge of what lies ahead of your ship, so you must explore until you find a suitable spot to lay down your first colony. As your[CR]colonies grow larger and larger, you inevitably encounter native populations and are confronted with competing imperial powers from the Old World.[CR]Each of your colonies is populated by a number of colonists, who you can assign to various tasks. Some chop wood, mine for ore and collect plants outside the colony, some others stay inside to turn those raw materials into more valuable cargo - such as rum (made from sugar), coats (made of furs) or hammers (made of lumber). Hammers which aren't a cargo you can sell, but represent the speed with which you construct new buildings in your colony. Some colonists are specialists, and thus are more effective at a certain job. [CR]The cargo you collect and produce is an important thing. You can take it to Europe to sell, and earn money to buy some other necessary things, hire colonists (though new, willing colonists appear in Europe by themselves) or buy ships and artillery. You can also trade it with the Indians or colonies of other nations. [CR]You'll construct various buildings in your colonies. They have a lot of different functions: some of them can improve the speed with which you produce valuable cargo, others allow you to defend yourself from attacks more easily or construct ships and artillery. Some buildings require you to spend a number of valuable Tools when constructed, though you can make new Tools out of ore. [CR]As you explore the land, you'll come across the Indian villages and some "places of interest" which can be investigated. A colonist that enters an Indian village can be welcomed with open hands, and the natives will reveal a map of nearby lands, or teach him a profession. Investigating places of interest has various consequences: sometimes you'll find nothing, sometimes you'll be killed for trespassing on ancient burial ground, but sometimes you'll find treasure! (Taking this treasure to Europe can be difficult though - if you don't have a sufficiently big ship, the King will agree to transport it for you... if you give him 50% of the gold). [CR]To defend yourself from enemies, you'll want to have some military units. Just give a colonist a musket and he'll turn into a Soldier, give him a horse, and he's a Scout or a Dragoon. However, such a warrior is typically inexperienced, though he might gain military experience in battle. Artillery is also good at defense, but don't try to leave your colonies with it - in the open field, it is useless. [CR]As you progress in the game, you'll feel that working for the King is getting more and more annoying, especially since he keeps raising your taxes, thus decreasing your income from sold goods. Your colonies produce "Liberty Bells", which increase rebel sentiment in the colonies. If the majority of colonists supports your yearning for freedom, you can declare independence. But when you do that, you'll have to deal with the King's expeditionary force arriving to teach you a lesson. If you manage to defeat all his incoming armies and emerge victorious from the American Revolutionary War, you've won!</plot>
    <genre>Historic</genre>
    <groups>Sid Meier's licensees,Merchant / Trade-oriented games,Historical conflict: American Revolutionary War,Games with randomly generated environments,Setting: Aztec,Setting: Inca,Game with Creator's name,Colonization series</groups>
    <nplayers>1</nplayers>
    <boxart1>9hLF98P.png</boxart1>
    <boxart2>60JWiNy.jpg</boxart2>
    <boxart3>j7iL0F2.jpg</boxart3>
    <boxart4>qAHQbDj.jpg</boxart4>
    <snapshot1>mVp9OUc.png</snapshot1>
    <snapshot2>SwRA3Y8.png</snapshot2>
    <snapshot3>B7dtBrd.png</snapshot3>
    <snapshot4>xvh9FYe.png</snapshot4>
    <snapshot5>LvfWDrB.png</snapshot5>
    <snapshot6>noWZU7Q.png</snapshot6>
    <snapshot7>GdwkkmK.png</snapshot7>
    <snapshot8>EU66JcX.png</snapshot8>
    <snapshot9>oTqDYAJ.png</snapshot9>
    <snapshot10>ugt4G5p.png</snapshot10>
    <emu_command>A4000</emu_command>
  </game>
  <game name="Eye Of The Beholder II: The Legend Of Darkmoon">
    <description>20.  Eye of the Beholder II - The Legend of Darkmoon</description>
    <rom name="amigaromset/CommodoreAmigaRomset1.zip/EyeOfTheBeholder2_v1.1_0834.hdf" size="4734976"/>
    <rating>4.0</rating>
    <perspective>1st-Person</perspective>
    <studio>SSI</studio>
    <releasedate>30/03/1992</releasedate>
    <year>1992</year>
    <plot>The Archmage Khelben summons the Heroes of Waterdeep, slayers of the Beholder Xanathar, for another mission. Strange things are happening in the forests near Waterdeep, centered around the Temple Darkmoon. People have been disappearing and shallow graves containing human remains have been found. Khelben teleports the party to the forests near Darkmoon so they may find out what kind of evil is working in the towers of the temple.[CR]Eye of the Beholder II: The Legend of Darkmoon is, like its predecessor, a first-person dungeon-crawling role-playing game based on the second edition of AD&amp;D; rules. It uses the same point-and-click gameplay mechanics and controls as the first game, with only minor changes. The game is set entirely in pseudo-3D maze-like areas; no automapping is available. Combat flows in real time, and characters can move as a single unit to lure enemies or avoid blows.[CR]A starting party consists of four characters, which can be transferred from the earlier game or created from scratch. Six classes (Fighter, Ranger, Paladin, Cleric, Mage, and Thief) are available. Characters can reach higher levels and learn new spells, must face new and tough monsters, and solve multiple puzzles. Compared to the first game, many more illustrated NPC encounters and cutscenes were added.</plot>
    <genre>Fantasy</genre>
    <groups>Dungeons &amp; Dragons (D&amp;D / AD&amp;D) licensees,Eye of the Beholder series,Dungeons &amp; Dragons Campaign Setting: Forgotten Realms,Gameplay feature: Hunger / Thirst,Gameplay feature: Importable characters,Gameplay feature: Character development - Automatic leveling,Fantasy Creatures: Elves,Fantasy Creatures: Dwarves,Fantasy Creatures: Dragons,Genre: Dungeon Crawler</groups>
    <nplayers>1</nplayers>
    <boxart1>LBNcYAc.jpg</boxart1>
    <boxart2>Z7yHka6.jpg</boxart2>
    <boxart3>uVfCrs4.jpg</boxart3>
    <boxart4>sw4sB3I.jpg</boxart4>
    <boxart5>U0Fybgj.jpg</boxart5>
    <boxart6>choLImK.jpg</boxart6>
    <boxart7>I2o9qec.jpg</boxart7>
    <boxart8>HsKidyY.jpg</boxart8>
    <snapshot1>OorsmY1.png</snapshot1>
    <snapshot2>pUOyp6q.png</snapshot2>
    <snapshot3>yekdOjh.png</snapshot3>
    <snapshot4>0XsUJgG.png</snapshot4>
    <snapshot5>Iqbt4YM.png</snapshot5>
    <snapshot6>0vlcO3o.png</snapshot6>
    <snapshot7>vg67flP.gif</snapshot7>
    <snapshot8>s3PxAH3.gif</snapshot8>
    <snapshot9>a1XoVlL.gif</snapshot9>
    <snapshot10>sGY3rsg.gif</snapshot10>
    <banner1>9kLIT5q.png</banner1>
    <emu_command>A4000</emu_command>
  </game>
  <game name="Lotus III: The Ultimate Challenge">
    <description>19.  Lotus III - The Ultimate Challenge</description>
    <rom name="amigaromset/CommodoreAmigaRomset1.zip/Lotus3_v1.3r3_0217.hdf" size="2408448"/>
    <rating>4.0</rating>
    <perspective>3rd-Person</perspective>
    <releasedate>30/03/1992</releasedate>
    <plot>Licensed by the classic British car company, this game featured 2 modes of play - one has you racing against 19 computer rivals (with witty names such as Alain Phosphate and Crash-Hard Banger), and the other pits you against the clock. [CR]There are 13 different types of races, ranging from Motorways to night-time to sections punctuated by roadworks, and some are lap-based with others being simple A-B. 2 players could play on a split screen mode.[CR]The game's crowning glory, however, was the RECS editor, which allowed you to create courses of your own, with theoretically millions possible.</plot>
    <genre>Driving</genre>
    <groups>Lotus Challenge series,Automobile: Lotus Esprit,Games with manual lookup copy protection,Physical Bonus Content: Poster</groups>
    <boxart1>http://www.mobygames.com/images/covers/l/45448-lotus-the-ultimate-challenge-amiga-front-cover.jpg</boxart1>
    <boxart2>zjI6RN3.jpg</boxart2>
    <boxart3>CtNNAFW.jpg</boxart3>
    <boxart4>tBpRMrx.jpg</boxart4>
    <snapshot1>http://www.mobygames.com/images/shots/l/159577-lotus-the-ultimate-challenge-amiga-screenshot-intro.png</snapshot1>
    <snapshot2>http://www.mobygames.com/images/shots/l/159578-lotus-the-ultimate-challenge-amiga-screenshot-another-intro.png</snapshot2>
    <snapshot3>http://www.mobygames.com/images/shots/l/159579-lotus-the-ultimate-challenge-amiga-screenshot-title-screen.png</snapshot3>
    <snapshot4>http://www.mobygames.com/images/shots/l/159580-lotus-the-ultimate-challenge-amiga-screenshot-main-menu.png</snapshot4>
    <snapshot7>NE1qE1N.png</snapshot7>
    <snapshot8>wTINgs3.png</snapshot8>
    <snapshot9>s1f8Em6.png</snapshot9>
    <snapshot10>rzfmAMS.png</snapshot10>
    <emu_command>A4000</emu_command>
  </game>
  <game name="Sensible World Of Soccer v1.1">
    <description>18.  Sensible World of Soccer</description>
    <rom name="amigaromset/CommodoreAmigaRomset1.zip/SensibleWorldOfSoccer11_v1.7_0201.hdf" size="2031616"/>
    <rating>4.0</rating>
    <perspective>Top-Down</perspective>
    <studio>Renegade</studio>
    <releasedate>30/03/1994</releasedate>
    <year>1994</year>
    <plot>This 94/95 version is an update of the classic Sensible Soccer action-oriented soccer game, this version sports sharper graphics, updated teams information, and more weather conditions you can choose from. As in the original, SWOS delivers a furious action on the pitch, with intuitive controls of tiny players that allow curve balls and bicycle kicks. Choose from a staggering number of league and national teams to compete in major tournaments.</plot>
    <genre>Management,Simulation</genre>
    <groups>Sensible Sports games,Sensible Soccer games</groups>
    <nplayers>1-2 Sim</nplayers>
    <boxart1>PnxvXAI.jpg</boxart1>
    <boxart2>RV80xvA.jpg</boxart2>
    <snapshot1>HAKauPa.png</snapshot1>
    <snapshot2>BnaTSGG.png</snapshot2>
    <snapshot3>SmBQ24t.png</snapshot3>
    <snapshot4>aRvYd3J.png</snapshot4>
    <snapshot5>k4IjD1N.png</snapshot5>
    <snapshot6>Z6es8cH.png</snapshot6>
    <snapshot7>YZUhsDx.gif</snapshot7>
    <snapshot8>091gnuH.gif</snapshot8>
    <snapshot9>kEPUSJR.gif</snapshot9>
    <snapshot10>FfUAJO1.gif</snapshot10>
    <clearlogo1>HWKv8IL.png</clearlogo1>
    <emu_command>A4000</emu_command>
  </game>
  <game name="Gunship 2000 (AGA)">
    <description>17.  Gunship 2000</description>
    <rom name="amigaromset/CommodoreAmigaRomset1.zip/Gunship2000_v3.1_AGA_0371.hdf" size="4456448"/>
    <rating>4.0</rating>
    <perspective>1st-Person</perspective>
    <studio>MicroProse</studio>
    <releasedate>30/03/1993</releasedate>
    <year>1993</year>
    <plot>Take the Apache, the new Longbow Apache, The Blackhawk, Comanche Scout, Comanche Gunship, or the MD-500 Defender on campaigns or missions. Updated graphics engine has much more detailed terrain variation with true valleys/hills and even train tunnels that you can fly through. When you are promoted to a sufficient rank you can take along multiple helicopters to accomplish your objectives. The dynamic campaign generates new missions based on multiple maps. Attack, defend, sweep, scout, rescue, drop... Lots of missions to keep you busy. Crew learn and grow in experience as they survive and succeed. A full mission recorder allows you to view EVERY member of your team as they fight or die. Plenty of weapons are available for your side from the latest Hellfire missiles and Sidearm anti-radar missiles to the old fashioned chain gun and gun pods are available for your use. The enemy can be well armed as well, from deadly 2S6 gun/missile combo to old-fashion ZSU-23, even the occasional MiGs.</plot>
    <genre>Flying,Flying,Helicopter</genre>
    <groups>Gunship series,Aircraft: AH-64 Apache,Aircraft: RAH-66 Comanche,Games with manual lookup copy protection,Gameplay feature: Recordable replays,Aircraft: UH-60 Black Hawk,Aircraft: Bell AH-1 Cobra</groups>
    <nplayers>1</nplayers>
    <boxart1>LJc3IFl.jpg</boxart1>
    <boxart2>zpSPEM3.jpg</boxart2>
    <boxart3>etIVMXO.jpg</boxart3>
    <boxart4>ICLj7DD.jpg</boxart4>
    <snapshot1>No0i4bK.png</snapshot1>
    <snapshot2>SF0zZPy.png</snapshot2>
    <snapshot3>PGJa7kW.png</snapshot3>
    <snapshot4>rvf7Egj.png</snapshot4>
    <snapshot5>w2AqI6T.png</snapshot5>
    <snapshot6>7XNFyHP.png</snapshot6>
    <snapshot7>QTHpJ5Y.png</snapshot7>
    <snapshot8>zfaihQy.png</snapshot8>
    <snapshot9>5QnGjQk.png</snapshot9>
    <snapshot10>dA257mi.png</snapshot10>
    <clearlogo1>6wwrgLh.png</clearlogo1>
    <emu_command>A4000</emu_command>
  </game>
  <game name="Wings">
    <description>16.  Wings</description>
    <rom name="amigaromset/CommodoreAmigaRomset1.zip/Wings_v1.0_0410.hdf" size="2048000"/>
    <rating>3.9</rating>
    <perspective>3rd-Person</perspective>
    <studio>Cinemaware / Mirrorsoft</studio>
    <releasedate>30/03/1990</releasedate>
    <year>1990</year>
    <plot>You are an allied fighter pilot in WW1, duking it out with the "Huns" up in the sky in over 200 missions.[CR]The missions usually come in three flavors: Top-down view bombing missions where you have to take out strategically important targets, isometric strafing runs where you get to blast anything that you fancy blasting with an unlimited supply of ammo, and of course the main part: Dogfights in the sky. Rendered in 3D, seems from behind your head.[CR]The game is set in the years 1916 through 1918, and to loosen things up a little, we get to read a page of our character's new entry for the diary-like journal in his company between every mission.</plot>
    <genre>Isometric</genre>
    <groups>Gameplay feature: Permadeath / permanent death,Wings games</groups>
    <nplayers>1</nplayers>
    <boxart1>dyzU79j.jpg</boxart1>
    <boxart2>7fwvfWA.jpg</boxart2>
    <boxart3>mPVUyfE.jpg</boxart3>
    <boxart4>wTJZndB.jpg</boxart4>
    <snapshot1>Cq9T4AY.png</snapshot1>
    <snapshot2>lfg0LRt.png</snapshot2>
    <snapshot3>nhGnqJD.png</snapshot3>
    <snapshot4>Y1iN72U.png</snapshot4>
    <snapshot5>eFRmzv2.png</snapshot5>
    <snapshot6>8AGz0KG.png</snapshot6>
    <snapshot7>rLMnv5j.gif</snapshot7>
    <snapshot8>bltMGFV.gif</snapshot8>
    <snapshot9>9dlZ4Ps.gif</snapshot9>
    <snapshot10>wFXCZyZ.gif</snapshot10>
    <banner1>EDL8A9x.png</banner1>
    <emu_command>A4000</emu_command>
  </game>
  <game name="Syndicate">
    <description>15.  Syndicate</description>
    <rom name="amigaromset/CommodoreAmigaRomset1.zip/Syndicate_v2.2_0739.hdf" size="3964928"/>
    <rating>4.0</rating>
    <perspective>Isometric</perspective>
    <studio>Electronic Arts</studio>
    <releasedate>30/03/1993</releasedate>
    <year>1993</year>
    <plot>In the future, the world is controlled by a handful of global corporations (syndicates). You are the Marketing director (hit man) for one of these companies. It is your job to take control away from the competitors. The job is not one of diplomacy, but one of brute force and physical control. Advance your way to the top of the corporation by successfully completing your missions and managing the money you make from your territories.[CR]The gameplay is visually reminiscent of X-Com, with an angled top-down perspective, but it is real time rather than turn based. You have missions ranging from infiltrate and capture, to seek and destroy. In each of these you direct a team of four agents as they move through the world shooting at anything that gets in their way.[CR]You can upgrade and modify your agents, as well as equip them with tools you have researched or liberated from opposing syndicates. As you complete missions, you gain more funds to use for purchasing agents or researching upgrades and equipment.</plot>
    <genre>Isometric</genre>
    <groups>Syndicate series,Setting: African,Gameplay feature: Squad management</groups>
    <nplayers>1</nplayers>
    <boxart1>vjUMKNP.png</boxart1>
    <boxart2>zNfFRVO.jpg</boxart2>
    <boxart3>L2ox31q.jpg</boxart3>
    <boxart4>lfqDD4f.jpg</boxart4>
    <snapshot1>QTUzbWQ.png</snapshot1>
    <snapshot2>lAGJBkk.png</snapshot2>
    <snapshot3>mTpGd0R.png</snapshot3>
    <snapshot4>37zCWhZ.png</snapshot4>
    <snapshot5>OP2qGP0.png</snapshot5>
    <snapshot6>QxX1cFT.png</snapshot6>
    <snapshot7>hGixCAD.jpg</snapshot7>
    <snapshot8>8hdFLAY.jpg</snapshot8>
    <snapshot9>8G9yOeJ.jpg</snapshot9>
    <snapshot10>6m1diVn.png</snapshot10>
    <banner1>JVuJ0e3.png</banner1>
    <clearlogo1>7u5bYkM.png</clearlogo1>
    <emu_command>A4000</emu_command>
  </game>
  <game name="Another World">
    <description>14.  Another World</description>
    <rom name="amigaromset/CommodoreAmigaRomset1.zip/AnotherWorld_v2.4_0425.hdf" size="1818624"/>
    <rating>3.7</rating>
    <perspective>1st-Person</perspective>
    <studio>US Gold</studio>
    <releasedate>30/03/1990</releasedate>
    <year>1991</year>
    <plot>A young physics professor named Lester conducts a particle experiment. Suddenly, something goes wrong, a lightning strikes, and in a moment Lester finds himself in a strange alien world. Now he must fight for his life, first with his bare hands, then with a gun he finds. But what gives him courage is that he is not alone. One of the aliens who escapes from the prison together with him helps him on his dangerous quest. Friendship can overcome all the obstacles.[CR]Another World combines shooting, platforming, and puzzle-solving elements. The game is divided into stages; some of them are straightforward and can only be accessed one time, while others are connected to each other, constituting a larger environment. Exploration and problem-solving are emphasized. Many levels include challenges not seen in the previous ones. Tasks may involve environmental puzzles, timed sequences, precise jumping, and combat.[CR]Typically, enemies are defeated by using an energy gun found in an early stage. The gun's regular function is shooting energy projectiles. By pressing down and holding the fire button the player can activate an energy shield which protects Lester from regular attacks, allowing him to fire from relative safety until it evaporates. Finally, by holding the fire button even longer the gun creates powerful blasts which can disrupt shields. Most enemies are equipped with similar guns and are able to perform the same actions as Lester. Fighting enemies therefore requires tactical usage of regular attacks, shields, and bombs, as well as learning enemy patterns.[CR]Each level can be accessed by typing a code the player learns after having completed the level. If Lester dies, the level must be restarted. There is no on-screen interface and no in-game dialogue in the game. Vector graphics are used for creating the game's environments and animated cutscenes.</plot>
    <genre>Fixed Screen</genre>
    <groups>Another World / Out of This World series,HUDless games,Games with code-wheel copy protection,Game Center CX challenge games,Genre: Cinematic Platformer</groups>
    <nplayers>1</nplayers>
    <boxart1>IploY7Q.jpg</boxart1>
    <boxart2>aFMr0l7.jpg</boxart2>
    <boxart3>kPEaxoS.jpg</boxart3>
    <boxart4>kPEaxoS.jpg</boxart4>
    <snapshot1>5SShoJm.png</snapshot1>
    <snapshot2>1iQkitM.png</snapshot2>
    <snapshot3>jKlz48M.png</snapshot3>
    <snapshot4>uOu5FkW.png</snapshot4>
    <snapshot5>Pvyw4a3.png</snapshot5>
    <snapshot6>3mEicgx.png</snapshot6>
    <snapshot7>WmJnTVP.png</snapshot7>
    <snapshot8>nfpJ0Ph.png</snapshot8>
    <snapshot9>nCL2oRw.png</snapshot9>
    <snapshot10>N37ntj0.png</snapshot10>
    <banner1>hnfMrTk.png</banner1>
    <clearlogo1>Hens2og.png</clearlogo1>
    <videoid>Zgkf6wooDmw</videoid>
    <emu_command>A4000</emu_command>
  </game>
  <game name="Flashback">
    <description>13.  Flashback</description>
    <rom name="amigaromset/CommodoreAmigaRomset1.zip/Flashback_v3.2_1163.hdf" size="3801088"/>
    <rating>4.0</rating>
    <perspective>Platform</perspective>
    <studio>US Gold</studio>
    <releasedate>30/03/1992</releasedate>
    <year>1993</year>
    <plot>The year is 2142. The player takes control of Conrad B. Hart, a man who has lost his memory. After barely escaping from hostile aliens, Conrad's bike crashes on an unknown planet. Conrad finds himself in the jungle, and from that moment on his quest for survival and his lost identity begins.[CR] _Flashback: The Quest for Identity_ incorporates elements of platforming, shooting, and problem-solving. The game can be described as a "cinematic platformer" (commonly referred to as Prince of Persia-style), following a design philosophy that was also manifested in Delphine Software's previous work, Another World. Compared to that game, _Flashback_ focuses more on platforming and exploration of large levels.[CR]While a large bulk of the gameplay is dedicated to running, jumping, and shooting enemies, there is also a considerable exploration element in the game, as well as some puzzle-solving. The player navigates Conrad through platform structures, performing various moves. It is possible to simply jump or do a longer run-and-jump, run, climb, hang off ledges, and pick up objects lying on the ground. [CR]To defend himself, Conrad can shoot enemies with his gun and also use various objects (such as stones) to harm or distract them. Crouching and rolling are possible (and often essential) moves that can be executed during combat. The gun has unlimited ammunition; however, shields that Conrad uses to protect himself from attacks are depleted when he is hit, and can be recharged at special stations. Though most environments in the game are hostile, there are a few locations that are devoid of enemies. The player is usually required to talk to characters, gather information and compete tasks in an adventure-like fashion in these areas. [CR]Most of the versions utilize cutscenes with polygonal vector graphics. The CD versions replace those with pre-rendered 3D animations. The Sega CD version also features voice-overs.</plot>
    <genre>Fixed Screen</genre>
    <groups>Flashback series,Theme: Amnesia,Games made into comics,Game Center CX challenge games,Genre: Cinematic Platformer</groups>
    <nplayers>1</nplayers>
    <boxart1>rmBGeZY.png</boxart1>
    <boxart2>REp271Y.jpg</boxart2>
    <snapshot1>MJXgQlR.png</snapshot1>
    <snapshot2>N56n1n8.png</snapshot2>
    <snapshot3>yZtpqq3.png</snapshot3>
    <snapshot4>GGrg1Z4.png</snapshot4>
    <snapshot5>Il215AW.png</snapshot5>
    <snapshot6>zADIA3u.png</snapshot6>
    <snapshot7>d3QhP0R.png</snapshot7>
    <snapshot8>YWYjU9Z.png</snapshot8>
    <snapshot9>hL3ox4i.png</snapshot9>
    <snapshot10>lzVBtna.png</snapshot10>
    <banner1>F6sPhl4.png</banner1>
    <fanart1>8JC3gco.jpg</fanart1>
    <clearlogo1>TVeG3qy.png</clearlogo1>
    <emu_command>A4000</emu_command>
  </game>
  <game name="Civilization (AGA)">
    <description>12.  Civilization</description>
    <rom name="amigaromset/CommodoreAmigaRomset1.zip/Civilization_v1.0_AGA_1633.hdf" size="6045696"/>
    <rating>3.9</rating>
    <perspective>Top-Down</perspective>
    <studio>MicroProse</studio>
    <releasedate>30/03/1992</releasedate>
    <year>1992</year>
    <plot>_Civilization_ has the widest scope of any strategy game of its time. You are a leader of a nation. You begin in the Stone Age, and complete the game in the XXIth century (unless your civilization gets destroyed earlier). Your eventual goal is to become the dominant civilization in the world, either by wiping out everybody else, or being the first to get a space ship to Alpha Centauri.[CR]As the nation's leader, you have many responsibilities. You have to build cities, and then micromanage them, constructing various buildings. Most of people in your cities will be working on the neighbouring lands to get food (without it, your city won't survive or grow), production (used to build military units and buildings) and trade (which can be exchanged for money, science (see below) or luxuries that make people happy. You decide how much trade you want to invest into each of these areas.) You have to make sure that your people are in a good mood; if they get too unhappy, the city will collapse into disorder, and won't produce anything until you fix the situation. [CR]If you're ambitious, you can build Wonders of the World - epic constructions, such as the Pyramids or the Hoover Dam. Each Wonder is an unique thing, and only one of each can exist in the world. They give you a lot of benefits if you complete them, but they take a long time to build, and many of them will eventually stop working. [CR]There are other nations in the world, and there are also barbarians, so you'll have to invest into the military to protect yourself and to attack. Sure, you can sign peace treaties with other nations, and even exchange scientific knowledge with them (although sometimes they'll demand tribute from you), but eventually you'll probably have to fight. You control each of your military units on the world map, attacking your opponents' units and cities (possibly taking over them). [CR]Not all units are for combat though. Settlers are used to build cities, create roads (for easier travel of your units) and improve the land around cities, increasing production. Diplomats can be sent to foreign cities to negotiate with the other nations or create embassies, but they can also bribe enemy units to join you and conduct espionage and sabotage in the enemies' cities. Caravans can be sent to faraway cities to increase trade in their home city, and they can also help in building Wonders of the World. [CR]Scientific progress is an important part of the game. The more science your cities produce, the faster you research new technologies. Initially, you'll be finding out about the wonders of Alphabet or Bronze Working, but late in the game you'll be researching Computers and Robotics. Most technologies give you some new units, buildings and other things, although some have more interesting effects - for example, after inventing the Automobile, you'll find out that your citizens started producing pollution. Pollution is a bad thing; if there's too much of it, global warming may occur. [CR]How your cities prosper depends partially on the type of government that your nation has. Initially you're living in Despotism, but this can stunt growth of your civilization, so it's a good idea to switch to something else - Monarchy, Republic, Democracy or Communism.</plot>
    <genre>Isometric</genre>
    <groups>Civilization series,Sid Meier's licensees,Video games turned into board / card games,Games with randomly generated environments,Games with classical music,Games with manual lookup copy protection,Game with Creator's name,Sound engine: MED,Games with game altering copy protection</groups>
    <nplayers>1</nplayers>
    <boxart1>0IzPrrr.jpg</boxart1>
    <boxart2>fDAsNMg.jpg</boxart2>
    <boxart3>168QOnw.jpg</boxart3>
    <boxart4>ozNAMuG.jpg</boxart4>
    <boxart5>jiIIMms.jpg</boxart5>
    <boxart6>At61kKO.jpg</boxart6>
    <snapshot1>yc6KIR5.png</snapshot1>
    <snapshot2>x8vC6uc.png</snapshot2>
    <snapshot3>tCPSzNY.png</snapshot3>
    <snapshot4>0RlWej3.png</snapshot4>
    <snapshot5>AqcN5fZ.png</snapshot5>
    <snapshot6>jpBSXUP.png</snapshot6>
    <snapshot7>C19GpKe.gif</snapshot7>
    <snapshot8>he2wAkA.gif</snapshot8>
    <snapshot9>6v7zhWI.gif</snapshot9>
    <snapshot10>vnkgvB7.gif</snapshot10>
    <banner1>485qFxE.png</banner1>
    <emu_command>A4000</emu_command>
  </game>
  <game name="Dune II: The Battle For Arrakis">
    <description>11.  Dune II - The Battle for Arrakis</description>
    <rom name="amigaromset/CommodoreAmigaRomset1.zip/Dune2_v1.10b_1548.hdf" size="4964352"/>
    <rating>4.0</rating>
    <studio>Virgin</studio>
    <year>1992</year>
    <plot>Based on the legendary Frank Herbert novel of the same name and visually inspired by the 1984 David Lynch movie, _Dune_ is a strategy-adventure hybrid where the player takes the role of young Paul Atreides, the son of Duke Leto. The Emperor Shaddam Corrino IV has given the Atreides House the rights to manage the extraction of the most precious substance in the entire universe - the Melange, commonly known as Spice in the desolate desert planet Arrakis (Dune), the only place in the universe capable of producing the substance. While everything indicates the offer is a trap orchestrated by their enemies the Harkonnen, the Atreides family agrees on moving, as _he who controls the spice, controls the universe_.[CR]The player arrives in Arrakis with the mission of contacting and convincing the Fremen tribes residing in sietches (desert settlements) near the Atreides palace to harvest the spice. Harvesting is the most important part of the game, required to purchase equipment from the smugglers and appease the emperor. To speed up the process of harvesting, the player can equip the tribes with harvesters to increase production and ornis to protect them from the gigantic protectors of the planet: Shai-Hulud - the sandworms. [CR]However, the spice doesn't last forever and new sietches must be prospected before having a mining crew assigned, but the player cannot run Southwards forever, as the Harkonnen enemy controls the North of the Planet, dangerously close to the Atreides Palace. Soon after the initial batches are sent to the Emperor, the player will have to actively deal with the Harkonnen, who will try to take control of player Sietches. For those, Fremen tribes can be assigned to military training with Gurney Halleck, but before doing such work Paul must have a certain reputation, gained by the control of Arrakis.[CR]As the game advances, the player will untap Paul's latent powers, as well as meeting other characters from the Dune universe, such as Duke Leto, Jessica, Thufir Hawat, Duncan Idaho, Harah, Chani, Stilgar and Liet Kynes, the mastermind behind the ecological plans on Dune - the ultimate goal.</plot>
    <genre>Sci-Fi,Sci-Fi</genre>
    <groups>Dune series,Inspiration: Movies,Games with manual lookup copy protection</groups>
    <nplayers>1</nplayers>
    <boxart1>9eRPtfK.jpg</boxart1>
    <snapshot1>w9isf0q.png</snapshot1>
    <snapshot2>kAhP8WA.png</snapshot2>
    <snapshot3>gLXkeYd.png</snapshot3>
    <snapshot4>GoD2ZfI.png</snapshot4>
    <snapshot5>NBIhNth.png</snapshot5>
    <snapshot6>qpi4gXC.png</snapshot6>
    <banner1>KDdGe9m.png</banner1>
    <emu_command>A4000</emu_command>
  </game>
  <game name="Sensible World Of Soccer 96/97">
    <description>10.  Sensible World of Soccer '96-'97</description>
    <rom name="amigaromset/CommodoreAmigaRomset1.zip/SensibleWorldOfSoccer9697_v1.7_0842.hdf" size="1998848"/>
    <rating>4.1</rating>
    <perspective>Top-Down</perspective>
    <studio>Renegade</studio>
    <releasedate>30/03/1996</releasedate>
    <year>1996</year>
    <plot>Undoubtedly the best game in the venerable Sensible Soccer series, Sensible World of Soccer 96/97 is the last annual update by Sensible Software.[CR]SWOS 96/97 basically upgrades the earlier version, SWOS 95/96 Euro '96 Edition, with 1997 teams from around the world. Innovations from the previous version (SWOS 95/96) includes bendy passes, looping headers, more international teams, and even bells and whistles such as crowd animation. The hallmark of the series has been spotless playability and the sheer adrenaline rush of controlling tiny players from a top-down view, and SWOS 96/97 takes the fun to new heights with smoother animations and even more coaching options such as trial players and international management, one of the best new features. International management essentially means that after at least 3 consecutive successful seasons as a club's manager, you can be offered a chance to manage your national team in international tournaments, such as the World Cup or European Championship. You can actually manage any other nation if you don't select a nationality at the start. This feature is a lot of fun, and greatly extends the game's longevity. The career mode also sees some tweaks that make the game longer and more realistic. There are also numerous little additions that make the game a lot more user-friendly, such as flashing the name of a player who has control of the ball on screen, so you can tell the little players apart.[CR]If you love soccer, this is THE soccer game to own. It may not have the realistic ball handling of Dino Dini's Goal! or complex simulation options of Championship Manager, but for sheer playability and joy of on-the-pitch action, SWOS 96/97 is the only game in town.</plot>
    <genre>2D,Side Scroller</genre>
    <groups>Sensible Sports games,Sensible Soccer games,Games with dynamic advertisements</groups>
    <nplayers>1-2 Sim</nplayers>
    <boxart1>uO3X7wB.png</boxart1>
    <boxart2>WvYzHxy.jpg</boxart2>
    <boxart3>0JR3O1B.jpg</boxart3>
    <snapshot1>6jozjUg.png</snapshot1>
    <snapshot2>CwK0tM1.png</snapshot2>
    <snapshot3>7K7CHuY.png</snapshot3>
    <snapshot4>dk1kX5j.png</snapshot4>
    <snapshot5>SyOI86s.png</snapshot5>
    <snapshot6>m3py3wu.png</snapshot6>
    <videoid>tNFOyF9bVt4</videoid>
    <emu_command>A4000</emu_command>
  </game>
  <game name="UFO: Enemy Unknown (AGA)">
    <description>9.  UFO - Enemy Unknown</description>
    <rom name="amigaromset/CommodoreAmigaRomset1.zip/UFOEnemyUnknown_v1.0_AGA_0157.hdf" size="4784128"/>
    <rating>4.0</rating>
    <studio>Microprose</studio>
    <year>1995</year>
    <plot>In the year 1998, the amount of reports of UFO sightings has been drastically increased. Stories about abductions and alien attacks became more and more widespread. Finally, after various nations of the world have failed to intercept the UFOs, their representatives met in a conference of global importance in Geneva, Switzerland. It was eventually decided to organize a secret paramilitary group, dubbed Extraterrestrial Combat Unit (X-COM). Starting with one base, two fighters, one transport, and a few soldiers, X-COM must locate the aliens, learn about their origins and technology, find out where their base is, and destroy it.[CR] _X-COM: UFO Defense_ is a strategy game featuring separate but interlinked elements. On the strategic side, called GeoScape, you get a rotating view of the globe, where you see all visible UFOs (those that are within your detection range) as well as major cities and your base(s). You order movements from here, such as sending out fighters to intercept UFOs, transports with soldiers to assault/recover UFOs, and perhaps assaults on alien bases (if you find any). You also control your research, as you must invent better weapons (the Terran weapons are just no match against the alien weapons) quickly, not to mention all the other cool tech you can recover from the aliens. You also need to control your budget, as you can't afford to overextend your reach. Researchers need to be paid, engineers (who build the new toys) need to be paid, base(s) need to be be built/expanded, planes need to be bought/maintained, supplies need to be replenished, and so on.[CR]You can earn money by selling unneeded stuff, and you receive funding from the nations of the world; however, a nation can decrease its funding if it decides you aren't operating efficiently enough within its region. It's even possible that a nation gets so fed up with you that it signs a pact with the aliens and ceases funding altogether. [CR]Once you join a ground battle, the game switches to Battlescape, which is an isometric view of the battlefield with realistic line-of-sight calculations and turn-based combat. Your mission is usually extermination of all aliens on the battlefield, though if you can capture a few it would surely help your research efforts. If you win, you also recover any alien artifacts left on the field, which can then be researched.[CR]In combat, each of your soldiers has a specific number of Time Units. Doing anything (moving, shooting, turning around, rearranging objects in the inventory etc.) costs a number of TUs. Once a soldier is out of TUs, he cannot act any more this turn (he gets all his TUs back on the next turn, though).</plot>
    <genre>Isometric</genre>
    <groups>X-COM series,Games made into books,Setting: Mars,Video games turned into board / card games,Games with manual lookup copy protection,Gameplay feature: Squad management</groups>
    <nplayers>1</nplayers>
    <boxart1>WhUXhjh.jpg</boxart1>
    <snapshot1>ZSe5YUu.png</snapshot1>
    <snapshot2>2Hig3Eu.png</snapshot2>
    <snapshot3>mSyq9l2.png</snapshot3>
    <snapshot4>WABVgPJ.png</snapshot4>
    <snapshot5>b354yZT.png</snapshot5>
    <snapshot6>8Ox1kOC.png</snapshot6>
    <banner1>KSW0TRh.png</banner1>
    <clearlogo1>H2aw2fp.png</clearlogo1>
    <emu_command>A4000</emu_command>
  </game>
  <game name="Turrican II">
    <description>8.  Turrican II - The Final Fight</description>
    <rom name="amigaromset/CommodoreAmigaRomset1.zip/Turrican2_v1.5_0029.hdf" size="1359872"/>
    <rating>3.9</rating>
    <perspective>3rd-Person</perspective>
    <studio>Rainbow Arts / Innerprise</studio>
    <releasedate>30/03/1991</releasedate>
    <year>1990</year>
    <plot>Turrican is a 1990 video game programmed and designed by Manfred Trenz. It was first developed for the Commodore 64 by Rainbow Arts, but was ported to other systems later. In addition to concept design and character creation, Trenz personally programmed Turrican on the Commodore 64. A sequel, Turrican II, followed 1991 for the Commodore 64 and other platforms.[CR]The lost colony of Alterra is a completely man-made lifeworld abandoned long ago in a nearby galaxy. Alterra is actually five colonies in one. Each self-contained habitat has been separately bio-engineered by a powerful ecosystem generation network known as a Multiple Organism Unit Link. MORGUL, for short. Early colonists used MORGUL to render Alterra inhabitable. But a cataclysmic quake severed all system interface functions, and MORGUL murderously rebelled. The few colonists lucky enough to escape told a grim tale of a higher intelligence gone berserk.[CR]For generations, mankind sought a return to Alterra. Finally, genetic science created a saviour: Turrican, a mutant warrior, bio-engineered for the task of planetary reclamation. In the meantime, MORGUL has diligently twisted Alterran life forms to his brutal, destructive purposes. Thus, Turrican's challenges consist of eliminating hostile organisms from Alterra's five multi-level worlds and, finally, destroying the three faces of MORGUL.</plot>
    <genre>2D,Side Scroller</genre>
    <groups>Turrican series</groups>
    <nplayers>1</nplayers>
    <boxart1>sFUx3O1.jpg</boxart1>
    <boxart2>V5hVa9p.jpg</boxart2>
    <boxart3>3MJ0bfx.jpg</boxart3>
    <boxart4>LCAWdzZ.jpg</boxart4>
    <snapshot1>SEIU3sh.png</snapshot1>
    <snapshot2>0MdHVby.png</snapshot2>
    <snapshot3>MUSDk5P.png</snapshot3>
    <snapshot4>9tgXBAW.png</snapshot4>
    <snapshot5>8i6tqY1.png</snapshot5>
    <snapshot6>hKNYiIj.png</snapshot6>
    <snapshot7>3J1XurH.jpg</snapshot7>
    <snapshot8>whew6mq.png</snapshot8>
    <snapshot9>ZsLE78H.png</snapshot9>
    <snapshot10>Qe5KgOf.png</snapshot10>
    <banner1>WKPpQso.png</banner1>
    <clearlogo1>vPBTgzw.png</clearlogo1>
    <emu_command>A4000</emu_command>
  </game>
  <game name="Simon The Sorcerer (AGA)">
    <description>7.  Simon the Sorcerer</description>
    <rom name="amigaromset/CommodoreAmigaRomset1.zip/SimonTheSorcerer_v1.3_AGA_0898.hdf" size="9011200"/>
    <rating>3.8</rating>
    <perspective>3rd-Person</perspective>
    <studio>Adventure Soft</studio>
    <releasedate>30/03/1994</releasedate>
    <year>1994</year>
    <plot>Simon is just an ordinary boy living in modern-day England. One day, his dog Chippy discovers a chest with a book inside, entitled Ye Olde Spellbooke. Without thinking too much, Simon throws the book on the floor; as a result, a portal opens, teleporting the boy and his dog into a fantasy world. Simon is promptly captured by goblins bent on cooking and eating him, but manages to escape. Soon he realizes that he must play the role of an apprentice sorcerer and rescue a benevolent wizard called Calypso from an evil one, aptly named Sordid.[CR] _Simon the Sorcerer_ is a point-and-click adventure game very similar to contemporary LucasArts titles (in particular Monkey Island) in concept and gameplay. It features twelve verbs displayed on the screen at all times for interaction with the environment. Objects that can be interacted with are highlighted when the player hovers the mouse cursor over them. The puzzles are inventory-based: Simon will have to collect and carry a large amount of items in order to advance in the game. Almost every character comes with an extended dialogue tree to explore. Most of the conversation choices are used for a humorous effect and are not required to pursue. [CR]Like in LucasArts' adventures, it is impossible to get irrevocably stuck or die in _Simon the Sorcerer_. The game world consists of dozens of interconnected screens, most of which are accessible from the very beginning. Although there is usually only one way to solve the puzzles, the player can work on multiple tasks at once, and exploration occupies a large portion of the game. Whenever an important location is discovered, it is marked on the map for instant access, so that the player is not required to retrace his steps in order to revisit it. The game frequently parodies popular fairy tales and fantasy works and sometimes breaks the fourth wall as Simon directly talks to the player, acknowledging he is a character in a computer game.</plot>
    <genre>Fantasy</genre>
    <groups>Simon the Sorcerer series,Game Engine: AGOS</groups>
    <nplayers>1</nplayers>
    <boxart1>gEANH7s.jpg</boxart1>
    <boxart2>DuRXwGE.jpg</boxart2>
    <boxart3>AyjuHzD.jpg</boxart3>
    <boxart4>8ORFIkR.jpg</boxart4>
    <boxart5>4L7Zton.jpg</boxart5>
    <boxart6>YghLIX5.jpg</boxart6>
    <boxart7>hsTyDPW.jpg</boxart7>
    <boxart8>sqyUpUv.jpg</boxart8>
    <boxart9>P8XLiA7.jpg</boxart9>
    <boxart10>8u6kXyY.jpg</boxart10>
    <snapshot1>k60lRNt.png</snapshot1>
    <snapshot2>8vKEC2n.png</snapshot2>
    <snapshot3>SrUuKxA.png</snapshot3>
    <snapshot4>lT1j39z.png</snapshot4>
    <snapshot5>P8oVtuv.png</snapshot5>
    <snapshot6>GTbbYsN.png</snapshot6>
    <snapshot7>osyLk6M.jpg</snapshot7>
    <snapshot8>OWExlPZ.jpg</snapshot8>
    <snapshot9>dnYmJQR.jpg</snapshot9>
    <snapshot10>Xvptlo5.jpg</snapshot10>
    <clearlogo1>GyF3NIC.png</clearlogo1>
    <emu_command>A4000</emu_command>
  </game>
  <game name="Slam Tilt (AGA)">
    <description>6.  Slam Tilt - The Pinball Game</description>
    <rom name="amigaromset/CommodoreAmigaRomset1.zip/SlamTilt_v3.4_AGA_1151.hdf" size="4702208"/>
    <rating>3.8</rating>
    <perspective>Top-Down</perspective>
    <studio>21st Century</studio>
    <releasedate>30/03/1996</releasedate>
    <year>1996</year>
    <plot>The game features four different tables, each with different layouts and features. A large number of sub-games are included, as well as a variety of animations on the LCD panel at the top. Each table has multi-ball features, with the view automatically switching to full-screen when this is activated. in total there are six different viewpoints, and no less than 47 different game modes are promised.</plot>
    <genre>Arcade</genre>
    <groups>21st Century Entertainment Pinball series</groups>
    <nplayers>1-8</nplayers>
    <boxart1>PFpuukM.png</boxart1>
    <snapshot1>gcZfx3t.png</snapshot1>
    <snapshot2>qBhgEp9.png</snapshot2>
    <snapshot3>ziQ7abg.png</snapshot3>
    <snapshot4>Slm3YQh.png</snapshot4>
    <snapshot5>4cVCO5t.png</snapshot5>
    <snapshot6>alDRMb2.png</snapshot6>
    <snapshot7>SfaqHrA.gif</snapshot7>
    <snapshot8>noHengN.gif</snapshot8>
    <snapshot9>27yozxS.gif</snapshot9>
    <snapshot10>VYl4hz2.gif</snapshot10>
    <emu_command>A4000</emu_command>
  </game>
  <game name="Settlers, The">
    <description>5.  The Settlers</description>
    <rom name="amigaromset/CommodoreAmigaRomset1.zip/Settlers_v1.3_0143.hdf" size="3178496"/>
    <rating>3.9</rating>
    <studio>Blue Byte</studio>
    <releasedate>12/01/1993</releasedate>
    <year>1993</year>
    <plot>A strategy game with cartoony graphics and an innocent line in humour. At the start of the level you choose a starting point, the intention being to get lots of flat land as well as resources to mine and ideally existing sources of trees, stones and water (for fish). Your people are vying for supremacy with up to 3 others.[CR]The gameplay focuses on resource management. Each building requires a certain amount of wood (and stones for some of them) to be constructed and requires particular resources to perform its function successfully. Food must be produced (either fish, bread (requiring a windmill, grain-farmer and baker) or pork (requiring a pig-farmer and butcher as well as the grain-farm) to feed the people working in mines to produce the iron, coal and gold (as well as additional stones).[CR]Huts and Watch-Towers are built to expand your territory, sometimes at the expense of an enemy's land (clever play involves targeting an area where your opponent has a crucial building, thus compromising his production). [CR]To finally win the level, you must defeat your opponents. Combat is fought one-at-a-time by the little soldiers and a victory results in all surrounding buildings being lost.[CR]The game features 30 preset missions. 6 tutorials missions will help beginners to learn the game mechanics.[CR]The game also offers the possibility to play semi-randomly (based on a 16-number key) generated maps.[CR]The map size varies from small maps, for quick matches, to large maps to, depending on how much RAM is available, huge maps, for very long matches as the fact that the in-game statistics can be displayed on a 50-hour scale illustrates.[CR]These semi-random maps can be played in single-player mode but can also be played by 2 players on one system, if you have 2 mice, in which case the screen is vertically split.</plot>
    <genre>Isometric</genre>
    <groups>The Settlers series,Sound engine: AIL/Miles Sound System</groups>
    <nplayers>1-2 Sim</nplayers>
    <boxart1>Bpi9bXt.jpg</boxart1>
    <snapshot1>roAntg1.png</snapshot1>
    <snapshot2>uJqeoUT.png</snapshot2>
    <snapshot3>M7coRBf.png</snapshot3>
    <snapshot4>R2TZ4Xv.png</snapshot4>
    <snapshot5>iJ6XV7C.png</snapshot5>
    <snapshot6>5mi0SF4.png</snapshot6>
    <banner1>4CqqUC8.png</banner1>
    <clearlogo1>RetGX7p.png</clearlogo1>
    <emu_command>A4000</emu_command>
  </game>
  <game name="Cannon Fodder">
    <description>4.  Cannon Fodder</description>
    <rom name="amigaromset/CommodoreAmigaRomset1.zip/CannonFodder_v1.0_0860.hdf" size="2752512"/>
    <rating>3.7</rating>
    <ESRB>T - Teen</ESRB>
    <perspective>3rd-Person</perspective>
    <studio>Virgin</studio>
    <releasedate>30/03/1994</releasedate>
    <year>1993</year>
    <plot>Guide a team of up to six soldiers through 72 levels of combat in this top-down action/strategy hybrid, best thought of as Lemmings crossed with Commando crossed with Dune 2. The characters are controlled indirectly using the mouse, as you activate each soldier or group of them by highlighting them, click the left button to move them to a particular spot, and the right button for them to fire guns at an enemy. You can also pick up grenades or rockets, which can be used to destroy groups of enemies, buildings or some vehicles (by pressing both buttons at once). [CR]Each mission has a specific objective, and some feature vehicles such as tanks that used make things easier. Your troops can cross water but can't shoot within it, so finding and controlling bridges is often crucial. You can use the arrangement of trees to find hiding places to shoot from, and should watch out for CPU soldiers also doing so.</plot>
    <genre>Isometric</genre>
    <groups>Cannon Fodder series,BPjS / BPjM indexed games,Gameplay feature: Squad management</groups>
    <nplayers>1</nplayers>
    <boxart1>hCJBrWF.jpg</boxart1>
    <boxart2>YqmbLmt.jpg</boxart2>
    <boxart3>ZstOP6U.jpg</boxart3>
    <boxart4>uFVidfs.jpg</boxart4>
    <boxart5>FZ6Zrf2.jpg</boxart5>
    <boxart6>GB9V17B.jpg</boxart6>
    <snapshot1>7OljtEk.png</snapshot1>
    <snapshot2>ZTmx9gk.png</snapshot2>
    <snapshot3>7JMRhb4.png</snapshot3>
    <snapshot4>cLYEgtx.png</snapshot4>
    <snapshot5>zoeuoGr.png</snapshot5>
    <snapshot6>KWhlSD1.png</snapshot6>
    <snapshot7>4djsRBG.gif</snapshot7>
    <snapshot8>KGw7RrF.gif</snapshot8>
    <snapshot9>Xe3NAiG.gif</snapshot9>
    <snapshot10>u3fja2X.gif</snapshot10>
    <banner1>bXQ7WRN.png</banner1>
    <clearlogo1>do0mT6z.png</clearlogo1>
    <videoid>HqRag50MCek</videoid>
    <emu_command>A4000</emu_command>
  </game>
  <game name="Sensible World Of Soccer 95/96 - European Championship Edition">
    <description>3.  Sensible World of Soccer '95-'96 - European Championship Edition</description>
    <rom name="amigaromset/CommodoreAmigaRomset1.zip/SensibleWorldOfSoccer9596EuropeanChampions_v1.7_1825.hdf" size="2031616"/>
    <rating>4.6</rating>
    <perspective>Top-Down</perspective>
    <studio>Renegade / Time Warner</studio>
    <releasedate>14/04/1996</releasedate>
    <year>1996</year>
    <plot>A "sequel" of sorts to Sensible Software's 1995 Sensible World of Soccer. Based on the teams that played in Euro '96 tournament, SWOS: European Championship Edition sports new features that make the game even more addictive than SWOS, including the ability to pull off looping headers and curved passes, trial players, international management, and more charming cartoony graphics such as animated crowd and goal celebrations. The game itself remains what SWOS is, and more: a very addictive football game featuring tiny players, top-notch feel of the game, and excellent management options (although that is never the focus of this series) to round things off. Anyone who prefers "realistic" players such as motion-captured 3D models of current football games might be disinclined to try the game, but if you are a real fan of the sport, you will recognize after a few minutes how authentic SWOS: ECE feels, despite its cartoony players. You need to dribble the ball for real in this game - it doesn't "stick" to your foot like in FIFA. This, plus a staggering range of moves and shots you can do, make SWOS ECE much more fun than most other football games in the market. Released right before the 1996 European Championship in England, SWOS: ECE was a great PR move by Sensible Software and a superb game to boot. But since everything in the game would be included and surpassed in the 96/97 edition of SWOS , there is little reason to play this game. [CR]Reviewed by: Underdogs</plot>
    <genre>Management,Simulation</genre>
    <groups>Sensible Sports games,Sensible Soccer games</groups>
    <nplayers>1-2 Sim</nplayers>
    <boxart1>WUJXByT.jpg</boxart1>
    <snapshot1>0dVtuAh.png</snapshot1>
    <snapshot2>R2t4KR9.png</snapshot2>
    <snapshot3>WL0qJU3.png</snapshot3>
    <snapshot4>YI3ffpp.png</snapshot4>
    <snapshot5>hs3Pi1L.png</snapshot5>
    <snapshot6>PSmCZWK.png</snapshot6>
    <emu_command>A4000</emu_command>
  </game>
  <game name="Lemmings (2 Disk)">
    <description>2.  Lemmings</description>
    <rom name="amigaromset/CommodoreAmigaRomset1.zip/Lemmings_v1.4_2Disk_0132.hdf" size="2424832"/>
    <rating>3.8</rating>
    <perspective>3rd-Person</perspective>
    <studio>Psygnosis</studio>
    <releasedate>14/02/1991</releasedate>
    <year>1991</year>
    <plot>The basic objective of the game is to guide a group of humanoid lemmings through a number of obstacles to a designated exit. In order to save the required number of lemmings to win, one must determine how to assign a limited number of eight different skills to specific lemmings that allow the selected lemming to alter the landscape, to affect the behavior of other lemmings, or to clear obstacles in order to create a safe passage for the rest of the lemmings.[CR]Lemmings was one of the best received video games of the early 1990s era. The popularity of the game led to development of its numerous ports to other systems and the creation of several sequels, remakes and spin-offs, as well as inspiring similar games.</plot>
    <genre>2D,Side Scroller</genre>
    <groups>Lemmings series,Games made into books,Game Center CX challenge games,Gameplay feature: Herding</groups>
    <nplayers>1-2 Sim</nplayers>
    <boxart1>hAOLbtd.jpg</boxart1>
    <boxart2>icCvAXD.jpg</boxart2>
    <boxart3>h8X2fUU.jpg</boxart3>
    <boxart4>JgnztMx.jpg</boxart4>
    <boxart5>81oLedE.jpg</boxart5>
    <boxart6>ZmmD0Rq.jpg</boxart6>
    <boxart7>ckxCn7D.jpg</boxart7>
    <boxart8>ktIvWMa.jpg</boxart8>
    <snapshot1>0RI1MX6.png</snapshot1>
    <snapshot2>esf4DB4.png</snapshot2>
    <snapshot3>H0UDH3V.png</snapshot3>
    <snapshot4>aTUaPAi.png</snapshot4>
    <snapshot5>LfZNJJE.png</snapshot5>
    <snapshot6>aoE8l6c.png</snapshot6>
    <snapshot7>XwPy4jZ.gif</snapshot7>
    <snapshot8>AHsxglm.gif</snapshot8>
    <snapshot9>KlqYSPH.gif</snapshot9>
    <snapshot10>2pTakS7.gif</snapshot10>
    <banner1>YwBnYNv.png</banner1>
    <clearlogo1>1jFdN2D.png</clearlogo1>
    <emu_command>A4000</emu_command>
  </game>
  <game name="Secret Of Monkey Island, The">
    <description>1.  The Secret of Monkey Island</description>
    <rom name="amigaromset/CommodoreAmigaRomset1.zip/SecretOfMonkeyIsland_v3.4_1625.hdf" size="4096000"/>
    <rating>4.0</rating>
    <perspective>3rd-Person</perspective>
    <studio>U.S. Gold / Ubi Soft</studio>
    <releasedate>30/03/1991</releasedate>
    <year>1991</year>
    <plot>Deep in the Caribbean lies Melee Island, ruled by the governor Elaine Marley. The cruel pirate LeChuck is deeply in love with her - so deeply that he refuses to accept his own death. As a ghost, he dwells with his undead crew somewhere near the mysterious Monkey Island. Meanwhile, a young fellow named Guybrush Threepwood is determined to become a real pirate. At the Scumm Bar he meets three pirates who tell him he has to complete three difficult tasks in order to be worthy of this title. But as Guybrush is trying to complete these tasks, he encounters the lovely governor, and this meeting changes his life forever. Risking to incur the wrath of LeChuck, Guybrush has to prove his wit is as sharp as his sword, and figure out a way to foil the ghost pirate's plans...[CR]The Secret of Monkey Island is a classic adventure game that utilizes the command verb-based SCUMM interface first introduced in Maniac Mansion: the player constructs commands for Guybrush by selecting an appropriate verb and then combining it with an object or an inventory item. Objects that can be interacted with are highlighted when the player places a cursor over them. The game is the first LucasArts adventure in which it is impossible to get irrevocably stuck; like in Loom, the player character also cannot die. The branching dialogue system, where the player chooses between several available responses during conversations, allows the player to talk to characters in different ways without fearing a wrong choice, and is often used as a humorous device.[CR]The puzzles are predominantly inventory-based; most of the problems in the game are solved by picking up items and combining them with each other or with objects (or people) in the game world. Several tasks are dialogue-based; among those is the humorous "insult swordfighting", which involves Guybrush learning and choosing witty insults while dueling pirates.</plot>
    <genre>2D,Side Scroller</genre>
    <groups>Monkey Island series,Game Engine: SCUMM,Theme: Sea Pirates,Games with code-wheel copy protection,Setting: Church / Monastery</groups>
    <nplayers>1</nplayers>
    <boxart1>r7dlhyc.jpg</boxart1>
    <boxart2>O3nHy4J.jpg</boxart2>
    <snapshot1>87KWvhv.png</snapshot1>
    <snapshot2>8KoHlVz.png</snapshot2>
    <snapshot3>CoDwHw6.png</snapshot3>
    <snapshot4>YB979h8.png</snapshot4>
    <snapshot5>4XwoNFx.png</snapshot5>
    <snapshot6>99LbJeU.png</snapshot6>
    <banner1>vQdifKW.png</banner1>
    <clearlogo1>7rsGeQ7.png</clearlogo1>
    <videoid>KFPFFZs5m_w</videoid>
    <emu_command>A4000</emu_command>
  </game>
</datafile>