<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<datafile>
	<header>
		<emu_name>Atari 5200</emu_name>
		<emu_description>Atari 5200</emu_description>
		<emu_category>Atari, 1980s, Console, 8 Bit</emu_category>
		<emu_version>04152019</emu_version>
		<emu_date>03/03/2013</emu_date>
		<emu_author>Zach Morris</emu_author>
		<emu_visibility>visible</emu_visibility>
		<emu_homepage>http://www.mame.org/</emu_homepage>
		<emu_baseurl>http://archive.org/download/</emu_baseurl>
		<emu_launcher>external</emu_launcher>
		<emu_default_addon>none</emu_default_addon>
		<emu_ext_launch_cmd>none</emu_ext_launch_cmd>
		<emu_downloadpath>default</emu_downloadpath>
		<emu_postdlaction>unzip_rom</emu_postdlaction>
		<emu_comment>The Atari 5200 SuperSystem, commonly known as the Atari 5200, is a video game console that was introduced in 1982 by Atari Inc. as a higher end complementary console for the popular Atari 2600. The 5200 was created to compete with the Intellivision, but wound up more directly competing with the ColecoVision shortly after its release. The 5200 was based on Atari Inc.'s existing 400/800 computers and the internal hardware was almost identical, although software was not directly compatible between the two systems. The 5200's controllers feature an analog joystick and a numeric keypad along with start, pause and reset buttons. The 360-degree non-centering joystick was touted as offering more control than the four-position joystick controller offered with the Atari 2600.[CR]Developer:  Atari[CR]Manufacturer:  Atari[CR]CPU:  MOS 6502C[CR]Memory:  16 KB[CR]Graphics:  Alphanumeric Television Interface Controller[CR]Sound:  Pot Keyboard Integrated Circuit[CR]Display:  320x192[CR]Media:  Cartridge[CR]Max Controllers:  2</emu_comment>
		<emu_thumb>IvMbKMz.jpg</emu_thumb>
		<emu_banner>zzee99d.jpg</emu_banner>
		<emu_fanart>IEtGxt9.jpg</emu_fanart>
		<emu_logo>cRaNQQk.png</emu_logo>
		<emu_trailer>aeGBf5lnhhY</emu_trailer>
	</header>
  <game name="A.E. (USA) (Proto)">
    <description>A.E. (USA) (Proto)</description>
    <title_clean>A.E.</title_clean>
    <rom name="no-intro-atari-5200-20130303/No-Intro%20-%20Atari%20-%205200%20%282013-03-03%29.zip/A.E.%20%28USA%29%20%28Proto%29.zip" size="10926"/>
    <rating>0.75</rating>
    <nplayers>1</nplayers>
    <releasedate>04/01/1984</releasedate>
    <plot>A port of the classic computer game, A.E. (Which stands for Anti Environmental) is a most unusual 5200 prototype.  It was never announced by Atari nor was it mentioned in any internal documents. A.E. is an arcade style shooting game in which you have to shoot down waves of evil flying mechanical stingrays in order to save your planet.[CR]The Atari 5200 version only has four levels as opposed to ten that the computer versions boast. The loading times for the levels are also longer due to hardware constraints of the Atari 5200.</plot>
    <genre>Shooter</genre>
    <boxart1>ZCw5BIy.png</boxart1>
    <clearlogo1>hRI8Y7w.png</clearlogo1>
    <snapshot1>0yvKh7g.png</snapshot1>
    <boxart2>um74y3W.png</boxart2>
    <snapshot2>i7tiDti.png</snapshot2>
    <videoid>jGSmCUto_Ak</videoid>
    <snapshot3>nRYNLbl.jpg</snapshot3>
    <studio>Broderbund Software Inc</studio>
  </game>
  <game name="Activision Decathlon, The (USA)">
    <description>Activision Decathlon, The (USA)</description>
    <title_clean>The Activision Decathlon</title_clean>
    <rom name="no-intro-atari-5200-20130303/No-Intro%20-%20Atari%20-%205200%20%282013-03-03%29.zip/Activision%20Decathlon%2C%20The%20%28USA%29.zip" size="12220"/>
    <releasedate>18/10/1984</releasedate>
    <genre>Sports,Olympic Sports</genre>
    <gamefaqs_url>http://www.gamefaqs.com/atari5200/585295-decathlon</gamefaqs_url>
    <plot>Up to four players compete in the ten different events of a real-life decathlon, either in sequence or individually. The events are -[CR]100-Meter Dash[CR]Long Jump[CR]Shot Put[CR]High Jump[CR]400-Meter Race[CR]110-Meter Hurdles[CR]Discus Throw[CR]Pole Vault[CR]Javelin Throw[CR]1500-Meter Race</plot>
    <rating>4.71</rating>
    <nplayers>4</nplayers>
    <studio>Activision</studio>
    <ESRB>ESRB - E (Everyone)</ESRB>
    <boxart1>G3Q03WL.png</boxart1>
    <clearlogo1>L9kZRTU.png</clearlogo1>
    <snapshot1>KFdjZzS.png</snapshot1>
    <boxart2>zvnhcRZ.jpg</boxart2>
    <snapshot2>vTgQKyE.png</snapshot2>
    <boxart3>vpbNCBM.png</boxart3>
    <boxart4>sUN5dwv.png</boxart4>
    <snapshot10>vxvSzB3.png</snapshot10>
    <snapshot3>eUTVxrD.gif</snapshot3>
    <snapshot4>6RKXQ6k.gif</snapshot4>
    <snapshot5>zxr6k4J.gif</snapshot5>
    <snapshot6>XRiAEHW.gif</snapshot6>
    <snapshot7>vqxxmR3.gif</snapshot7>
    <snapshot8>SvxeaaH.gif</snapshot8>
    <snapshot9>nCAi1gB.png</snapshot9>
  </game>
  <game name="Asteroids (USA) (Proto)">
    <description>Asteroids (USA) (Proto)</description>
    <title_clean>Asteroids</title_clean>
    <rom name="no-intro-atari-5200-20130303/No-Intro%20-%20Atari%20-%205200%20%282013-03-03%29.zip/Asteroids%20%28USA%29%20%28Proto%29.zip" size="5142"/>
    <rating>1.38</rating>
    <nplayers>4</nplayers>
    <releasedate>11/05/1982</releasedate>
    <plot>Trapped in space somewhere between the planets Ortanus and Earth, your ship is suddenly surrounded by a field of massive asteroids. And, as if that weren't enough excitement for one day, a group of alien saucers stage a surprise attack. Quickly you take over the controls to save your ship from imminent doom. You must thrust away from the path of the oncoming asteroids. Put up shields to protect the ship. Hyperspace into thin air. Flip over and get the asteroids attacking from behind. It's all in your hands now. Good luck![CR]Thought to have been planned to be a launch title for the Atari 5200 system due to the catalog number of CX5201. However it was never officially released but the prototype was found eventually. It's very similar to the Atari 8-Bit version of the game but unfortunately the controls are pretty poor with the 5200 joystick. There was an official controller that was planned to be released along with the game but sadly this was not to be.</plot>
    <genre>Shooter</genre>
    <boxart1>0f6dKSs.png</boxart1>
    <clearlogo1>ZUFKYrD.png</clearlogo1>
    <snapshot1>vZrPXtq.png</snapshot1>
    <boxart2>1Y4sFan.png</boxart2>
    <snapshot2>UV39JSD.png</snapshot2>
    <boxart3>U3HjNHK.jpg</boxart3>
    <videoid>7GPmG6S7UXE</videoid>
    <studio>Atari</studio>
  </game>
  <game name="Astro Chase (USA)">
    <description>Astro Chase (USA)</description>
    <title_clean>Astro Chase</title_clean>
    <rom name="no-intro-atari-5200-20130303/No-Intro%20-%20Atari%20-%205200%20%282013-03-03%29.zip/Astro%20Chase%20%28USA%29.zip" size="10266"/>
    <releasedate>18/10/1983</releasedate>
    <genre>Action,Shooter,Scrolling</genre>
    <gamefaqs_url>http://www.gamefaqs.com/atari5200/585284-astro-chase</gamefaqs_url>
    <plot>As pilot of a spaceship, your job is to save the planet Earth! Eight mega mines are slowly homing in, and you need to destroy them all before they reach Earth. Trying to stop you are a variety of flying saucers which will constantly be chasing you around the planet. Your ship is equipped with lasers which can be used to destroy enemy saucers and the mega mines. Located throughout the space around Earth are eight shield depots; if you fly through one of these, you will temporarily become invincible. Your spaceship also has a limited energy supply; if you get too low on energy, it can be resupplied at one of the generators located in the four corners of the play area. When all of the mega mines have been destroyed, you will move on to the next, faster chase!</plot>
    <rating>4.50</rating>
    <nplayers>1</nplayers>
    <studio>Parker Brothers</studio>
    <ESRB>ESRB - E (Everyone)</ESRB>
    <boxart1>Y6IWaP4.png</boxart1>
    <clearlogo1>p1xspQ8.png</clearlogo1>
    <snapshot1>H1PugA5.png</snapshot1>
    <boxart2>nIHn9tf.jpg</boxart2>
    <snapshot2>GCqkqMg.png</snapshot2>
    <boxart3>nE91G53.png</boxart3>
    <boxart4>rQisidd.png</boxart4>
    <snapshot3>pbYgNcO.gif</snapshot3>
    <snapshot4>PNRHiX9.png</snapshot4>
    <snapshot5>joRmgAe.png</snapshot5>
    <snapshot6>Fezc3jr.png</snapshot6>
    <snapshot7>4jEB4RY.png</snapshot7>
    <snapshot8>1DYHLVf.png</snapshot8>
    <snapshot9>YtN08I8.png</snapshot9>
  </game>
  <game name="Ballblazer (USA)">
    <description>Ballblazer (USA)</description>
    <title_clean>Ballblazer</title_clean>
    <rom name="no-intro-atari-5200-20130303/No-Intro%20-%20Atari%20-%205200%20%282013-03-03%29.zip/Ballblazer%20%28USA%29.zip" size="18569"/>
    <releasedate>18/10/1986</releasedate>
    <genre>Action,General</genre>
    <gamefaqs_url>http://www.gamefaqs.com/atari5200/585285-ballblazer</gamefaqs_url>
    <plot>Ballblazer is a simple one-on-one sports-style game bearing similarities to basketball and soccer. Each side is represented by a craft called a "rotofoil", which can be controlled by either a human player or a computer-controlled "droid" with ten levels of difficulty. (The game allows for human vs. human, human vs. droid, and droid vs. droid matches.) The basic objective of the game is to score points by either firing or carrying a floating ball into the opponent's goal. The game takes place on a flat, checkerboard playfield, and each player's half of the screen is presented in a first-person perspective.</plot>
    <rating>2.80</rating>
    <nplayers>2</nplayers>
    <studio>Atari</studio>
    <ESRB>ESRB - E (Everyone)</ESRB>
    <boxart1>VOj9ku8.png</boxart1>
    <banner1>ngJsrRI.jpg</banner1>
    <clearlogo1>cbOVG5Y.png</clearlogo1>
    <snapshot1>pMG14K5.png</snapshot1>
    <boxart2>Q8yLwT9.jpg</boxart2>
    <snapshot2>ByZNQC4.png</snapshot2>
    <boxart3>jWRCN6P.png</boxart3>
    <boxart4>VmI8XL1.png</boxart4>
    <snapshot10>2MBZGZ6.png</snapshot10>
    <snapshot3>vR46TVe.gif</snapshot3>
    <snapshot4>WmaPVgK.gif</snapshot4>
    <snapshot5>qf2yx3B.gif</snapshot5>
    <snapshot6>QsZxmsh.png</snapshot6>
    <snapshot7>2cf10nP.png</snapshot7>
    <snapshot8>X8S6aLl.png</snapshot8>
    <snapshot9>dhggEyD.png</snapshot9>
  </game>
  <game name="Barroom Baseball (USA) (Proto)">
    <description>Barroom Baseball (USA) (Proto)</description>
    <title_clean>Barroom Baseball</title_clean>
    <rom name="no-intro-atari-5200-20130303/No-Intro%20-%20Atari%20-%205200%20%282013-03-03%29.zip/Barroom%20Baseball%20%28USA%29%20%28Proto%29.zip" size="17166"/>
    <plot>Barroom Baseball is an interesting prototype in that it was never intended for home use.  As the name suggests Barroom Baseball was a special version of Realsports Baseball modified for use in 5200 arcade units.  These special 5200's were modified to run off of a coin operated timer and were intended for use in bars and in Latin American countries where such machines were popular.  It is unknown if any of these units were actually produced, but according to internal company memos at least one may have been field tested.  To date no other specially modified games have been found.</plot>
    <boxart1>BBuJHpL.png</boxart1>
    <snapshot1>dsgRJbs.png</snapshot1>
    <boxart2>MYkyO82.jpg</boxart2>
    <snapshot2>AuQHJWl.png</snapshot2>
    <ESRB>E - Everyone</ESRB>
    <genre>Sports</genre>
    <nplayers>1-2 Alt</nplayers>
    <releasedate>01/01/1983</releasedate>
    <studio>Atari</studio>
  </game>
  <game name="Battlezone (USA) (Proto)">
    <description>Battlezone (USA) (Proto)</description>
    <title_clean>Battlezone</title_clean>
    <rom name="no-intro-atari-5200-20130303/No-Intro%20-%20Atari%20-%205200%20%282013-03-03%29.zip/Battlezone%20%28USA%29%20%28Proto%29.zip" size="9990"/>
    <rating>4.00</rating>
    <nplayers>1</nplayers>
    <releasedate>15/09/1983</releasedate>
    <plot>A port of the arcade game Battlezone for Atari 5200. Like the arcade game you drive a tank around and shoot enemy tanks while trying to avoid their fire in a 3d environment. It was unfortunately never released and only exists in prototype form. The prototype seems mostly finished but the hit detection seems off at times and not perfected. It also replaces some of the vector based graphics of the arcade with raster likely due to limitations of the Atari 5200. You can also play this with two joysticks which is said to help with controlling the game versus single if you get used to it.</plot>
    <genre>Action, Shooter</genre>
    <boxart1>UJEV3nA.png</boxart1>
    <clearlogo1>V6jTnpo.png</clearlogo1>
    <snapshot1>fVFrlj9.png</snapshot1>
    <snapshot2>9WfUnhK.png</snapshot2>
    <videoid>LsYDnNiEuIA</videoid>
    <studio>Atari</studio>
  </game>
  <game name="Beamrider (USA)">
    <description>Beamrider (USA)</description>
    <title_clean>Beamrider</title_clean>
    <rom name="no-intro-atari-5200-20130303/No-Intro%20-%20Atari%20-%205200%20%282013-03-03%29.zip/Beamrider%20%28USA%29.zip" size="11194"/>
    <releasedate>18/10/1984</releasedate>
    <genre>Action,Shooter,Scrolling</genre>
    <gamefaqs_url>http://www.gamefaqs.com/atari5200/585287-beamrider</gamefaqs_url>
    <plot>Beamrider takes place above Earth's atmosphere, where a large alien shield called the Restrictor Shield surrounds the Earth. The player's objective is to clear the Shield's 99 sectors of alien craft while piloting the Beamrider ship. The Beamrider is equipped with a short-rage laser lariat and a limited supply of torpedos. The player is given three at the start of each sector.[CR]To clear a sector, fifteen enemy ships must be destroyed. A "Sentinel ship" will then appear, which can be destroyed using a torpedo (if any remain) for bonus points. Some enemy ships can only be destroyed with torpedoes, and some must simply be dodged. Occasionally during a sector, "Yellow Rejuvenators" (extra lives) appear. They can be picked up for an extra ship, but if they are shot they will transform into ship-damaging debris.</plot>
    <nplayers>1</nplayers>
    <studio>Activision</studio>
    <ESRB>ESRB - E (Everyone)</ESRB>
    <rating>3.4</rating>
    <boxart1>Y4j4e1x.png</boxart1>
    <banner1>DyG6QA6.jpg</banner1>
    <clearlogo1>ujofJCz.png</clearlogo1>
    <snapshot1>pbvrN65.png</snapshot1>
    <fanart1>y45OiuY.jpg</fanart1>
    <boxart2>vg84tTp.jpg</boxart2>
    <snapshot2>JJvD4Gr.png</snapshot2>
    <boxart3>5wGsrvw.png</boxart3>
    <snapshot10>gz5JpUf.png</snapshot10>
    <snapshot3>Ii1iqcr.gif</snapshot3>
    <snapshot4>h4RknOI.gif</snapshot4>
    <snapshot5>5KMMvXq.gif</snapshot5>
    <snapshot6>vRVHxJt.gif</snapshot6>
    <snapshot7>3TgI4xj.png</snapshot7>
    <snapshot8>DSbST8a.png</snapshot8>
    <snapshot9>2onSkmy.png</snapshot9>
  </game>
  <game name="BerZerk (USA)">
    <description>BerZerk (USA)</description>
    <title_clean>BerZerk</title_clean>
    <rom name="no-intro-atari-5200-20130303/No-Intro%20-%20Atari%20-%205200%20%282013-03-03%29.zip/BerZerk%20%28USA%29.zip" size="12069"/>
    <releasedate>18/10/1983</releasedate>
    <genre>Action,General</genre>
    <gamefaqs_url>http://www.gamefaqs.com/atari5200/563258-berzerk</gamefaqs_url>
    <plot>'Intruder Alert!' warns the robot. You are the intruder in a hostile maze-like planet where even the walls are death to touch. Relentlessly pursued by robot gangs, you must pulverize these androids with your laser gun before they blast you with theirs. 'The humanoid must not escape!' shouts the robot master. Evil Otto, as he heads toward you. How long can you survive such madness?</plot>
    <nplayers>1-2</nplayers>
    <ESRB>ESRB - E (Everyone)</ESRB>
    <studio>Atari</studio>
    <rating>3.5</rating>
    <boxart1>Qb9l7qw.png</boxart1>
    <snapshot1>wH1UbKu.png</snapshot1>
    <snapshot2>3ilQauj.png</snapshot2>
  </game>
  <game name="Black Belt (USA) (Proto)">
    <description>Black Belt (USA) (Proto)</description>
    <title_clean>Black Belt</title_clean>
    <rom name="no-intro-atari-5200-20130303/No-Intro%20-%20Atari%20-%205200%20%282013-03-03%29.zip/Black%20Belt%20%28USA%29%20%28Proto%29.zip" size="11887"/>
    <plot>This unreleased, unfinished game is similar to Broderbund's famous game, Karateka. Select your black belt level (difficulty level) and fight your way through eight rooms. The keypad is used to execute a variety of karate moves, although the game has no collision detection so you can't really fight your enemies. While the game looks promising, you cannot progress beyond eight rooms because you can't defeat your enemies.</plot>
    <boxart1>wEZY3Z9.png</boxart1>
    <snapshot1>rMkNXxg.png</snapshot1>
    <boxart2>NUAbgg7.jpg</boxart2>
    <snapshot2>JNVlvus.png</snapshot2>
    <boxart3>Gusf4Dl.jpg</boxart3>
    <genre>Fighting</genre>
    <nplayers>1</nplayers>
    <snapshot3>zlovdoV.jpg</snapshot3>
    <snapshot4>c8ldOPn.jpg</snapshot4>
    <snapshot5>AbYh81t.jpg</snapshot5>
    <snapshot6>CUA08ya.jpg</snapshot6>
    <snapshot7>QVRZxnz.jpg</snapshot7>
    <studio>Atari</studio>
  </game>
  <game name="Blaster (USA) (Proto)">
    <description>Blaster (USA) (Proto)</description>
    <title_clean>Blaster</title_clean>
    <rom name="no-intro-atari-5200-20130303/No-Intro%20-%20Atari%20-%205200%20%282013-03-03%29.zip/Blaster%20%28USA%29%20%28Proto%29.zip" size="12582"/>
    <nplayers>1</nplayers>
    <studio>Williams</studio>
    <plot>Blaster developed by Vid Kidz for Williams was released for the arcades and is quite obscure. What is interesting however is that the Atari 5200 version that was not released was actually made before the arcade game.[CR]An unofficial sequel to Robotron 2084 (As it takes place in 2085) Blaster is a 3d style shooter with impressive graphics for the time. In it the player takes the view from a spaceship cockpit so moving in the different directions shifts the entire screen. There are four levels you will play through avoiding obstacles, saving humans, and defeating alien enemies. Upon beating the four levels the game loops but will be more difficult.</plot>
    <genre>Shooter</genre>
    <boxart1>TxURpjY.png</boxart1>
    <snapshot1>I5jEuWb.png</snapshot1>
    <boxart2>itYewv2.png</boxart2>
    <snapshot2>6Q2cCOD.png</snapshot2>
    <videoid>sg5yD_HKMkU</videoid>
  </game>
  <game name="Blue Print (USA)">
    <description>Blue Print (USA)</description>
    <title_clean>Blue Print</title_clean>
    <rom name="no-intro-atari-5200-20130303/No-Intro%20-%20Atari%20-%205200%20%282013-03-03%29.zip/Blue%20Print%20%28USA%29.zip" size="11150"/>
    <releasedate>18/10/1983</releasedate>
    <genre>Action,General</genre>
    <gamefaqs_url>http://www.gamefaqs.com/atari5200/585289-blue-print</gamefaqs_url>
    <plot>Chivalry is not dead! Fair Daisy Damsel is being pursued by mean Ollie Ogre! Only you have the blueprint for the machine that can stop him, but--Oh no! Where did the parts go?!In and out of houses you go, searching for the pieces that will fit the blueprint. But beware! A bomb may be waiting for you as soon as you enter. Quick--get it to the Pit before it blows!Fiendish Fuzzy Wuzzy also stands in your way. If he gets hold of you, it's curtains! And the neighborhood nerd, Sneaky Pete, keeps trying to throw a monkey wrench into your plans. Plus, a blow from a falling Flower Pot can prove fatal! But if you complete your contraption and knock off Ollie, you'll have saved Daisy!But alas! A true hero never rests. Ollie's at it again, faster than ever! And this time it's going to be more of a challenge to get your machine finished. Hurry, there's no time to lose!It's a nonstop cliffhanger that really tests your memory! Go to it, hero--do it for Daisy!</plot>
    <nplayers>1-2</nplayers>
    <ESRB>ESRB - E (Everyone)</ESRB>
    <studio>CBS Electronics</studio>
    <rating>3.0</rating>
    <boxart1>j8x4Bs2.png</boxart1>
    <snapshot1>WW8loLh.png</snapshot1>
    <snapshot2>5x5TGuf.png</snapshot2>
  </game>
  <game name="Boogie (USA) (Demo)">
    <description>Boogie (USA) (Demo)</description>
    <title_clean>Boogie</title_clean>
    <rom name="no-intro-atari-5200-20130303/No-Intro%20-%20Atari%20-%205200%20%282013-03-03%29.zip/Boogie%20%28USA%29%20%28Demo%29.zip" size="713"/>
    <plot>As the name implies, Boogie is not a game but a music demo.  This prototype displays the 5200 splash screen while continuously playing a "boogie" tune.  The music is somewhat interesting, and shows off the 5200's music abilities fairly well.  It's unknown whether this prototype was made simply as a learning tool, or if some kind of music game was being planned.</plot>
    <boxart1>zKVqMsv.png</boxart1>
    <snapshot1>2rcRi18.png</snapshot1>
    <boxart2>aTNFeb0.jpg</boxart2>
    <snapshot2>9rAUsqX.png</snapshot2>
  </game>
  <game name="Bounty Bob Strikes Back! (USA)">
    <description>Bounty Bob Strikes Back! (USA)</description>
    <title_clean>Bounty Bob Strikes Back!</title_clean>
    <rom name="no-intro-atari-5200-20130303/No-Intro%20-%20Atari%20-%205200%20%282013-03-03%29.zip/Bounty%20Bob%20Strikes%20Back%21%20%28USA%29.zip" size="33427"/>
    <releasedate>18/10/1984</releasedate>
    <genre>Action,Platformer,2D</genre>
    <gamefaqs_url>http://www.gamefaqs.com/atari5200/563259-bounty-bob-strikes-back</gamefaqs_url>
    <plot>Bounty Bob Strikes Back! is the sequel to Miner 2049er and features similar gameplay. As Bounty Bob, your goal is to claim every inch of 25 challenging mines. To do this, you must walk over each segment of the framework in the mines. To reach each segment of framework, you will need to figure out a way to jump, climb, or use one of the many devices occasionally available to get there. To your help you get around (or sometimes hinder progress) are ladders, slides, suction tubes, cannons, transporters, and other devices. Wandering about the mines are many dangerous mutants. If you come in contact with one of these, you will lose a life. Scattered throughout each mine are special food items; collect one of these, and you will temporarily be able to eliminate the mutants by walking into them. You will need to figure out a unique strategy for each level in order to complete it, plus there is a time limit so claim all the territory quickly!</plot>
    <rating>4.00</rating>
    <studio>Big Five Software</studio>
    <nplayers>1-2</nplayers>
    <ESRB>ESRB - E (Everyone)</ESRB>
    <boxart1>tapj0j7.png</boxart1>
    <clearlogo1>BQpodCj.png</clearlogo1>
    <snapshot1>ZDn0b2y.png</snapshot1>
    <boxart2>ehfgKfk.jpg</boxart2>
    <snapshot2>65l1sO1.png</snapshot2>
    <boxart3>PdoIhVj.png</boxart3>
    <snapshot10>WR3wiYW.gif</snapshot10>
    <snapshot3>d7k7Okv.gif</snapshot3>
    <snapshot4>pVkwjTn.gif</snapshot4>
    <snapshot5>134VNC8.gif</snapshot5>
    <snapshot6>X2dIJHL.gif</snapshot6>
    <snapshot7>4hj8IbG.gif</snapshot7>
    <snapshot8>cf3LILT.gif</snapshot8>
    <snapshot9>04fZydz.gif</snapshot9>
  </game>
  <game name="Buck Rogers - Planet of Zoom (USA)">
    <description>Buck Rogers - Planet of Zoom (USA)</description>
    <title_clean>Buck Rogers - Planet of Zoom</title_clean>
    <rom name="no-intro-atari-5200-20130303/No-Intro%20-%20Atari%20-%205200%20%282013-03-03%29.zip/Buck%20Rogers%20-%20Planet%20of%20Zoom%20%28USA%29.zip" size="9763"/>
    <releasedate>18/10/1983</releasedate>
    <genre>Action,Shooter,Scrolling</genre>
    <gamefaqs_url>http://www.gamefaqs.com/atari5200/585290-buck-rogers-planet-of-zoom</gamefaqs_url>
    <plot>Fast and furious racing game taking place on a futuristic racetrack. Guide your spaceship between the pylons and shoot down other enemy racers.[CR]Based on the arcade game (which is even more loosely based on the Buck Rogers comic strips).</plot>
    <studio>Sega</studio>
    <nplayers>1</nplayers>
    <ESRB>ESRB - E (Everyone)</ESRB>
    <rating>3.3</rating>
    <boxart1>skhMzg3.png</boxart1>
    <snapshot1>QIM2jGA.png</snapshot1>
    <snapshot2>jrYJVzm.png</snapshot2>
    <banner1>SOk5J6i.jpg</banner1>
    <boxart2>WHVb6kF.jpg</boxart2>
    <boxart3>jIoYrKZ.jpg</boxart3>
    <clearlogo1>Iwtl45S.png</clearlogo1>
    <snapshot10>MlkkkU9.png</snapshot10>
    <snapshot3>QtKeo1b.gif</snapshot3>
    <snapshot4>8blxl4X.gif</snapshot4>
    <snapshot5>gycV1Pw.png</snapshot5>
    <snapshot6>7rC8cOG.png</snapshot6>
    <snapshot7>o3t04zf.png</snapshot7>
    <snapshot8>hQSr3hJ.png</snapshot8>
    <snapshot9>cyAxjld.png</snapshot9>
  </game>
  <game name="Carol Shaw's River Raid (USA)">
    <description>Carol Shaw's River Raid (USA)</description>
    <title_clean>Carol Shaw's River Raid</title_clean>
    <rom name="no-intro-atari-5200-20130303/No-Intro%20-%20Atari%20-%205200%20%282013-03-03%29.zip/Carol%20Shaw%27s%20River%20Raid%20%28USA%29.zip" size="6470"/>
    <releasedate>18/10/1983</releasedate>
    <genre>Action,Shooter,Scrolling</genre>
    <gamefaqs_url>http://www.gamefaqs.com/atari5200/585348-river-raid</gamefaqs_url>
    <plot>An ever-changing, ever-challenging water fortress of enemy activity is your destination. A series of vital enemy bridges is your targest. Unfortunately, there's only one way at 'em: straight up the River, through the thick of trigger-happy choppers, lethal land tanks, helicopters and hot air balloons. Treacherous bays reek of peril. Icy currents promise danger. Brilliantly detailed graphics and outrageous sound effects are guaranteed. Your safety's not.</plot>
    <nplayers>1-2</nplayers>
    <ESRB>ESRB - E (Everyone)</ESRB>
    <studio>Activision</studio>
    <rating>3.3</rating>
    <boxart1>Q32zTWU.png</boxart1>
    <snapshot1>bdBgiYN.png</snapshot1>
    <snapshot2>KEf0nsB.png</snapshot2>
  </game>
  <game name="Castle Blast (USA) (Unl)">
    <description>Castle Blast (USA) (Unl)</description>
    <title_clean>Castle Blast</title_clean>
    <rom name="no-intro-atari-5200-20130303/No-Intro%20-%20Atari%20-%205200%20%282013-03-03%29.zip/Castle%20Blast%20%28USA%29%20%28Unl%29.zip" size="6431"/>
    <rating>4.00</rating>
    <nplayers>1</nplayers>
    <releasedate>10/08/2002</releasedate>
    <plot>Castle Blast is shoot'em up based on the 5th screen of Atari's 2600 Phoenix where you take on the mothership. Castle Blast is Ronen Habot's first foray into programming the Atari 5200. Ronen used this experience as a means to write a tutorial on Atari 5200 programming to assist others who might want to write games for the system.[CR]Castle Blast made its debut at the 2002 Classic Gaming Expo, where it was sold with a box, manual and cart. AtariAge held a Castle Blast Label Contest in April, 2002. Castle Blast may be ordered directly from the author, Ronen Habot, by visiting the Castle Blast Development Page.[CR]The object of this game is to destroy the Castle on the Mothership. You fire Vertical Trajectory Missiles, or VTMs, at the shield on the bottom of the Mothership. When you penetrate the shield, then blast the Castle. To score extra points, you can also shoot the enemy spaceships flying overhead.[CR]If you destroy the Castle, you advance to the next level, where you will need to contend with Focused Energy Beams, or FEBs, fired from the Mothership. There will also be stars appearing in the sky, making it harder to target the spaceships.[CR]If you manage to obliterate the Castle again, you will proceed to the next level, which adds ground-based tanks assaulting you. You have Horizontal Trajectory Missiles, or HTMs, to deal with this new enemy but do not lose sight of your primary goal.[CR]Your joystick moves you left or right. The lower button fires VTMs, the upper button fires HTMs.</plot>
    <genre>Action, Flight Simulator</genre>
    <ESRB>ESRB - E (Everyone)</ESRB>
    <studio>Self-Published</studio>
    <boxart1>A1hqeLy.png</boxart1>
    <banner1>ewxMBiA.jpg</banner1>
    <clearlogo1>QBx0BvH.png</clearlogo1>
    <snapshot1>aShXyex.png</snapshot1>
    <fanart1>FSXeIVR.jpg</fanart1>
    <boxart2>sa5FwM2.jpg</boxart2>
    <snapshot2>UIufcZL.png</snapshot2>
    <boxart3>ZtA6Hxr.png</boxart3>
    <boxart4>lA20Ilg.png</boxart4>
  </game>
  <game name="Castle Crisis (USA) (Unl)">
    <description>Castle Crisis (USA) (Unl)</description>
    <title_clean>Castle Crisis</title_clean>
    <rom name="no-intro-atari-5200-20130303/No-Intro%20-%20Atari%20-%205200%20%282013-03-03%29.zip/Castle%20Crisis%20%28USA%29%20%28Unl%29.zip" size="20398"/>
    <studio>AtariAge</studio>
    <plot>This is a version of the Atari coin-op game Warlords, designed to look and play as much like the coin-op version as possible. Use your shield to deflect fireballs away from your castle and towards your opponents. You can also capture fireballs and launch them at your opponents with even greater force.</plot>
    <nplayers>1-4</nplayers>
    <ESRB>ESRB - E (Everyone)</ESRB>
    <rating>5.0</rating>
    <boxart1>WGj8fPo.png</boxart1>
    <banner1>6q30ApU.jpg</banner1>
    <clearlogo1>9Y4QEYF.png</clearlogo1>
    <snapshot1>FmuqEoD.png</snapshot1>
    <boxart2>L1zCzDb.jpg</boxart2>
    <snapshot2>C2PMjGX.png</snapshot2>
    <boxart3>wlGNcmF.png</boxart3>
    <boxart4>BY0MFWH.png</boxart4>
  </game>
  <game name="Centipede (USA)">
    <description>Centipede (USA)</description>
    <title_clean>Centipede</title_clean>
    <rom name="no-intro-atari-5200-20130303/No-Intro%20-%20Atari%20-%205200%20%282013-03-03%29.zip/Centipede%20%28USA%29.zip" size="8698"/>
    <releasedate>18/10/1982</releasedate>
    <genre>Action,Shooter,Static</genre>
    <gamefaqs_url>http://www.gamefaqs.com/atari5200/585291-centipede</gamefaqs_url>
    <plot>Venture into an enchanted forest filled with magic mushrooms that is ruled by a giant centipede along with poisonous spiders, scorpions and fleas. You go to battle against these evil creatures armed with three magic wands. If they reach ylou before you zap them, they'll snatch your wand away. But, don't be faint-hearted, stand and fight!</plot>
    <rating>3.75</rating>
    <studio>Atari</studio>
    <nplayers>1-2</nplayers>
    <ESRB>ESRB - E (Everyone)</ESRB>
    <boxart1>VD6kqSc.png</boxart1>
    <banner1>Ld6orv1.jpg</banner1>
    <clearlogo1>SroWMC9.png</clearlogo1>
    <snapshot1>mmeZUjT.png</snapshot1>
    <boxart2>w9P2ijx.jpg</boxart2>
    <snapshot2>NnjuZ7U.png</snapshot2>
    <boxart3>y68GZ8y.png</boxart3>
    <snapshot10>f4VVI7N.png</snapshot10>
    <snapshot3>etACY3J.gif</snapshot3>
    <snapshot4>2OpJy1h.gif</snapshot4>
    <snapshot5>ulUXcoD.gif</snapshot5>
    <snapshot6>414sfBu.gif</snapshot6>
    <snapshot7>PBGLiJE.png</snapshot7>
    <snapshot8>Itq6tb5.png</snapshot8>
    <snapshot9>KbG3AKV.png</snapshot9>
  </game>
  <game name="Choplifter! (USA)">
    <description>Choplifter! (USA)</description>
    <title_clean>Choplifter!</title_clean>
    <rom name="no-intro-atari-5200-20130303/No-Intro%20-%20Atari%20-%205200%20%282013-03-03%29.zip/Choplifter%21%20%28USA%29.zip" size="11128"/>
    <releasedate>18/10/1984</releasedate>
    <genre>Action,Shooter,Scrolling</genre>
    <gamefaqs_url>http://www.gamefaqs.com/atari5200/585292-choplifter</gamefaqs_url>
    <plot>In Choplifter, the player assumes the role of a combat helicopter pilot. The player attempts to save hostages being held in prisoner of war camps in territory ruled by the evil Bungeling Empire. The player must collect the hostages and transport them safely to the nearby friendly base, all the while fighting off hostile tanks and other enemy combatants.</plot>
    <rating>5.00</rating>
    <nplayers>1</nplayers>
    <studio>Atari</studio>
    <year>1984</year>
    <ESRB>ESRB - E (Everyone)</ESRB>
    <boxart1>XGkFV8L.png</boxart1>
    <banner1>FDHJ7bB.jpg</banner1>
    <clearlogo1>Fi68lpp.png</clearlogo1>
    <snapshot1>gzk47uv.png</snapshot1>
    <boxart2>TVenUYd.jpg</boxart2>
    <snapshot2>v3eYlMx.png</snapshot2>
    <boxart3>CGdcdt8.png</boxart3>
    <snapshot10>6skkJeb.jpg</snapshot10>
    <snapshot3>QxNwSsx.png</snapshot3>
    <snapshot4>GwsXpH9.png</snapshot4>
    <snapshot5>XfSPC6s.png</snapshot5>
    <snapshot6>SClzPpt.png</snapshot6>
    <snapshot7>1sCu3gk.jpg</snapshot7>
    <snapshot8>XyL3hsZ.jpg</snapshot8>
    <snapshot9>FeelBoc.jpg</snapshot9>
  </game>
  <game name="Congo Bongo (USA)">
    <description>Congo Bongo (USA)</description>
    <title_clean>Congo Bongo</title_clean>
    <rom name="no-intro-atari-5200-20130303/No-Intro%20-%20Atari%20-%205200%20%282013-03-03%29.zip/Congo%20Bongo%20%28USA%29.zip" size="11679"/>
    <releasedate>18/10/1984</releasedate>
    <genre>Action,General</genre>
    <gamefaqs_url>http://www.gamefaqs.com/atari5200/585293-congo-bongo</gamefaqs_url>
    <plot>In the first of three screens, you must climb the cliffs of Jungle Mountain in order to get to Congo Bongo, the jungle gorilla. You must also cross a bridge and jump a chasm. Along the way, Congo will throw coconuts at you, and monkeys will try to jump on your back. The monkeys slow you down tremendously, but a couple of jumps will send them scurrying.</plot>
    <rating>5.00</rating>
    <studio>Sega</studio>
    <year>1983</year>
    <nplayers>1-2</nplayers>
    <ESRB>ESRB - E (Everyone)</ESRB>
    <boxart1>FEMcw3I.png</boxart1>
    <clearlogo1>EiM3vFt.png</clearlogo1>
    <snapshot1>9B6xDgR.png</snapshot1>
    <boxart2>mvJR6Pn.jpg</boxart2>
    <snapshot2>TgLw2Qh.png</snapshot2>
    <boxart3>bPKgRCl.png</boxart3>
    <snapshot3>XhTugbR.gif</snapshot3>
    <snapshot4>nZPF0wp.png</snapshot4>
    <snapshot5>Qf5NujA.jpg</snapshot5>
    <snapshot6>LlN6ciP.png</snapshot6>
    <snapshot7>OeeIp7I.jpg</snapshot7>
    <snapshot8>AdLZSAj.png</snapshot8>
    <snapshot9>VG5sYFF.png</snapshot9>
  </game>
  <game name="Countermeasure (USA)">
    <description>Countermeasure (USA)</description>
    <title_clean>Countermeasure</title_clean>
    <rom name="no-intro-atari-5200-20130303/No-Intro%20-%20Atari%20-%205200%20%282013-03-03%29.zip/Countermeasure%20%28USA%29.zip" size="11257"/>
    <releasedate>18/10/1984</releasedate>
    <genre>Action,General</genre>
    <gamefaqs_url>http://www.gamefaqs.com/atari5200/563260-countermeasure</gamefaqs_url>
    <plot>CONDITION RED! Terrorists have seized a silo complex and aimed the missiles at Washington, D.C. Blast the silos and save the country before the launch sequence timer runs out. Fail and your only hope is to guess the fail-safe code that disarms the missiles in the seconds before impact.</plot>
    <studio>Atari</studio>
    <nplayers>1-2</nplayers>
    <ESRB>ESRB - E (Everyone)</ESRB>
    <rating>3.2</rating>
    <boxart1>wXKQJ6A.png</boxart1>
    <banner1>mnM6Ilk.jpg</banner1>
    <clearlogo1>R9Z0Oak.png</clearlogo1>
    <snapshot1>4NVBobT.png</snapshot1>
    <boxart2>HqwzcY7.jpg</boxart2>
    <snapshot2>F4nxiAe.png</snapshot2>
    <boxart3>KEv79fO.png</boxart3>
    <boxart4>eMAxUqL.png</boxart4>
    <snapshot10>aciufox.png</snapshot10>
    <snapshot3>SXoWMKf.gif</snapshot3>
    <snapshot4>cGzHwCD.gif</snapshot4>
    <snapshot5>CYnTTCi.gif</snapshot5>
    <snapshot6>LCyVFCL.gif</snapshot6>
    <snapshot7>bYaWuok.gif</snapshot7>
    <snapshot8>U16lA3H.gif</snapshot8>
    <snapshot9>xzeS6RI.gif</snapshot9>
  </game>
  <game name="David Crane's Pitfall II - Lost Caverns (USA)">
    <description>David Crane's Pitfall II - Lost Caverns (USA)</description>
    <title_clean>David Crane's Pitfall II - Lost Caverns</title_clean>
    <rom name="no-intro-atari-5200-20130303/No-Intro%20-%20Atari%20-%205200%20%282013-03-03%29.zip/David%20Crane%27s%20Pitfall%20II%20-%20Lost%20Caverns%20%28USA%29.zip" size="11125"/>
    <releasedate>18/10/1984</releasedate>
    <genre>Action,Platformer,2D</genre>
    <gamefaqs_url>http://www.gamefaqs.com/atari5200/585336-pitfall-ii-lost-caverns</gamefaqs_url>
    <plot>Join Pitfall Harry as he searches a vast subterranean cliff dwelling high in the Andes. He's looking for the fabled Raj Diamond, gold bricks, his niece Rhonda and the cowardly lion Quickclaw. He finds more than he bargained for--eels, poisonous frogs, albino scorpions, bats, condors, a raging river--in the greatest challenge of his career!</plot>
    <nplayers>1</nplayers>
    <ESRB>ESRB - E (Everyone)</ESRB>
    <studio>Activision</studio>
    <rating>4.0</rating>
    <boxart1>GwM1Clf.png</boxart1>
    <snapshot1>pTqpzc7.png</snapshot1>
    <snapshot2>tsRqwVm.png</snapshot2>
    <boxart2>HmDfRtg.jpg</boxart2>
    <boxart3>baxpu2z.jpg</boxart3>
    <snapshot3>bmjIN4O.gif</snapshot3>
    <snapshot4>tBFmtPO.gif</snapshot4>
    <snapshot5>ycotpkC.gif</snapshot5>
    <snapshot6>4oLWxaM.gif</snapshot6>
  </game>
  <game name="Defender (USA)">
    <description>Defender (USA)</description>
    <title_clean>Defender</title_clean>
    <rom name="no-intro-atari-5200-20130303/No-Intro%20-%20Atari%20-%205200%20%282013-03-03%29.zip/Defender%20%28USA%29.zip" size="9385"/>
    <releasedate>18/10/1983</releasedate>
    <genre>Action,Shooter,Scrolling</genre>
    <gamefaqs_url>http://www.gamefaqs.com/atari5200/585296-defender</gamefaqs_url>
    <plot>Defender is a two-dimensional, side-scrolling shooting game set on the surface of an unnamed planet. The player controls a space ship as it navigates the terrain, flying either to the left or right. A joystick controls the ship's elevation, and five buttons control its horizontal direction and weapons. The object is to destroy alien invaders, while protecting astronauts on the landscape from abduction. Humans that are successfully abducted return as mutants that attack the ship. Defeating the aliens allows the player to progress to the next level. Failing to protect the astronauts, however, causes the planet to explode and the level to become populated with mutants. Surviving the waves of mutants results in the restoration of the planet. Players are allotted three chances (lives) to progress through the game and are able to earn more by reaching certain scoring benchmarks.</plot>
    <rating>2.69</rating>
    <nplayers>2</nplayers>
    <studio>Atari</studio>
    <year>1982</year>
    <ESRB>ESRB - E (Everyone)</ESRB>
    <boxart1>7eN2kPh.png</boxart1>
    <banner1>3bNPgsv.jpg</banner1>
    <clearlogo1>b7CfP9G.png</clearlogo1>
    <snapshot1>cuUGqT3.png</snapshot1>
    <boxart2>jbXDzU8.jpg</boxart2>
    <snapshot2>POFUdwG.png</snapshot2>
    <boxart3>DMhfUtb.png</boxart3>
    <snapshot10>jEW7h5t.png</snapshot10>
    <snapshot3>hO7sgax.gif</snapshot3>
    <snapshot4>HHhHddK.gif</snapshot4>
    <snapshot5>tcFAmFG.gif</snapshot5>
    <snapshot6>nztPcfY.gif</snapshot6>
    <snapshot7>SHZ3rhn.jpg</snapshot7>
    <snapshot8>9w3BmKY.jpg</snapshot8>
    <snapshot9>uVqyd38.png</snapshot9>
  </game>
  <game name="Dig Dug (USA)">
    <description>Dig Dug (USA)</description>
    <title_clean>Dig Dug</title_clean>
    <rom name="no-intro-atari-5200-20130303/No-Intro%20-%20Atari%20-%205200%20%282013-03-03%29.zip/Dig%20Dug%20%28USA%29.zip" size="11887"/>
    <releasedate>18/10/1983</releasedate>
    <genre>Miscellaneous,Puzzle,General</genre>
    <gamefaqs_url>http://www.gamefaqs.com/atari5200/585298-dig-dug</gamefaqs_url>
    <plot>The objective of Dig Dug is to eliminate underground-dwelling monsters by inflating them until they pop, or by dropping rocks on them. There are two kinds of enemies in the game:[CR]Pookas - A race of round red monsters (said to be modeled after tomatoes) who wear yellow goggles.[CR]Fygars - A race of green dragons who can breathe fire.[CR]The player's character is Dig Dug, dressed in white and blue, and able to dig tunnels through destructible environments. Dig Dug is killed if he is caught by either Pooka or Fygar, burned by a Fygar's fire, or crushed by a rock.[CR]A partially inflated monster will gradually deflate and recover after a few seconds, during which time the player can pass safely through it. The monsters normally crawl through the tunnels in the dirt but can turn into ghostly eyes and travel slowly through the dirt. The last enemy on a level will try to escape off the top left of the screen.[CR]More points are awarded for popping an enemy further down in the dirt (the levels are color-coded). In addition, Fygars are worth double points if exploded horizontally, since they can only breathe fire horizontally in the direction they are facing. Extra points are also awarded for dropping rocks on enemies in order to eliminate them rather than inflating them. If one enemy is killed by the rock, it is worth 1000 points. The next two add 1500 points each, and any after that add 2000. The act of digging is itself worth points, giving 10 points for each block dug, so some players do as much of it as possible in situations where the threat from the remaining monsters is minimal.[CR]After the player drops two rocks, fruits and vegetables and other edible bonus items, such as Galaxian flagships appear in the center of the play field, and can be collected for points if the player is able to reach them before they disappear. These edible bonus items will appear even if the rocks fail to hit any enemies. In some versions of the game, the most points attainable from a single bonus fruit is 8,000 from the pineapple.</plot>
    <rating>3.50</rating>
    <nplayers>2</nplayers>
    <year>1983</year>
    <ESRB>ESRB - E (Everyone)</ESRB>
    <studio>Atari</studio>
    <boxart1>pxESwJW.png</boxart1>
    <banner1>ioOLYBr.jpg</banner1>
    <clearlogo1>iLmXMLE.png</clearlogo1>
    <snapshot1>4czk6Hy.png</snapshot1>
    <fanart1>cB0Hf7X.jpg</fanart1>
    <boxart2>02nnr50.jpg</boxart2>
    <snapshot2>UaXoliN.png</snapshot2>
    <boxart3>ekJISss.png</boxart3>
    <videoid>Pd6TTrVdm7s</videoid>
    <snapshot10>xWPUNde.jpg</snapshot10>
    <snapshot3>nmNvt74.gif</snapshot3>
    <snapshot4>4Du4cip.gif</snapshot4>
    <snapshot5>IzaS3Mo.gif</snapshot5>
    <snapshot6>9HI7mv2.gif</snapshot6>
    <snapshot7>Ecmb8bj.jpg</snapshot7>
    <snapshot8>ehaEtba.jpg</snapshot8>
    <snapshot9>EuWybtR.jpg</snapshot9>
  </game>
  <game name="Dreadnaught Factor, The (USA)">
    <description>Dreadnaught Factor, The (USA)</description>
    <title_clean>The Dreadnaught Factor</title_clean>
    <rom name="no-intro-atari-5200-20130303/No-Intro%20-%20Atari%20-%205200%20%282013-03-03%29.zip/Dreadnaught%20Factor%2C%20The%20%28USA%29.zip" size="7129"/>
    <releasedate>18/10/1983</releasedate>
    <genre>Action,Shooter,Scrolling</genre>
    <gamefaqs_url>http://www.gamefaqs.com/atari5200/585299-the-dreadnought-factor</gamefaqs_url>
    <plot>The Zorban Dreadnaughts are spaceships that are 140,000 feet long and weigh 970 megatons, making them the largest, most heavily armoured spaceships ever created. A fleet of these large battlecraft are now heading towards your home planet, and it is your job to stop them! The game is played from a side scrolling overhead point of view as your small but agile spaceship flies past the dreadnaughts. On each pass your spaceship makes, you need to try and bomb as many of the energy vents as possible. When all energy vents on a dreadnaught are destroyed, that dreadnaught will explode. Time is limited, though, and if you make too many passes to destroy the energy vents the dreadnaught will be within firing range of your home planet and will destroy it. Each of the dreadnaughts are heavily armed; guns, canons, missiles, and other weapons are located on each dreadnaught and will be trying their best to end your mission. Multiple skill levels are included which alter the number of dreadnaughts you must destroy, as well as their speed and firing capabilities.</plot>
    <rating>3.50</rating>
    <nplayers>1</nplayers>
    <studio>Activision</studio>
    <year>1984</year>
    <ESRB>ESRB - E (Everyone)</ESRB>
    <boxart1>fLGD5AF.png</boxart1>
    <clearlogo1>GrtXQb8.png</clearlogo1>
    <snapshot1>Kpm3MTR.png</snapshot1>
    <boxart2>ZKWvN9T.jpg</boxart2>
    <snapshot2>7n5eHxS.png</snapshot2>
    <boxart3>vrpqiJJ.png</boxart3>
    <snapshot3>bNpTe9B.gif</snapshot3>
    <snapshot4>Iqf7pdn.gif</snapshot4>
    <snapshot5>DmLrcU6.gif</snapshot5>
  </game>
  <game name="Final Legacy (USA) (Proto)">
    <description>Final Legacy (USA) (Proto)</description>
    <title_clean>Final Legacy</title_clean>
    <rom name="no-intro-atari-5200-20130303/No-Intro%20-%20Atari%20-%205200%20%282013-03-03%29.zip/Final%20Legacy%20%28USA%29%20%28Proto%29.zip" size="13259"/>
    <rating>0.50</rating>
    <nplayers>1</nplayers>
    <studio>Atari</studio>
    <plot>This is a battle on three fronts. You are the captain of the ship Legacy. Your ultimate goal is to destroy the Warmongers' missile bases but you must also protect your cities.[CR]You begin the game in command mode. You select your other modes with the joystick. Up for navigation, down for torpedo, left for sea-to-air and right for sea-to-land.[CR]Navigation[CR]In navigation mode, you will see an overhead map of the world. You will note that there is a black dot in a black circle. This is you and the circle represents your effective range. You move the circle about the screen to target ships or known missile bases or to refuel at a city. You use fuel only when you are in navigation mode. When you are within range, or if an enemy ships comes within your range, press the space bar to return to the command mode then change to the desired mode.[CR]Torpedo[CR]If you are within range of an enemy ship, switch to torpedo mode. In this mode, you will use the scanner at the bottom to line up your target. Move out of line to avoid a direct hit. Beware of war ship as they will chase you and have the most firepower. Hunter ships will also chase you. While their firepower is not as high as war ships, it is still fairly good. Intelligence ships have the weakest firepower and will not chase you. They can be found on the right side of the screen. If one is destroyed and there are any hidden missile bases, there is a eighty percent chance a hidden base will be revealed.[CR]Sea-to-land[CR]If you want to destroy a missile base or refuel, enter sea-to-land mode. To refuel, get near a city then enter this mode. When you are in sea-to-land mode, you will know you are within range if you see "Dock for refueling" on the screen. You then place the cross hairs on the base of the city and wait for refueling to complete, unless you or a city are under attack. Do not use the fire button to exit or you will fire on your city. To destroy a missile base, position your cross hairs using the scanner on the screen until you are on a missile launcher then fire. Be advised that when you fire on a missile base, they will shoot missiles at a city.[CR]Sea-to-air[CR]If a city is under attach, switch to this mode. You will control a weapons satellite. Use you joystick, or the trak-ball , if you plugged one into port 2, to aim at an incoming missile and press fire to blast it. If it gets past you but has not reached your city, you get a "Refocusing" message and the view switches to a short range view where you will get one more try.[CR]Be warned that ships can attack you no matter what mode you are in. On the easiest level, there are no hidden bases nor do you use fuel.[CR]The Atari 5200 version of this game was never released but is however mostly identical to the Atari 8-Bit version that was released.</plot>
    <genre>Flight Simulator, Shooter, Strategy</genre>
    <boxart1>FvE7soO.png</boxart1>
    <clearlogo1>m2JZJjB.jpg</clearlogo1>
    <snapshot1>bm0mpmN.png</snapshot1>
    <boxart2>xDkgMTi.jpg</boxart2>
    <snapshot2>FXu4VPw.png</snapshot2>
    <boxart3>kifvkGq.png</boxart3>
    <videoid>ncLHZgMoqgY</videoid>
    <releasedate>31/12/1987</releasedate>
    <snapshot3>hTUcelG.jpg</snapshot3>
    <snapshot4>iF3YOCe.png</snapshot4>
    <snapshot5>anijGoW.jpg</snapshot5>
    <snapshot6>eW2JJsA.png</snapshot6>
    <snapshot7>9wMU7Ve.png</snapshot7>
    <snapshot8>G8iNfD0.png</snapshot8>
    <snapshot9>8aYCMfe.png</snapshot9>
  </game>
  <game name="Frisky Tom (USA) (Proto)">
    <description>Frisky Tom (USA) (Proto)</description>
    <title_clean>Frisky Tom</title_clean>
    <rom name="no-intro-atari-5200-20130303/No-Intro%20-%20Atari%20-%205200%20%282013-03-03%29.zip/Frisky%20Tom%20%28USA%29%20%28Proto%29.zip" size="9275"/>
    <nplayers>1</nplayers>
    <studio>Atari</studio>
    <releasedate>04/07/1983</releasedate>
    <plot>A prototype game that was never officially released for the Atari 5200, Frisky Tom is a port of the obscure Nichibutsu coin-op of the same name in which you play a plumber who must climb up and fix broken pipes to keep a steady stream of water flowing from the tank at the top of the screen to the reservoir at the bottom.  Unfortunately this house is infested with mice which roam the screen, gnawing through pipes and generally causing problems for our man Tom.[CR]Once a mouse gnaws through a pipe, you'll see the flow of water stop and a pipe piece will fall to the ground.  To repair the pipe Tom must pick up the fallen piece (you can hold two pieces a time), and put it back into the hole.  To get to where the holes are, Tom must carefully climb up and navigate the maze of pipes.  Although Tom can cross short gaps in the pipes, he'll need to go around the larger ones.  While climbing around on the pipes, Tom will run across several different kinds of mice. Each mouse has its own color and purpose.[CR]When the flow of water is interrupted, the timer in the reservoir will begin to count downward from 5000 at the rate of 100 points per second.  The only way to stop this countdown is to restore the water flow by fixing the pipes.  If the timer reaches zero, Tom will lose a life and play the current level over again.  If Tom is able to get enough water into the reservoir (keeping the timer above 1500), he'll be rewarded with a bonus intermission showing a woman taking a shower.[CR]- Excerpt from www.atariprotos.com</plot>
    <genre>Action</genre>
    <boxart1>Y0rtt8k.jpg</boxart1>
    <snapshot1>dQEyEVE.png</snapshot1>
    <boxart2>S1i0MsK.png</boxart2>
    <snapshot2>mWxMu4I.png</snapshot2>
    <videoid>wswlpoL6wRc</videoid>
    <clearlogo1>yWskbKT.png</clearlogo1>
  </game>
  <game name="Frogger (USA)">
    <description>Frogger (USA)</description>
    <title_clean>Frogger</title_clean>
    <rom name="no-intro-atari-5200-20130303/No-Intro%20-%20Atari%20-%205200%20%282013-03-03%29.zip/Frogger%20%28USA%29.zip" size="6039"/>
    <releasedate>18/10/1983</releasedate>
    <genre>Action,General</genre>
    <gamefaqs_url>http://www.gamefaqs.com/atari5200/585301-frogger</gamefaqs_url>
    <plot>Your task in this arcade conversion is to guide a frog across a treacherous road and river, and to safety at the top of the screen. Both these sections are fraught with a variety of hazards, each of which will kill the frog and cost you a life if contact is made.</plot>
    <nplayers>2</nplayers>
    <ESRB>ESRB - E (Everyone)</ESRB>
    <studio>Parker Brothers</studio>
    <rating>4.1</rating>
    <boxart1>MC2OmLg.png</boxart1>
    <snapshot1>myBj1Fs.png</snapshot1>
    <snapshot2>N9hVyVc.png</snapshot2>
    <boxart2>GN40HWt.jpg</boxart2>
    <boxart3>QFXM2BM.jpg</boxart3>
    <clearlogo1>Fh1buQN.png</clearlogo1>
    <fanart1>fqrrZjC.jpg</fanart1>
    <snapshot10>bBrYsud.png</snapshot10>
    <snapshot3>E5HiEHP.gif</snapshot3>
    <snapshot4>qNhRWmy.png</snapshot4>
    <snapshot5>LIPAKlu.png</snapshot5>
    <snapshot6>Sanq2NY.png</snapshot6>
    <snapshot7>5crR6UN.png</snapshot7>
    <snapshot8>XH9Ml2n.png</snapshot8>
    <snapshot9>lwnXYfL.png</snapshot9>
  </game>
  <game name="Frogger II - Threeedeep! (USA)">
    <description>Frogger II - Threeedeep! (USA)</description>
    <title_clean>Frogger II - Threeedeep!</title_clean>
    <rom name="no-intro-atari-5200-20130303/No-Intro%20-%20Atari%20-%205200%20%282013-03-03%29.zip/Frogger%20II%20-%20Threeedeep%21%20%28USA%29.zip" size="9061"/>
    <releasedate>18/10/1984</releasedate>
    <genre>Action,General</genre>
    <gamefaqs_url>http://www.gamefaqs.com/atari5200/585302-frogger-ii-threeedeep</gamefaqs_url>
    <plot>Look who's resurfaced in an all-new adventure. It's Frogger! Thress distinctly different screens take our fearless frog on another homeward-bound journey, but this time it's under water, over water, and through the air! Frogger must swim against strong currents, whisk past whales and hippos, sidestep snapping barracudas, spring from cloud trampolines to high-flying birds, contend with Clyde the Flying Dragon and so much more. So, Frogger lovers, kiss your lily pads good-bye and get set for some fast and frantic fun with FROGGER&amp;reg;II: THREEEDEEP!&amp;trade;*</plot>
    <rating>2.75</rating>
    <studio>Parker Brothers</studio>
    <nplayers>1</nplayers>
    <ESRB>ESRB - E (Everyone)</ESRB>
    <boxart1>vdYMHve.png</boxart1>
    <clearlogo1>MEBCxlT.png</clearlogo1>
    <snapshot1>jn8blHo.png</snapshot1>
    <boxart2>piPFXiA.jpg</boxart2>
    <snapshot2>RPnqWYL.png</snapshot2>
    <boxart3>okXqLxk.png</boxart3>
    <snapshot10>S7S39fO.png</snapshot10>
    <snapshot3>hOOjDEB.gif</snapshot3>
    <snapshot4>zyuh9Oj.gif</snapshot4>
    <snapshot5>w6XNm7o.png</snapshot5>
    <snapshot6>xdrV2yG.png</snapshot6>
    <snapshot7>Ky64F7J.png</snapshot7>
    <snapshot8>2rdi14d.png</snapshot8>
    <snapshot9>eztZSXj.png</snapshot9>
  </game>
  <game name="Galaxian (USA)">
    <description>Galaxian (USA)</description>
    <title_clean>Galaxian</title_clean>
    <rom name="no-intro-atari-5200-20130303/No-Intro%20-%20Atari%20-%205200%20%282013-03-03%29.zip/Galaxian%20%28USA%29.zip" size="5933"/>
    <releasedate>18/10/1982</releasedate>
    <genre>Action,Shooter,Static</genre>
    <gamefaqs_url>http://www.gamefaqs.com/atari5200/585303-galaxian</gamefaqs_url>
    <plot>Galaxian expanded on the formula pioneered by Space Invaders. As in the earlier game, Galaxian featured a horde of attacking aliens that exchanged shots with the player. In contrast to Space Invaders, Galaxian added an element of drama by having the aliens periodically make kamikaze-like dives at the player's ship, the Galaxip.</plot>
    <nplayers>2</nplayers>
    <studio>Atari</studio>
    <ESRB>ESRB - E (Everyone)</ESRB>
    <rating>4.0</rating>
    <boxart1>D1hQQSk.png</boxart1>
    <banner1>zs9Rxx2.jpg</banner1>
    <clearlogo1>V1Y3Clg.png</clearlogo1>
    <snapshot1>GdHb8SM.png</snapshot1>
    <boxart2>ZE2dC11.jpg</boxart2>
    <snapshot2>lQP0neL.png</snapshot2>
    <boxart3>iPjiWFS.png</boxart3>
    <videoid>GSh528KGCfE</videoid>
    <snapshot10>pb637wF.jpg</snapshot10>
    <snapshot3>0Gosjgb.gif</snapshot3>
    <snapshot4>SmBTHrT.gif</snapshot4>
    <snapshot5>yMaVjnJ.jpg</snapshot5>
    <snapshot6>fHeAS9p.jpg</snapshot6>
    <snapshot7>0woZ85r.jpg</snapshot7>
    <snapshot8>q83lvm1.jpg</snapshot8>
    <snapshot9>bwL37tX.jpg</snapshot9>
  </game>
  <game name="Gorf (USA)">
    <description>Gorf (USA)</description>
    <title_clean>Gorf</title_clean>
    <rom name="no-intro-atari-5200-20130303/No-Intro%20-%20Atari%20-%205200%20%282013-03-03%29.zip/Gorf%20%28USA%29.zip" size="8091"/>
    <releasedate>18/10/1983</releasedate>
    <genre>Action,Shooter,Static</genre>
    <gamefaqs_url>http://www.gamefaqs.com/atari5200/585304-gorf</gamefaqs_url>
    <plot>The evil Gorfian Empire has launched an all-out attack! Flying Gorfs, Deadly Droids, Kamikaze Invaders, and Laser Ships are headed this way! HELP!</plot>
    <studio>CBS</studio>
    <nplayers>1-2</nplayers>
    <ESRB>ESRB - E (Everyone)</ESRB>
    <rating>2.9</rating>
    <boxart1>1BHmcsV.png</boxart1>
    <banner1>AUsZidb.jpg</banner1>
    <clearlogo1>aCYDIy0.png</clearlogo1>
    <snapshot1>rFHLwRK.png</snapshot1>
    <boxart2>GPvtZeh.jpg</boxart2>
    <snapshot2>0DjiYnE.png</snapshot2>
    <boxart3>B5OdsMm.png</boxart3>
    <videoid>NH0mZ4UdiCc</videoid>
    <snapshot10>d0iGle9.png</snapshot10>
    <snapshot3>KK3X4YZ.gif</snapshot3>
    <snapshot4>So9DGJc.gif</snapshot4>
    <snapshot5>jhH7yYt.gif</snapshot5>
    <snapshot6>A8YczZs.gif</snapshot6>
    <snapshot7>uc2ggbZ.png</snapshot7>
    <snapshot8>ym4bYxS.png</snapshot8>
    <snapshot9>zSuy4PW.png</snapshot9>
  </game>
  <game name="Gremlins (USA)">
    <description>Gremlins (USA)</description>
    <title_clean>Gremlins</title_clean>
    <rom name="no-intro-atari-5200-20130303/No-Intro%20-%20Atari%20-%205200%20%282013-03-03%29.zip/Gremlins%20%28USA%29.zip" size="15120"/>
    <releasedate>18/10/1987</releasedate>
    <genre>Action,General</genre>
    <gamefaqs_url>http://www.gamefaqs.com/atari5200/585305-gremlins</gamefaqs_url>
    <plot>Gremlins is an action game based on the Steven Spielberg movie of the same name. The game takes place just after midnight when there are Gremlins and Mogwai running around Billy's living room![CR]You control Billy from a 3rd person point of view. On each level, your goal is to catch all of the Mogwai and return them to their cage (located in the upper right corner of the screen) and to destroy all of the Gremlins with a sword. Each level has a time limit - at 6:00 am when the sun rises. You move on to the next level by completing your tasks or just surviving until 6:00, although more points are awarded for the former. You will also receive bonus points for each Mogwai returned to the cage. [CR]On many of the levels there will be various types of food lying about the screen. If a Mogwai eats any food, it will turn into a gremlin. There may also be puddles of water; if a Gremlin or Mogwai runs into the water, it will split into two. Some levels also contain a refrigerator or popcorn machine which will throw food out onto the screen, or a television which will distract the Gremlins. [CR]You also begin the game with a limited number of flash cubes; if you get into trouble, you can use these to temporarily stun all of the Gremlins and Mogwai. As the levels progress gameplay becomes faster and the Gremlins and Mogwai more numerous.</plot>
    <rating>3.00</rating>
    <nplayers>2</nplayers>
    <year>1986</year>
    <ESRB>ESRB - E (Everyone)</ESRB>
    <studio>Atari</studio>
    <boxart1>huqqoau.png</boxart1>
    <banner1>TTUC9sI.jpg</banner1>
    <clearlogo1>L4j6DFK.png</clearlogo1>
    <snapshot1>KmoBm0J.png</snapshot1>
    <boxart2>KLXnCgi.jpg</boxart2>
    <snapshot2>5AzL4Et.png</snapshot2>
    <boxart3>YTMke5v.png</boxart3>
    <videoid>Of4FjKRo024</videoid>
    <snapshot10>iD3SbkB.png</snapshot10>
    <snapshot3>Dvacxe4.gif</snapshot3>
    <snapshot4>JPQsrR4.gif</snapshot4>
    <snapshot5>EQbinGn.gif</snapshot5>
    <snapshot6>0gG0nSu.gif</snapshot6>
    <snapshot7>dyPvAYz.png</snapshot7>
    <snapshot8>o4a7yL9.png</snapshot8>
    <snapshot9>oEIHBHt.png</snapshot9>
  </game>
  <game name="Gyruss (USA)">
    <description>Gyruss (USA)</description>
    <title_clean>Gyruss</title_clean>
    <rom name="no-intro-atari-5200-20130303/No-Intro%20-%20Atari%20-%205200%20%282013-03-03%29.zip/Gyruss%20%28USA%29.zip" size="12371"/>
    <releasedate>18/10/1984</releasedate>
    <genre>Action,Shooter,Static</genre>
    <gamefaqs_url>http://www.gamefaqs.com/atari5200/585306-gyruss</gamefaqs_url>
    <plot>Three billion miles is a long way from home. But there's no shorter route from outer Neptune to Earth. As if that weren't enough...it's got to be a shoot-out all the way. You alone in your rapid-firing spaceship, swirling in a circular flight pattern...orbiting to the right...arcing to the left...trying to mow down wave after wave of enemy plane formations, rocketing meteors and run-away satellites. Stops at Uranus, Saturn, Jupiter, and Mars will mark your progression towards Earth. Each one's a short visit, though. Then it's off again to the next planet--and the next wave of enemies. Reach Earth in one piece and maybe you'll think twice about leaving home. Then again...maybe not!</plot>
    <rating>3.50</rating>
    <nplayers>2</nplayers>
    <studio>Parker Bros</studio>
    <ESRB>ESRB - E (Everyone)</ESRB>
    <boxart1>RZSEtl0.png</boxart1>
    <clearlogo1>dErpsDK.png</clearlogo1>
    <snapshot1>3NbsH13.png</snapshot1>
    <boxart2>hjqxbFn.jpg</boxart2>
    <snapshot2>7r4OcG0.png</snapshot2>
    <boxart3>DJ69qX9.png</boxart3>
    <videoid>Tr00Yuy2rnE</videoid>
    <snapshot10>fxcBVBx.jpg</snapshot10>
    <snapshot3>HMP1ORo.gif</snapshot3>
    <snapshot4>UTWLRKN.gif</snapshot4>
    <snapshot5>Z2kMhz2.gif</snapshot5>
    <snapshot6>K4q9l1b.gif</snapshot6>
    <snapshot7>bj6tvDO.jpg</snapshot7>
    <snapshot8>AezlQWS.jpg</snapshot8>
    <snapshot9>KucOJw1.jpg</snapshot9>
  </game>
  <game name="H.E.R.O. (USA)">
    <description>H.E.R.O. (USA)</description>
    <title_clean>H.E.R.O.</title_clean>
    <rom name="no-intro-atari-5200-20130303/No-Intro%20-%20Atari%20-%205200%20%282013-03-03%29.zip/H.E.R.O.%20%28USA%29.zip" size="8530"/>
    <releasedate>18/10/1984</releasedate>
    <genre>Action,General</genre>
    <gamefaqs_url>http://www.gamefaqs.com/atari5200/585307-hero</gamefaqs_url>
    <plot>Desperate miners trapped! Will these tunnels be their tombs? Rod Hero is their last hope! His Prop-pack powers him into the mine shafts--and peril!</plot>
    <rating>1.88</rating>
    <studio>Activision</studio>
    <nplayers>1</nplayers>
    <ESRB>ESRB - E (Everyone)</ESRB>
    <boxart1>vz5PrxE.png</boxart1>
    <clearlogo1>OWlKQiu.png</clearlogo1>
    <snapshot1>bUOFGir.png</snapshot1>
    <boxart2>O5Zq9pi.jpg</boxart2>
    <snapshot2>QWQb3VK.png</snapshot2>
    <boxart3>bjIBEVn.png</boxart3>
    <snapshot3>NRF83rk.gif</snapshot3>
    <snapshot4>LoJ2CTi.gif</snapshot4>
    <snapshot5>UPUydN2.gif</snapshot5>
    <snapshot6>OJmigNl.png</snapshot6>
  </game>
  <game name="James Bond 007 (USA)">
    <description>James Bond 007 (USA)</description>
    <title_clean>James Bond 007</title_clean>
    <rom name="no-intro-atari-5200-20130303/No-Intro%20-%20Atari%20-%205200%20%282013-03-03%29.zip/James%20Bond%20007%20%28USA%29.zip" size="9889"/>
    <releasedate>18/10/1984</releasedate>
    <genre>Action,General</genre>
    <gamefaqs_url>http://www.gamefaqs.com/atari5200/585308-james-bond-007</gamefaqs_url>
    <plot>When it comes to fast-paced action and intrigue, nobody does it better than Bond. James Bond.[CR]But you can try when you reenact scenes from four great James Bond movie classics.[CR]007's specially designed vehicle will take you on the ride of your life--over land, in the air, and under the sea! Through it all you must avoid obstacles, avert enemies, and accomplish four different missions!</plot>
    <rating>3.00</rating>
    <nplayers>1</nplayers>
    <studio>Parker Bros</studio>
    <ESRB>ESRB - E (Everyone)</ESRB>
    <boxart1>s2JPjI8.png</boxart1>
    <clearlogo1>ZWWg0yC.png</clearlogo1>
    <snapshot1>2RCoL62.png</snapshot1>
    <fanart1>Ti75w5n.jpg</fanart1>
    <boxart2>0zzNPb4.jpg</boxart2>
    <snapshot2>DLPTPRC.png</snapshot2>
    <boxart3>q9rx8VW.png</boxart3>
  </game>
  <game name="Joust (USA)">
    <description>Joust (USA)</description>
    <title_clean>Joust</title_clean>
    <rom name="no-intro-atari-5200-20130303/No-Intro%20-%20Atari%20-%205200%20%282013-03-03%29.zip/Joust%20%28USA%29.zip" size="11749"/>
    <releasedate>18/10/1983</releasedate>
    <genre>Action,Platformer,2D</genre>
    <gamefaqs_url>http://www.gamefaqs.com/atari5200/585309-joust</gamefaqs_url>
    <plot>Joust is a platforming game where the player controls a yellow knight riding a flying ostrich from a third-person perspective. The player navigates the protagonist around the game world, which consists of rock platforms floating above a flat island surrounded by lava.</plot>
    <nplayers>1</nplayers>
    <studio>Williams</studio>
    <year>1983</year>
    <ESRB>ESRB - E (Everyone)</ESRB>
    <rating>4.2</rating>
    <boxart1>Am9mqrq.png</boxart1>
    <banner1>K82h4Xl.jpg</banner1>
    <clearlogo1>H3lOSZ5.png</clearlogo1>
    <snapshot1>LkWoyoa.png</snapshot1>
    <boxart2>XYN9tug.jpg</boxart2>
    <snapshot2>ioRZpfQ.png</snapshot2>
    <boxart3>GoDGUIo.png</boxart3>
    <videoid>YKevASnO1hE</videoid>
    <snapshot10>obtKxb3.jpg</snapshot10>
    <snapshot3>7vRufvw.gif</snapshot3>
    <snapshot4>2AcuJmm.gif</snapshot4>
    <snapshot5>wMRp8Mg.gif</snapshot5>
    <snapshot6>Genn64g.gif</snapshot6>
    <snapshot7>r7Zwpuy.jpg</snapshot7>
    <snapshot8>icZpeJs.jpg</snapshot8>
    <snapshot9>50ge0vf.jpg</snapshot9>
  </game>
  <game name="Jr. Pac-Man (USA) (Proto)">
    <description>Jr. Pac-Man (USA) (Proto)</description>
    <title_clean>Jr. Pac-Man</title_clean>
    <rom name="no-intro-atari-5200-20130303/No-Intro%20-%20Atari%20-%205200%20%282013-03-03%29.zip/Jr.%20Pac-Man%20%28USA%29%20%28Proto%29.zip" size="10473"/>
    <rating>5.00</rating>
    <studio>Atari</studio>
    <releasedate>28/02/1984</releasedate>
    <plot>Jr.Pac-Man was never released for the Atari 5200, however a prototype does exist. In this Pac-man spin off you now take control of junior who has to contend with much more than his parents did! The mazes are so large now they require the screen to scroll. On top of that the items that appear will cause the dots to enlarge. This gives Junior more points when he eats them but also slows him down a bit making it difficult to avoid the ghosts. What's worse is if they hit a power pellet they will destroy it![CR]Like other Pac-Man games intermissions are shown between levels. They mainly have to do with Junior and a ghost girl falling in love despite their parents disapproval.</plot>
    <genre>Action</genre>
    <boxart1>t0pmoET.png</boxart1>
    <clearlogo1>it9CxaH.png</clearlogo1>
    <snapshot1>MfO8jjV.png</snapshot1>
    <boxart2>LO6H9e5.png</boxart2>
    <snapshot2>VRo8no6.png</snapshot2>
    <videoid>MWIHwsXEC3s</videoid>
  </game>
  <game name="Jungle Hunt (USA)">
    <description>Jungle Hunt (USA)</description>
    <title_clean>Jungle Hunt</title_clean>
    <rom name="no-intro-atari-5200-20130303/No-Intro%20-%20Atari%20-%205200%20%282013-03-03%29.zip/Jungle%20Hunt%20%28USA%29.zip" size="12276"/>
    <releasedate>18/10/1983</releasedate>
    <genre>Action,Platformer,2D</genre>
    <gamefaqs_url>http://www.gamefaqs.com/atari5200/585311-jungle-hunt</gamefaqs_url>
    <plot>Jungle Hunt offers four unique adventure experiences, which repeat with greater difficulty once all four have been survived. If you don't survive these adventures, you will not only lose your own life but that of the lovely Penelope, who has been captured by cannibals![CR]The first part challenges your Tarzan skills - can you swing on the vines without plummeting to your doom? The second part pits you against a whole bunch of nasty crocodiles in a mighty river. Fortunately, you have a knife to fight back with. Don't forget to go up for air! In the third part, you face a battle against oncoming boulders of varying sizes and physics. Once you've cleared all these treacherous hazards, you still must confront the dreaded cannibal, who is armed with a wicked spear. Can you get past him and save the lovely Penelope?</plot>
    <studio>Taito</studio>
    <nplayers>1-2</nplayers>
    <ESRB>ESRB - E (Everyone)</ESRB>
    <rating>3.5</rating>
    <boxart1>mmNIrjA.png</boxart1>
    <banner1>z82UQ8o.jpg</banner1>
    <clearlogo1>Jfc25RU.png</clearlogo1>
    <snapshot1>G3zalLm.png</snapshot1>
    <boxart2>PnaGmGl.jpg</boxart2>
    <snapshot2>m02rrcM.png</snapshot2>
    <boxart3>hPSmufL.png</boxart3>
    <videoid>ULTx81KjQYU</videoid>
    <snapshot10>Crdf8t6.jpg</snapshot10>
    <snapshot3>qhGcQet.gif</snapshot3>
    <snapshot4>VstewjH.gif</snapshot4>
    <snapshot5>1YPTjA5.gif</snapshot5>
    <snapshot6>MldPttU.gif</snapshot6>
    <snapshot7>Q5nE1IC.gif</snapshot7>
    <snapshot8>y2nXvgV.jpg</snapshot8>
    <snapshot9>BDOygrT.jpg</snapshot9>
  </game>
  <game name="K-Razy Shoot-Out (USA)">
    <description>K-Razy Shoot-Out (USA)</description>
    <title_clean>K-Razy Shoot-Out</title_clean>
    <rom name="no-intro-atari-5200-20130303/No-Intro%20-%20Atari%20-%205200%20%282013-03-03%29.zip/K-Razy%20Shoot-Out%20%28USA%29.zip" size="5550"/>
    <releasedate>18/10/1983</releasedate>
    <genre>Action,General</genre>
    <gamefaqs_url>http://www.gamefaqs.com/atari5200/563261-k-razy-shoot-out</gamefaqs_url>
    <plot>Trapped within deadly Alien Control Sectors, your squad of Space Commanders must shoot it out with dangerous Alien Droids in order to survive. Only your keen reflexes and trusty laser pistol stand in the way of your total annihilation! You'll have to be sharp, though. Droids lurk behind every corner of each randomly generated Sector, and all of them must be destroyed before you can make a break into a more challenging maze! And watch out for the walls! They're radioactive. The slightest contact will quickly turn you into a cloud of debris.</plot>
    <year>1983</year>
    <nplayers>1</nplayers>
    <ESRB>ESRB - E (Everyone)</ESRB>
    <studio>CBS Electronics</studio>
    <rating>3.0</rating>
    <boxart1>zas9tPY.png</boxart1>
    <clearlogo1>PGmQSjZ.png</clearlogo1>
    <snapshot1>OsroKV1.png</snapshot1>
    <boxart2>MVQRTCk.jpg</boxart2>
    <snapshot2>gPLt1oc.png</snapshot2>
    <boxart3>K2B8DXY.png</boxart3>
    <boxart4>aA1YzoK.png</boxart4>
    <snapshot10>uQ0QedF.jpg</snapshot10>
    <snapshot3>fL19y3c.gif</snapshot3>
    <snapshot4>0jqNfpz.gif</snapshot4>
    <snapshot5>p2czbi8.gif</snapshot5>
    <snapshot6>P9DXPXt.gif</snapshot6>
    <snapshot7>PHRHDUL.jpg</snapshot7>
    <snapshot8>ImttMVA.jpg</snapshot8>
    <snapshot9>YvzjjMS.jpg</snapshot9>
  </game>
  <game name="Kaboom! (USA)">
    <description>Kaboom! (USA)</description>
    <title_clean>Kaboom!</title_clean>
    <rom name="no-intro-atari-5200-20130303/No-Intro%20-%20Atari%20-%205200%20%282013-03-03%29.zip/Kaboom%21%20%28USA%29.zip" size="3335"/>
    <releasedate>18/10/1983</releasedate>
    <genre>Action,General</genre>
    <gamefaqs_url>http://www.gamefaqs.com/atari5200/585312-kaboom</gamefaqs_url>
    <plot>Kaboom! is an Activision published in 1981 for Atari 2600 that was designed by Larry Kaplan. It was well-received and successful commercially, selling over one million cartridges by 1983.[citation needed][CR]Kaboom! is an unauthorized adaptation of the 1978 Atari coin-op Avalanche.[1] The gameplay of both games is fundamentally the same, but Kaboom! was re-themed to be about a mad bomber instead of falling rocks. As an ex-Atari programmer, Larry Kaplan, originally wanted to port Avalanche to the Atari 2600. In Avalanche all the boulders are lined up at the top which is difficult to accomplish on the 2600, hence the shift to the Mad Bomber. David Crane coded the overlaid sprites for the Mad Bomber.[2]</plot>
    <rating>1.50</rating>
    <nplayers>1</nplayers>
    <studio>Activision</studio>
    <ESRB>ESRB - E (Everyone)</ESRB>
    <boxart1>YjdU8gW.png</boxart1>
    <clearlogo1>sz2Aecp.png</clearlogo1>
    <snapshot1>Z7dcffD.png</snapshot1>
    <boxart2>WzEEiBa.jpg</boxart2>
    <snapshot2>XAOiCdy.png</snapshot2>
    <boxart3>Z7WoazZ.png</boxart3>
    <boxart4>OcQIPWL.png</boxart4>
    <snapshot10>SQg4wUD.png</snapshot10>
    <snapshot3>4aNvwUk.gif</snapshot3>
    <snapshot4>Fdq3V46.png</snapshot4>
    <snapshot5>ccWODrm.png</snapshot5>
    <snapshot6>VIjNv0H.png</snapshot6>
    <snapshot7>LYAGDk4.png</snapshot7>
    <snapshot8>qEXdFkp.png</snapshot8>
    <snapshot9>b1hQMnh.png</snapshot9>
  </game>
  <game name="Kangaroo (USA)">
    <description>Kangaroo (USA)</description>
    <title_clean>Kangaroo</title_clean>
    <rom name="no-intro-atari-5200-20130303/No-Intro%20-%20Atari%20-%205200%20%282013-03-03%29.zip/Kangaroo%20%28USA%29.zip" size="10005"/>
    <releasedate>18/10/1983</releasedate>
    <genre>Action,Platformer,2D</genre>
    <gamefaqs_url>http://www.gamefaqs.com/atari5200/585313-kangaroo</gamefaqs_url>
    <plot>Baby Roo has been kidnapped by monkeys, and it's up to Mama Roo to come to the rescue! Your kangaroo starts out at the bottom of the screen. You need to guide the kangaroo up the various ladders and platforms to the top where Baby Roo is being held captive. The monkeys will be trying to stop you by throwing or dropping apples and knocking you off the platforms. Your kangaroo has boxing gloves, however, and can knock out the monkeys with a single punch! Along the way various types of fruit can be collected to earn bonus points.</plot>
    <rating>3.00</rating>
    <nplayers>1</nplayers>
    <year>1983</year>
    <ESRB>ESRB - E (Everyone)</ESRB>
    <studio>Atari</studio>
    <boxart1>I0Ijgzt.png</boxart1>
    <banner1>vUtHjta.jpg</banner1>
    <clearlogo1>eQFdtOi.png</clearlogo1>
    <snapshot1>mIhUfdF.png</snapshot1>
    <boxart2>NnoCQPb.jpg</boxart2>
    <snapshot2>SSwkSNs.png</snapshot2>
    <boxart3>CGlt7Wm.png</boxart3>
    <boxart4>eWr5upG.png</boxart4>
    <snapshot10>MV66Jkg.png</snapshot10>
    <snapshot3>6sEjDqT.gif</snapshot3>
    <snapshot4>xoyhSxV.gif</snapshot4>
    <snapshot5>C0kIHYn.png</snapshot5>
    <snapshot6>VmuJihC.png</snapshot6>
    <snapshot7>O8w92Cc.jpg</snapshot7>
    <snapshot8>YEBjJuk.jpg</snapshot8>
    <snapshot9>L8YBUGD.png</snapshot9>
  </game>
  <game name="Keystone Kapers (USA)">
    <description>Keystone Kapers (USA)</description>
    <title_clean>Keystone Kapers</title_clean>
    <rom name="no-intro-atari-5200-20130303/No-Intro%20-%20Atari%20-%205200%20%282013-03-03%29.zip/Keystone%20Kapers%20%28USA%29.zip" size="6443"/>
    <releasedate>18/10/1984</releasedate>
    <genre>Action,General</genre>
    <gamefaqs_url>http://www.gamefaqs.com/atari5200/585314-keystone-kapers</gamefaqs_url>
    <plot>Keystone Kapers is a video game published by Activision for the Atari 2600 in 1983, and later ported to the Atari 5200, Atari 8-bit family, ColecoVision, and MSX. Inspired by Mack Sennett's slapstick Keystone Cops series of silent films, the object of the game is for Officer Keystone Kelly (the player) to catch Harry Hooligan before he can escape from a department store.</plot>
    <nplayers>1</nplayers>
    <ESRB>ESRB - E (Everyone)</ESRB>
    <studio>Activision</studio>
    <rating>3.1</rating>
    <boxart1>SMxvEC5.png</boxart1>
    <clearlogo1>7Z5xeqM.png</clearlogo1>
    <snapshot1>i8fQkag.png</snapshot1>
    <boxart2>3Hr2pJJ.jpg</boxart2>
    <snapshot2>9aOFtar.png</snapshot2>
    <boxart3>5u4ungC.png</boxart3>
    <snapshot10>B7Sy3IM.png</snapshot10>
    <snapshot3>mGkNEeK.gif</snapshot3>
    <snapshot4>UerOIFm.gif</snapshot4>
    <snapshot5>HIxnHuu.gif</snapshot5>
    <snapshot6>z4VL3dv.png</snapshot6>
    <snapshot7>cx4ZADD.png</snapshot7>
    <snapshot8>KyLTlCQ.png</snapshot8>
    <snapshot9>Tx70peH.png</snapshot9>
  </game>
  <game name="Koffi - Yellow Kopter (USA) (Unl)">
    <description>Koffi - Yellow Kopter (USA) (Unl)</description>
    <title_clean>Koffi - Yellow Kopter</title_clean>
    <rom name="no-intro-atari-5200-20130303/No-Intro%20-%20Atari%20-%205200%20%282013-03-03%29.zip/Koffi%20-%20Yellow%20Kopter%20%28USA%29%20%28Unl%29.zip" size="15820"/>
    <nplayers>1</nplayers>
    <studio>AtariAge</studio>
    <releasedate>24/02/2003</releasedate>
    <plot>Koffi is a little kopter so when the emergencies came, the big kopters wouldn't let him go. But now he has heard that Pyro the thundercloud is using lightning to start fires in the forest. The fire needs to be put out, the animals need saving. Koffi wasn't allowed to help the big kopters but he can't just ignore this until they return.[CR]You, as Koffi, must gather water from the raindrops or snowflakes and destroy Pyro. You destroy him by bumping into him but watch out for his lightning. After Pyro is gone, you must hover close to the fire then press your button to release water to put out. If you don't have enough water, grab more raindrops or snowflakes but don't delay or the fire will rage out of control. You can get bonus points by shoving the animal under the trees off the screen. The forest areas are mountain valley, coniferous forest and windy vines, where you have to watch that you are not blown into lightning. After you clear the three forest areas, you must face Pyro's mom, and she is not happy that you beat up on her son. You kill her the same way as her son but she throws longer and faster lightning and there is an angry cloud moving up and down and slowly towards you. Once she is dead, you restart mountain valley at a harder level.</plot>
    <ESRB>ESRB - E (Everyone)</ESRB>
    <rating>2.5</rating>
    <boxart1>MZNwQqB.png</boxart1>
    <banner1>EJbWpSn.jpg</banner1>
    <clearlogo1>oBYV6J7.png</clearlogo1>
    <snapshot1>h6x6e3T.png</snapshot1>
    <boxart2>jnLrs6f.jpg</boxart2>
    <snapshot2>zF76Jsu.png</snapshot2>
    <boxart3>CPtuAyg.png</boxart3>
    <boxart4>sMXSNiO.png</boxart4>
  </game>
  <game name="Last Starfighter, The (USA) (Proto)">
    <description>Last Starfighter, The (USA) (Proto)</description>
    <title_clean>The Last Starfighter</title_clean>
    <rom name="no-intro-atari-5200-20130303/No-Intro%20-%20Atari%20-%205200%20%282013-03-03%29.zip/Last%20Starfighter%2C%20The%20%28USA%29%20%28Proto%29.zip" size="12917"/>
    <studio>Atari</studio>
    <releasedate>08/05/1984</releasedate>
    <plot>Greetings Starfighter. You have been recruited by the Star League to defend the Frontier against Xur and the Ko-Dan armada."[CR]It's not just a tag line, it's also the instructions!  Yes, you've been recruited to help the Star League destroy Xur and his forces once and for all.  To accomplish this, you'll have to travel to the Procyon system and destroy the Ko-Dan in their own galaxy.  However, while you're off playing cowboy in a distant galaxy, the Ko-Dan armada are planning their own attack on your home system of Celos IV.  So not only must you defeat the whole Ko-Dan empire single handed, you must also defend your galaxy at the same time.  Accomplishing both tasks at once is all about strategy, sharp shooting, and a little luck. [CR]The Last Starfighter is based on the 80s movie. Unfortunately despite being finished it wasn't released for the Atari 5200. However it does exist in prototype form and was eventually officially released for the Atari XE/XL as Star Raiders II with some minor changes. Also an arcade version was supposed to be released but was canned as well. On top of all that this game wasn't even originally The Last Starfighter and instead was originally called Orbiter that was retooled. Quite a history for a prototype!</plot>
    <genre>Flight Simulator, Shooter</genre>
    <boxart1>MiIxE2O.png</boxart1>
    <clearlogo1>PX0qxPi.png</clearlogo1>
    <snapshot1>waOqFJW.png</snapshot1>
    <boxart2>8Y7HAu0.jpg</boxart2>
    <snapshot2>PtLf85d.png</snapshot2>
    <boxart3>FXmsbJ8.png</boxart3>
    <videoid>eKYToZkShSA</videoid>
  </game>
  <game name="Looney Tunes Hotel (USA) (Proto)">
    <description>Looney Tunes Hotel (USA) (Proto)</description>
    <title_clean>Looney Tunes Hotel</title_clean>
    <rom name="no-intro-atari-5200-20130303/No-Intro%20-%20Atari%20-%205200%20%282013-03-03%29.zip/Looney%20Tunes%20Hotel%20%28USA%29%20%28Proto%29.zip" size="9472"/>
    <plot>Looney Tunes Hotel was a nearly completed video game that was going to be released for the Atari 5200. Players were to play on a set of hotels, but Atari never got to finishing the game.</plot>
    <boxart1>Asj7Ps9.png</boxart1>
    <snapshot1>ea2SbgO.png</snapshot1>
    <boxart2>X3QAePo.png</boxart2>
    <snapshot2>rFhsdak.png</snapshot2>
    <genre>Platform, Stealth</genre>
    <studio>Atari</studio>
  </game>
  <game name="Mario Bros. (USA)">
    <description>Mario Bros. (USA)</description>
    <title_clean>Mario Bros.</title_clean>
    <rom name="no-intro-atari-5200-20130303/No-Intro%20-%20Atari%20-%205200%20%282013-03-03%29.zip/Mario%20Bros.%20%28USA%29.zip" size="12347"/>
    <releasedate>18/10/1983</releasedate>
    <genre>Action,Platformer,2D</genre>
    <gamefaqs_url>http://www.gamefaqs.com/atari5200/585318-mario-bros</gamefaqs_url>
    <plot>Mario Bros. features two plumbers, Mario and Luigi, having to investigate the sewers of New York after strange creatures have been appearing down there. The objective of the game is to defeat all of the enemies in each phase. The mechanics of Mario Bros. involve only running and jumping.</plot>
    <nplayers>2</nplayers>
    <ESRB>ESRB - E (Everyone)</ESRB>
    <studio>Atari</studio>
    <rating>3.6</rating>
    <boxart1>gg5ThD5.png</boxart1>
    <banner1>6UX6IqL.jpg</banner1>
    <clearlogo1>Yb6mly0.png</clearlogo1>
    <snapshot1>nI4iiLU.png</snapshot1>
    <fanart1>VipRerE.jpg</fanart1>
    <boxart2>TfoaPUm.jpg</boxart2>
    <snapshot2>mRgfyoE.png</snapshot2>
    <boxart3>C5YSf2C.png</boxart3>
    <snapshot10>Jq3ixW7.png</snapshot10>
    <snapshot3>KLijaPm.gif</snapshot3>
    <snapshot4>OEUJ5oA.gif</snapshot4>
    <snapshot5>AePzv5h.gif</snapshot5>
    <snapshot6>CAcvNYp.gif</snapshot6>
    <snapshot7>Tseed5i.png</snapshot7>
    <snapshot8>SEjtiSN.png</snapshot8>
    <snapshot9>N3GD6wc.png</snapshot9>
  </game>
  <game name="Meebzork (USA) (Proto)">
    <description>Meebzork (USA) (Proto)</description>
    <title_clean>Meebzork</title_clean>
    <rom name="no-intro-atari-5200-20130303/No-Intro%20-%20Atari%20-%205200%20%282013-03-03%29.zip/Meebzork%20%28USA%29%20%28Proto%29.zip" size="15103"/>
    <nplayers>1</nplayers>
    <studio>Atari</studio>
    <releasedate>16/11/1983</releasedate>
    <plot>An unfinished prototype game that was originally planned as a shooter but the last available version ends up being more an action/adventure game. There is an early build available of the shooter as well.[CR]You are a warrior named Meebzork who can practice or play through 6 different levels (not including another level that was going to be after you completed a board and would allow you to choose a next one). All 6 levels are different in what they require. While unfinished and unpolished you can see a lot of potential.</plot>
    <genre>Adventure</genre>
    <boxart1>HBKHntE.png</boxart1>
    <clearlogo1>Gunef2H.png</clearlogo1>
    <snapshot1>BKqEbDw.png</snapshot1>
    <snapshot2>L87saEm.png</snapshot2>
    <videoid>adxE-tHynl0</videoid>
  </game>
  <game name="MegaMania (USA)">
    <description>MegaMania (USA)</description>
    <title_clean>MegaMania</title_clean>
    <rom name="no-intro-atari-5200-20130303/No-Intro%20-%20Atari%20-%205200%20%282013-03-03%29.zip/MegaMania%20%28USA%29.zip" size="6051"/>
    <releasedate>18/10/1983</releasedate>
    <genre>Action,Shooter,Static</genre>
    <gamefaqs_url>http://www.gamefaqs.com/atari5200/585320-megamania</gamefaqs_url>
    <plot>A quick midnight snack in front of the tube? Unfortunately, hidden under a pepperoni particle, you didn't see the slender slice of anchovy. Then, with a roaring rush, your eyelids crash. And, as sleep overwhelms...Gastric juices grind. Galant dreams dissolve. Space objects streak. Ice cream sandiwches scream. Party bow ties pound. Radial tires rage. Steaming irons scorch. Space dice storm.</plot>
    <nplayers>1-2</nplayers>
    <ESRB>ESRB - E (Everyone)</ESRB>
    <studio>Activision</studio>
    <rating>2.6</rating>
    <boxart1>Z9U6mCn.png</boxart1>
    <snapshot1>FMRTC9A.png</snapshot1>
    <snapshot2>PNJS8kD.png</snapshot2>
    <boxart2>EnDW8bV.jpg</boxart2>
    <boxart3>PZD6gQA.jpg</boxart3>
    <snapshot10>PjtziN8.png</snapshot10>
    <snapshot3>IZNKKBZ.gif</snapshot3>
    <snapshot4>xKg62UA.gif</snapshot4>
    <snapshot5>fHbyP8n.gif</snapshot5>
    <snapshot6>6FIkQq9.png</snapshot6>
    <snapshot7>ptoini9.png</snapshot7>
    <snapshot8>RBSNSi2.png</snapshot8>
    <snapshot9>9mvUDwn.png</snapshot9>
  </game>
  <game name="Meteorites (USA)">
    <description>Meteorites (USA)</description>
    <title_clean>Meteorites</title_clean>
    <rom name="no-intro-atari-5200-20130303/No-Intro%20-%20Atari%20-%205200%20%282013-03-03%29.zip/Meteorites%20%28USA%29.zip" size="7320"/>
    <releasedate>18/10/1984</releasedate>
    <genre>Action,Shooter,Scrolling</genre>
    <gamefaqs_url>http://www.gamefaqs.com/atari5200/585321-meteorites</gamefaqs_url>
    <plot>Meteorites - true arcade action and control with exciting challenges and superior gameplay! Featuring new levels of superb gameplay capability from full 12K programming, 24 progressive game skill levels, exciting new challenges for beginner and advanced players, and one or two player option.</plot>
    <year>1983</year>
    <nplayers>1-2</nplayers>
    <ESRB>ESRB - E (Everyone)</ESRB>
    <studio>Electra Concepts International Corp.</studio>
    <rating>2.5</rating>
    <boxart1>K0GM154.png</boxart1>
    <banner1>MJzTmIh.jpg</banner1>
    <clearlogo1>UNNtB8d.png</clearlogo1>
    <snapshot1>I1Xa9XH.png</snapshot1>
    <boxart2>yrpdKbU.jpg</boxart2>
    <snapshot2>LQJzi1d.png</snapshot2>
    <boxart3>6p4TaxQ.png</boxart3>
    <snapshot3>ZCwVIcw.gif</snapshot3>
    <snapshot4>JL7IX7a.gif</snapshot4>
    <snapshot5>8YtayzI.png</snapshot5>
    <snapshot6>opDFOtn.png</snapshot6>
    <snapshot7>ZJfxijg.png</snapshot7>
  </game>
  <game name="Microgammon SB (USA) (Proto)">
    <description>Microgammon SB (USA) (Proto)</description>
    <title_clean>Microgammon SB</title_clean>
    <rom name="no-intro-atari-5200-20130303/No-Intro%20-%20Atari%20-%205200%20%282013-03-03%29.zip/Microgammon%20SB%20%28USA%29%20%28Proto%29.zip" size="6448"/>
    <nplayers>2</nplayers>
    <studio>Atari</studio>
    <releasedate>15/08/1983</releasedate>
    <plot>An unreleased prototype game created by Steve Baker. Originally released for the Apple II he decided to port it to the Atari 5200 since it had a similar high resolution mode. Which only allowed it to be black and white. Luckily this is perfect for Backgammon!</plot>
    <genre>Strategy</genre>
    <boxart1>fN52CtP.png</boxart1>
    <snapshot1>6kbfqUC.png</snapshot1>
    <boxart2>Y212ady.png</boxart2>
    <snapshot2>Bxdwj31.png</snapshot2>
    <boxart3>I1xfpPM.png</boxart3>
    <ESRB>E - Everyone</ESRB>
  </game>
  <game name="Millipede (USA) (Proto)">
    <description>Millipede (USA) (Proto)</description>
    <title_clean>Millipede</title_clean>
    <rom name="no-intro-atari-5200-20130303/No-Intro%20-%20Atari%20-%205200%20%282013-03-03%29.zip/Millipede%20%28USA%29%20%28Proto%29.zip" size="11669"/>
    <rating>4.00</rating>
    <nplayers>2</nplayers>
    <releasedate>31/01/1984</releasedate>
    <plot>An unreleased prototype conversion of the arcade game Millipede. It was completed but never released due to Atari abandoning the 5200 near it's completion.[CR]The goal is to survive wave after wave of various insects while trying to destroy a Millipede that makes its way down the screen towards your player. While very similar to Centipede it adds quite a few new quirks such as new insects to contend with and DDT bombs that when shot will destroy what is around them.</plot>
    <genre>Shooter</genre>
    <boxart1>gkisbKZ.png</boxart1>
    <clearlogo1>AnLj31g.png</clearlogo1>
    <snapshot1>vtNYhB5.png</snapshot1>
    <boxart2>ljzcZ1V.png</boxart2>
    <snapshot2>Pgd4UFp.png</snapshot2>
    <videoid>vgg8OHjPito</videoid>
    <studio>Atari</studio>
  </game>
  <game name="Miner 2049er Starring Bounty Bob (USA)">
    <description>Miner 2049er Starring Bounty Bob (USA)</description>
    <title_clean>Miner 2049er Starring Bounty Bob</title_clean>
    <rom name="no-intro-atari-5200-20130303/No-Intro%20-%20Atari%20-%205200%20%282013-03-03%29.zip/Miner%202049er%20Starring%20Bounty%20Bob%20%28USA%29.zip" size="12584"/>
    <releasedate>18/10/1983</releasedate>
    <genre>Action,Platformer,2D</genre>
    <gamefaqs_url>http://www.gamefaqs.com/atari5200/585323-miner-2049er</gamefaqs_url>
    <plot>You control 'Bounty Bob', as he climbs ladders and walks on the framework. Use the special equipment like the transporters, the life, and the cannon to help Bob claim the mine. Find the various possessions left by previous explorers, but watch out for mutant organisms that lurk everywhere and try to waste you!</plot>
    <nplayers>1-2</nplayers>
    <ESRB>ESRB - E (Everyone)</ESRB>
    <studio>Big Five Software</studio>
    <rating>3.9</rating>
    <boxart1>omhuQ7p.png</boxart1>
    <snapshot1>JGiEsTU.png</snapshot1>
    <snapshot2>iP2u242.png</snapshot2>
  </game>
  <game name="Miniature Golf (USA) (Proto)">
    <description>Miniature Golf (USA) (Proto)</description>
    <title_clean>Miniature Golf</title_clean>
    <rom name="no-intro-atari-5200-20130303/No-Intro%20-%20Atari%20-%205200%20%282013-03-03%29.zip/Miniature%20Golf%20%28USA%29%20%28Proto%29.zip" size="7050"/>
    <rating>4.00</rating>
    <nplayers>2</nplayers>
    <releasedate>10/02/1983</releasedate>
    <plot>Unreleased prototype game by Steve Baker for the Atari 5200. However it was completed and is fully playable. Due to the Hi-Res mode used the game has some odd choices for colors but other than that is quite well done and simulates Miniature Golf very well. [CR]Control is handled entirely by the keypad, so the non-centering 5200 joystick doesn't hinder the gameplay.  Pushing the # and * keys changes the direction the ball will be hit (represented by an arrow) and the 1-9 keys are used to indicate the power of the swing (1=lowest and 9=highest).</plot>
    <genre>Sports</genre>
    <boxart1>chAGyS2.png</boxart1>
    <clearlogo1>PMQxeoQ.png</clearlogo1>
    <snapshot1>WyfjNh1.png</snapshot1>
    <boxart2>CdjoSD4.png</boxart2>
    <snapshot2>0A17i1N.png</snapshot2>
    <boxart3>uWqiP76.jpg</boxart3>
    <videoid>gNJuO19kEgM</videoid>
    <studio>Atari</studio>
  </game>
  <game name="Missile Command (USA)">
    <description>Missile Command (USA)</description>
    <title_clean>Missile Command</title_clean>
    <rom name="no-intro-atari-5200-20130303/No-Intro%20-%20Atari%20-%205200%20%282013-03-03%29.zip/Missile%20Command%20%28USA%29.zip" size="4889"/>
    <releasedate>18/10/1982</releasedate>
    <genre>Action,Shooter,Static</genre>
    <gamefaqs_url>http://www.gamefaqs.com/atari5200/585325-missile-command</gamefaqs_url>
    <plot>The game is played by moving a crosshair across the sky background  and launch a counter-missile from the appropriate battery. Counter-missiles explode upon reaching the crosshair, leaving a fireball that persists for several seconds and destroys any enemy missiles that enter it. There are three batteries, each with ten missiles; a missile battery becomes useless when all its missiles are fired, or if the battery is destroyed by enemy fire. The missiles of the central battery fly to their targets at much greater speed; only these missiles can effectively kill a smart bomb at a distance.</plot>
    <nplayers>2</nplayers>
    <studio>Atari</studio>
    <ESRB>ESRB - E (Everyone)</ESRB>
    <rating>3.5</rating>
    <boxart1>KYFRnYX.png</boxart1>
    <banner1>ob6Zi86.jpg</banner1>
    <clearlogo1>OvLdqUf.png</clearlogo1>
    <snapshot1>AJPuDe5.png</snapshot1>
    <boxart2>MKAvhFA.jpg</boxart2>
    <snapshot2>xJXY7U8.png</snapshot2>
    <boxart3>05Yni08.png</boxart3>
    <snapshot10>UiMy5U1.jpg</snapshot10>
    <snapshot3>75UWkJx.gif</snapshot3>
    <snapshot4>0VpGLsf.gif</snapshot4>
    <snapshot5>XCs92rp.gif</snapshot5>
    <snapshot6>UuiWKvV.gif</snapshot6>
    <snapshot7>3MUPV0q.jpg</snapshot7>
    <snapshot8>HOG7fuH.jpg</snapshot8>
    <snapshot9>chhQWax.jpg</snapshot9>
  </game>
  <game name="Montezuma's Revenge featuring Panama Joe (USA)">
    <description>Montezuma's Revenge featuring Panama Joe (USA)</description>
    <title_clean>Montezuma's Revenge featuring Panama Joe</title_clean>
    <rom name="no-intro-atari-5200-20130303/No-Intro%20-%20Atari%20-%205200%20%282013-03-03%29.zip/Montezuma%27s%20Revenge%20featuring%20Panama%20Joe%20%28USA%29.zip" size="10011"/>
    <releasedate>18/10/1983</releasedate>
    <genre>Action,General</genre>
    <gamefaqs_url>http://www.gamefaqs.com/atari5200/585326-montezumas-revenge-featuring-panama-joe</gamefaqs_url>
    <plot>Wherever there's mind-twisting mystery, hair-raising adventure, and non-stop action--PANAMA JOE is sure to be there. And in MONTEZUMA'S REVENGE, he's got more than he bargained for as you help him through 100 danger-filled chambers in the Aztec emperor's fortress. The stakes? Priceless treasure. And lots of it. But finding necessary keys, torches, swords, and amulets is no small feat as PANAMA JOE tries to avoid deadly snakes, menacing spiders, and bouncing skulls. But then disappearing floors, bridges, and laser walls are no picnic either! It's up to you to lead this undaunted adventurer through the labyrinth of chambers in an attempt to solve the riddle of the fortress and escape with the loot!</plot>
    <nplayers>1</nplayers>
    <ESRB>ESRB - E (Everyone)</ESRB>
    <studio>Parker Brothers</studio>
    <rating>3.0</rating>
    <boxart1>xOgEFs7.png</boxart1>
    <snapshot1>Jt6rNJq.png</snapshot1>
    <snapshot2>I8SHVyU.png</snapshot2>
  </game>
  <game name="Moon Patrol (USA)">
    <description>Moon Patrol (USA)</description>
    <title_clean>Moon Patrol</title_clean>
    <rom name="no-intro-atari-5200-20130303/No-Intro%20-%20Atari%20-%205200%20%282013-03-03%29.zip/Moon%20Patrol%20%28USA%29.zip" size="12037"/>
    <releasedate>18/10/1983</releasedate>
    <genre>Action,Shooter,Scrolling</genre>
    <gamefaqs_url>http://www.gamefaqs.com/atari5200/585327-moon-patrol</gamefaqs_url>
    <plot>he player takes the role of a Luna City police officer assigned to Sector Nine, the home of the "toughest thugs in the galaxy."[CR]The top portion of the screen shows a timeline-style map of the current course, and three indicator lights. The top light indicates upcoming enemy aerial attacks, the middle one indicates an upcoming minefield, and the bottom one indicates enemies approaching from behind.[CR]The map shows five different checkpoints labeled E, J, O, T and Z. Similar to racing games, the time spent during between each checkpoint is compared to the average which determines the number of bonus points allocated to the player. The game contains two courses, the regular and champion course; after completing the first course your buggy's color changes from pink to red and the game continues on.</plot>
    <rating>3.12</rating>
    <nplayers>2</nplayers>
    <ESRB>ESRB - E (Everyone)</ESRB>
    <studio>Atari</studio>
    <boxart1>VdEJnKo.png</boxart1>
    <banner1>lJJKMwU.jpg</banner1>
    <clearlogo1>tNQK8Nq.png</clearlogo1>
    <snapshot1>YVCDgQy.png</snapshot1>
    <boxart2>ySHW5Ek.jpg</boxart2>
    <snapshot2>IPTn64d.png</snapshot2>
    <boxart3>ijQT9T8.png</boxart3>
    <videoid>HBOKWCpwGfM</videoid>
    <snapshot10>rtcSJEw.png</snapshot10>
    <snapshot3>SXteTwF.gif</snapshot3>
    <snapshot4>tRQxBsO.gif</snapshot4>
    <snapshot5>JiJsUpa.gif</snapshot5>
    <snapshot6>XQ6IoAg.gif</snapshot6>
    <snapshot7>wSGeQaa.gif</snapshot7>
    <snapshot8>td0BLPl.gif</snapshot8>
    <snapshot9>Cl9Xa70.png</snapshot9>
  </game>
  <game name="Mountain King (USA)">
    <description>Mountain King (USA)</description>
    <title_clean>Mountain King</title_clean>
    <rom name="no-intro-atari-5200-20130303/No-Intro%20-%20Atari%20-%205200%20%282013-03-03%29.zip/Mountain%20King%20%28USA%29.zip" size="6571"/>
    <releasedate>18/10/1984</releasedate>
    <genre>Action,General</genre>
    <gamefaqs_url>http://www.gamefaqs.com/atari5200/585329-mountain-king</gamefaqs_url>
    <plot>Deep within a multi platformed diamond mine is a valuable crown. Your goal is to locate and retrieve the crown, then make it to the top of the mine alive! There are several steps that need to be completed before you can retrieve the crown. First you need to collect enough diamonds to earn 1,000 points. After you have enough points, you need to locate the flame spirit which is hidden somewhere within the mine. Since the mine is rather dark, you carry a flashlight with you which can be used to locate objects (such as treasure chests full of diamonds and the flame spirit.) Once you have the flame spirit, you need to find the entrance to the temple the crown is in. Offer the flame spirit to the skull spirit guarding the entrance, and you can get in and take the crown. Once you have the crown, you need to make it to the top of the mine before time runs out. To make this task more challenging, numerous cave bats fly around which can steal the crown. If this happens, you need to begin again! At the very bottom of the mine is a deadly spider; if you're not careful while exploring this region of the mine, you could become caught in it's web and be eaten. Each level has a time limit, and the more levels you complete the shorter the time limit becomes!</plot>
    <rating>4.29</rating>
    <nplayers>1</nplayers>
    <studio>CBS Electronics</studio>
    <ESRB>ESRB - E (Everyone)</ESRB>
    <boxart1>MXDsKXj.png</boxart1>
    <clearlogo1>mIpQmgc.png</clearlogo1>
    <snapshot1>JnQCPb6.png</snapshot1>
    <boxart2>79hXXIT.jpg</boxart2>
    <snapshot2>0aCZr3F.png</snapshot2>
    <boxart3>qYNqaxT.png</boxart3>
    <snapshot10>Ubpd6qu.png</snapshot10>
    <snapshot3>1qvLLSm.gif</snapshot3>
    <snapshot4>TVT7Ieu.gif</snapshot4>
    <snapshot5>xlucbW5.png</snapshot5>
    <snapshot6>TBg2iYZ.png</snapshot6>
    <snapshot7>uPyQDNf.png</snapshot7>
    <snapshot8>CssVx6b.png</snapshot8>
    <snapshot9>LMXfrWt.png</snapshot9>
  </game>
  <game name="Mr. Do!'s Castle (USA)">
    <description>Mr. Do!'s Castle (USA)</description>
    <title_clean>Mr. Do!'s Castle</title_clean>
    <rom name="no-intro-atari-5200-20130303/No-Intro%20-%20Atari%20-%205200%20%282013-03-03%29.zip/Mr.%20Do%21%27s%20Castle%20%28USA%29.zip" size="6831"/>
    <releasedate>18/10/1984</releasedate>
    <genre>Action,General</genre>
    <gamefaqs_url>http://www.gamefaqs.com/atari5200/585330-mr-dos-castle</gamefaqs_url>
    <plot>Mr. Do's Castle is an arcade game created by Universal in September 1983. The Asian title of the game is Mr. Do! versus Unicorns. Though marketed as a sequel to the original Mr. Do! released one year earlier, the game bears a far closer resemblance to Space Panic. It is the second of the Mr. Do series of video games, although it wasn't intended to be. It began life as a game called "Knights vs. Unicorns", but the U.S. division of Universal persuaded the Japanese arm to modify the graphics into a Mr. Do! game, taking into account the first game's popularity.</plot>
    <nplayers>1</nplayers>
    <ESRB>ESRB - E (Everyone)</ESRB>
    <studio>Parker Brothers</studio>
    <rating>3.3</rating>
    <boxart1>UzwA4w2.png</boxart1>
    <clearlogo1>UZ8RIVo.png</clearlogo1>
    <snapshot1>3rJ7vu2.png</snapshot1>
    <boxart2>9NcKIuB.jpg</boxart2>
    <snapshot2>RBlsV4n.png</snapshot2>
    <boxart3>g15LzXA.png</boxart3>
    <snapshot10>JQiwOLw.png</snapshot10>
    <snapshot3>0yJSrCx.gif</snapshot3>
    <snapshot4>BvAWn3d.gif</snapshot4>
    <snapshot5>rryNYzd.png</snapshot5>
    <snapshot6>Vd2hC0Q.png</snapshot6>
    <snapshot7>SSTzka4.png</snapshot7>
    <snapshot8>H6S34jC.png</snapshot8>
    <snapshot9>bZ7E5V5.png</snapshot9>
  </game>
  <game name="Ms. Pac-Man (USA)">
    <description>Ms. Pac-Man (USA)</description>
    <title_clean>Ms. Pac-Man</title_clean>
    <rom name="no-intro-atari-5200-20130303/No-Intro%20-%20Atari%20-%205200%20%282013-03-03%29.zip/Ms.%20Pac-Man%20%28USA%29.zip" size="10137"/>
    <releasedate>18/10/1983</releasedate>
    <genre>Action,General</genre>
    <gamefaqs_url>http://www.gamefaqs.com/atari5200/585331-ms-pac-man</gamefaqs_url>
    <plot>The gameplay of Ms. Pac-Man is largely identical to that of the original Pac-Man. The player gathers points by eating dots and avoiding ghosts (contact with one loses a life). Power-pellets or energizers change the ghosts, which reverse their course and can be eaten for bonus points. Fruit bonuses can be consumed for increasing point values, twice per level.</plot>
    <rating>5.00</rating>
    <nplayers>2</nplayers>
    <studio>Atari</studio>
    <ESRB>ESRB - E (Everyone)</ESRB>
    <boxart1>5UaBESK.png</boxart1>
    <banner1>Wj2LHqs.jpg</banner1>
    <clearlogo1>CIZj995.png</clearlogo1>
    <snapshot1>QPOkh7p.png</snapshot1>
    <fanart1>od8XLOx.jpg</fanart1>
    <boxart2>qKPk0Od.jpg</boxart2>
    <snapshot2>Hg9qrcF.png</snapshot2>
    <boxart3>w1bqys5.png</boxart3>
    <videoid>3-upWtww9b4</videoid>
  </game>
  <game name="Pac-Man (USA)">
    <description>Pac-Man (USA)</description>
    <title_clean>Pac-Man</title_clean>
    <rom name="no-intro-atari-5200-20130303/No-Intro%20-%20Atari%20-%205200%20%282013-03-03%29.zip/Pac-Man%20%28USA%29.zip" size="8358"/>
    <releasedate>18/10/1982</releasedate>
    <genre>Action,General</genre>
    <gamefaqs_url>http://www.gamefaqs.com/atari5200/585333-pac-man</gamefaqs_url>
    <plot>The player controls Pac-Man through a maze, eating pac-dots. When all dots are eaten, Pac-Man is taken to the next stage, between some stages one of three intermission animations plays. Four enemies (Blinky, Pinky, Inky and Clyde) roam the maze, trying to catch Pac-Man. If an enemy touches Pac-Man, a life is lost. When all lives have been lost, the game ends.</plot>
    <rating>5.00</rating>
    <nplayers>2</nplayers>
    <studio>Atari</studio>
    <ESRB>ESRB - E (Everyone)</ESRB>
    <boxart1>eAFWaIX.png</boxart1>
    <banner1>pIGOtie.jpg</banner1>
    <clearlogo1>RZIbf7y.png</clearlogo1>
    <snapshot1>Xnpxabj.png</snapshot1>
    <fanart1>vbPlTuB.jpg</fanart1>
    <boxart2>NBbK1M7.jpg</boxart2>
    <snapshot2>UouJtOT.png</snapshot2>
    <boxart3>IdyX2l6.png</boxart3>
  </game>
  <game name="Pengo (USA)">
    <description>Pengo (USA)</description>
    <title_clean>Pengo</title_clean>
    <rom name="no-intro-atari-5200-20130303/No-Intro%20-%20Atari%20-%205200%20%282013-03-03%29.zip/Pengo%20%28USA%29.zip" size="10935"/>
    <releasedate>18/10/1983</releasedate>
    <genre>Action,General</genre>
    <gamefaqs_url>http://www.gamefaqs.com/atari5200/585334-pengo</gamefaqs_url>
    <plot>The player uses a joystick and a single button as controls. Pressing the button while pushing the joystick will cause Pengo to push forward the ice block he is facing, which will slide until it hits a wall or another ice block, crushing any intervening Sno-Bees. Crushing more than one Sno-Bee at once will increase the number of points awarded. There are a total of sixteen levels, which repeat in order starting on the seventeenth round.[CR]As the player crushes those on patrol, new Sno-Bees hatch from eggs located within ice blocks. At the start of each level, blocks that contain these eggs are briefly identified by flashing the color of that level's Sno-Bees. Eggs can be eliminated by crushing the ice blocks that contain them. If Pengo pushes a side wall the water "vibrates", any adjacent Sno-Bees will be briefly stunned, and are eliminated (for 100 points) if Pengo walks over them in this state. Eliminating all Sno-Bees in a round will progress the player to the next.[CR]Diamond blocks are unbreakable; when connected in a horizontal or vertical line the player earns bonus points: 10,000 points if aligned without being against a wall or if only one diamond block is touching a wall, 5,000 points if all three are against the wall. Alignment will also temporarily stun all Sno-Bees.[CR]After 60 seconds elapse in a round without a death, the game enters into sudden death mode; the music tempo and movement of the Sno-Bees accelerates. If a single Sno-Bee remains in the round, a jingle plays and the Sno-Bee accelerates in an attempt to reach a corner where it safely fades away.[CR]The game will always start with the same maze on power up. Once the game has gone through the attract mode, the maze will change.</plot>
    <nplayers>1-2</nplayers>
    <ESRB>ESRB - E (Everyone)</ESRB>
    <studio>Atari</studio>
    <rating>4.1</rating>
    <boxart1>s6QryJj.png</boxart1>
    <banner1>Uh26sme.jpg</banner1>
    <clearlogo1>GaOWMhM.png</clearlogo1>
    <snapshot1>i3q8pIn.png</snapshot1>
    <boxart2>0qQfT9Y.jpg</boxart2>
    <snapshot2>NWWMQZo.png</snapshot2>
    <boxart3>tLaDube.png</boxart3>
    <snapshot10>abJRYC6.jpg</snapshot10>
    <snapshot3>faqR4dQ.gif</snapshot3>
    <snapshot4>nCkrgJf.png</snapshot4>
    <snapshot5>LGBGPlr.png</snapshot5>
    <snapshot6>OT9xBaG.png</snapshot6>
    <snapshot7>A6u0wjA.png</snapshot7>
    <snapshot8>PpvFYjF.png</snapshot8>
    <snapshot9>PTPqqpz.png</snapshot9>
  </game>
  <game name="Pitfall! (USA)">
    <description>Pitfall! (USA)</description>
    <title_clean>Pitfall!</title_clean>
    <rom name="no-intro-atari-5200-20130303/No-Intro%20-%20Atari%20-%205200%20%282013-03-03%29.zip/Pitfall%21%20%28USA%29.zip" size="5735"/>
    <releasedate>18/10/1983</releasedate>
    <genre>Action,Platformer,2D</genre>
    <gamefaqs_url>http://www.gamefaqs.com/atari5200/585335-pitfall</gamefaqs_url>
    <plot>The player must maneuver a character known as Pitfall Harry through a maze-like jungle in an attempt to recover 32 treasures in a 20-minute time period. Along the way, he must negotiate numerous hazards, including pits, quicksand, rolling logs, fire, rattlesnakes, scorpions, and crocodiles. Harry may jump over or otherwise avoid these obstacles by climbing, running, or swinging on a vine to avoid them. Treasure includes gold and silver bars, diamond rings, and bags of money. Under the jungle there is a tunnel which Harry can access through ladders found at various places. This is required to get around some surface areas that have no way across otherwise. The tunnels are filled with dead-ends blocked by brick walls, forcing the player return to the surface at one of the ladders, and try to find a way around again. The tunnels also contain treasure and scorpions Harry must jump over.</plot>
    <rating>3.00</rating>
    <studio>Activision</studio>
    <nplayers>1</nplayers>
    <ESRB>ESRB - E (Everyone)</ESRB>
    <boxart1>BSHfvMC.png</boxart1>
    <banner1>nl72h1a.jpg</banner1>
    <clearlogo1>iEnXv2C.png</clearlogo1>
    <snapshot1>Wqkya7Z.png</snapshot1>
    <fanart1>WgDdwD2.jpg</fanart1>
    <boxart2>6FhFetZ.jpg</boxart2>
    <snapshot2>7KU3Ltu.png</snapshot2>
    <boxart3>D7bUQBS.png</boxart3>
    <snapshot10>rwlu5Xm.png</snapshot10>
    <snapshot3>F0TLz0Q.png</snapshot3>
    <snapshot4>V1zy2dE.png</snapshot4>
    <snapshot5>VNBfOda.png</snapshot5>
    <snapshot6>DnoSEDo.png</snapshot6>
    <snapshot7>2HMbe3J.png</snapshot7>
    <snapshot8>Rnmyafp.png</snapshot8>
    <snapshot9>yCJXLJX.png</snapshot9>
  </game>
  <game name="Pole Position (USA)">
    <description>Pole Position (USA)</description>
    <title_clean>Pole Position</title_clean>
    <rom name="no-intro-atari-5200-20130303/No-Intro%20-%20Atari%20-%205200%20%282013-03-03%29.zip/Pole%20Position%20%28USA%29.zip" size="11886"/>
    <releasedate>18/10/1983</releasedate>
    <genre>Driving,Racing,Arcade</genre>
    <gamefaqs_url>http://www.gamefaqs.com/atari5200/585337-pole-position</gamefaqs_url>
    <plot>In this game, the player controls a Formula One race car. The player completes a time trial lap within a certain amount of time to qualify for an F1 race at the Fuji Racetrack. After qualifying, the player races against other cars in a championship race.</plot>
    <rating>3.50</rating>
    <nplayers>1</nplayers>
    <studio>Atari</studio>
    <ESRB>ESRB - E (Everyone)</ESRB>
    <boxart1>dhEYnCM.png</boxart1>
    <banner1>kaZXVJU.jpg</banner1>
    <clearlogo1>VcTQ56U.png</clearlogo1>
    <snapshot1>LvLo8V1.png</snapshot1>
    <boxart2>nNzzCEQ.jpg</boxart2>
    <snapshot2>eXoGBFF.png</snapshot2>
    <boxart3>lDdbtE5.png</boxart3>
    <videoid>kdXNpEUT54o</videoid>
    <snapshot10>NoAtupM.png</snapshot10>
    <snapshot3>hMOolUq.gif</snapshot3>
    <snapshot4>KZwu0Yc.gif</snapshot4>
    <snapshot5>TliP6Db.gif</snapshot5>
    <snapshot6>JDbQaSt.png</snapshot6>
    <snapshot7>BxUeqB6.jpg</snapshot7>
    <snapshot8>Q20MReL.jpg</snapshot8>
    <snapshot9>nB8Cb9i.jpg</snapshot9>
  </game>
  <game name="Popeye (USA)">
    <description>Popeye (USA)</description>
    <title_clean>Popeye</title_clean>
    <rom name="no-intro-atari-5200-20130303/No-Intro%20-%20Atari%20-%205200%20%282013-03-03%29.zip/Popeye%20%28USA%29.zip" size="12116"/>
    <releasedate>18/10/1983</releasedate>
    <genre>Action,Platformer,2D</genre>
    <gamefaqs_url>http://www.gamefaqs.com/atari5200/585338-popeye</gamefaqs_url>
    <plot>Popeye (popai Popai?) is a 1982 arcade platform game developed and released by Nintendo based on the Popeye characters licensed from King Features Syndicate. Unlike most platform games, the player cannot jump; the only button is "punch." The game was licensed by Atari for exclusive release in the United Kingdom and Ireland, and featured in an Atari designed and manufactured cabinet. Some sources[2][3][4] claim that Ikegami Tsushinki also did design work on Popeye.[CR]The Popeye characters were originally going to be used in the game that later became Donkey Kong.[5] However at that time on the development of the game, Nintendo could not get the licenses to use the characters.[CR]Ben Falls holds the world record score of 3,023,060 earned on December 20, 2011, according to Twin Galaxies International Scoreboard.[6][CR]The Family Computer (Famicom) saw an educational sequel on November 22, 1983: Popeye no Eigo Asobi, an English teaching game akin to the later Donkey Kong Jr. Math.</plot>
    <nplayers>1-2</nplayers>
    <ESRB>ESRB - E (Everyone)</ESRB>
    <studio>Parker Brothers</studio>
    <rating>3.4</rating>
    <boxart1>wyyRkTY.png</boxart1>
    <banner1>wiSxgQs.jpg</banner1>
    <clearlogo1>7NiYrkb.png</clearlogo1>
    <snapshot1>Wdlgr6v.png</snapshot1>
    <boxart2>xsMa2Cw.jpg</boxart2>
    <snapshot2>6UK5Plv.png</snapshot2>
    <boxart3>GPinSSy.png</boxart3>
    <snapshot10>GFYdCad.jpg</snapshot10>
    <snapshot3>ht9lnXQ.gif</snapshot3>
    <snapshot4>Ipu1lMz.png</snapshot4>
    <snapshot5>Zvewv5A.png</snapshot5>
    <snapshot6>1dQ11w7.png</snapshot6>
    <snapshot7>CrRGtT9.png</snapshot7>
    <snapshot8>XvQaXsa.png</snapshot8>
    <snapshot9>EanGp89.jpg</snapshot9>
  </game>
  <game name="Q-bert (USA)">
    <description>Q-bert (USA)</description>
    <title_clean>Q-bert</title_clean>
    <rom name="no-intro-atari-5200-20130303/No-Intro%20-%20Atari%20-%205200%20%282013-03-03%29.zip/Q-bert%20%28USA%29.zip" size="6108"/>
    <nplayers>1-2</nplayers>
    <ESRB>ESRB - E (Everyone)</ESRB>
    <plot>Q bert is a conversion of the popular arcade game. The goal is to change all of the tiles on a pyramid to the target color. To do this you guide Q bert around the pyramid, and every tile he hops on will change color. On early levels, a single hop will change the tile to the desired color, but on later levels you may need to hop on a tile multiple times or even avoid hopping on a tile multiple times! Trying to stop Q bert are many different creatures which wander around the board, including Coily the snake, Slick and Sam, and falling balls. On the edge of the board are floating discs; if Q bert jumps on one of these discs when the snake is in pursuit, the snake will fall off the board while Q bert is safely transported to the top.</plot>
    <studio>Parker Brothers</studio>
    <rating>3.4</rating>
    <boxart1>LHNbkOP.png</boxart1>
    <snapshot1>7gLJesb.png</snapshot1>
    <snapshot2>05DHztG.png</snapshot2>
  </game>
  <game name="QIX (USA)">
    <description>QIX (USA)</description>
    <title_clean>QIX</title_clean>
    <rom name="no-intro-atari-5200-20130303/No-Intro%20-%20Atari%20-%205200%20%282013-03-03%29.zip/QIX%20%28USA%29.zip" size="7391"/>
    <releasedate>18/10/1982</releasedate>
    <genre>Miscellaneous,Puzzle,Action</genre>
    <gamefaqs_url>http://www.gamefaqs.com/atari5200/585340-qix</gamefaqs_url>
    <plot>In this game, you guide a marker which must draw rectangles and other weird objects in order to claim your territory, and you can either draw these rectangles fast or slow. Drawing the rectangles using the "slow" method awards you the most points. Once a rectangle has been made, it will be colored in to show that you have claimed your territory. While drawing the rectangles, you need to watch out for Qix (pronounced "kicks"), a series of colored lines that crawl the screen. In addition to Qix, you also need to avoid the Sparks who travel around the border, as well as any lines that you have made, as well as The Fuse, who travels along the line that you are drawing. Once you have claimed enough territory, you proceed to the next level.</plot>
    <rating>2.75</rating>
    <nplayers>2</nplayers>
    <studio>Atari</studio>
    <year>1982</year>
    <boxart1>odfAQaw.png</boxart1>
    <banner1>4B30Esp.jpg</banner1>
    <clearlogo1>wNep6pq.png</clearlogo1>
    <snapshot1>BDRZdYA.png</snapshot1>
    <boxart2>aUGJNax.jpg</boxart2>
    <snapshot2>iT2qshF.png</snapshot2>
    <boxart3>79yeGTY.png</boxart3>
  </game>
  <game name="Quest for Quintana Roo (USA)">
    <description>Quest for Quintana Roo (USA)</description>
    <title_clean>Quest for Quintana Roo</title_clean>
    <rom name="no-intro-atari-5200-20130303/No-Intro%20-%20Atari%20-%205200%20%282013-03-03%29.zip/Quest%20for%20Quintana%20Roo%20%28USA%29.zip" size="11298"/>
    <releasedate>18/10/1984</releasedate>
    <genre>Action,General</genre>
    <gamefaqs_url>http://www.gamefaqs.com/atari5200/585341-quest-for-quintana-roo</gamefaqs_url>
    <plot>Help Yucatan Sam explore the dozens of terror filled chambers that create the mystical temple of the Mayan god Quintana Roo. You must use your supplies as well as your cat-like reactions to avoid the sleeping snakes, overcome the mummy's curse, and eliminate the other adversaries while attempting to solve the mystery that will deliver the hidden treasure to you and Yucatan Sam. Since a different solution is required each time the game is started, you will be assured hours of mind-challenging, reflex-testing entertainment.</plot>
    <nplayers>1</nplayers>
    <studio>Sunrise Software</studio>
    <year>1984</year>
    <ESRB>ESRB - E (Everyone)</ESRB>
    <rating>2.5</rating>
    <boxart1>KZsP1h2.png</boxart1>
    <banner1>3eB0azs.jpg</banner1>
    <clearlogo1>oJY5Vlt.png</clearlogo1>
    <snapshot1>bgoup7S.png</snapshot1>
    <boxart2>GyfCVUG.jpg</boxart2>
    <snapshot2>D8Xtkyg.png</snapshot2>
    <boxart3>pr7dn7M.png</boxart3>
    <snapshot3>uZzQxez.gif</snapshot3>
    <snapshot4>3EsrqiR.gif</snapshot4>
    <snapshot5>itzDAt5.gif</snapshot5>
    <snapshot6>fvzXb4u.gif</snapshot6>
    <snapshot7>evU1gme.png</snapshot7>
    <snapshot8>bopDWjS.png</snapshot8>
    <snapshot9>sfxqBIe.png</snapshot9>
  </game>
  <game name="RealSports Baseball (USA)">
    <description>RealSports Baseball (USA)</description>
    <title_clean>RealSports Baseball</title_clean>
    <rom name="no-intro-atari-5200-20130303/No-Intro%20-%20Atari%20-%205200%20%282013-03-03%29.zip/RealSports%20Baseball%20%28USA%29.zip" size="17394"/>
    <releasedate>18/10/1983</releasedate>
    <genre>Sports,Traditional,Baseball,Sim</genre>
    <gamefaqs_url>http://www.gamefaqs.com/atari5200/585342-realsports-baseball</gamefaqs_url>
    <plot>Join the Atari Aces in the World Series of video baseball--RealSports[CR]BASEBALL!  It's a hot day in the ballpark--you can see the hot dog and soda[CR]pop vendors making their way up and down the bleachers.  The crowd roars after[CR]each pitch, and filling the stadium is the sound of "STEERIKE!  YOU'RE OUT!" [CR]Down on the field it's a different story--just you and the pitcher facing each[CR]other in an enormous diamond of brown and green.[CR]The roar of the spectators fades into the distance as the pitcher winds up. [CR]His arm arches back, his leg goes up, and...THUNK!  The ball flashes by and[CR]hits the catcher's glove at 90 miles an hour.  "STEERIKE!"  Another windup,[CR]another 90 mile an hour fastball, and "STEERIKE TWO!"  Gripping the bat[CR]tightly, you stare down at the pitcher, see him wind up, and watch as the ball[CR]seems to float in slow motion down the field toward you.  Everything falls[CR]into place as you swing with perfect timing, feel the contact, and see the[CR]ball sail over the right fielders outstretched glove and over the wall.  HOME[CR]RUN!</plot>
    <nplayers>2</nplayers>
    <studio>Atari</studio>
    <year>1983</year>
    <ESRB>ESRB - E (Everyone)</ESRB>
    <rating>3.5</rating>
    <boxart1>7dBYfh1.png</boxart1>
    <banner1>D2nUjzN.jpg</banner1>
    <clearlogo1>mQ0q2Ae.png</clearlogo1>
    <snapshot1>2CKuxTd.png</snapshot1>
    <boxart2>ttMym6I.jpg</boxart2>
    <snapshot2>nJG8Hmx.png</snapshot2>
    <boxart3>Uq9CoX3.png</boxart3>
    <boxart4>mmsEoPW.png</boxart4>
    <snapshot10>tdxrdT9.png</snapshot10>
    <snapshot3>kJJGFga.gif</snapshot3>
    <snapshot4>oGzmJAv.gif</snapshot4>
    <snapshot5>I3CHsRU.jpg</snapshot5>
    <snapshot6>JTkrbag.jpg</snapshot6>
    <snapshot7>KCinu7a.jpg</snapshot7>
    <snapshot8>pXqa3yk.jpg</snapshot8>
    <snapshot9>K4rQf62.jpg</snapshot9>
  </game>
  <game name="RealSports Basketball (USA)">
    <description>RealSports Basketball (USA)</description>
    <title_clean>RealSports Basketball</title_clean>
    <rom name="no-intro-atari-5200-20130303/No-Intro%20-%20Atari%20-%205200%20%282013-03-03%29.zip/RealSports%20Basketball%20%28USA%29.zip" size="9602"/>
    <nplayers>2</nplayers>
    <studio>Atari</studio>
    <releasedate>27/05/1983</releasedate>
    <plot>There are two significantly different versions of Realsports Basketball for the Atari 5200, both programmed by Patrick Bass. This version is what would become the final version of the game, which seems fairly complete, including easter eggs. However, like the Atari 2600 game of the same name, Realsports Basketball was never released for sale. It's unknown why Atari programmed two different versions of the game.[CR]Sadly, Patrick Bass died in an automobile crash in 1998. Patrick's brother, Ben Bass, worked with Ken Van Mersbergen to ensure this final version of the game would be shared with the public.</plot>
    <genre>Sports</genre>
    <ESRB>ESRB - E (Everyone)</ESRB>
    <rating>3.5</rating>
    <boxart1>s7n9mcd.png</boxart1>
    <clearlogo1>lUeDOfH.png</clearlogo1>
    <snapshot1>Cj4BoGR.png</snapshot1>
    <boxart2>e3X6WyL.png</boxart2>
    <snapshot2>Ysw9qWY.png</snapshot2>
    <boxart3>40bZJKg.png</boxart3>
    <snapshot10>tdxrdT9.png</snapshot10>
    <snapshot3>xG2PVE6.jpg</snapshot3>
    <snapshot4>pvZ3QfI.jpg</snapshot4>
    <snapshot5>I3CHsRU.jpg</snapshot5>
    <snapshot6>JTkrbag.jpg</snapshot6>
    <snapshot7>KCinu7a.jpg</snapshot7>
    <snapshot8>pXqa3yk.jpg</snapshot8>
    <snapshot9>K4rQf62.jpg</snapshot9>
  </game>
  <game name="RealSports Basketball (USA) (82-11-05) (Proto)">
    <description>RealSports Basketball (USA) (82-11-05) (Proto)</description>
    <title_clean>RealSports Basketball</title_clean>
    <rom name="no-intro-atari-5200-20130303/No-Intro%20-%20Atari%20-%205200%20%282013-03-03%29.zip/RealSports%20Basketball%20%28USA%29%20%2882-11-05%29%20%28Proto%29.zip" size="4537"/>
    <nplayers>2</nplayers>
    <studio>Atari</studio>
    <releasedate>27/05/1983</releasedate>
    <plot>There are two significantly different versions of Realsports Basketball for the Atari 5200, both programmed by Patrick Bass. This version is what would become the final version of the game, which seems fairly complete, including easter eggs. However, like the Atari 2600 game of the same name, Realsports Basketball was never released for sale. It's unknown why Atari programmed two different versions of the game.[CR]Sadly, Patrick Bass died in an automobile crash in 1998. Patrick's brother, Ben Bass, worked with Ken Van Mersbergen to ensure this final version of the game would be shared with the public.</plot>
    <genre>Sports</genre>
    <ESRB>ESRB - E (Everyone)</ESRB>
    <rating>3.5</rating>
    <boxart1>w0kTI6Y.png</boxart1>
    <clearlogo1>lUeDOfH.png</clearlogo1>
    <snapshot1>wGpKMqf.png</snapshot1>
    <boxart2>e3X6WyL.png</boxart2>
    <snapshot2>U5tkhhY.png</snapshot2>
    <boxart3>40bZJKg.png</boxart3>
    <snapshot10>tdxrdT9.png</snapshot10>
    <snapshot3>xG2PVE6.jpg</snapshot3>
    <snapshot4>pvZ3QfI.jpg</snapshot4>
    <snapshot5>I3CHsRU.jpg</snapshot5>
    <snapshot6>JTkrbag.jpg</snapshot6>
    <snapshot7>KCinu7a.jpg</snapshot7>
    <snapshot8>pXqa3yk.jpg</snapshot8>
    <snapshot9>K4rQf62.jpg</snapshot9>
  </game>
  <game name="RealSports Basketball (USA) (83-10-31) (Proto)">
    <description>RealSports Basketball (USA) (83-10-31) (Proto)</description>
    <title_clean>RealSports Basketball</title_clean>
    <rom name="no-intro-atari-5200-20130303/No-Intro%20-%20Atari%20-%205200%20%282013-03-03%29.zip/RealSports%20Basketball%20%28USA%29%20%2883-10-31%29%20%28Proto%29.zip" size="9448"/>
    <nplayers>2</nplayers>
    <studio>Atari</studio>
    <releasedate>27/05/1983</releasedate>
    <plot>There are two significantly different versions of Realsports Basketball for the Atari 5200, both programmed by Patrick Bass. This version is what would become the final version of the game, which seems fairly complete, including easter eggs. However, like the Atari 2600 game of the same name, Realsports Basketball was never released for sale. It's unknown why Atari programmed two different versions of the game.[CR]Sadly, Patrick Bass died in an automobile crash in 1998. Patrick's brother, Ben Bass, worked with Ken Van Mersbergen to ensure this final version of the game would be shared with the public.</plot>
    <genre>Sports</genre>
    <ESRB>ESRB - E (Everyone)</ESRB>
    <rating>3.5</rating>
    <boxart1>SOfWNRj.png</boxart1>
    <clearlogo1>lUeDOfH.png</clearlogo1>
    <snapshot1>ndUyLMr.png</snapshot1>
    <boxart2>e3X6WyL.png</boxart2>
    <snapshot2>xGvkilS.png</snapshot2>
    <boxart3>40bZJKg.png</boxart3>
    <snapshot10>tdxrdT9.png</snapshot10>
    <snapshot3>xG2PVE6.jpg</snapshot3>
    <snapshot4>pvZ3QfI.jpg</snapshot4>
    <snapshot5>I3CHsRU.jpg</snapshot5>
    <snapshot6>JTkrbag.jpg</snapshot6>
    <snapshot7>KCinu7a.jpg</snapshot7>
    <snapshot8>pXqa3yk.jpg</snapshot8>
    <snapshot9>K4rQf62.jpg</snapshot9>
  </game>
  <game name="RealSports Football (USA)">
    <description>RealSports Football (USA)</description>
    <title_clean>RealSports Football</title_clean>
    <rom name="no-intro-atari-5200-20130303/No-Intro%20-%20Atari%20-%205200%20%282013-03-03%29.zip/RealSports%20Football%20%28USA%29.zip" size="10493"/>
    <releasedate>18/10/1983</releasedate>
    <genre>Sports,Traditional,Football,Sim</genre>
    <gamefaqs_url>http://www.gamefaqs.com/atari5200/585344-realsports-football</gamefaqs_url>
    <plot>You're the quarterback on a 4th and goal situation. You gotta have this touchdown to win, but that defense is tough, real tough. You call a rollout pass. Good choice. Uh-oh, here comes that blitzing linebacker. Do you run or pass? Quick, decide! Ah, there, your receiver is free. Hurry, the clock's running out.</plot>
    <rating>2.50</rating>
    <nplayers>1-2</nplayers>
    <ESRB>ESRB - E (Everyone)</ESRB>
    <studio>Atari</studio>
    <boxart1>A3dUkFa.png</boxart1>
    <banner1>s3KIsb5.jpg</banner1>
    <clearlogo1>n64E0GY.png</clearlogo1>
    <snapshot1>rGAcFct.png</snapshot1>
    <boxart2>q5zP5fF.jpg</boxart2>
    <snapshot2>LTqIBlI.png</snapshot2>
    <boxart3>LRqDUFn.png</boxart3>
    <boxart4>4YI5aem.png</boxart4>
    <snapshot3>Y3F1rch.gif</snapshot3>
    <snapshot4>HLudo07.gif</snapshot4>
    <snapshot5>Q2tDVVZ.jpg</snapshot5>
    <snapshot6>yybHPxp.jpg</snapshot6>
    <snapshot7>vyBaQW6.jpg</snapshot7>
    <snapshot8>kQYdmJR.jpg</snapshot8>
    <snapshot9>EauTtMM.jpg</snapshot9>
  </game>
  <game name="RealSports Soccer (USA)">
    <description>RealSports Soccer (USA)</description>
    <title_clean>RealSports Soccer</title_clean>
    <rom name="no-intro-atari-5200-20130303/No-Intro%20-%20Atari%20-%205200%20%282013-03-03%29.zip/RealSports%20Soccer%20%28USA%29.zip" size="7082"/>
    <releasedate>18/10/1983</releasedate>
    <genre>Sports,Traditional,Soccer,Sim</genre>
    <gamefaqs_url>http://www.gamefaqs.com/atari5200/585345-realsports-soccer</gamefaqs_url>
    <plot>Hi, soccer fans! Here's Atari's new life-like three-dimensional SOCCER with the most exciting games you'll ever experience outside a stadium. Beat the computer, trounce the visiting team, or cheer from the stands as the computer plays against itself in Auto-Play mode. Halves last from 5 to 45 minutes and there are 4 skill levels.</plot>
    <nplayers>2</nplayers>
    <studio>Atari</studio>
    <year>1983</year>
    <ESRB>ESRB - E (Everyone)</ESRB>
    <rating>2.4</rating>
    <boxart1>n3FziHR.png</boxart1>
    <banner1>v82PHFZ.jpg</banner1>
    <clearlogo1>nTtlRFy.png</clearlogo1>
    <snapshot1>2wA09ec.png</snapshot1>
    <boxart2>QU1psxa.jpg</boxart2>
    <snapshot2>Vh5GOQZ.png</snapshot2>
    <boxart3>ynHuolD.png</boxart3>
    <boxart4>gzXWQZF.png</boxart4>
    <videoid>O4tmBJ26Kjc</videoid>
    <snapshot3>xnccYCM.gif</snapshot3>
    <snapshot4>GeNdcdT.gif</snapshot4>
    <snapshot5>G3AmIuU.png</snapshot5>
    <snapshot6>fm7HQiP.png</snapshot6>
    <snapshot7>cknczjz.png</snapshot7>
    <snapshot8>iu4vIHc.jpg</snapshot8>
    <snapshot9>MvWBQIh.png</snapshot9>
  </game>
  <game name="RealSports Tennis (USA)">
    <description>RealSports Tennis (USA)</description>
    <title_clean>RealSports Tennis</title_clean>
    <rom name="no-intro-atari-5200-20130303/No-Intro%20-%20Atari%20-%205200%20%282013-03-03%29.zip/RealSports%20Tennis%20%28USA%29.zip" size="6535"/>
    <releasedate>18/10/1983</releasedate>
    <genre>Sports,Traditional,Tennis</genre>
    <gamefaqs_url>http://www.gamefaqs.com/atari5200/585346-realsports-tennis</gamefaqs_url>
    <plot>Your name's on the scoreboard and the ball's in your court. It's Atari RealSports TENNIS - with real tennis game play and lifelike players. Play slow or high speed against a friend. Then - if you dare - play against the computer for the challenge of your life!</plot>
    <nplayers>2</nplayers>
    <studio>Atari</studio>
    <year>1983</year>
    <ESRB>ESRB - E (Everyone)</ESRB>
    <rating>2.1</rating>
    <boxart1>HFrHZiW.png</boxart1>
    <banner1>JFPaYAW.jpg</banner1>
    <clearlogo1>2TdTcxD.png</clearlogo1>
    <snapshot1>cTnl8hU.png</snapshot1>
    <boxart2>SHmvrES.jpg</boxart2>
    <snapshot2>5uebfRH.png</snapshot2>
    <boxart3>BhrFpk0.png</boxart3>
    <boxart4>bmSq7XS.png</boxart4>
    <snapshot3>RbUv50E.gif</snapshot3>
    <snapshot4>ggD7Xgy.jpg</snapshot4>
    <snapshot5>ufMhziP.jpg</snapshot5>
    <snapshot6>9lvTFrP.jpg</snapshot6>
    <snapshot7>oyipk6c.jpg</snapshot7>
    <snapshot8>gGF6tcr.jpg</snapshot8>
    <snapshot9>T8IgXvR.jpg</snapshot9>
  </game>
  <game name="Rescue on Fractalus! (USA)">
    <description>Rescue on Fractalus! (USA)</description>
    <title_clean>Rescue on Fractalus!</title_clean>
    <rom name="no-intro-atari-5200-20130303/No-Intro%20-%20Atari%20-%205200%20%282013-03-03%29.zip/Rescue%20on%20Fractalus%21%20%28USA%29.zip" size="24397"/>
    <releasedate>18/10/1986</releasedate>
    <genre>Action,General</genre>
    <gamefaqs_url>http://www.gamefaqs.com/atari5200/585347-rescue-on-fractalus</gamefaqs_url>
    <plot>The game utilizes fractal technology to create the craggy mountains of an alien planet, where the visilibility was drastically reduced by the dense atmosphere. The player controls a fictional "Valkyrie" space fighter[2] (converted for search and rescue duty) from a first-person view, attempting to land and pick up downed Ethercorps pilots. Some of these mountains hold anti-aircraft guns, which have to be avoided or destroyed. Due to the varied terrain, the direction finder has to be used to locate the pilots, whose visual beacons are often masked by mountain ridges.[CR]At higher levels, the enemy Jaggis begin flying kamikaze saucers. The mission area also moves into day/night boundaries. Night missions are particularly difficult, requiring diligent use of the altimeter to avoid crashing.[CR]Flying consumes fuel. The way to replenish this supply is to rescue downed pilots who bring their remaining fuel supplies on board.</plot>
    <rating>0.50</rating>
    <nplayers>1</nplayers>
    <studio>Atari</studio>
    <ESRB>ESRB - E (Everyone)</ESRB>
    <boxart1>gJlpiOG.png</boxart1>
    <banner1>BCTvNZN.jpg</banner1>
    <clearlogo1>JELU34v.png</clearlogo1>
    <snapshot1>HYZQfqx.png</snapshot1>
    <boxart2>biD0QZU.jpg</boxart2>
    <snapshot2>srb1ncq.png</snapshot2>
    <boxart3>XaYgJpv.png</boxart3>
    <boxart4>G7BN7jk.png</boxart4>
    <snapshot3>J6xwpKd.gif</snapshot3>
    <snapshot4>Du6MYRb.gif</snapshot4>
    <snapshot5>KEelNAz.gif</snapshot5>
    <snapshot6>bzYe9sQ.gif</snapshot6>
    <snapshot7>781kxQa.gif</snapshot7>
    <snapshot8>Z0shj9U.jpg</snapshot8>
    <snapshot9>wn3idtO.jpg</snapshot9>
  </game>
  <game name="Road Runner (USA) (Proto)">
    <description>Road Runner (USA) (Proto)</description>
    <title_clean>Road Runner</title_clean>
    <rom name="no-intro-atari-5200-20130303/No-Intro%20-%20Atari%20-%205200%20%282013-03-03%29.zip/Road%20Runner%20%28USA%29%20%28Proto%29.zip" size="7673"/>
    <nplayers>1</nplayers>
    <studio>Atari</studio>
    <releasedate>03/06/1983</releasedate>
    <plot>An unreleased prototype game staring the popular Road Runner cartoon character. Thought to have been based on perhaps a port of the arcade game Locomotion before being re skinned with Roadrunner and Wiley E Coyote.[CR]At the start of each level a birdseed truck will weave its way through the maze dropping off piles of birdseed as it goes.  The goal of Roadrunner is to move the tiles around so Wiley Coyote eats as much birdseed as he can before the Roadrunner gets it.  Each tile contains a portion of the road which Wiley and the Roadrunner walk on, by sliding the tiles around you can make paths leading to the piles of birdseed or to the tunnels on the side of the board.  The tunnels connect one side of the screen to the other, and can be useful for warping across the screen.  Unfortunately some of these tunnel entrances are really just painted on, so if Wiley attempts to enter one he'll knock himself out.  The only way to tell if a tunnel is real is to watch the Roadrunner and see which tunnels he takes.[CR]Wiley can die if he either runs off the end of the tile or runs into a false tunnel.  The Roadrunner appears to be able to back up from dead end track pieces and tunnels so he is impossible to kill, but you can trap him on two dead end pieces and complete the level at your leisure.  Once all the birdseed is gone the game moves to the next level.  If you happen to run into the Roadrunner you will score 10 points, and you the Roadrunner will be transported back to your starting points.  Wiley also scores 35 points for each tile he crosses, and 50 points for each pile of birdseed he collects.[CR]- Excerpt from AtariProtos.com</plot>
    <genre>Action, Puzzle</genre>
    <boxart1>yroTi4U.png</boxart1>
    <clearlogo1>TwIx7Rh.png</clearlogo1>
    <snapshot1>pqar9TU.png</snapshot1>
    <snapshot2>bjsRAUg.png</snapshot2>
    <videoid>hBz7-YfqosA</videoid>
  </game>
  <game name="Robotron 2084 (USA)">
    <description>Robotron 2084 (USA)</description>
    <title_clean>Robotron 2084</title_clean>
    <rom name="no-intro-atari-5200-20130303/No-Intro%20-%20Atari%20-%205200%20%282013-03-03%29.zip/Robotron%202084%20%28USA%29.zip" size="10950"/>
    <releasedate>18/10/1983</releasedate>
    <genre>Action,Shooter,Static</genre>
    <gamefaqs_url>http://www.gamefaqs.com/atari5200/585350-robotron-2084</gamefaqs_url>
    <plot>You are a mutant human, who by some freak of nature has the ability to shoot energy pulses from his body in eight different directions! Your job is simple: save humanity from their own creation -- the ROBOTRONS! The gameplay is pretty unique for the time. You can move and fire in any of eight directions. You get thrown in a room with various evil baddies strewn about, you've got to kill all the robots while at the same time finding some way to grab humans and avoid death.</plot>
    <studio>Atari</studio>
    <nplayers>1-2</nplayers>
    <ESRB>ESRB - E (Everyone)</ESRB>
    <rating>3.9</rating>
    <boxart1>HAZ21vc.png</boxart1>
    <snapshot1>EnqYgOP.png</snapshot1>
    <snapshot2>MZqcF7K.png</snapshot2>
    <banner1>cT0Wrz6.jpg</banner1>
    <boxart2>cjO17IQ.jpg</boxart2>
    <boxart3>75n7ZhI.jpg</boxart3>
    <clearlogo1>zq1zq04.png</clearlogo1>
    <snapshot10>2jcM5N0.png</snapshot10>
    <snapshot3>cWiER5h.gif</snapshot3>
    <snapshot4>BSQt1K4.gif</snapshot4>
    <snapshot5>FYrbc9s.gif</snapshot5>
    <snapshot6>bbXmaEu.png</snapshot6>
    <snapshot7>81ZXIzp.png</snapshot7>
    <snapshot8>yvkLA2f.png</snapshot8>
    <snapshot9>cVeXPNU.png</snapshot9>
  </game>
  <game name="Space Dungeon (USA)">
    <description>Space Dungeon (USA)</description>
    <title_clean>Space Dungeon</title_clean>
    <rom name="no-intro-atari-5200-20130303/No-Intro%20-%20Atari%20-%205200%20%282013-03-03%29.zip/Space%20Dungeon%20%28USA%29.zip" size="10866"/>
    <releasedate>18/10/1983</releasedate>
    <genre>Action,General</genre>
    <gamefaqs_url>http://www.gamefaqs.com/atari5200/585352-space-dungeon</gamefaqs_url>
    <plot>At last! Dual joystick action at home. Enjoy all the exciting arcade game--SPACE DUNGEON. Search for treasure in the antechambers of outer space. Keep that laser cannon blasting away at all times. Deep space is full of cosmic enemies, all quite determined that you never get back alive!</plot>
    <rating>4.00</rating>
    <studio>Atari</studio>
    <nplayers>1-2</nplayers>
    <ESRB>ESRB - E (Everyone)</ESRB>
    <boxart1>98PuOph.png</boxart1>
    <banner1>blEIIUc.jpg</banner1>
    <clearlogo1>6KudPj0.png</clearlogo1>
    <snapshot1>ySzP7dJ.png</snapshot1>
    <boxart2>7pIcax2.jpg</boxart2>
    <snapshot2>uWpHdY5.png</snapshot2>
    <boxart3>5nW9mEX.png</boxart3>
    <boxart4>CSNJ5hX.png</boxart4>
    <snapshot10>so9gWLb.png</snapshot10>
    <snapshot3>wZNon8d.gif</snapshot3>
    <snapshot4>ZygjUT5.gif</snapshot4>
    <snapshot5>oN3fFyf.gif</snapshot5>
    <snapshot6>eWgYqYN.gif</snapshot6>
    <snapshot7>CS1FcWf.gif</snapshot7>
    <snapshot8>DL0mcRO.png</snapshot8>
    <snapshot9>eBNCh2O.png</snapshot9>
  </game>
  <game name="Space Invaders (USA)">
    <description>Space Invaders (USA)</description>
    <title_clean>Space Invaders</title_clean>
    <rom name="no-intro-atari-5200-20130303/No-Intro%20-%20Atari%20-%205200%20%282013-03-03%29.zip/Space%20Invaders%20%28USA%29.zip" size="5616"/>
    <releasedate>18/10/1982</releasedate>
    <genre>Action,Shooter,Static</genre>
    <gamefaqs_url>http://www.gamefaqs.com/atari5200/585353-space-invaders</gamefaqs_url>
    <plot>Space Invaders is a game in which the player controls a laser cannon by moving it horizontally across the bottom of the screen and firing at descending aliens. [CR]The aim is to defeat five rows of eleven aliens--some versions feature different numbers--that move horizontally back and forth across the screen as they advance towards the bottom of the screen. The player defeats an alien, and earns points, by shooting it with the laser cannon. As more aliens are defeated, the aliens' movement and the game's music both speed up.</plot>
    <rating>3.00</rating>
    <nplayers>2</nplayers>
    <studio>Atari</studio>
    <ESRB>ESRB - E (Everyone)</ESRB>
    <boxart1>5c8DJR8.png</boxart1>
    <banner1>VyclfZo.jpg</banner1>
    <clearlogo1>cKZhYik.png</clearlogo1>
    <snapshot1>PykAV1h.png</snapshot1>
    <boxart2>5abUyJO.jpg</boxart2>
    <snapshot2>2YsJUFV.png</snapshot2>
    <boxart3>T3IVdtt.png</boxart3>
    <videoid>qBDW3IervjI</videoid>
    <snapshot10>9lsjQIg.jpg</snapshot10>
    <snapshot3>utjfmrb.gif</snapshot3>
    <snapshot4>aasToVP.gif</snapshot4>
    <snapshot5>OOQlN3X.gif</snapshot5>
    <snapshot6>UXyXmsE.gif</snapshot6>
    <snapshot7>jV50Lhk.jpg</snapshot7>
    <snapshot8>PFAV9y7.jpg</snapshot8>
    <snapshot9>Y7CwWzv.jpg</snapshot9>
  </game>
  <game name="Space Shuttle - A Journey Into Space (USA)">
    <description>Space Shuttle - A Journey Into Space (USA)</description>
    <title_clean>Space Shuttle - A Journey Into Space</title_clean>
    <rom name="no-intro-atari-5200-20130303/No-Intro%20-%20Atari%20-%205200%20%282013-03-03%29.zip/Space%20Shuttle%20-%20A%20Journey%20Into%20Space%20%28USA%29.zip" size="11779"/>
    <releasedate>18/10/1984</releasedate>
    <genre>Action,General</genre>
    <gamefaqs_url>http://www.gamefaqs.com/atari5200/585354-space-shuttle</gamefaqs_url>
    <plot>Up.Straight up. Soaring. Goodbye Earth. Blast away boosters. Open cargo bay doors. And rest, just for a second.Time to tackle orbital mechanics. Try to rendezvous with an elusive satellite. Now you see it, now you don't. Finally: contact.Then down.Nice and easy. Deorbit. Down through the atmosphere to land back home.A simulation designed after consultation with NASA. The controls, the animation and the decision-making make this flight absolutely first class.Take it.</plot>
    <rating>3.00</rating>
    <studio>Activision</studio>
    <nplayers>1</nplayers>
    <ESRB>ESRB - E (Everyone)</ESRB>
    <boxart1>8fmUCqd.png</boxart1>
    <banner1>gx1pUa6.jpg</banner1>
    <clearlogo1>OcGwnpd.png</clearlogo1>
    <snapshot1>acpMk6H.png</snapshot1>
    <boxart2>mpk2Lia.jpg</boxart2>
    <snapshot2>YylPVGq.png</snapshot2>
    <boxart3>ddepjjN.png</boxart3>
    <snapshot3>fmZIJBH.gif</snapshot3>
  </game>
  <game name="Spitfire (USA) (Proto)">
    <description>Spitfire (USA) (Proto)</description>
    <title_clean>Spitfire</title_clean>
    <rom name="no-intro-atari-5200-20130303/No-Intro%20-%20Atari%20-%205200%20%282013-03-03%29.zip/Spitfire%20%28USA%29%20%28Proto%29.zip" size="11174"/>
    <boxart1>rlxg850.png</boxart1>
    <snapshot1>crhPrBc.png</snapshot1>
    <snapshot2>qeZQBw8.png</snapshot2>
    <ESRB>E - Everyone</ESRB>
    <genre>Shooter</genre>
    <nplayers>1</nplayers>
    <plot>Of all the prototypes that have passed through my hands over the years, Spitfire is definitely one of the strangest.  Part Zaxxon and part Star Raiders, Spitfire appears to have been Atari's first attempt into the realm of 3D shooters.  While the current known prototype may not be very complete (approx. 50%), it shows that the 5200 was indeed capable of 3D graphics.[CR]According to the dictionary, a Spitfire is a plane from World War II.  From the name of the game one would expect at WWII simulation game, but instead Spitfire is actually a Zaxxon style game with some elements of Star Raiders thrown in.  From the first screen it's obvious that the programmer was keen on 3D as all the text is in the same 3D style.  After selecting a skill level (0-2) with the * key, you are presented with the game map.[CR]The game map appears as a grid of 20x13 octagons (that's 260 octagons!).  While this may look a bit overwhelming, only the first three rows of octagons are ever used.  While the units may be spaced out over the map, this doesn't make any difference since your target is selected with the * key (perhaps you may have had to fly to your target in later versions?).  After selecting a target its statistics will be displayed in the status bar at the bottom of the screen.  In addition to the size of the target (Very Small, Small, Large, or Very Large), the status bar displays the possible elements on that target.</plot>
    <releasedate>01/01/1983</releasedate>
    <studio>Atari</studio>
  </game>
  <game name="Sport Goofy (USA) (Proto)">
    <description>Sport Goofy (USA) (Proto)</description>
    <title_clean>Sport Goofy</title_clean>
    <rom name="no-intro-atari-5200-20130303/No-Intro%20-%20Atari%20-%205200%20%282013-03-03%29.zip/Sport%20Goofy%20%28USA%29%20%28Proto%29.zip" size="9495"/>
    <nplayers>2</nplayers>
    <studio>Atari</studio>
    <releasedate>15/06/1983</releasedate>
    <plot>An unreleased prototype for the Atari 5200. You take control of goofy as he competes in two events, the Marathon Dive and the Pogo Pop.[CR]The Marathon Dive is a game in which you must guide Goofy up a series of platforms so he can reach the diving platform and jump off before the timer runs out.  As Goofy climbs up the platforms he must avoid little armored tanks, which will chase Goofy around.  Thankfully these tanks can't jump, reverse direction, or use the ladders, so they can be avoided by jumping over them or leading them into a hole (which will cause them to fall down to the next level).  Also hindering Goofy's progress are large gaps in the platforms which must be carefully jumped over.  If Goofy falls through a hole he'll fall down one level but is otherwise unharmed, however if he is hit by a tank he'll loose a life.[CR] [CR]If Goofy makes it to the top of the platform he will run off the end, making it about halfway across the screen before realizing that he's running in mid-air.  Now Goofy will begin to fall, and you must guide him down to the little floating platform below.  However the floating platform is constantly moving in an erratic fashion, so hitting it can be tough.  If you successfully reach the platform, Goofy will smash into it and have his parachute open a second too late (in typical cartoon fashion).  If you miss the platform Goofy will fall into the water and drown (I guess he doesn't know how to swim).  As the levels progress the tanks will begin to move faster and faster, the diving platform has more holes in it, and the floating platform moves more erratically.  Eventually the difficulty will wrap around however, and the game will get very easy again.[CR]Pogo Pop takes place on a series of squares where Goofy bounces up and down on a pogo stick in an effort to touch every tile.  This may sound easy but there's a catch, every time you jump one of the tiles disappears, so the tile that was below you may not be there when you land.  As the levels progress the frequency of the tiles disappearing increases, making it harder and harder not to fall through the floor.  [CR] [CR]While you're jumping on tiles you can attempt to pop the Mickey Mouse balloons floating above you for extra points.  The balloons come in several different colors and are worth a varying amount of points.</plot>
    <genre>Action, Sports</genre>
    <boxart1>d4gfB9J.png</boxart1>
    <snapshot1>1nBIL1z.png</snapshot1>
    <boxart2>1yzONPv.png</boxart2>
    <snapshot2>c5MqLwW.png</snapshot2>
    <videoid>khYbKE34oqU</videoid>
  </game>
  <game name="Star Raiders (USA)">
    <description>Star Raiders (USA)</description>
    <title_clean>Star Raiders</title_clean>
    <rom name="no-intro-atari-5200-20130303/No-Intro%20-%20Atari%20-%205200%20%282013-03-03%29.zip/Star%20Raiders%20%28USA%29.zip" size="7285"/>
    <releasedate>18/10/1982</releasedate>
    <genre>Simulation,Sci-Fi,Small Spaceship</genre>
    <gamefaqs_url>http://www.gamefaqs.com/atari5200/585357-star-raiders</gamefaqs_url>
    <plot>The code name for this operation is WIPEOUT. Seek out and destroy the Zylons." These are the orders you have been given by Commander Champion of the Star Raiders. This first-person style space combat sim tests your nerve and stamina as you seek to destroy all the Zylons in the galaxy before they destroy the Federation starbases.[CR]The game may be played at four different difficulty levels. The difficulty level varies the number of starbases you must protect and the number of enemy ships that must be defeated. At higher difficulty levels, your starship is more susceptible to damage and more difficult to control.</plot>
    <studio>Atari</studio>
    <nplayers>1</nplayers>
    <ESRB>ESRB - E (Everyone)</ESRB>
    <rating>3.6</rating>
    <boxart1>r9xUPYf.png</boxart1>
    <snapshot1>efagitA.png</snapshot1>
    <snapshot2>47yZZ6J.png</snapshot2>
    <banner1>B1iGlrm.jpg</banner1>
    <boxart2>M5D92Nk.jpg</boxart2>
    <boxart3>G8tZ16s.jpg</boxart3>
    <snapshot10>9ZT3ubE.png</snapshot10>
    <snapshot3>oKgPR7g.gif</snapshot3>
    <snapshot4>BBEBKPB.gif</snapshot4>
    <snapshot5>PnZjtt3.gif</snapshot5>
    <snapshot6>g3in1GA.gif</snapshot6>
    <snapshot7>Z8qLSFT.gif</snapshot7>
    <snapshot8>6SW0AIk.png</snapshot8>
    <snapshot9>hijtSvM.png</snapshot9>
  </game>
  <game name="Star Trek - Strategic Operations Simulator (USA)">
    <description>Star Trek - Strategic Operations Simulator (USA)</description>
    <title_clean>Star Trek - Strategic Operations Simulator</title_clean>
    <rom name="no-intro-atari-5200-20130303/No-Intro%20-%20Atari%20-%205200%20%282013-03-03%29.zip/Star%20Trek%20-%20Strategic%20Operations%20Simulator%20%28USA%29.zip" size="10494"/>
    <releasedate>18/10/1983</releasedate>
    <genre>Action,Shooter,Scrolling</genre>
    <gamefaqs_url>http://www.gamefaqs.com/atari5200/585358-star-trek</gamefaqs_url>
    <plot>Now you can command the fate of the U.S.S. Enterprise in this home version of the hit arcade game. You're training to become a Federation Starship Captain. Fight off deadly Klingon Battle Cruisers that threaten the existence of your Starbases. Skillfully navigate through perilous asteroid fields and comet storms. Prepare to encounter the most powerful enemy of them all: Nomad! Hours of challenge await you, if you date to venture where no home video game has ever dared to go...</plot>
    <rating>1.00</rating>
    <studio>Sega</studio>
    <nplayers>1</nplayers>
    <ESRB>ESRB - E (Everyone)</ESRB>
    <boxart1>WImS4uo.png</boxart1>
    <banner1>VQN0UuZ.jpg</banner1>
    <clearlogo1>NmxnEqu.png</clearlogo1>
    <snapshot1>IaN1mqu.png</snapshot1>
    <boxart2>UKGdgHk.jpg</boxart2>
    <snapshot2>bqZAKpg.png</snapshot2>
    <boxart3>4ddWbNF.png</boxart3>
  </game>
  <game name="Star Wars - Return of the Jedi - Death Star Battle (USA)">
    <description>Star Wars - Return of the Jedi - Death Star Battle (USA)</description>
    <title_clean>Star Wars - Return of the Jedi - Death Star Battle</title_clean>
    <rom name="no-intro-atari-5200-20130303/No-Intro%20-%20Atari%20-%205200%20%282013-03-03%29.zip/Star%20Wars%20-%20Return%20of%20the%20Jedi%20-%20Death%20Star%20Battle%20%28USA%29.zip" size="6534"/>
    <releasedate>18/10/1983</releasedate>
    <genre>Action,General</genre>
    <gamefaqs_url>http://www.gamefaqs.com/atari5200/585359-star-wars-death-star-battle</gamefaqs_url>
    <plot>Death Star Battle is loosely based on the events of the film Star Wars Episode VI: Return of the Jedi. Your task is to destroy the Death Star before its construction is finished. You start the task outside the shield perimeter of the Death Star. There you'll have to combat different imperial vessels and avoid the death ray while waiting for an opportunity to slip through one of the random openings in the energy shield. After reaching the Death Star you must reduce its structure up to the point where you can hit the core. In the following destruction of the station you must avoid collision with Death Star debris.</plot>
    <rating>5.00</rating>
    <nplayers>1</nplayers>
    <studio>Parker Brothers</studio>
    <ESRB>ESRB - E (Everyone)</ESRB>
    <boxart1>y8ET6ah.png</boxart1>
    <clearlogo1>esieHl7.png</clearlogo1>
    <snapshot1>P81qycX.png</snapshot1>
    <boxart2>RhD8jha.jpg</boxart2>
    <snapshot2>S2jwDNl.png</snapshot2>
    <boxart3>RB9YMyW.png</boxart3>
    <boxart4>TgN9pqk.png</boxart4>
    <snapshot3>W6JXZMt.gif</snapshot3>
    <snapshot4>KM6Heje.gif</snapshot4>
    <snapshot5>ANTch15.png</snapshot5>
  </game>
  <game name="Star Wars - The Arcade Game (USA)">
    <description>Star Wars - The Arcade Game (USA)</description>
    <title_clean>Star Wars - The Arcade Game</title_clean>
    <rom name="no-intro-atari-5200-20130303/No-Intro%20-%20Atari%20-%205200%20%282013-03-03%29.zip/Star%20Wars%20-%20The%20Arcade%20Game%20%28USA%29.zip" size="11423"/>
    <releasedate>18/10/1983</releasedate>
    <genre>Action,General</genre>
    <gamefaqs_url>http://www.gamefaqs.com/atari5200/585360-star-wars-the-arcade-game</gamefaqs_url>
    <plot>You're at the controls of LUKE's X-WING FIGHTER, heading straight for the DEATH STAR. Your mission: to destroy it before the EMPIRE seeks its revenge on the REBEL base. Lock your sights on attacking TIE FIGHTERS and blast them with your proton torpedoes. Race along the DEATH STAR's surface, firing on giant towers. Finally, dive full throttle into the DEATH STAR's equatorial trench. You'll need split-second timing to avoid all the obstacles as you streak through the trench in search of the main reactor. Hit it and you've blown the DEATH STAR out of existence! MAY THE FORCE BE WITH YOU.</plot>
    <studio>Parker Brothers</studio>
    <nplayers>1</nplayers>
    <ESRB>ESRB - E (Everyone)</ESRB>
    <rating>2.1</rating>
    <boxart1>mcH0Wnd.png</boxart1>
    <clearlogo1>TFQS29F.png</clearlogo1>
    <snapshot1>MjWE4p2.png</snapshot1>
    <boxart2>y1LlKMq.jpg</boxart2>
    <snapshot2>kb8W7Ng.png</snapshot2>
    <boxart3>9kB3GNx.png</boxart3>
    <videoid>iWYjXnP8aw4</videoid>
    <snapshot10>23HxqPl.png</snapshot10>
    <snapshot3>JkWk2lA.gif</snapshot3>
    <snapshot4>JSiqBbR.gif</snapshot4>
    <snapshot5>eqb44gF.png</snapshot5>
    <snapshot6>aLteYPD.png</snapshot6>
    <snapshot7>MsMZSCU.png</snapshot7>
    <snapshot8>0NeecN7.png</snapshot8>
    <snapshot9>s5GgJX2.png</snapshot9>
  </game>
  <game name="Stargate (USA) (Proto)">
    <description>Stargate (USA) (Proto)</description>
    <title_clean>Stargate</title_clean>
    <rom name="no-intro-atari-5200-20130303/No-Intro%20-%20Atari%20-%205200%20%282013-03-03%29.zip/Stargate%20%28USA%29%20%28Proto%29.zip" size="11455"/>
    <nplayers>2</nplayers>
    <studio>Atari</studio>
    <releasedate>05/01/1984</releasedate>
    <plot>An unreleased prototype port of the popular Williams game Stargate.[CR]The sequel to Defender and much like the arcade game you fly around blasting aliens and trying to survive long enough to save humanoids. You also have a Hyperspace button that can teleport you to a random area which can be good or bad. Also new in Stargate was an Inviso button that would cloak your fighter for a limited time.</plot>
    <genre>Shooter</genre>
    <boxart1>pdHN6Kn.png</boxart1>
    <clearlogo1>LzM3CvF.png</clearlogo1>
    <snapshot1>cLvMjtU.png</snapshot1>
    <boxart2>fXHcfN2.png</boxart2>
    <snapshot2>zHkIeOA.png</snapshot2>
    <videoid>wXMrd2BjkJQ</videoid>
  </game>
  <game name="Super Breakout (USA)">
    <description>Super Breakout (USA)</description>
    <title_clean>Super Breakout</title_clean>
    <rom name="no-intro-atari-5200-20130303/No-Intro%20-%20Atari%20-%205200%20%282013-03-03%29.zip/Super%20Breakout%20%28USA%29.zip" size="3225"/>
    <releasedate>18/10/1982</releasedate>
    <genre>Action,General</genre>
    <gamefaqs_url>http://www.gamefaqs.com/atari5200/585362-super-breakout</gamefaqs_url>
    <plot>In Super Breakout, there are three different and more advanced game types from which the player can choose:[CR]Double gives the player control of two bats at the same time--one placed above the other--and two balls. Losing a life occurs only when both balls go out of play, and points are doubled while the player is able to juggle both balls without losing either.[CR]Cavity retains the single bat and ball of Breakout, but two other balls are enclosed on the other side of the wall, which the player must free before they, too, can be used to destroy additional bricks. Points are increased for this, but triple points are available if the player can keep all three balls in play.[CR]Progressive also has the single bat and ball, but as the ball hits the paddle, the entire wall gradually advances downwards step by step, gaining in speed the longer the ball lasts in play.</plot>
    <rating>5.00</rating>
    <nplayers>2</nplayers>
    <studio>Atari</studio>
    <ESRB>ESRB - E (Everyone)</ESRB>
    <boxart1>gD3DLXo.png</boxart1>
    <clearlogo1>lJ9yftP.png</clearlogo1>
    <snapshot1>wpEIAVL.png</snapshot1>
    <boxart2>u195sg2.jpg</boxart2>
    <snapshot2>cWPwYlN.png</snapshot2>
    <boxart3>QgVXxwq.png</boxart3>
    <snapshot3>oyAyVcY.gif</snapshot3>
    <snapshot4>jlBkIEw.gif</snapshot4>
    <snapshot5>sEo3al7.gif</snapshot5>
    <snapshot6>QZenNtM.png</snapshot6>
    <snapshot7>PiOinZU.jpg</snapshot7>
    <snapshot8>F4IDWRz.jpg</snapshot8>
  </game>
  <game name="Super Cobra (USA)">
    <description>Super Cobra (USA)</description>
    <title_clean>Super Cobra</title_clean>
    <rom name="no-intro-atari-5200-20130303/No-Intro%20-%20Atari%20-%205200%20%282013-03-03%29.zip/Super%20Cobra%20%28USA%29.zip" size="6320"/>
    <releasedate>18/10/1983</releasedate>
    <genre>Action,Shooter,Scrolling</genre>
    <gamefaqs_url>http://www.gamefaqs.com/atari5200/585363-super-cobra</gamefaqs_url>
    <plot>The player controls a helicopter and has to guide it across a scrolling terrain, battling obstacles along the way. The player uses a joystick to accelerate, decelerate, move up, and move down. The ship uses a laser and bomb to destroy defenders, tanks, and UFO's while infiletrating 10 Super Cobra defense systems.[CR]The ship has a limited fuel supply, which is depleted over time. More fuel can be acquired by destroying fuel tanks in the game.[CR]The game is divided into ten sections, plus a finale, each with a different style of terrain and different obstacles. Players navigate through ten levels and a base, where they must safely make it through the level and safely remove the booty. The levels are described as follows,[CR]Player must maneuver the chopper over mountainous terrain against fast and slow firing rockets.[CR]Chopper faces Arcing missiles over a mountain terrain.[CR]Smart Bombs flying in groups of four over mountainous terrain. Rockets appear, but do not fire.[CR]Single Smart Bombs over mountainous terrain. Again, Rockets appear, but do not fire.[CR]Chopper flies through a cavern-like terrain against falling mines.[CR]Rapidly firing, roving tanks over mountainous terrain. Rockets appear, but do not fire.[CR]Maneuver through a field of meteors which explode when hit with bombs or 3 times with laser, plus a single, green, shadow meteor directly in front of chopper which explodes when hit five times with laser. Rockets appear but do not fire.[CR]Chopper flies over mountainous terrain against rapidly firing UFOs. Tanks and rockets appear, but do not fire.[CR]Chopper faces arcing missiles over tall buildings.[CR]Firing rockets in a building maze.[CR]Base: Player must maneuver the chopper over tall buildings against arcing missiles and rapidly firing tanks to reach the Booty and safely carry it away.[CR]There is no intermission between each section; the game simply scrolls into the new terrain. If the player destroys the booty on the final level, they must start back at the beginning of the level.</plot>
    <rating>1.50</rating>
    <nplayers>1</nplayers>
    <studio>Parker Bros</studio>
    <ESRB>ESRB - E (Everyone)</ESRB>
    <boxart1>VGmbpGB.png</boxart1>
    <banner1>5Clg4Ds.jpg</banner1>
    <clearlogo1>fvEmcBc.png</clearlogo1>
    <snapshot1>N1XL8mN.png</snapshot1>
    <boxart2>WAF0lnR.jpg</boxart2>
    <snapshot2>0cRoKZa.png</snapshot2>
    <boxart3>dwHIajH.png</boxart3>
    <snapshot10>jClbxtG.jpg</snapshot10>
    <snapshot3>GUlE7bi.gif</snapshot3>
    <snapshot4>upRRJCf.gif</snapshot4>
    <snapshot5>ybt2XBk.gif</snapshot5>
    <snapshot6>70MFEAt.jpg</snapshot6>
    <snapshot7>O43TavE.jpg</snapshot7>
    <snapshot8>BsLnzZ1.jpg</snapshot8>
    <snapshot9>cVtWgQq.jpg</snapshot9>
  </game>
  <game name="Super Pac-Man (USA) (Proto)">
    <description>Super Pac-Man (USA) (Proto)</description>
    <title_clean>Super Pac-Man</title_clean>
    <rom name="no-intro-atari-5200-20130303/No-Intro%20-%20Atari%20-%205200%20%282013-03-03%29.zip/Super%20Pac-Man%20%28USA%29%20%28Proto%29.zip" size="11759"/>
    <studio>Atari</studio>
    <boxart1>M04hpCs.png</boxart1>
    <banner1>t7Dly2b.jpg</banner1>
    <clearlogo1>qZX3pG4.png</clearlogo1>
    <snapshot1>u60uxS5.png</snapshot1>
    <boxart2>JdGqI1B.jpg</boxart2>
    <snapshot2>vyMAsuV.png</snapshot2>
    <boxart3>QhG3SQ9.png</boxart3>
    <videoid>JYyt8T4rzp0</videoid>
  </game>
  <game name="Tempest (USA) (Proto)">
    <description>Tempest (USA) (Proto)</description>
    <title_clean>Tempest</title_clean>
    <rom name="no-intro-atari-5200-20130303/No-Intro%20-%20Atari%20-%205200%20%282013-03-03%29.zip/Tempest%20%28USA%29%20%28Proto%29.zip" size="7250"/>
    <plot>Tempest is a shooter using wire-frame graphics. Each Wireway is taken on in turn, and has a network of lines guiding the movement paths of both yourself and the aliens. You remain on the outside and keep shooting as the aliens move towards you. Any that reach the outside are fatal to touch, thus limiting your range of movement greatly if 2 or more achieve this. Some aliens move sideways - in dealing with these, plan ahead allowing for the time your shots to take to travel.</plot>
    <boxart1>sr3v2M2.png</boxart1>
    <banner1>xwdJMQJ.jpg</banner1>
    <clearlogo1>MGEzCqC.png</clearlogo1>
    <snapshot1>w8Uhu0d.png</snapshot1>
    <boxart2>I6PLRsl.jpg</boxart2>
    <snapshot2>Lw4MRpQ.png</snapshot2>
    <studio>Atari</studio>
  </game>
  <game name="Track and Field (USA) (Proto)">
    <description>Track and Field (USA) (Proto)</description>
    <title_clean>Track and Field</title_clean>
    <rom name="no-intro-atari-5200-20130303/No-Intro%20-%20Atari%20-%205200%20%282013-03-03%29.zip/Track%20and%20Field%20%28USA%29%20%28Proto%29.zip" size="11671"/>
    <rating>4.00</rating>
    <nplayers>2</nplayers>
    <releasedate>10/05/1984</releasedate>
    <plot>An unreleased prototype game for the Atari 5200 based on the popular arcade game. While it went unreleased it was ported and released for the Atari 8-Bit computers. Players take part in 6 events.[CR]100 Meter Dash - Running by quickly alternating button presses.[CR]Long jump - Running by alternating button press and correct timing for jump. Hold jump button to set angle (42 degrees is optimal).[CR]Javelin throw - Running by alternating button presses and then using action button correct timing for angle (43 degrees is optimal).[CR]110 Meter Hurdles - Running by alternating button presses and using action button to time hurdles[CR]Hammer throw - Spinning initiated by pressing a run button once and then correctly timed press of action button to choose angle (45 is optimal).[CR]High jump - Running (speed set by computer) and then action button must be held down to determine angle of jump. Once in the air, the run button can be rapidly pressed for additional height.[CR]Gameplay screenshot of the long jump event.[CR]In each event, there is a qualifying time or level that the player must achieve to advance to the next event; failing to qualify (in one heat for running events or three tries in the other events) will reduce the player's number of lives by one, but if none are present in his/her disposal, the game will end.</plot>
    <genre>Sports</genre>
    <boxart1>VkojYTs.png</boxart1>
    <clearlogo1>0WddLqv.png</clearlogo1>
    <snapshot1>udNykmu.png</snapshot1>
    <boxart2>1EGsfFa.png</boxart2>
    <snapshot2>yGs7C4K.png</snapshot2>
    <videoid>4BfPGbV5a-0 Apr</videoid>
    <studio>Atari</studio>
  </game>
  <game name="Vanguard (USA)">
    <description>Vanguard (USA)</description>
    <title_clean>Vanguard</title_clean>
    <rom name="no-intro-atari-5200-20130303/No-Intro%20-%20Atari%20-%205200%20%282013-03-03%29.zip/Vanguard%20%28USA%29.zip" size="13754"/>
    <releasedate>18/10/1984</releasedate>
    <genre>Action,Shooter,Scrolling</genre>
    <gamefaqs_url>http://www.gamefaqs.com/atari5200/585367-vanguard</gamefaqs_url>
    <plot>Vanguard for the Atari 5200 would be an exceptional port of the 1981 arcade game were it not for the control. While the coin-op has a four-button arrangement for aiming lasers, this version uses the joystick, meaning the ship fires in the same direction it is moving as long as the fire button is pressed. This is inexcusable, as each 5200 controller is equipped with four fire buttons (not to mention a keypad). As with many 5200 titles, this one responds sluggishly to the non-centering joysticks, making for a less enjoyable experience. Fans of the original will notice a couple of other differences between versions. The 5200's ship slows down when it fires and can be set to single shots or rapid fire in the options screen.</plot>
    <rating>3.50</rating>
    <nplayers>1</nplayers>
    <ESRB>ESRB - E (Everyone)</ESRB>
    <studio>Atari</studio>
    <boxart1>oJAg7B6.png</boxart1>
    <banner1>QseqR2d.jpg</banner1>
    <clearlogo1>8H3ZRtQ.png</clearlogo1>
    <snapshot1>cmaO2Ek.png</snapshot1>
    <boxart2>cXsK9Cp.jpg</boxart2>
    <snapshot2>UnMmej8.png</snapshot2>
    <boxart3>YVcvKAg.png</boxart3>
    <snapshot10>0mENzbi.png</snapshot10>
    <snapshot3>U3spj1Y.gif</snapshot3>
    <snapshot4>8u8Msq0.gif</snapshot4>
    <snapshot5>68PiGyi.gif</snapshot5>
    <snapshot6>fmWbMCH.gif</snapshot6>
    <snapshot7>vDgUCFE.gif</snapshot7>
    <snapshot8>9Qd44YS.gif</snapshot8>
    <snapshot9>ANbAWMQ.png</snapshot9>
  </game>
  <game name="Wizard of Wor (USA)">
    <description>Wizard of Wor (USA)</description>
    <title_clean>Wizard of Wor</title_clean>
    <rom name="no-intro-atari-5200-20130303/No-Intro%20-%20Atari%20-%205200%20%282013-03-03%29.zip/Wizard%20of%20Wor%20%28USA%29.zip" size="12158"/>
    <releasedate>18/10/1981</releasedate>
    <genre>Action,Shooter,Static</genre>
    <gamefaqs_url>http://www.gamefaqs.com/atari5200/585368-wizard-of-wor</gamefaqs_url>
    <plot>Trapped within the diabolical dungeons of the wicked Wizard, your elite squadron of Worriors must defeat his legion of weird Worlings!First come the fiendish Burwors. Then, the devilish Garwords and Thorwors, creatures who seem to vanish and reappear at will. If you're expert with your Laser Blaster and use your Radar Screen, you just might manage to stay alive long enough to get a shot at the winged Worluk and maybe even the Wizard himself! But beware, Worrior--his is a fight to the finish!Deeper and deeper into the Wizard's labyrinthrine mazes you'll descend...into the Arena and maybe even the Worlord Dungeons! Prove yourself worthy of that honor and you may make it into the Pit, the Wizard's most deadly dungeon with no lace to hid!</plot>
    <rating>4.00</rating>
    <studio>CBS</studio>
    <nplayers>1-2</nplayers>
    <ESRB>ESRB - E (Everyone)</ESRB>
    <boxart1>o3hO0JW.png</boxart1>
    <clearlogo1>Dus23of.png</clearlogo1>
    <snapshot1>vScQSY1.png</snapshot1>
    <fanart1>eZad5sx.jpg</fanart1>
    <boxart2>C7x0QqE.jpg</boxart2>
    <snapshot2>CQ7plwM.png</snapshot2>
    <boxart3>aflyYH7.png</boxart3>
    <snapshot3>r4hFBx9.gif</snapshot3>
    <snapshot4>MrDG7Qc.gif</snapshot4>
    <snapshot5>qAyo7A5.gif</snapshot5>
    <snapshot6>P6T89aa.jpg</snapshot6>
    <snapshot7>a9D3M9M.png</snapshot7>
  </game>
  <game name="Xari Arena (USA) (Proto)">
    <description>Xari Arena (USA) (Proto)</description>
    <title_clean>Xari Arena</title_clean>
    <rom name="no-intro-atari-5200-20130303/No-Intro%20-%20Atari%20-%205200%20%282013-03-03%29.zip/Xari%20Arena%20%28USA%29%20%28Proto%29.zip" size="11097"/>
    <nplayers>2</nplayers>
    <plot>An unreleased prototype game for the Atari 5200.[CR]Your goal is to destroy all the Xari's that come out of the well in the center of the screen before they can destroy all your blocks. You can use the joystick or the trackball controller.[CR] [CR]Each player resembles a hollow paddle (like a capsule), which you can move around your side of the screen.  Your paddle can catch and hold up to three fireballs (the little star looking things that the Xari's shoot), and each stored fireball allows you to destroy one Xari by running into it.  If you hit a Xari without any fireballs stored in your paddle, it is temporarily stunned and you cannot catch or deflect any shots for a few seconds.  If you already have three fireballs stored up, your paddle will start reflecting the fireballs back at the Xari's (a great tactic for those hard to reach guys that won't come near you) and at your partner (which is not so good).  You can choose to reflect shots even if you don't have three fireballs stored up by pressing the bottom controller button.[CR] [CR]If things start to get out of control you can activate your fire extinguisher (using the top controller button) to temporarily protect your blocks.  The fire extinguisher coats your blocks with foam and will destroy any shots that touch it.  the foam moves quickly down your blocks and only lasts for a few seconds so you have to use it wisely (like when fireballs get behind your blocks).  You get one new fire extinguisher each level, which can be stored for later use.</plot>
    <genre>Action</genre>
    <boxart1>DFKG26f.png</boxart1>
    <clearlogo1>k7CMQRn.png</clearlogo1>
    <snapshot1>1R6Z66l.png</snapshot1>
    <boxart2>I96Bbt5.png</boxart2>
    <snapshot2>gTkye5k.png</snapshot2>
    <boxart3>iwjFOYd.jpg</boxart3>
    <videoid>88d4-1dOMW0</videoid>
    <releasedate>20/09/1983</releasedate>
    <studio>Atari</studio>
  </game>
  <game name="Xevious (USA) (Proto)">
    <description>Xevious (USA) (Proto)</description>
    <title_clean>Xevious</title_clean>
    <rom name="no-intro-atari-5200-20130303/No-Intro%20-%20Atari%20-%205200%20%282013-03-03%29.zip/Xevious%20%28USA%29%20%28Proto%29.zip" size="15081"/>
    <nplayers>2</nplayers>
    <studio>Atari</studio>
    <releasedate>04/01/1984</releasedate>
    <plot>An unreleased prototype based on the popular Namco shooting game.[CR]It's a nightmare, but it's true.  Scientific research has determined that we are the actual aliens on Earth and the evil Xevions are the original inhabitants.  Now the Xevions want Earth back. minus the humans! Earth's last hope is an experimental fighter plane known as the Solvalou.  The mission is dangerous, success isn't guaranteed, and odds are this is a one-way trip.  But at this point it's do or die![CR]As Earth's last hope, you must successfully defeat the Xevion assault fleet before they reclaim earth.  However this won't be an easy task, the Xevions have had over a millennia to develop the biggest, nastiest, and most destructive ships Earth has ever seen.  Thankfully the Solvalou is armed with the latest in weapons technology which will cut through the Xevion hordes like a hot knife through butter.  The Solvalou has two main weapons, a laser blaster for taking out air targets, and a photon bomber for destroying ground targets.  Over the course of the game you'll run into numerous enemy types which can only be destroyed using the appropriate weapon, so mastering the dual shot (air and ground) technique is vital.</plot>
    <genre>Shooter</genre>
    <boxart1>BJa831k.png</boxart1>
    <snapshot1>GyKBA4u.png</snapshot1>
    <boxart2>wEXNhGK.png</boxart2>
    <snapshot2>2NHcjXw.png</snapshot2>
    <videoid>u9Iy6C28c88</videoid>
  </game>
  <game name="Yellow Submarine (USA) (Demo)">
    <description>Yellow Submarine (USA) (Demo)</description>
    <title_clean>Yellow Submarine</title_clean>
    <rom name="no-intro-atari-5200-20130303/No-Intro%20-%20Atari%20-%205200%20%282013-03-03%29.zip/Yellow%20Submarine%20%28USA%29%20%28Demo%29.zip" size="1045"/>
    <plot>This prototype is simply a movement demo featuring the famous Beatles yellow submarine.  Using the joystick you can move the submarine in all eight directions until you get bored and shut it off.  There are no borders, and the sub will wrap around to the other side of the screen after a second or two.</plot>
    <boxart1>kWEjNZv.png</boxart1>
    <snapshot1>wWVttRZ.png</snapshot1>
    <boxart2>xQEHfzQ.jpg</boxart2>
    <snapshot2>w5OXnOO.png</snapshot2>
  </game>
  <game name="Zaxxon (USA)">
    <description>Zaxxon (USA)</description>
    <title_clean>Zaxxon</title_clean>
    <rom name="no-intro-atari-5200-20130303/No-Intro%20-%20Atari%20-%205200%20%282013-03-03%29.zip/Zaxxon%20%28USA%29.zip" size="9041"/>
    <releasedate>18/10/1983</releasedate>
    <genre>Action,Shooter,Scrolling</genre>
    <gamefaqs_url>http://www.gamefaqs.com/atari5200/585371-zaxxon</gamefaqs_url>
    <plot>ZAXXON thrusts you into the depths of outer space. Test your pilot skills as you strap into the command position. Prepare for an action-packed challenge of space survival.Score points as you dive, climb, and swoop down to destroy the enemy's floating fortress. Dodge deadly laser barriers, enemy missiles, and rapid gunfire! Destroy enemy fuel tanks and your own supply is replenished. Survive the enemy's fighter fleet attack and face the ultimate challenge...the powerful, armored ZAXXON ROBOT.</plot>
    <rating>3.00</rating>
    <studio>Sega</studio>
    <nplayers>1-2</nplayers>
    <ESRB>ESRB - E (Everyone)</ESRB>
    <boxart1>0J3e6tj.png</boxart1>
    <banner1>HyL5QtJ.jpg</banner1>
    <clearlogo1>s8OECXM.png</clearlogo1>
    <snapshot1>BkZx4A4.png</snapshot1>
    <boxart2>ukHgH4Q.jpg</boxart2>
    <snapshot2>CrMKxzm.png</snapshot2>
    <boxart3>1RhagAE.png</boxart3>
    <snapshot10>cvZh21t.png</snapshot10>
    <snapshot3>Ax6dvn0.gif</snapshot3>
    <snapshot4>lGkJEDG.gif</snapshot4>
    <snapshot5>lCRVWB8.gif</snapshot5>
    <snapshot6>PcS4oNm.gif</snapshot6>
    <snapshot7>FIx7OPL.png</snapshot7>
    <snapshot8>mVanOIA.png</snapshot8>
    <snapshot9>iSDJVnC.png</snapshot9>
  </game>
  <game name="Zenji (USA)">
    <description>Zenji (USA)</description>
    <title_clean>Zenji</title_clean>
    <rom name="no-intro-atari-5200-20130303/No-Intro%20-%20Atari%20-%205200%20%282013-03-03%29.zip/Zenji%20%28USA%29.zip" size="6621"/>
    <releasedate>18/10/1984</releasedate>
    <genre>Action,General</genre>
    <gamefaqs_url>http://www.gamefaqs.com/atari5200/585372-zenji</gamefaqs_url>
    <plot>Zenji is an action/strategy game where you control a rolling face throughout a maze. Each section of the maze can be rotated by the face. The goal is to turn the entire maze green by connecting each section of the maze to the source at the center of the screen. After all sections of the maze have been connected, you can move on to the next, more challenging level. In addition to having a time limit to complete your task, you need to avoid the flames and sparks which wander about the maze. From time to time a number will appear in a maze section and count down from 9 to 0. If you touch the number before it disappears, bonus points are earned. As the levels progress, the mazes become larger, trickier and more flames will appear.</plot>
    <studio>Activision</studio>
    <nplayers>1-2</nplayers>
    <ESRB>ESRB - E (Everyone)</ESRB>
    <rating>4.5</rating>
    <boxart1>A2UHTiW.png</boxart1>
    <banner1>RcGuR4b.jpg</banner1>
    <clearlogo1>7h3MAUO.png</clearlogo1>
    <snapshot1>WHGTpSs.png</snapshot1>
    <boxart2>gjza1Ly.jpg</boxart2>
    <snapshot2>31wAwY4.png</snapshot2>
    <boxart3>dywkjR2.png</boxart3>
    <videoid>mJfy_vl0yj0</videoid>
    <snapshot10>hUgpmjK.png</snapshot10>
    <snapshot3>gTySb9k.gif</snapshot3>
    <snapshot4>VowMimF.gif</snapshot4>
    <snapshot5>e8mDAxi.gif</snapshot5>
    <snapshot6>dtwPQnu.png</snapshot6>
    <snapshot7>ZUJf9RQ.png</snapshot7>
    <snapshot8>5Pexb6h.png</snapshot8>
    <snapshot9>Bk4o1C4.png</snapshot9>
  </game>
  <game name="Zone Ranger (USA)">
    <description>Zone Ranger (USA)</description>
    <title_clean>Zone Ranger</title_clean>
    <rom name="no-intro-atari-5200-20130303/No-Intro%20-%20Atari%20-%205200%20%282013-03-03%29.zip/Zone%20Ranger%20%28USA%29.zip" size="11788"/>
    <releasedate>18/10/1984</releasedate>
    <genre>Action,Shooter,Scrolling</genre>
    <gamefaqs_url>http://www.gamefaqs.com/atari5200/585373-zone-ranger</gamefaqs_url>
    <plot>Over 30 seperate zones of indescribable danger. Pitting you against a devastatingly evil minefield of destruction. Not to mention countless horrible enemies. Strike them and they only multiply.[CR] Detonate the deadly mines that litter your cosmos or you'll be sorry. Find an elusive, mysterious superportal and you'll get even. It's intense multiscreen action. Which loosely translated, simply means, it's awesome fun.</plot>
    <rating>4.50</rating>
    <studio>Activision</studio>
    <nplayers>1-2</nplayers>
    <ESRB>ESRB - E (Everyone)</ESRB>
    <boxart1>8jcbfbz.png</boxart1>
    <clearlogo1>fSfyolR.png</clearlogo1>
    <snapshot1>8YAv7IF.png</snapshot1>
    <boxart2>f5cc7QW.jpg</boxart2>
    <snapshot2>vOfZL7G.png</snapshot2>
    <boxart3>CzWqtqR.png</boxart3>
    <boxart4>eRyYbko.png</boxart4>
    <snapshot10>QqKrRT6.png</snapshot10>
    <snapshot3>7TWP18Z.gif</snapshot3>
    <snapshot4>Zsk6prG.gif</snapshot4>
    <snapshot5>nTaKyBK.gif</snapshot5>
    <snapshot6>XSTVnHI.jpg</snapshot6>
    <snapshot7>JjM1gcv.png</snapshot7>
    <snapshot8>KR1YzhR.png</snapshot8>
    <snapshot9>wVBOJY8.png</snapshot9>
  </game>
</datafile>