<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<datafile>
	<header>
		<emu_name>Atari 7800</emu_name>
		<emu_description>Atari 7800</emu_description>
		<emu_category>Atari, 1980s, Console, 8 Bit</emu_category>
		<emu_version>04012017</emu_version>
		<emu_date>12/09/2013</emu_date>
		<emu_author>Zach Morris</emu_author>
		<emu_visibility>visible</emu_visibility>
		<emu_homepage>https://www.archive.org</emu_homepage>
		<emu_baseurl>https://archive.org/download/</emu_baseurl>
		<emu_launcher>retroplayer</emu_launcher>
		<emu_default_addon>none</emu_default_addon>
		<emu_ext_launch_cmd>none</emu_ext_launch_cmd>
		<emu_downloadpath>default</emu_downloadpath>
		<emu_postdlaction>none</emu_postdlaction>
		<emu_comment>Internet Archives Atari 7800 Collection.[CR]The Atari 7800 ProSystem, or simply the Atari 7800, is a home video game console officially released by Atari Corporation in 1986.  It had simple digital joysticks and was almost fully backward-compatible with the Atari 2600, the first console to have backward compatibility without the use of additional modules. It was considered affordable at a price of US$140.[CR]Developer:  Atari[CR]CPU:  Atari SALLY 6502 ("6502C")[CR]Memory:  4KB RAM[CR]Graphics:  MARIA[CR]Sound:  Pot Keyboard Integrated Circuit[CR]Display:  320x240[CR]Media:  Cartridge[CRMax Controllers:  2</emu_comment>
		<emu_thumb>KoCk43c.jpg</emu_thumb>
		<emu_banner>11m2Z4M.png</emu_banner>
		<emu_fanart>esZyjyl.jpg</emu_fanart>
		<emu_logo>bWSvewe.png</emu_logo>
		<emu_trailer>Oxfsb1wvWb8</emu_trailer>
	</header>
	<game name="Asteroids (1987)(Atari)(NTSC)">
		<rom name="Asteroids_1987_Atari_NTSC/Asteroids_1987_Atari_NTSC.a78" size="0"/>
		<description>Asteroids (1987)(Atari)(NTSC)</description>
		<plot>Start blasting! It's your only way out of this cloud of hurtling astral bodies. Peripheral vision. Lightning reflexes. And cool control. That's what it takes to save your ship. And your life![CR]- 8 waves of devastating asteroids.[CR]- For 1 or 2 players.[CR]- Competing player ships can appear on screen simultaneously.</plot>
		<genre>Action,Shooter</genre>
		<releasedate>11/01/1987</releasedate>
		<nplayers>2</nplayers>
		<boxart1>p66aGeN.jpg</boxart1>
		<boxart2>9yXBPLy.jpg</boxart2>
		<boxart3>K9eF4ob.jpg</boxart3>
		<boxart4>wRBgloe.jpg</boxart4>
		<boxart5>Q8XxBNl.jpg</boxart5>
		<snapshot1>7MJsdIG.png</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>cBiuGQ2.gif</snapshot2>
		<snapshot3>ZDJRzfx.gif</snapshot3>
		<snapshot4>S5g9nY9.gif</snapshot4>
		<snapshot5>NyiUfHY.gif</snapshot5>
		<snapshot6>v6syfP6.gif</snapshot6>
	</game>
	<game name="Double Dragon (1989)(Activision)(NTSC)">
		<rom name="Double_Dragon_1989_Activision_NTSC/Double_Dragon_1989_Activision_NTSC.a78" size="0"/>
		<description>Double Dragon (1989)(Activision)(NTSC)</description>
		<plot>Twin brothers Billy and Jimmy Lee learned to fight the hard way -- for survival in the unforgiving city streets. Their brand of combat -- classic martial arts maneuvers mixed with anything-goes street brawling -- has turned them into walking lethal weapons.[CR]Now, the Lees must summon all their fighting abilities and cunning into meeting the greatest challenge of their lives -- rescuing Billy's girlfriend, Marion.  She's been kidnapped by the Black Warriors, the savage street gang led by the mysterious Shadow Boss.[CR]The twins pursue the Black Warriors through the city streets and its outskirts.  Finally they fight their way into the Secret Enemy Base.  There, Billy and Jimmy meet the Shadow Boss.  It's a battle to the finish, with Marion as the prize!</plot>
		<genre>Platform</genre>
		<releasedate>01/01/1989</releasedate>
		<nplayers>2</nplayers>
		<boxart1>S0zzLJ1.jpg</boxart1>
		<boxart2>2UBxCGy.jpg</boxart2>
		<boxart3>VEJEp4s.jpg</boxart3>
		<boxart4>6PG8RV6.jpg</boxart4>
		<boxart5>Y6k93uU.jpg</boxart5>
		<snapshot1>kuXUU2X.png</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>fYPXA6Y.gif</snapshot2>
		<snapshot3>xe0qir8.gif</snapshot3>
		<snapshot4>277BDfg.gif</snapshot4>
		<snapshot5>1odzNyK.gif</snapshot5>
	</game>
	<game name="Kung-Fu Master (1989)(Absolute Entertainment)(NTSC)">
		<rom name="Kung-Fu_Master_1989_Absolute_Entertainment_NTSC/Kung-Fu_Master_1989_Absolute_Entertainment_NTSC.a78" size="0"/>
		<description>Kung-Fu Master (1989)(Absolute Entertainment)(NTSC)</description>
		<plot>The gorgeous Princess Victoria is imprisoned in the Evil Wizard's Temple.  As Kung-Fu Master, you must free her.  Unfortunately, the Temple's five tortuous levels are seething with menacing foes.[CR]Smash your way through one level and start the next with a renewed energy meter and timer. Once you free your Princess, it's back to the beginning where your foes return faster and nastier.</plot>
		<genre>Action</genre>
		<releasedate>06/01/1989</releasedate>
		<nplayers>2</nplayers>
		<boxart1>wAYVjz4.jpg</boxart1>
		<snapshot1>c1TfuMS.png</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>b8B8NNc.png</snapshot2>
		<snapshot3>Efxii9S.png</snapshot3>
		<snapshot4>KODgMgj.png</snapshot4>
		<snapshot5>4aYKlqa.png</snapshot5>
	</game>
	<game name="Rampage (1989)(Activision)(NTSC)">
		<rom name="Rampage_1989_Activision_NTSC/Rampage_1989_Activision_NTSC.a78" size="0"/>
		<description>Rampage (1989)(Activision)(NTSC)</description>
		<plot>Based on the 1985 Bally Midway coin-op, the 7800 was produced by Activision and distributed by Mediagenic. This is a movie-monster game in which you control the beasts and destroy the city.</plot>
		<genre>Action</genre>
		<releasedate>01/01/1988</releasedate>
		<nplayers>2</nplayers>
		<boxart1>Xgp5js3.jpg</boxart1>
		<boxart2>OGZLTgp.jpg</boxart2>
		<boxart3>sIyUaef.jpg</boxart3>
		<snapshot1>SZKEqFG.png</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>id1XTZv.jpg</snapshot2>
		<snapshot3>EAPEPWy.jpg</snapshot3>
		<snapshot4>VHKfHoI.jpg</snapshot4>
		<snapshot5>WVr1Zd4.jpg</snapshot5>
		<snapshot6>owjNs6I.jpg</snapshot6>
		<snapshot7>skeWRFO.jpg</snapshot7>
		<snapshot8>Lv2iVAI.jpg</snapshot8>
		<snapshot9>LkupWu1.gif</snapshot9>
		<snapshot10>7XIrMoc.gif</snapshot10>
	</game>
	<game name="F-18 Hornet (1988)(Absolute Entertainment)(NTSC)">
		<rom name="F-18_Hornet_1988_Absolute_Entertainment_NTSC/F-18_Hornet_1988_Absolute_Entertainment_NTSC.a78" size="0"/>
		<description>F-18 Hornet (1988)(Absolute Entertainment)(NTSC)</description>
		<plot>Attention all Naval Aviators! Report to your squadron leaders and prepare for deployment. Your tour of duty will take you around the world on some of the most challenging and dangerous missions of your career. F-18 Hornet is a carrier based adventure. Fast, solid 3-D graphics and responsive instrumentation make for an incredible sensation of flight. Fly missions through a variety of terrain executing aerial combat, emergency supply drops, strafing and bombing runs while battling hostile jets, helicopters and tanks. F-18 Hornet features all of the action of carrier based jets including thrilling aircraft carrier take-offs and landings in smooth 3-D animation.</plot>
		<genre>Flight Simulator</genre>
		<releasedate>01/01/1988</releasedate>
		<nplayers>1</nplayers>
		<boxart1>5NjnieD.jpg</boxart1>
		<boxart2>UYx9l8q.jpg</boxart2>
		<boxart3>KgwNcw9.jpg</boxart3>
		<snapshot1>GrK5Uez.png</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>OpeA0O8.jpg</snapshot2>
		<snapshot3>hiDZrn4.gif</snapshot3>
		<snapshot4>8QOwuJb.gif</snapshot4>
		<snapshot5>k8oNf2y.gif</snapshot5>
		<snapshot6>kK8438W.gif</snapshot6>
		<snapshot7>vqm9miV.gif</snapshot7>
		<snapshot8>5V2ft8l.gif</snapshot8>
		<snapshot9>05iVfO1.gif</snapshot9>
		<snapshot10>r3YQl8z.gif</snapshot10>
	</game>
	<game name="Tomcat - The F-14 Fighter Simulator (1989)(Absolute Entertainment)(NTSC)">
		<rom name="Tomcat_-_The_F-14_Fighter_Simulator_1989_Absolute_Entertainment_NTSC/Tomcat_-_The_F-14_Fighter_Simulator_1989_Absolute_Entertainment_NTSC.a78" size="0"/>
		<description>Tomcat - The F-14 Fighter Simulator (1989)(Absolute Entertainment)(NTSC)</description>
		<plot>Become a F-14 Naval Aviator undergoing seek and destroy missions while dodging and gunning enemy bogeys in deadly dogfights with your 20mm cannon and air-to-air missiles.[CR]Your cockpit comes with state of the art technology, courtesy of the U.S. Air Force: Display and main computer, Bogey Alert Indicator, G-Force Indicator, Electronic Counter Measures, and a Cannon Overheat Indicator (yes, it can overheat!)...and if your feeling up to it, give the ol'bird a boost to Mach 1.0![CRThe gameplay like other simulation games consists of taking off, flying, combat and landing. Though most of the gameplay focuses around dogfighting with enemy bogeys (dodging missiles). In addition to that, there are also night-flying missions that add difficulty due to limited vision.[CR]Taking off and landing however, also requires additional skill as your doing it on the USS Enterprise (No relation to Star Trek), not on your standard airstrip. Pay attention to the F.D. officer as your preparing to take off (since he's the boss when it comes to this stuff...and try not to run over him...yet).[CR]Your weaponry consists of a M 61 Machine Gun and 3 different AIM Missiles (AIM 7, 9, 54) each packed with 15 missiles (that's a lot of missiles!).[CR]After each mission you will receive a Mission Rating which is based on your flying skill, number of bogey kill and number of weapons fired.</plot>
		<genre>Action, Flight Simulator</genre>
		<releasedate>01/01/1989</releasedate>
		<nplayers>1</nplayers>
		<boxart1>APtM2sP.jpg</boxart1>
		<boxart2>TvZAina.jpg</boxart2>
		<snapshot1>IcmX7oK.png</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>u5qecm5.jpg</snapshot2>
		<snapshot3>kbSDy8j.jpg</snapshot3>
		<snapshot4>nRHmboT.jpg</snapshot4>
		<snapshot5>GOjkUeL.jpg</snapshot5>
		<snapshot6>AuUDfX3.jpg</snapshot6>
		<snapshot7>nI1aHre.jpg</snapshot7>
		<snapshot8>2pVELEL.jpg</snapshot8>
		<snapshot9>yNyWuVH.gif</snapshot9>
		<snapshot10>3BvOD3E.gif</snapshot10>
	</game>
	<game name="Tank Command (1988)(Froggo)(NTSC)">
		<rom name="Tank_Command_1988_Froggo_NTSC/Tank_Command_1988_Froggo_NTSC.a78" size="0"/>
		<description>Tank Command (1988)(Froggo)(NTSC)</description>
		<plot>Tank Command is a vertically scrolling action game. You control a tank on a mission to capture the enemy flag as well as earn as many points as possible. To do this, you will need to blast your way through their defenses on three levels of increasing difficulty. Blocking your progress are enemy tanks, pillboxes, missiles, jeeps, infantry, huts, and more, all of which earn you points when destroyed. Your tank is equipped with a limited amount of fuel and ammo, however it can be replenished occasionally by collecting the bonus icons when they appear on the screen. If you can make it past all of the obstacles and capture the flag, then you win the game![CR]The 7800 is pretty much void of super-rare games like the 2600'?s Tooth Protectors and Chase the Chuckwagon, but don't worry, tracking down Tank Command in a box will cost you a pretty penny. As far as gameplay goes, Tank Command is not going to blow anyone away. Here you have a vertical scroller like Commando or Ikari Warriors minus the charm, quality level design, and reasonable difficulty. There are only three levels in the game, but just like its Froggo cousin Water Ski, the difficulty ramps so severely after the mindless first level that continuing takes strong will. The pink terrain is a bit odd, as well. Tank Command was only released in NTSC format.</plot>
		<genre>Action</genre>
		<releasedate>01/01/1988</releasedate>
		<nplayers>1</nplayers>
		<boxart1>XBXCM3G.jpg</boxart1>
		<boxart2>HSCe6NZ.jpg</boxart2>
		<snapshot1>6LRrA0K.png</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>JgtftsC.jpg</snapshot2>
		<snapshot3>FYPA8Wn.jpg</snapshot3>
		<snapshot4>oSD9DFn.jpg</snapshot4>
		<snapshot5>Mzoh6nC.jpg</snapshot5>
		<snapshot6>iPbcGR6.jpg</snapshot6>
		<snapshot7>wNeiyRn.jpg</snapshot7>
		<snapshot8>Ezu6OLC.jpg</snapshot8>
		<snapshot9>kJewaq6.png</snapshot9>
		<snapshot10>ybRuQW2.png</snapshot10>
	</game>
	<game name="Food Fight">
		<rom name="Food_Fight_1987_Atari_NTSC/Food_Fight_1987_Atari_NTSC.a78" size="0"/>
		<description>Food Fight</description>
		<plot>Hurry! Hurry! Step Right Up! Earn Your Just Desserts![CR]Once there was a fellow named Charley Chuck. More than anything, Charley loved to eat. So when he went to the carnival one hot summer day, he headed straight for the Food Fight contest.</plot>
		<genre>Action</genre>
		<releasedate>01/01/1987</releasedate>
		<nplayers>2</nplayers>
		<boxart1>Jm9hRPA.jpg</boxart1>
		<boxart2>dcG57uD.jpg</boxart2>
		<boxart3>6P2l43t.jpg</boxart3>
		<boxart4>hWl6zhJ.jpg</boxart4>
		<snapshot1>fThpiv8.png</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>LV98DPH.gif</snapshot2>
		<snapshot3>E1RPGg5.gif</snapshot3>
		<snapshot4>4P0xTHJ.gif</snapshot4>
		<snapshot5>iRUT9zo.gif</snapshot5>
		<snapshot6>oB6Uelt.gif</snapshot6>
	</game>
	<game name="Baseball (1989)(Absolute Entertainment)(PAL)">
		<rom name="Baseball_1989_Absolute_Entertainment_PAL/Baseball_1989_Absolute_Entertainment_PAL.a78" size="0"/>
		<description>Baseball (1989)(Absolute Entertainment)(PAL)</description>
		<plot>It's the last game of the World Series. You're in the 9th innings. Bases loaded. One out. And your up to bat.  What do you do? Swing away? Wait for a walk? Go for the fences? It's all up to you, just like in real pro ball.[CR]Sure, we'll give you the options. And some tips. Like in pitching. Batting. And Fielding. But, it's you call.[CR]There are 6 full-color, live action screens - just like the ones you see on TV! The pitching/battting screen, left infield, right infield, leftfield, centerfield and rightfield.[CR]So, start warming up. Step up to the plate. And take your best swing at winning the series![CR]Originally designed by Alex DeMeo, the 7800 version was programmed by Robert Curtiss.</plot>
		<genre>Sports</genre>
		<releasedate>05/27/1989</releasedate>
		<nplayers>2</nplayers>
		<boxart1>1g2LUHh.jpg</boxart1>
		<boxart2>Tq6HOW6.jpg</boxart2>
		<boxart3>J3jv7UY.jpg</boxart3>
		<boxart4>IF5OO0b.jpg</boxart4>
		<boxart5>J0whYb8.jpg</boxart5>
		<snapshot1>0yuB8dv.png</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>Rgu5vqV.jpg</snapshot2>
		<snapshot3>EZqjWVL.jpg</snapshot3>
		<snapshot4>a9CS3hr.jpg</snapshot4>
		<snapshot5>bqbN7gO.jpg</snapshot5>
		<snapshot6>EMuQstl.jpg</snapshot6>
		<snapshot7>rBrEMs7.jpg</snapshot7>
		<snapshot8>5zmTejk.jpg</snapshot8>
		<snapshot9>dAF4RiJ.gif</snapshot9>
		<snapshot10>Wg2EbLz.gif</snapshot10>
	</game>
	<game name="Space War! Rev 20040318 (2004)(Eric Ball)(PD)">
		<rom name="Space_War_Rev_20040318_2004_Eric_Ball_PD/Space_War_Rev_20040318_2004_Eric_Ball_PD.a78" size="0"/>
		<description>Space War! Rev 20040318 (2004)(Eric Ball)(PD)</description>
		<plot>In a desperate attempt to stop inner-city gang wars, the city leaders organized a basketball league.  The league is scheduled to play on three courts: a street, a junkyard, and a rooftop.  The mayor figured that a friendly game of hoops would be a much more peaceful way to settle disputes. He was wrong.You can choose 1-on-1 or 2-on-2 game modes. There are six characters to choose from (ten in Atari Lynx version); each with their own health, speed, and power attributes. Each player without the ball can jump to block a shot or punch there opponent to get the ball. There's also an option to perform a power throw on an opposing player. Players with the ball can shoot or pass. Power ups appear on the court at random instances. These power up one attribute for the player. For example, the lightning power up increases the player's speed. The referee does not call fouls, but does hurl knives at the players.</plot>
		<genre>Sports</genre>
		<releasedate>1990</releasedate>
		<nplayers>1-2 Sim</nplayers>
		<boxart1>Tq6HOW6.jpg</boxart1>
		<boxart2>IF5OO0b.jpg</boxart2>
		<boxart3>J0whYb8.jpg</boxart3>
		<snapshot1>dAF4RiJ.gif</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>Wg2EbLz.gif</snapshot2>
		<snapshot3>QK1m0H7.gif</snapshot3>
		<snapshot4>BBbv7Ik.gif</snapshot4>
		<snapshot5>kt8iQTB.gif</snapshot5>
		<snapshot6>VhG2tzr.gif</snapshot6>
		<snapshot7>4bbg4Bf.gif</snapshot7>
	</game>
	<game name="Pete Rose Baseball (1989)(Absolute Entertainment)(NTSC)">
		<rom name="Pete_Rose_Baseball_1989_Absolute_Entertainment_NTSC/Pete_Rose_Baseball_1989_Absolute_Entertainment_NTSC.a78" size="0"/>
		<description>Pete Rose Baseball (1989)(Absolute Entertainment)(NTSC)</description>
		<plot>It's the last game of the World Series. You're in the 9th innings. Bases loaded. One out. And your up to bat.  What do you do? Swing away? Wait for a walk? Go for the fences? It's all up to you, just like in real pro ball.  Sure, we'll give you the options. And some tips. Like in pitching. Batting. And Fielding. But, it's you call.[CR]There are 6 full-color, live action screens - just like the ones you see on TV! The pitching/battting screen, left infield, right infield, leftfield, centerfield and rightfield.[CR]So, start warming up. Step up to the plate. And take your best swing at winning the series![CR]Originally designed by Alex DeMeo, the 7800 version was programmed by Robert Curtiss.</plot>
		<genre>Sports</genre>
		<releasedate>05/27/1989</releasedate>
		<nplayers>2</nplayers>
		<boxart1>1g2LUHh.jpg</boxart1>
		<boxart2>Tq6HOW6.jpg</boxart2>
		<boxart3>J3jv7UY.jpg</boxart3>
		<boxart4>IF5OO0b.jpg</boxart4>
		<boxart5>J0whYb8.jpg</boxart5>
		<snapshot1>S2alH5h.jpg</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>Rgu5vqV.jpg</snapshot2>
		<snapshot3>EZqjWVL.jpg</snapshot3>
		<snapshot4>a9CS3hr.jpg</snapshot4>
		<snapshot5>bqbN7gO.jpg</snapshot5>
		<snapshot6>EMuQstl.jpg</snapshot6>
		<snapshot7>rBrEMs7.jpg</snapshot7>
		<snapshot8>5zmTejk.jpg</snapshot8>
		<snapshot9>dAF4RiJ.gif</snapshot9>
		<snapshot10>Wg2EbLz.gif</snapshot10>
	</game>
	<game name="Barnyard Blaster (1988)(Atari)(NTSC)">
		<rom name="Barnyard_Blaster_1988_Atari_NTSC/Barnyard_Blaster_1988_Atari_NTSC.a78" size="0"/>
		<description>Barnyard Blaster (1988)(Atari)(NTSC)</description>
		<plot>You and Grandpa are down on the farm. There are critters, bottles, and varmints everywhere -- in the barn, in the yard, and in the cornfield. Grandpa has given you an Atari light gun to help protect the farm. The moving targets are a challenge. Can you hit them? If not, try the veggies! They're fun to shoot at.[CR]In the barnyard, bottles and cans on the fence provide great practive for warming up the old shootin' iron. But perfect aim alone isn't enough. You'll need speed, too.[CR]In the cornfield, birds swoop from the sky and rabbits scamper among the stalks, Owls and other pests appear inside a barn. Each scene can only be reached by hitting enough targest in the scene before. Once you zero in on some fancy shooting scores, Gramps offers you a bonus round by tossing target bottles in the air.</plot>
		<genre>Action</genre>
		<releasedate>06/05/1988</releasedate>
		<nplayers>2</nplayers>
		<boxart1>PO4sEkb.jpg</boxart1>
		<boxart2>ANiQxun.jpg</boxart2>
		<boxart3>sMbollW.jpg</boxart3>
		<boxart4>jKpGVH2.jpg</boxart4>
		<boxart5>rFWr5Y0.jpg</boxart5>
		<snapshot1>VeqwRPc.png</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>WRyA9Ls.gif</snapshot2>
		<snapshot3>WktsPsM.gif</snapshot3>
		<snapshot4>EliWujR.gif</snapshot4>
		<snapshot5>HNIjbI8.gif</snapshot5>
		<snapshot6>TdsZh9A.gif</snapshot6>
		<snapshot7>7ihoOQk.gif</snapshot7>
		<snapshot8>cgyPxmb.gif</snapshot8>
		<snapshot9>uer8n1q.gif</snapshot9>
	</game>
	<game name="Super Skateboardin' (1988)(Absolute Entertainment)(NTSC)">
		<rom name="Super_Skateboardin_1988_Absolute_Entertainment_NTSC/Super_Skateboardin_1988_Absolute_Entertainment_NTSC.a78" size="0"/>
		<description>Super Skateboardin' (1988)(Absolute Entertainment)(NTSC)</description>
		<plot>Your Dad got you an after-school job at the factory where he works.  You need the money 'cuz being the most radical boarder around means you've got heavy expenses.[CR]The job is a skateboarder's dream come true.  Miles of halls and tubes to perfect your moves.  Just cruise through and turn off all the machines and lights in the factory.  Hurry up 'cuz power is leaking out fast![CR]Naturally, there's a catch.  You get paid depending on how much power you save.  And you've got to be out of the factory by 5:15 pm today.  One second more and you'll never make the deadline for entering the Skateboarding Championship.</plot>
		<genre>Action, Sports</genre>
		<releasedate>01/01/1988</releasedate>
		<nplayers>1</nplayers>
		<boxart1>sJlAN6z.jpg</boxart1>
		<boxart2>q80nQk0.jpg</boxart2>
		<boxart3>lr9dtNT.jpg</boxart3>
		<snapshot1>7MmJxLv.png</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>p2m3PMe.gif</snapshot2>
		<snapshot3>wWkqFfA.gif</snapshot3>
		<snapshot4>XxJ1I05.gif</snapshot4>
		<snapshot5>3251iq0.gif</snapshot5>
	</game>
	<game name="Water Ski (1988)(Froggo)(NTSC)">
		<rom name="Water_Ski_1988_Froggo_NTSC/Water_Ski_1988_Froggo_NTSC.a78" size="0"/>
		<description>Water Ski (1988)(Froggo)(NTSC)</description>
		<plot>In Water Ski you are water skiing on the Pharonna River. You control both the boat and skier in this vertically scrolling action game. Your goal is to reach the finish line before time runs out and also to earn as many points as possible. The river is quite dangerous, and features many twists and turns along with rocks, logs and other obstacles. For bonus points there are numerous ramps located throughout the river which your skier can jump over (and if you can manage to ski over every ramp on the level, you'll earn even more points!). You start the game with four skiers, and the game ends when all of you skiers have crashed.</plot>
		<genre>Sports</genre>
		<releasedate>05/27/1988</releasedate>
		<nplayers>1</nplayers>
		<boxart1>BEeZACD.jpg</boxart1>
		<boxart2>MaWKT4l.jpg</boxart2>
		<boxart3>OuqlInN.jpg</boxart3>
		<boxart4>AxNXfAK.jpg</boxart4>
		<boxart5>UUb8Iqk.jpg</boxart5>
		<snapshot1>NmZiT4d.png</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>5dqbRpa.jpg</snapshot2>
		<snapshot3>d1Xt6Cm.jpg</snapshot3>
		<snapshot4>RCsRnc3.jpg</snapshot4>
		<snapshot5>jH0068A.jpg</snapshot5>
		<snapshot6>rCGsDmP.jpg</snapshot6>
		<snapshot7>it1VpmS.jpg</snapshot7>
		<snapshot8>TCB2ibm.jpg</snapshot8>
		<snapshot9>Uq4JT2I.png</snapshot9>
		<snapshot10>Z5Ro96X.png</snapshot10>
	</game>
	<game name="Title Match Pro Wrestling (1989)(Absolute Entertainment)(NTSC)">
		<rom name="Title_Match_Pro_Wrestling_1989_Absolute_Entertainment_NTSC/Title_Match_Pro_Wrestling_1989_Absolute_Entertainment_NTSC.a78" size="0"/>
		<description>Title Match Pro Wrestling (1989)(Absolute Entertainment)(NTSC)</description>
		<plot>The screams of the crowd shake the arena as the Title Belt contenders circle one another.  Mad Dog makes the first move smashing his fists into Skin Head's chest who gasps for air, then retaliates with a shin cracking kick.[CR]Mad Dog growls and grabbing from behind drags Skin Head across the ring whipping him around in an airplane spin;  letting go so he flies into the ropes and bounces back to meet Mad Dog's concrete forearm across his neck...a perfectly executed clothesline.[CR]Wasting no time Mad Dog elbow drops him. Skin Head's face winces in pain as he fights his way up and staggers to his corner to tag his partner in.[CR]Big Chief takes the tag, grabs Mad Dog lifting him over his head and body slams him into the mat.  Mad Dog's stunned, he's not getting up.  Big Chief, looking for the pin, climbs the ropes for a dive.[CR]As he lunges into the air, Mad Dog scrambles to his feet and Big Chief's sweaty red skinned body splatters on the empty mat.</plot>
		<genre>Sports</genre>
		<releasedate>01/01/1989</releasedate>
		<nplayers>2</nplayers>
		<boxart1>LhC7vM5.jpg</boxart1>
		<boxart2>wjo3Dme.jpg</boxart2>
		<snapshot1>ZGQL3io.png</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>U3ACCLq.png</snapshot2>
		<snapshot3>P0fUDty.png</snapshot3>
		<snapshot4>o4nO5U9.png</snapshot4>
		<snapshot5>rmDosE6.png</snapshot5>
		<snapshot6>ud2kbKQ.png</snapshot6>
	</game>
	<game name="Senso 7800 DX4 (2003)(Taquart)(PD)">
		<rom name="Senso_7800_DX4_2003_Taquart_PD/Senso_7800_DX4_2003_Taquart_PD.a78" size="0"/>
		<description>Senso 7800 DX4 (2003)(Taquart)(PD)</description>
		<plot>Beef Drop is a port of the popular arcade game Burgertime, which Ken Siders first ported to the Atari 5200 and 8-bit computers. This version of Beef Drop beature POKEY sound support, for much better audio than the 7800 can produce without this chip. The 7800 version also features better graphics than the 5200/8-bit version, making the 7800 version the definitive release of Beef Drop.</plot>
		<genre>Sports</genre>
		<releasedate>1989</releasedate>
		<nplayers>2</nplayers>
		<boxart1>TegVo82.jpg</boxart1>
		<snapshot1>0jDtCXx.png</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>udEKHD2.png</snapshot2>
		<snapshot3>U3ACCLq.png</snapshot3>
		<snapshot4>P0fUDty.png</snapshot4>
		<snapshot5>o4nO5U9.png</snapshot5>
		<snapshot6>rmDosE6.png</snapshot6>
		<snapshot7>ud2kbKQ.png</snapshot7>
	</game>
	<game name="GATO (1987)(Atari)(NTSC)(proto)">
		<rom name="GATO_1987_Atari_NTSC_proto/GATO_1987_Atari_NTSC_proto.a78" size="0"/>
		<description>GATO (1987)(Atari)(NTSC)(proto)</description>
		<plot>Title Match is a wrestling game which can be played by one or two players. There are four different wrestlers you can choose from, and two modes of gameplay (one on one, or tag team). Each wrestler can kick, punch, and perform several moves such as the airplane spin, body slam, power lift, and more. Using the available moves you need to deplete your opponents energy  and pin him for three counts (though be careful, as some of the more powerful moves also use up a bit of your own energy). If your opponents energy is low enough and you successfully pin him that will count as a fall, and the best out of three falls will win the match! </plot>
		<genre>Sports</genre>
		<releasedate>1989</releasedate>
		<nplayers>1</nplayers>
		<boxart1>M6OZL7H.jpg</boxart1>
		<snapshot1>INYBpg7.png</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>U3ACCLq.png</snapshot2>
		<snapshot3>P0fUDty.png</snapshot3>
		<snapshot4>o4nO5U9.png</snapshot4>
		<snapshot5>rmDosE6.png</snapshot5>
		<snapshot6>ud2kbKQ.png</snapshot6>
	</game>
	<game name="Color Selector (1987)(Atari)">
		<rom name="Color_Selector_1987_Atari/Color_Selector_1987_Atari.a78" size="0"/>
		<description>Color Selector (1987)(Atari)</description>
		<plot>Title Match is a wrestling game which can be played by one or two players. There are four different wrestlers you can choose from, and two modes of gameplay (one on one, or tag team). Each wrestler can kick, punch, and perform several moves such as the airplane spin, body slam, power lift, and more. Using the available moves you need to deplete your opponents energy  and pin him for three counts (though be careful, as some of the more powerful moves also use up a bit of your own energy). If your opponents energy is low enough and you successfully pin him that will count as a fall, and the best out of three falls will win the match! </plot>
		<genre>Sports</genre>
		<releasedate>1989</releasedate>
		<nplayers>1-2 Sim</nplayers>
		<snapshot1>EvFQAJp.png</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>U3ACCLq.png</snapshot2>
		<snapshot3>P0fUDty.png</snapshot3>
		<snapshot4>o4nO5U9.png</snapshot4>
		<snapshot5>rmDosE6.png</snapshot5>
		<snapshot6>ud2kbKQ.png</snapshot6>
	</game>
	<game name="Mean 18 Ultimate Golf (1989)(Atari)(NTSC)">
		<rom name="Mean_18_Ultimate_Golf_1989_Atari_NTSC/Mean_18_Ultimate_Golf_1989_Atari_NTSC.a78" size="0"/>
		<description>Mean 18 Ultimate Golf (1989)(Atari)(NTSC)</description>
		<plot>This is it! A hush falls over the California countryside as you stand on the eighteenth hole of Pebble Beach. Youre five long feet from the hole and you have a one-stroke lead in the biggest tournament of your life. Your caddy hands you your lucky putter. You line up your shot, and swing. The ball rolls slowly toward the hole. Theres a tense moment as it almost rings the cup. finally, the ball falls in. You retain your title!</plot>
		<genre>Sports</genre>
		<releasedate>01/01/1989</releasedate>
		<nplayers>2</nplayers>
		<boxart1>y3CtEeS.jpg</boxart1>
		<boxart2>D4MGAqg.jpg</boxart2>
		<snapshot1>Yo8dWOo.png</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>U3ACCLq.png</snapshot2>
		<snapshot3>P0fUDty.png</snapshot3>
		<snapshot4>o4nO5U9.png</snapshot4>
		<snapshot5>rmDosE6.png</snapshot5>
		<snapshot6>ud2kbKQ.png</snapshot6>
	</game>
	<game name="Space War! Rev 20030930 (2003)(Eric Ball)(PD)">
		<rom name="Space_War_Rev_20030930_2003_Eric_Ball_PD/Space_War_Rev_20030930_2003_Eric_Ball_PD.a78" size="0"/>
		<description>Space War! Rev 20030930 (2003)(Eric Ball)(PD)</description>
		<plot>Title Match is a wrestling game which can be played by one or two players. There are four different wrestlers you can choose from, and two modes of gameplay (one on one, or tag team). Each wrestler can kick, punch, and perform several moves such as the airplane spin, body slam, power lift, and more. Using the available moves you need to deplete your opponents energy  and pin him for three counts (though be careful, as some of the more powerful moves also use up a bit of your own energy). If your opponents energy is low enough and you successfully pin him that will count as a fall, and the best out of three falls will win the match! </plot>
		<genre>Sports</genre>
		<releasedate>1989</releasedate>
		<nplayers>1-2 Sim</nplayers>
		<snapshot1>udEKHD2.png</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>U3ACCLq.png</snapshot2>
		<snapshot3>P0fUDty.png</snapshot3>
		<snapshot4>o4nO5U9.png</snapshot4>
		<snapshot5>rmDosE6.png</snapshot5>
		<snapshot6>ud2kbKQ.png</snapshot6>
	</game>
	<game name="Atari 7800 Symbolic Debug Monitor and Downloader (1988)(Atari)(NTSC)">
		<rom name="Atari_7800_Symbolic_Debug_Monitor_and_Downloader_1988_Atari_NTSC/Atari_7800_Symbolic_Debug_Monitor_and_Downloader_1988_Atari_NTSC.a78" size="0"/>
		<description>Atari 7800 Symbolic Debug Monitor and Downloader (1988)(Atari)(NTSC)</description>
		<plot>Beef Drop is a port of the popular arcade game Burgertime, which Ken Siders first ported to the Atari 5200 and 8-bit computers. This version of Beef Drop beature POKEY sound support, for much better audio than the 7800 can produce without this chip. The 7800 version also features better graphics than the 5200/8-bit version, making the 7800 version the definitive release of Beef Drop.</plot>
		<genre>Sports</genre>
		<releasedate>1989</releasedate>
		<nplayers>2</nplayers>
		<boxart1>TegVo82.jpg</boxart1>
		<snapshot1>MBAYlwH.jpg</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>udEKHD2.png</snapshot2>
		<snapshot3>U3ACCLq.png</snapshot3>
		<snapshot4>P0fUDty.png</snapshot4>
		<snapshot5>o4nO5U9.png</snapshot5>
		<snapshot6>rmDosE6.png</snapshot6>
		<snapshot7>ud2kbKQ.png</snapshot7>
	</game>
	<game name="Senso 7800 DX3 (2003)(Taquart)(PD)">
		<rom name="Senso_7800_DX3_2003_Taquart_PD/Senso_7800_DX3_2003_Taquart_PD.a78" size="0"/>
		<description>Senso 7800 DX3 (2003)(Taquart)(PD)</description>
		<plot>Beef Drop is a port of the popular arcade game Burgertime, which Ken Siders first ported to the Atari 5200 and 8-bit computers. This version of Beef Drop beature POKEY sound support, for much better audio than the 7800 can produce without this chip. The 7800 version also features better graphics than the 5200/8-bit version, making the 7800 version the definitive release of Beef Drop.</plot>
		<genre>Sports</genre>
		<releasedate>1989</releasedate>
		<nplayers>2</nplayers>
		<boxart1>TegVo82.jpg</boxart1>
		<snapshot1>MBAYlwH.jpg</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>udEKHD2.png</snapshot2>
		<snapshot3>U3ACCLq.png</snapshot3>
		<snapshot4>P0fUDty.png</snapshot4>
		<snapshot5>o4nO5U9.png</snapshot5>
		<snapshot6>rmDosE6.png</snapshot6>
		<snapshot7>ud2kbKQ.png</snapshot7>
	</game>
	<game name="Senso 7800 Test 5 (2001)(Taquart)(PD)">
		<rom name="Senso_7800_Test_5_2001_Taquart_PD/Senso_7800_Test_5_2001_Taquart_PD.a78" size="0"/>
		<description>Senso 7800 Test 5 (2001)(Taquart)(PD)</description>
		<plot>Beef Drop is a port of the popular arcade game Burgertime, which Ken Siders first ported to the Atari 5200 and 8-bit computers. This version of Beef Drop beature POKEY sound support, for much better audio than the 7800 can produce without this chip. The 7800 version also features better graphics than the 5200/8-bit version, making the 7800 version the definitive release of Beef Drop.</plot>
		<genre>Sports</genre>
		<releasedate>1989</releasedate>
		<nplayers>2</nplayers>
		<boxart1>TegVo82.jpg</boxart1>
		<snapshot1>MBAYlwH.jpg</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>udEKHD2.png</snapshot2>
		<snapshot3>U3ACCLq.png</snapshot3>
		<snapshot4>P0fUDty.png</snapshot4>
		<snapshot5>o4nO5U9.png</snapshot5>
		<snapshot6>rmDosE6.png</snapshot6>
		<snapshot7>ud2kbKQ.png</snapshot7>
	</game>
	<game name="Senso 7800 DX2 (2002)(Taquart)(PD)">
		<rom name="Senso_7800_DX2_2002_Taquart_PD/Senso_7800_DX2_2002_Taquart_PD.a78" size="0"/>
		<description>Senso 7800 DX2 (2002)(Taquart)(PD)</description>
		<plot>Beef Drop is a port of the popular arcade game Burgertime, which Ken Siders first ported to the Atari 5200 and 8-bit computers. This version of Beef Drop beature POKEY sound support, for much better audio than the 7800 can produce without this chip. The 7800 version also features better graphics than the 5200/8-bit version, making the 7800 version the definitive release of Beef Drop.</plot>
		<genre>Sports</genre>
		<releasedate>1989</releasedate>
		<nplayers>2</nplayers>
		<boxart1>TegVo82.jpg</boxart1>
		<snapshot1>MBAYlwH.jpg</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>udEKHD2.png</snapshot2>
		<snapshot3>U3ACCLq.png</snapshot3>
		<snapshot4>P0fUDty.png</snapshot4>
		<snapshot5>o4nO5U9.png</snapshot5>
		<snapshot6>rmDosE6.png</snapshot6>
		<snapshot7>ud2kbKQ.png</snapshot7>
	</game>
</datafile>