<datafile>
	<header>
		<emu_name>Atari 5200</emu_name>
		<emu_description>Atari 5200</emu_description>
		<emu_category>Atari, 1980s, Console, 8 Bit</emu_category>
		<emu_version>04012018</emu_version>
		<emu_date>04/26/2017</emu_date>
		<emu_author>Zach Morris</emu_author>
		<emu_visibility>visible</emu_visibility>
		<emu_homepage>http://www.mame.org/</emu_homepage>
		<emu_baseurl>http://archive.org/download/</emu_baseurl>
		<emu_launcher>retroplayer</emu_launcher>
		<emu_default_addon>none</emu_default_addon>
		<emu_ext_launch_cmd>none</emu_ext_launch_cmd>
		<emu_downloadpath>default</emu_downloadpath>
		<emu_postdlaction>unzip_and_rename_file</emu_postdlaction>
		<emu_comment>The Atari 5200 SuperSystem, commonly known as the Atari 5200, is a video game console that was introduced in 1982 by Atari Inc. as a higher end complementary console for the popular Atari 2600. The 5200 was created to compete with the Intellivision, but wound up more directly competing with the ColecoVision shortly after its release. The 5200 was based on Atari Inc.'s existing 400/800 computers and the internal hardware was almost identical, although software was not directly compatible between the two systems. The 5200's controllers feature an analog joystick and a numeric keypad along with start, pause and reset buttons. The 360-degree non-centering joystick was touted as offering more control than the four-position joystick controller offered with the Atari 2600.[CR]Developer:  Atari[CR]Manufacturer:  Atari[CR]CPU:  MOS 6502C[CR]Memory:  16 KB[CR]Graphics:  Alphanumeric Television Interface Controller[CR]Sound:  Pot Keyboard Integrated Circuit[CR]Display:  320x192[CR]Media:  Cartridge[CR]Max Controllers:  2</emu_comment>
		<emu_thumb>IvMbKMz.jpg</emu_thumb>
		<emu_banner>zzee99d.jpg</emu_banner>
		<emu_fanart>IEtGxt9.jpg</emu_fanart>
		<emu_logo>cRaNQQk.png</emu_logo>
		<emu_trailer>aeGBf5lnhhY</emu_trailer>
	</header>
		<game name="5200 Menu (Prototype)">
			<description>5200 Menu (Prototype)</description>
			<rom crc="0de2db48" name="MAME_0.185_Software_List_ROMs_non-merged/MAME_0.185_Software_List_ROMs_non-merged.zip/MAME%200.185%20Software%20List%20ROMs%20%28non-merged%29%2Fa5200%2F5200menu.zip" sha1="e64fb1a353c72b87c5483bb88cb3523ea5d37b59" size="895" />
			<title_clean>5200 Menu</title_clean>
			<plot>[CR][B]Overview:[/B][CR]5200 Menu is a rare prototype that seems to be a kiosk of sorts. The game features Asteroids, which was never released for the system, Quagmire, which nothing is known about as it was canceled, and Failsafe, which was the working-title name for Countermeasure.[CR]</plot>
			<releasedate>31/12/1983</releasedate>
			<year>1983</year>
			<studio>Atari</studio>
			<giantbomb_url>http://www.giantbomb.com/5200-menu/3030-38519/</giantbomb_url>
			<boxart1>SHKgmDb.jpg</boxart1>
		</game>
		<game name="A.E. (Prototype)">
			<description>A.E. (Prototype)</description>
			<rom crc="35484751" name="MAME_0.185_Software_List_ROMs_non-merged/MAME_0.185_Software_List_ROMs_non-merged.zip/MAME%200.185%20Software%20List%20ROMs%20%28non-merged%29%2Fa5200%2Faep.zip" sha1="e18a603b18b85e24f9c938b33b6077a767c1fa9c" size="10918" />
			<title_clean>A.E.</title_clean>
			<plot>A port of the classic computer game, A.E. (Which stands for Anti Environmental) is a most unusual 5200 prototype.  It was never announced by Atari nor was it mentioned in any internal documents. A.E. is an arcade style shooting game in which you have to shoot down waves of evil flying mechanical stingrays in order to save your planet.[CR]The Atari 5200 version only has four levels as opposed to ten that the computer versions boast. The loading times for the levels are also longer due to hardware constraints of the Atari 5200.</plot>
			<releasedate>4/1/1984</releasedate>
			<year>1984</year>
			<genre>Shooter</genre>
			<studio>Broderbund Software Inc</studio>
			<nplayers>1</nplayers>
			<videoid>jGSmCUto_Ak</videoid>
			<thegamesdb_id>34468</thegamesdb_id>
			<giantbomb_url>http://www.giantbomb.com/ae/3030-17120/</giantbomb_url>
			<boxart1>VXwL1bp.jpg</boxart1>
			<snapshot1>cHl2ZGz.jpg</snapshot1>
			<snapshot2>eWtsS3b.jpg</snapshot2>
			<snapshot3>nRYNLbl.jpg</snapshot3>
		</game>
		<game name="The Activision Decathlon">
			<description>The Activision Decathlon</description>
			<rom crc="f43e7cd0" name="MAME_0.185_Software_List_ROMs_non-merged/MAME_0.185_Software_List_ROMs_non-merged.zip/MAME%200.185%20Software%20List%20ROMs%20%28non-merged%29%2Fa5200%2Fdecathln.zip" sha1="db203973df13b071da46d52fdb078a76f4db428d" size="12196" />
			<title_clean>The Activision Decathlon</title_clean>
			<plot>The classic game of button smashing and joystick torturing puts you through the series (ten by the number) of track and field events, ranging from long jump over hurdles to javelin throwing, which comprise the Decathlon.The events are:100-Meter DashLong JumpShot PutHigh Jump400-Meter Race110-Meter HurdlesDiscus ThrowPole VaultJavelin Throw1500-Meter RacePoints are awarded for each event with running events garnering the player more points for lower times, jumping events garnering more points for further or higher jumps (this includes the pole vault) and throwing events garnering more points for longer distances thrown. The points are tallied and shown at the end of each event with the final total being given at the end of the game.Game PlayThe Activision Decathlon is a one-player only side-to-side game.This game uses a power meter for each event with power generated by quick side-to-side motion of the players joystick. The faster the side-to-side motion, the higher the power meter goes. Players must generate the highest amount of power possible for each event with some, such as running events, requiring power being generated as quickly as possible and then maintained until the finish of the race. Other events, such as jumping and throwing, require that the player generate the highest amount of power possible and then maintain that power while simultaneously pressing the joystick's button to achieve the furthest jumps and throws and the highest jumps and vaults. Maintaining the highest possible level of power while timing and pressing the button at the best possible moment can be quite challenging.[CR]</plot>
			<releasedate>7/7/1984</releasedate>
			<year>1984</year>
			<genre>Sports</genre>
			<studio>Activision</studio>
			<nplayers>1-4 Alt</nplayers>
			<perspective>3rd-Person</perspective>
			<rating>3.5</rating>
			<thegamesdb_id>5150</thegamesdb_id>
			<mobygames_url>http://www.mobygames.com/game/atari-5200/activision-decathlon</mobygames_url>
			<giantbomb_url>http://www.giantbomb.com/the-activision-decathlon/3030-15063/</giantbomb_url>
			<boxart1>dz0oJSz.jpg</boxart1>
			<boxart2>d3yaORu.jpg</boxart2>
			<boxart3>xVlkdF3.jpg</boxart3>
			<snapshot1>TjJD3h4.gif</snapshot1>
			<snapshot2>KqTsiG2.gif</snapshot2>
			<snapshot3>eUTVxrD.gif</snapshot3>
			<snapshot4>6RKXQ6k.gif</snapshot4>
			<snapshot5>zxr6k4J.gif</snapshot5>
			<snapshot6>XRiAEHW.gif</snapshot6>
			<snapshot7>vqxxmR3.gif</snapshot7>
			<snapshot8>SvxeaaH.gif</snapshot8>
			<snapshot9>nCAi1gB.png</snapshot9>
			<snapshot10>vxvSzB3.png</snapshot10>
		</game>
		<game name="Asteroids (Prototype)">
			<description>Asteroids (Prototype)</description>
			<rom crc="38480891" name="MAME_0.185_Software_List_ROMs_non-merged/MAME_0.185_Software_List_ROMs_non-merged.zip/MAME%200.185%20Software%20List%20ROMs%20%28non-merged%29%2Fa5200%2Fasteroid.zip" sha1="18697dd8e640fa1578b3b4ae09af484c14fb8410" size="5134" />
			<title_clean>Asteroids</title_clean>
			<plot>Trapped in space somewhere between the planets Ortanus and Earth, your ship is suddenly surrounded by a field of massive asteroids. And, as if that weren't enough excitement for one day, a group of alien saucers stage a surprise attack. Quickly you take over the controls to save your ship from imminent doom. You must thrust away from the path of the oncoming asteroids. Put up shields to protect the ship. Hyperspace into thin air. Flip over and get the asteroids attacking from behind. It's all in your hands now. Good luck![CR]Thought to have been planned to be a launch title for the Atari 5200 system due to the catalog number of CX5201. However it was never officially released but the prototype was found eventually. It's very similar to the Atari 8-Bit version of the game but unfortunately the controls are pretty poor with the 5200 joystick. There was an official controller that was planned to be released along with the game but sadly this was not to be.</plot>
			<releasedate>11/5/1982</releasedate>
			<year>1982</year>
			<genre>Shooter</genre>
			<studio>Atari</studio>
			<nplayers>1-4 Sim</nplayers>
			<videoid>7GPmG6S7UXE</videoid>
			<thegamesdb_id>34466</thegamesdb_id>
			<boxart1>9dje1FY.jpg</boxart1>
			<clearlogo1>Suw2HUG.png</clearlogo1>
		</game>
		<game name="Astro Chase">
			<description>Astro Chase</description>
			<rom crc="4019ecec" name="MAME_0.185_Software_List_ROMs_non-merged/MAME_0.185_Software_List_ROMs_non-merged.zip/MAME%200.185%20Software%20List%20ROMs%20%28non-merged%29%2Fa5200%2Fachase.zip" sha1="67e405c37e55dec4071018e8166ab4faf9f21df5" size="10270" />
			<title_clean>Astro Chase</title_clean>
			<plot>As pilot of a spaceship, your job is to save the planet Earth! Eight mega mines are slowly homing in, and you need to destroy them all before they reach Earth. Trying to stop you are a variety of flying saucers which will constantly be chasing you around the planet. Your ship is equipped with lasers which can be used to destroy enemy saucers and the mega mines. Located throughout the space around Earth are eight shield depots; if you fly through one of these, you will temporarily become invincible. Your spaceship also has a limited energy supply; if you get too low on energy, it can be resupplied at one of the generators located in the four corners of the play area. When all of the mega mines have been destroyed, you will move on to the next, faster chase!</plot>
			<releasedate>7/7/1983</releasedate>
			<year>1983</year>
			<genre>Action</genre>
			<studio>Parker Brothers</studio>
			<nplayers>1</nplayers>
			<perspective>3rd-Person</perspective>
			<rating>1.8</rating>
			<thegamesdb_id>5126</thegamesdb_id>
			<mobygames_url>http://www.mobygames.com/game/atari-5200/astro-chase</mobygames_url>
			<giantbomb_url>http://www.giantbomb.com/astro-chase/3030-18571/</giantbomb_url>
			<boxart1>dkFwA7y.jpg</boxart1>
			<boxart2>vL0rhca.jpg</boxart2>
			<boxart3>i2i0Qlj.jpg</boxart3>
			<snapshot1>tM25hoi.gif</snapshot1>
			<snapshot2>l1Gi2ii.gif</snapshot2>
			<snapshot3>pbYgNcO.gif</snapshot3>
			<snapshot4>PNRHiX9.png</snapshot4>
			<snapshot5>joRmgAe.png</snapshot5>
			<snapshot6>Fezc3jr.png</snapshot6>
			<snapshot7>4jEB4RY.png</snapshot7>
			<snapshot8>1DYHLVf.png</snapshot8>
			<snapshot9>YtN08I8.png</snapshot9>
		</game>
		<game name="Ballblazer">
			<description>Ballblazer</description>
			<rom crc="94d97d14" name="MAME_0.185_Software_List_ROMs_non-merged/MAME_0.185_Software_List_ROMs_non-merged.zip/MAME%200.185%20Software%20List%20ROMs%20%28non-merged%29%2Fa5200%2Fballblaz.zip" sha1="ed92ffd21abd50339f5be0cbff9bdcc8fafbc67f" size="18565" />
			<title_clean>Ballblazer</title_clean>
			<plot>In the year 3037, the most competitive sport in the known universe is Ballblazer. For the first time ever, humans from the planet Earth have won the right to compete in the final round of the Ballblazer Championship, to fight for Earth's honor and the title Masterblazer![CR]Ballblazer is a 3D futuristic soccer-like game, where the player (inside a Rotofoil) is set on a one-on-one 1,155 square playing field (the Grid). The objective of the player to kick a floating ball (Plasmorb) inside the opponent's goal (Goalbeams). A player may compete against a human or computer opponent.[CR]The Rotofoil is equipped with a multi-purpose forcefield. This forcefield when in short distance of the Plasmorb will act as a pull field, automatically pulling the Plasmorb towards to player. When a player in possession of the Plasmorb shoots, the forcefield will act as push field and launches the ball. When the match starts, the player must move down field and attempt to gain possession of the Plasmorb using the joystick and blast the Plasmorb to an intended direction. [CR]The player should also be aware that the Goldbeams move slightly every second and the distance between them will shrink. The highest scoring goals are goals made when Goldbeams have disappeared across the horizon (Over The Horizon/OTH shots). A player may also attempt to steal possession of a Plasmorb by rushing beside the opponent and blast the Plasmorb away. The game ends when time runs out or a player wins 10 consecutive goals. If the game ends in a draw, over-time will apply and the first player to score will win the game.[CR][B]Scoring:[/B][CR]Close-in goals - 1 point[CR]Goals near Goldbeams - 2 points[CR]OTH shots - 3 points[CR]Players may steal points from each other by making goals. [CR]The total combined score of both players cannot accede more than 10 points.[CR]A player winning 10 consecutive points automatically wins the game.</plot>
			<releasedate>7/7/1984</releasedate>
			<year>1986</year>
			<genre>Action, Sports</genre>
			<studio>Atari Corporation</studio>
			<nplayers>1-2 Alt</nplayers>
			<perspective>1st-Person</perspective>
			<rating>3.4</rating>
			<thegamesdb_id>5129</thegamesdb_id>
			<mobygames_url>http://www.mobygames.com/game/atari-5200/ballblazer</mobygames_url>
			<giantbomb_url>http://www.giantbomb.com/ballblazer/3030-19682/</giantbomb_url>
			<boxart1>xaZsrAy.jpg</boxart1>
			<boxart2>PqQYPv5.jpg</boxart2>
			<boxart3>EUCU6O1.jpg</boxart3>
			<snapshot1>8UBafui.gif</snapshot1>
			<snapshot2>TKYnWWE.gif</snapshot2>
			<snapshot3>vR46TVe.gif</snapshot3>
			<snapshot4>WmaPVgK.gif</snapshot4>
			<snapshot5>qf2yx3B.gif</snapshot5>
			<snapshot6>QsZxmsh.png</snapshot6>
			<snapshot7>2cf10nP.png</snapshot7>
			<snapshot8>X8S6aLl.png</snapshot8>
			<snapshot9>dhggEyD.png</snapshot9>
			<snapshot10>2MBZGZ6.png</snapshot10>
			<banner1>Md7d0HT.jpg</banner1>
		</game>
		<game name="Barroom Baseball (Prototype)">
			<description>Barroom Baseball (Prototype)</description>
			<rom crc="21d19c8f" name="MAME_0.185_Software_List_ROMs_non-merged/MAME_0.185_Software_List_ROMs_non-merged.zip/MAME%200.185%20Software%20List%20ROMs%20%28non-merged%29%2Fa5200%2Fbarbball.zip" sha1="510ccb20df2ecdbe7f8373de6a9fc11493e8c3f2" size="17144" />
			<title_clean>Barroom Baseball</title_clean>
			<plot>Barroom Baseball was a prototype game coded by Atari in 1983 for use within Atari 5200 arcade machines but it was never released. The game itself is essentially RealSports Baseball modified to remove some of the game options. It was also intended to be a timed game, requiring additional coins or tokens in order to continue with the game. As with RealSports Baseball, Barroom Baseball includes steals, nine different pitch types, hit-and-run plays, synthesized speech, a detailed scoreboard, tag-ups, dirt-colored base paths, the ability to control the speed of pitches and swings of the bat, and other such bells, whistles, and necessities</plot>
			<releasedate>1/1/1983</releasedate>
			<year>1983</year>
			<genre>Sports</genre>
			<studio>Atari</studio>
			<nplayers>1-2 Alt</nplayers>
			<ESRB>E - Everyone</ESRB>
			<thegamesdb_id>37033</thegamesdb_id>
			<boxart1>ZepbVkI.png</boxart1>
		</game>
		<game name="Battlezone (Prototype)">
			<description>Battlezone (Prototype)</description>
			<rom crc="b3b8e314" name="MAME_0.185_Software_List_ROMs_non-merged/MAME_0.185_Software_List_ROMs_non-merged.zip/MAME%200.185%20Software%20List%20ROMs%20%28non-merged%29%2Fa5200%2Fbzone.zip" sha1="a339cddfc28477c21c58783d2d3b0cf0f4626ddf" size="9974" />
			<title_clean>Battlezone</title_clean>
			<plot>A port of the arcade game Battlezone for Atari 5200. Like the arcade game you drive a tank around and shoot enemy tanks while trying to avoid their fire in a 3d environment. It was unfortunately never released and only exists in prototype form. The prototype seems mostly finished but the hit detection seems off at times and not perfected. It also replaces some of the vector based graphics of the arcade with raster likely due to limitations of the Atari 5200. You can also play this with two joysticks which is said to help with controlling the game versus single if you get used to it.</plot>
			<releasedate>15/9/1983</releasedate>
			<year>1983</year>
			<genre>Action, Shooter</genre>
			<studio>Atari</studio>
			<nplayers>1</nplayers>
			<videoid>LsYDnNiEuIA</videoid>
			<thegamesdb_id>34467</thegamesdb_id>
			<boxart1>ccnPZWY.jpg</boxart1>
			<snapshot1>Mhezjez.jpg</snapshot1>
			<snapshot2>HIXoskH.jpg</snapshot2>
			<clearlogo1>XatCMrh.png</clearlogo1>
		</game>
		<game name="Beamrider">
			<description>Beamrider</description>
			<rom crc="9bae58dc" name="MAME_0.185_Software_List_ROMs_non-merged/MAME_0.185_Software_List_ROMs_non-merged.zip/MAME%200.185%20Software%20List%20ROMs%20%28non-merged%29%2Fa5200%2Fbeamridr.zip" sha1="b75d555d059ad61992f9f5a234129ecbf9504c35" size="11200" />
			<title_clean>Beamrider</title_clean>
			<plot>A vast beam matrix has enshrouded the Earth. This glowing blue grid forms the Restrictor Shield, 99 sectors deep and teeming with hostile alien life. Your mission is to move through all sectors, destroying the enemy craft as you progress. Deeper sectors reveal new enemy types, each with their own method of impeding your success.The player's ship can only move left and right, travelling along one of five beams as the blue beam matrix scrolls towards them. The ship is armed a laser lariat and torpedoes, with the laser being the principle weapon. When the fire button is pressed, the laser will shoot along the beam the player is currently on. The main aim is to destroy all white saucers in a sector, causing the Sector Sentinel to appear. This can only be destroyed with a torpedo &#8211; three are given to the player at the start of each sector &#8211; and a successful hit awards bonus points before play progresses to the next sector.  [CR][B]Enemies:[/B][CR]  White Enemy Saucers      These are the main enemies you'll encounter. There are 15 in each sector, and you'll need to blast every one of them before you can progress. Saucers change up their attack pattern every few sectors e.g. dodging from left to right while spewing a string of bombs, or simply flying towards your ship in an attempt to ram you. Once you've destroyed all of the saucers in a sector a Sentinel craft will appear, giving you a chance to destroy it. Saucers appear from Sector 1.  Brown Space Debris      This rock-hard refuse will fly in a straight line down a beam at you. Normal laser fire will not damage it, so it can be avoided or destroyed with one of the three torpedoes you are given at the start of each life. Space debris starts appearing from Sector 2 onwards.    Yellow Chirper Ships      These mouthy aliens will announce their arrival with a twin-trill alert. They will then fly horizontally from one side of the screen to the other. Chirpers do not fire at your ship, and cannot collide with it. As such, they serve merely to provide bonus points for any player with a quick trigger finger. Chirpers start appearing from Sector 4.  Green Blocker Ships         Nigh-indestructible enemies that will streak in from the side of the screen, locking onto the beam that your ship is travelling down before trying to ram you. They must then either be avoided or destroyed with a torpedo, as they are impervious to regular laser fire. Although blockers can appear while clearing a sector of white saucers, they predominantly show up to protect a Sector Sentinel. On later levels, more and more green blockers will assault your craft, attempting to thwart any effort to blow up the Sentinel by blocking your torpedoes and causing you to switch beams to get a clear shot. Blockers start appearing as regular enemies from Sector 6.  Green Bounce Craft      This rotund enemy comes from the side of the screen and bounces horizontally across from one beam to the next, hoping to land on your ship to destroy it. If it is unsuccessful, it will bounce off the opposite side of the screen to return at another random interval. Regular lasers cannot harm it, so shoot it with a torpedo or try not to be on the beam it bounces on. Green bouncers appear from Sector 7.Blue Chargers      Chargers will zip down the screen at you along a random beam. They have two methods of attack, depending on what beam your ship is travelling on. If you're on the same beam as a charger when it reaches the bottom of the screen, it will collide with your ship and destroy it. If you're not on the same beam, the charger will wait for a few seconds before leaving the screen. During this small pause there is a chance that you will move sideways and onto the beam where the stationary charger is lurking, resulting in your death. While they aren't actually destroyed by your laser, firing a quick shot up the beam will cause a charger to bounce backwards into the distance from where it came. Chargers begin to appear from Sector 10.Orange Trackers      These devilish ships will track onto the beam your ship is flying along and attempt to ram you. Unlike green blockers, however, trackers will change beams to follow you should you try to avoid them. Initially, they will only change beam once to try and cause a collision. However, the further into the beam matrix you travel, the more intent the trackers will become; soon they will start to change course two or more times in their efforts. Additionally, they are invulnerable to common laser fire, meaning you'll need to be fast to avoid them or see them off with one of your precious torpedoes. Trackers start appearing at Sector 12.Red Zig Bombs      The final enemy to appear is one of the trickiest. Like the chirper, a Zig bomb will make a sound before making its way onscreen. When it does, it will find the beam your ship is on and start to come towards you. Zig bombs cannot be killed outright with regular laser fire, but they can be handled in various ways. If you manage to shoot a Zig bomb with your laser, it will change from red to green. It will then continue its flight down the beam it has chosen, before disappearing off the bottom of the screen. If, for whatever reason, you don't shoot the Zig bomb, it will travel down the beam before performing a last-minute flip across one beam towards your ship. This means if you fail to shoot the Zig, you should ensure that you are at least two beams away from it before it leaves the screen. Of course, the third method of taking a Zig out is to blast it with a torpedo. Zig bombs will appear from Sector 14 onwards.Sector Sentinel      Once all of the white saucers in a sector have been eliminated, an alarm will sound. The Sector Sentinel will then slide into view from either side of the screen. It will continue across the beam matrix horizon until it is either destroyed or leaves on the side opposite its starting position. During its migration, you can attempt to bring it down with any torpedoes you have in your stock. The higher the sector number, the more green blockers will flood onto the screen to prevent the Sentinel from being destroyed. A successful hit will cause the Sentinel to explode and bonus points are given depending on the number of lives you have accrued. Whether or not you destroy a Sentinel, the sector has been cleared and you move onto the next one. [CR]</plot>
			<releasedate>7/7/1983</releasedate>
			<year>1983</year>
			<genre>Action</genre>
			<studio>Activision</studio>
			<nplayers>1</nplayers>
			<perspective>3rd-Person</perspective>
			<rating>4.0</rating>
			<thegamesdb_id>5131</thegamesdb_id>
			<mobygames_url>http://www.mobygames.com/game/atari-5200/beamrider</mobygames_url>
			<giantbomb_url>http://www.giantbomb.com/beamrider/3030-16123/</giantbomb_url>
			<boxart1>K2qpsbB.jpg</boxart1>
			<boxart2>dk9Uj5W.jpg</boxart2>
			<boxart3>Y2gSbhC.jpg</boxart3>
			<snapshot1>jwgwDWv.gif</snapshot1>
			<snapshot2>NOKezSP.gif</snapshot2>
			<snapshot3>Ii1iqcr.gif</snapshot3>
			<snapshot4>h4RknOI.gif</snapshot4>
			<snapshot5>5KMMvXq.gif</snapshot5>
			<snapshot6>vRVHxJt.gif</snapshot6>
			<snapshot7>3TgI4xj.png</snapshot7>
			<snapshot8>DSbST8a.png</snapshot8>
			<snapshot9>2onSkmy.png</snapshot9>
			<snapshot10>gz5JpUf.png</snapshot10>
			<fanart1>ecYrhPb.jpg</fanart1>
			<banner1>CMuZymt.jpg</banner1>
			<clearlogo1>gr7eoSg.png</clearlogo1>
		</game>
		<game name="Berzerk">
			<description>Berzerk</description>
			<rom crc="be3cd348" name="MAME_0.185_Software_List_ROMs_non-merged/MAME_0.185_Software_List_ROMs_non-merged.zip/MAME%200.185%20Software%20List%20ROMs%20%28non-merged%29%2Fa5200%2Fberzerk.zip" sha1="e56ccc6bf427a832ce00540b02d065a2688260dc" size="12079" />
			<title_clean>Berzerk</title_clean>
			<plot>[CR][B]Overview:[/B][CR]Berzerk is a multi-directional shooter game requiring players to navigate mazes filled with enemy robots. This was one of the first video games to use speech synthesis, featuring robots that talked.The game also features an infamously bizarre variation of a pressured-on-time element. Occasionally a yellow smiley face called " Evil Otto" would appear and feverishly roam about the mazes in attempt to catch the player, while destroying robots standing it his way.[CR]Other Versions[CR]In addition to the arcade original and the popular Atari 2600 version (1982), Berzerk was also ported by General Consumer Electronics for the Vectrex in 1982, and by Atari to the Atari 5200 in 1983. Stern Electronics made one sequel to the game titled Frenzy, which was only in arcades and ported to the ColecoVision.[CR]Deaths Associated with Berzerk[CR]In 1981, Berzerk became an early example of death by playing a video game. After attaining a score of 1660, a 19 year old named Jeff Dailey died from a heart attack. The very next year, another player named Peter Burkowski also died from a heart attack. This happened shortly after he achieved two high scores within a fifteen minute time span. He was 18 years old.[CR]</plot>
			<releasedate>7/7/1983</releasedate>
			<year>1983</year>
			<genre>Action</genre>
			<studio>Atari</studio>
			<nplayers>1-2 Sim</nplayers>
			<perspective>Top-Down</perspective>
			<rating>4.1</rating>
			<thegamesdb_id>5133</thegamesdb_id>
			<mobygames_url>http://www.mobygames.com/game/atari-5200/berzerk</mobygames_url>
			<giantbomb_url>http://www.giantbomb.com/berzerk/3030-4010/</giantbomb_url>
			<boxart1>2knpPOb.jpg</boxart1>
			<boxart2>h1JvRJf.jpg</boxart2>
			<boxart3>4RHwjCU.jpg</boxart3>
			<snapshot1>JKxwwki.gif</snapshot1>
			<snapshot2>g5EwHJ4.gif</snapshot2>
			<snapshot3>beTkngm.gif</snapshot3>
			<snapshot4>cZCctvx.gif</snapshot4>
			<snapshot5>oSEyPl6.gif</snapshot5>
			<snapshot6>SqWchcI.png</snapshot6>
			<snapshot7>Oyh2LyY.png</snapshot7>
			<snapshot8>jWHduJt.png</snapshot8>
			<snapshot9>l6LoYWU.png</snapshot9>
			<snapshot10>bLusJki.png</snapshot10>
			<banner1>s020ThD.jpg</banner1>
			<clearlogo1>0V6WrpQ.png</clearlogo1>
		</game>
		<game name="Black Belt (Prototype)">
			<description>Black Belt (Prototype)</description>
			<rom crc="ed47b0d8" name="MAME_0.185_Software_List_ROMs_non-merged/MAME_0.185_Software_List_ROMs_non-merged.zip/MAME%200.185%20Software%20List%20ROMs%20%28non-merged%29%2Fa5200%2Fblckbelt.zip" sha1="9b7ecd444b6239442ef1f54cd8e14c294c064da2" size="11877" />
			<title_clean>Black Belt</title_clean>
			<plot>This unreleased, unfinished game is similar to Broderbund's famous game, Karateka. Select your black belt level (difficulty level) and fight your way through eight rooms. The keypad is used to execute a variety of karate moves, although the game has no collision detection so you can't really fight your enemies. While the game looks promising, you cannot progress beyond eight rooms because you can't defeat your enemies.</plot>
			<genre>Fighting</genre>
			<studio>Atari</studio>
			<nplayers>1</nplayers>
			<thegamesdb_id>32353</thegamesdb_id>
			<boxart1>F1PuDkY.png</boxart1>
			<boxart2>vsXYtP6.jpg</boxart2>
			<snapshot1>ulQCvpD.jpg</snapshot1>
			<snapshot2>1cP2VkK.jpg</snapshot2>
			<snapshot3>zlovdoV.jpg</snapshot3>
			<snapshot4>c8ldOPn.jpg</snapshot4>
			<snapshot5>AbYh81t.jpg</snapshot5>
			<snapshot6>CUA08ya.jpg</snapshot6>
			<snapshot7>QVRZxnz.jpg</snapshot7>
		</game>
		<game name="Blaster (Prototype)">
			<description>Blaster (Prototype)</description>
			<rom crc="c8f9c094" name="MAME_0.185_Software_List_ROMs_non-merged/MAME_0.185_Software_List_ROMs_non-merged.zip/MAME%200.185%20Software%20List%20ROMs%20%28non-merged%29%2Fa5200%2Fblaster.zip" sha1="ab3130256d16af09cac8b11749dfaff6aaaa3ea3" size="12576" />
			<title_clean>Blaster</title_clean>
			<plot>Blaster developed by Vid Kidz for Williams was released for the arcades and is quite obscure. What is interesting however is that the Atari 5200 version that was not released was actually made before the arcade game.[CR]An unofficial sequel to Robotron 2084 (As it takes place in 2085) Blaster is a 3d style shooter with impressive graphics for the time. In it the player takes the view from a spaceship cockpit so moving in the different directions shifts the entire screen. There are four levels you will play through avoiding obstacles, saving humans, and defeating alien enemies. Upon beating the four levels the game loops but will be more difficult.</plot>
			<genre>Shooter</genre>
			<studio>Atari</studio>
			<nplayers>1</nplayers>
			<videoid>sg5yD_HKMkU</videoid>
			<thegamesdb_id>34470</thegamesdb_id>
			<boxart1>o0SvpTz.jpg</boxart1>
			<snapshot1>k6JLXnq.jpg</snapshot1>
			<snapshot2>gCVItRQ.jpg</snapshot2>
		</game>
		<game name="Blue-Print">
			<description>Blue-Print</description>
			<rom crc="0624e6e7" name="MAME_0.185_Software_List_ROMs_non-merged/MAME_0.185_Software_List_ROMs_non-merged.zip/MAME%200.185%20Software%20List%20ROMs%20%28non-merged%29%2Fa5200%2Fblueprnt.zip" sha1="1e1a20c104bf4d55eca0ca1e72dc5dc64fa6b1b5" size="11156" />
			<title_clean>Blue-Print</title_clean>
			<plot>Your girlfriend Daisy is in trouble! Ollie Org is chasing her across the top of the screen, and you need to come to the rescue. To stop Ollie before time runs out, you need to construct a machine. The blue print for the machine is at the bottom of the screen, so all you need to do is locate the parts which are hidden in the numerous houses in a maze like town. When you locate a part, drag it back and place it on the blue print. When all parts have been located, press the start button and the machine is ready to go! To make your task more difficult, there are several obstacles that get in the way. If you enter a house which doesn't contain a part, you will instead be stuck with a bomb. You will need to hurry and diffuse any bombs in the bomb pit before they explode! From time to time, a flower pot will fall from above and then hop off the screen. Get hit by a flower pot, and you lose a life. You also need to be careful of Fuzzy Wuzzy, who wanders around the neighborhood randomly. An encounter with Fuzzy Wuzzy will also be deadly! Hiding in the bomb pit is Sneaky Pete; while he isn't deadly, he will occasionally appear and press the start button before your machine is complete. If this happens, you will need to drag Pete back to the bomb pit and reassemble all of the machine parts.</plot>
			<releasedate>31/12/1983</releasedate>
			<year>1983</year>
			<genre>Action</genre>
			<studio>CBS Electronics, Bally Midway MFG. Co.</studio>
			<nplayers>1</nplayers>
			<perspective>3rd-Person</perspective>
			<rating>4.2</rating>
			<thegamesdb_id>5134</thegamesdb_id>
			<mobygames_url>http://www.mobygames.com/game/atari-5200/blueprint</mobygames_url>
			<giantbomb_url>http://www.giantbomb.com/blue-print/3030-12545/</giantbomb_url>
			<boxart1>FR5URrZ.jpg</boxart1>
			<boxart2>h8FBasj.jpg</boxart2>
			<boxart3>f3vg2zK.jpg</boxart3>
			<snapshot1>Zicfeej.gif</snapshot1>
			<snapshot2>6NzVtM5.gif</snapshot2>
			<snapshot3>C8amBYK.gif</snapshot3>
			<snapshot4>zlAfsHa.gif</snapshot4>
			<snapshot5>PPtrO6Q.gif</snapshot5>
			<snapshot6>0HEvxOE.png</snapshot6>
			<snapshot7>rOEWT8K.png</snapshot7>
			<snapshot8>rXNI9Ar.png</snapshot8>
			<clearlogo1>DjeJ6Xh.png</clearlogo1>
		</game>
		<game name="Bounty Bob Strikes Back!">
			<description>Bounty Bob Strikes Back!</description>
			<rom crc="7873c6dd" name="MAME_0.185_Software_List_ROMs_non-merged/MAME_0.185_Software_List_ROMs_non-merged.zip/MAME%200.185%20Software%20List%20ROMs%20%28non-merged%29%2Fa5200%2Fbbsb.zip" sha1="cfdd2f8dabb03d8784f336bb0c804270dc3a8a6c" size="33405" />
			<title_clean>Bounty Bob Strikes Back!</title_clean>
			<plot>[CR]Players control a miner named Bounty Bob that has to claim every square of a mine while pursuing the evil Yukon Yohan.[CR][B]Gameplay:[/B][CR]The game, as originally developed on Atari 8-bit platforms, consists of 25 levels where players complete a series of jumping puzzles in order to claim all the land in a mine. Ladders, Slides, and Suction Cups are there to help the player along the way. Land is "claimed" by walking over it, which fills in lines on the various platforms that make up each level. When the entire level is filled in, the level is complete and play proceeds onto the next stage.Bounty Bob will lose a life if he falls down or comes into contact with a mutant. Mutants can be made safe by collecting any of the irradiated objects strewn about the level, which turns the glowing mutants into harmless green creatures for a brief period. The nature of the collectable items and the limited time with which the player can turn the tables on the enemies are reminiscent of elements of Donkey Kong and Pac-Man.The different ports of BBSB! made various changes to "fit" the game onto different hardware. The BBC Micro version, for example, has 20 levels.[CR]</plot>
			<releasedate>7/7/1985</releasedate>
			<year>1985</year>
			<genre>Action</genre>
			<studio>Big Five Software</studio>
			<nplayers>1</nplayers>
			<perspective>3rd-Person</perspective>
			<rating>4.0</rating>
			<thegamesdb_id>5136</thegamesdb_id>
			<mobygames_url>http://www.mobygames.com/game/atari-5200/bounty-bob-strikes-back</mobygames_url>
			<giantbomb_url>http://www.giantbomb.com/bounty-bob-strikes-back/3030-5532/</giantbomb_url>
			<boxart1>nffZ77M.jpg</boxart1>
			<boxart2>DJItcuL.jpg</boxart2>
			<snapshot1>BQ3E2Qd.gif</snapshot1>
			<snapshot2>84gdoSB.gif</snapshot2>
			<snapshot3>d7k7Okv.gif</snapshot3>
			<snapshot4>pVkwjTn.gif</snapshot4>
			<snapshot5>134VNC8.gif</snapshot5>
			<snapshot6>X2dIJHL.gif</snapshot6>
			<snapshot7>4hj8IbG.gif</snapshot7>
			<snapshot8>cf3LILT.gif</snapshot8>
			<snapshot9>04fZydz.gif</snapshot9>
			<snapshot10>WR3wiYW.gif</snapshot10>
		</game>
		<game name="Buck Rogers - Planet of Zoom">
			<description>Buck Rogers - Planet of Zoom</description>
			<rom crc="04807705" name="MAME_0.185_Software_List_ROMs_non-merged/MAME_0.185_Software_List_ROMs_non-merged.zip/MAME%200.185%20Software%20List%20ROMs%20%28non-merged%29%2Fa5200%2Fbuckrog.zip" sha1="bc7c81f758dd3e224e42ac8a16c1a12d69aed722" size="9731" />
			<title_clean>Buck Rogers - Planet of Zoom</title_clean>
			<plot>[CR][B]Overview:[/B][CR]Originally released as Zoom 909 in Japan, this arcade game is a forward-scrolling, pseudo-3D, third-person rail shooter, released by Sega in 1982. Its gameplay is a precursor to Sega's 1983 laserdisc arcade game Astron Belt and 1985 arcade hit Space Harrier.The game released in both upright and cockpit cabinet versions. It released Japan and North America in 1982, and in Europe in 1983. The July 1983 issue of British magazine Computer &amp; Video Games noted that the setting resembles the Death Star in Star Wars. [CR]</plot>
			<releasedate>7/7/1983</releasedate>
			<year>1983</year>
			<genre>Action</genre>
			<studio>Sega</studio>
			<nplayers>1</nplayers>
			<perspective>3rd-Person</perspective>
			<thegamesdb_id>5138</thegamesdb_id>
			<mobygames_url>http://www.mobygames.com/game/atari-5200/buck-rogers-planet-of-zoom</mobygames_url>
			<giantbomb_url>http://www.giantbomb.com/buck-rogers-planet-of-zoom/3030-12285/</giantbomb_url>
			<boxart1>u41G6wL.jpg</boxart1>
			<boxart2>WHVb6kF.jpg</boxart2>
			<boxart3>jIoYrKZ.jpg</boxart3>
			<snapshot1>ZpxHq6h.gif</snapshot1>
			<snapshot2>Sbbktu0.gif</snapshot2>
			<snapshot3>QtKeo1b.gif</snapshot3>
			<snapshot4>8blxl4X.gif</snapshot4>
			<snapshot5>gycV1Pw.png</snapshot5>
			<snapshot6>7rC8cOG.png</snapshot6>
			<snapshot7>o3t04zf.png</snapshot7>
			<snapshot8>hQSr3hJ.png</snapshot8>
			<snapshot9>cyAxjld.png</snapshot9>
			<snapshot10>MlkkkU9.png</snapshot10>
			<banner1>SOk5J6i.jpg</banner1>
			<clearlogo1>Iwtl45S.png</clearlogo1>
		</game>
		<game name="Centipede">
			<description>Centipede</description>
			<rom crc="536a70fe" name="MAME_0.185_Software_List_ROMs_non-merged/MAME_0.185_Software_List_ROMs_non-merged.zip/MAME%200.185%20Software%20List%20ROMs%20%28non-merged%29%2Fa5200%2Fcentiped.zip" sha1="eb343b90d3de696e69b1f039d4fb2c6afb0d80c0" size="8706" />
			<title_clean>Centipede</title_clean>
			<plot>In Centipede, the player is trapped in the Enchanted Forest. Armed with only a magic wand to ward off the forest's insect denizens, all of which apparently are attacking in the player in continuous waves. [CR]The player must use the magic wand to shoot sparks at approaching insects to score points by pressing the controller button. Holding down the controller button will set the wand to rapid fire shots. If the player is bitten by an insect, the player will be temporarily paralyzed and lose one of the three starting magic wands. [CR]Insect Opponents and Mushrooms[CR]All enemy insects have a distinctive sound before attacking, which may help the player identify which insect is attacking. Enemies and objects in the game are as the following:[CR]1. The Centipede[CR]The Centipede will attack in 12 waves. In the first wave, the Centipede will have a head attached to 11 body segments. In the second wave, the Centipede will have a head attached to 10 body segments, in addition to a detached head. The third wave will have the Centipede with an attached head, 9 body segments, plus two detached heads. These body segments will transform into heads and continue to do so until Wave 12. In the last wave, the Centipede will have 12 detached heads, independently attacking the player. Centipede heads are worth more points than body segments.[CR]Attacks from the Centipede will come from the top of the screen, moving downward. If a spark hits any part of the Centipede, that particular body segment will transform into a mushroom, while the body segment behind it will become the new Centipede head. When the Centipede is destroyed, it will briefly disappear and re-appear from the top of the screen again.[CR]The Spider[CR]The Spider will attempt to distract the player from attacking the Centipede. It will destroy any mushroom it touches. Spiders will score more points if it is hit in closer distances.[CR]The Flea[CR]The Flea will appear if the player has destroyed most of the existing mushrooms. It will drop down creating a new batch of mushrooms where it falls. The Flea will disappear after two hits. After the first hit, the Flea will drop down much faster.[CR]The Scorpion[CR]The Scorpion will appear in the third wave. It moves slowly but will pick up speed, moving faster. While doing so, it will poison any mushroom it touches.[CR]Mushrooms[CR]Mushrooms fill the Enchanted Forest and may act as obstacles or cover for the player, with added effects to enemy insects. It takes for shots to complete destroy a mushroom. There are two type of mushrooms: Magic Mushrooms and Poisonous mushrooms. Magic mushrooms are the default mushrooms in the game and are also the the result of the player destroying an insect or Centipede body segment. Poisonous Mushrooms are the result of the Scorpion touching a mushroom. Poisonous Mushrooms will prompt the Centipede near it to move straight towards the player through any mushroom. Losing a wand will restore any partially damaged mushroom.[CR]Game Difficulty and Variations[CR]The game offers four difficulty levels: Novice, Standard, Advanced, and Expert. Game Variations are as the following:[CR]1. One Player[CR]Two Player Alternating[CR]Two players will take turns when the active player is bitten.[CR]Dual Player Competition[CR]Two players will appear on the screen at the same time. Scoring is separate. Shots fired from one player will paralyze the other player.[CR]Team Play[CR]Two players will appear on the screen at the same time. Scoring is combined. Shots fired from one player will not paralyze the other player.[CR][B]Scoring:[/B][CR]The player will win a bonus magic wand for every 12,000 points to a maximum of six wands. The game will end when all wands are lost. Scoring are as the following:[CR]Centipede Head - 100 points[CR]Centipede Body Segment - 10 points[CR]Spider at close range - 900 points[CR]Spider at medium range - 600 points[CR]Flea - 200 points[CR]Scorpion - 1,000 points[CR]Flea - 200 points[CR]Restored mushroom - 5 points[CR]Destroyed mushroom - 1 points</plot>
			<releasedate>7/7/1982</releasedate>
			<year>1982</year>
			<studio>Atari</studio>
			<nplayers>1-2 Sim</nplayers>
			<rating>4.3</rating>
			<thegamesdb_id>5141</thegamesdb_id>
			<mobygames_url>http://www.mobygames.com/game/atari-5200/centipede_</mobygames_url>
			<giantbomb_url>http://www.giantbomb.com/centipede/3030-1157/</giantbomb_url>
			<boxart1>46LPnWK.jpg</boxart1>
			<boxart2>DXQhiTf.jpg</boxart2>
			<boxart3>mZaLrVh.jpg</boxart3>
			<snapshot1>XpljU4I.jpg</snapshot1>
			<snapshot2>Y2jqzow.gif</snapshot2>
			<snapshot3>etACY3J.gif</snapshot3>
			<snapshot4>2OpJy1h.gif</snapshot4>
			<snapshot5>ulUXcoD.gif</snapshot5>
			<snapshot6>414sfBu.gif</snapshot6>
			<snapshot7>PBGLiJE.png</snapshot7>
			<snapshot8>Itq6tb5.png</snapshot8>
			<snapshot9>KbG3AKV.png</snapshot9>
			<snapshot10>f4VVI7N.png</snapshot10>
			<banner1>GBoFLcB.jpg</banner1>
			<clearlogo1>5geAvTt.png</clearlogo1>
		</game>
		<game name="Choplifter!">
			<description>Choplifter!</description>
			<rom crc="9ad53bbc" name="MAME_0.185_Software_List_ROMs_non-merged/MAME_0.185_Software_List_ROMs_non-merged.zip/MAME%200.185%20Software%20List%20ROMs%20%28non-merged%29%2Fa5200%2Fchoplift.zip" sha1="9f1ee191319ef0261cc7074a81c0e6d6b7464cd2" size="11132" />
			<title_clean>Choplifter!</title_clean>
			<plot>[CR][B]Overview:[/B][CR]Choplifter is a side-scrolling action game in which the player controls a helicopter that must elude the various enemy military forces trying to shoot it down while rescuing prisoners. It debuted on the Apple-II home computer in 1982 before being ported or adapted for a number of other home computers and consoles throughout the 1980s. It also saw multiple sequels.One of the earliest video games to have an  exclaimed! title. While the original game and early licensed ports of Choplifter! have an exclamation point on the box art and/or title screen, later ports (notably Sega's) omitted it and subsequent games in the series followed suit.[CR]</plot>
			<releasedate>7/7/1984</releasedate>
			<year>1984</year>
			<genre>Action</genre>
			<studio>Midway Games West</studio>
			<nplayers>1</nplayers>
			<perspective>Side-Scrolling</perspective>
			<rating>2.2</rating>
			<thegamesdb_id>5143</thegamesdb_id>
			<mobygames_url>http://www.mobygames.com/game/atari-5200/choplifter</mobygames_url>
			<giantbomb_url>http://www.giantbomb.com/choplifter/3030-18152/</giantbomb_url>
			<boxart1>lASSrum.jpg</boxart1>
			<boxart2>7PLtuqC.jpg</boxart2>
			<boxart3>dOltD6a.jpg</boxart3>
			<snapshot1>4mJpqFo.png</snapshot1>
			<snapshot2>HMaLmym.png</snapshot2>
			<snapshot3>QxNwSsx.png</snapshot3>
			<snapshot4>GwsXpH9.png</snapshot4>
			<snapshot5>XfSPC6s.png</snapshot5>
			<snapshot6>SClzPpt.png</snapshot6>
			<snapshot7>1sCu3gk.jpg</snapshot7>
			<snapshot8>XyL3hsZ.jpg</snapshot8>
			<snapshot9>FeelBoc.jpg</snapshot9>
			<snapshot10>6skkJeb.jpg</snapshot10>
			<banner1>qb54Xtq.jpg</banner1>
			<clearlogo1>HvrgzS9.png</clearlogo1>
		</game>
		<game name="Congo Bongo">
			<description>Congo Bongo</description>
			<rom crc="f1f42bbd" name="MAME_0.185_Software_List_ROMs_non-merged/MAME_0.185_Software_List_ROMs_non-merged.zip/MAME%200.185%20Software%20List%20ROMs%20%28non-merged%29%2Fa5200%2Fcongo.zip" sha1="e0203c2124127eba2d679be548fa257ecc5b2607" size="11677" />
			<title_clean>Congo Bongo</title_clean>
			<plot>[CR][B]Overview:[/B][CR] One levels plays very much like Donkey KongCongo Bongo was first created by    Sega to compete with arcade games such as   Donkey Kong or  Frogger. It never found the success of Donkey Kong and Frogger, and it was very much a commercial failure. Despite its lack of success in the arcades, it was eventually ported to most home computers and game home consoles.     [CR][B]Story:[/B][CR] Bongo is a mischievous ape that sets the tent of safari hunter on fire. The safari hunter lost his tent and possessions, and he seeks revenge on the ape for his practical joke. The safari hunter chases Bongo and through the dangerous Congo to get his revenge. [CR][B]Gameplay:[/B] [CR] Rhinos, one of the many dangers in the CongoCongo Bongo takes place in an isometric perspective, and requires the player to move a safari hunter through for different levels. One level, that resembles Donkey Kong, has the hunter climbing a mountain while simultaneously avoiding coconuts that a gorilla is hurling its way. Two levels have that hunter moving through a level avoiding hippos and rhinos. The last level very much resembles frogger, and has the hunter crossing a river across logs and lily pads.  These four levels will loop until the player loses all their lives.[CR]</plot>
			<releasedate>7/7/1983</releasedate>
			<year>1983</year>
			<genre>Action</genre>
			<studio>SEGA Corporation</studio>
			<nplayers>1-2 Sim</nplayers>
			<perspective>Isometric</perspective>
			<rating>2.0</rating>
			<thegamesdb_id>5147</thegamesdb_id>
			<mobygames_url>http://www.mobygames.com/game/atari-5200/congo-bongo</mobygames_url>
			<giantbomb_url>http://www.giantbomb.com/congo-bongo/3030-4169/</giantbomb_url>
			<boxart1>jvRwqYb.jpg</boxart1>
			<boxart2>KQdHlP1.jpg</boxart2>
			<boxart3>Fzqfxyu.jpg</boxart3>
			<snapshot1>05zUvkv.gif</snapshot1>
			<snapshot2>1Fdnxhm.gif</snapshot2>
			<snapshot3>XhTugbR.gif</snapshot3>
			<snapshot4>nZPF0wp.png</snapshot4>
			<snapshot5>Qf5NujA.jpg</snapshot5>
			<snapshot6>LlN6ciP.png</snapshot6>
			<snapshot7>OeeIp7I.jpg</snapshot7>
			<snapshot8>AdLZSAj.png</snapshot8>
			<snapshot9>VG5sYFF.png</snapshot9>
			<clearlogo1>4OfqtHm.png</clearlogo1>
		</game>
		<game name="Countermeasure">
			<description>Countermeasure</description>
			<rom crc="fd541c80" name="MAME_0.185_Software_List_ROMs_non-merged/MAME_0.185_Software_List_ROMs_non-merged.zip/MAME%200.185%20Software%20List%20ROMs%20%28non-merged%29%2Fa5200%2Fcntrmsre.zip" sha1="fa6d77e6e9afd0ea42fc9f9807932bf9e8fb170e" size="11255" />
			<title_clean>Countermeasure</title_clean>
			<plot>Terrorists have seized control of several missile silos and are planning on launching missiles to blow up Washington D.C. Your job is to stop them! From a top down point of view, you control a tank over varied, scrolling terrain. To stop the missiles, you have two options: you can destroy all of the missiles, or attempt to guess the fail safe code. If you try to destroy all the missiles, you must do so in under ten minutes. The missiles silos have many defenses which the terrorists also control; pillboxes, tanks, jeeps, and cruise missiles are all capable of destroying your tank. Should you attempt to guess the fail safe code, clues can be found by docking at supply depots. The code is three letters long, and can consist of any combination of L, E and O. When you enter a war room, you have a very short time to enter the code correctly or the missiles will launch. When the missiles have been stopped (by either means), the level is complete and you continue on to the next, more difficult round.</plot>
			<releasedate>7/7/1982</releasedate>
			<year>1982</year>
			<genre>Action</genre>
			<studio>Midway Games West</studio>
			<nplayers>1-2 Sim</nplayers>
			<perspective>3rd-Person</perspective>
			<rating>3.2</rating>
			<thegamesdb_id>5148</thegamesdb_id>
			<mobygames_url>http://www.mobygames.com/game/atari-5200/countermeasure</mobygames_url>
			<giantbomb_url>http://www.giantbomb.com/countermeasure/3030-13853/</giantbomb_url>
			<boxart1>G9nYZFT.jpg</boxart1>
			<boxart2>PRbFtm6.jpg</boxart2>
			<boxart3>EjiaQJV.jpg</boxart3>
			<snapshot1>QCVc8nd.gif</snapshot1>
			<snapshot2>ZVj8n56.gif</snapshot2>
			<snapshot3>SXoWMKf.gif</snapshot3>
			<snapshot4>cGzHwCD.gif</snapshot4>
			<snapshot5>CYnTTCi.gif</snapshot5>
			<snapshot6>LCyVFCL.gif</snapshot6>
			<snapshot7>bYaWuok.gif</snapshot7>
			<snapshot8>U16lA3H.gif</snapshot8>
			<snapshot9>xzeS6RI.gif</snapshot9>
			<snapshot10>aciufox.png</snapshot10>
			<banner1>aEoERWS.jpg</banner1>
		</game>
		<game name="David Crane's Pitfall II - Lost Caverns">
			<description>David Crane's Pitfall II - Lost Caverns</description>
			<rom crc="4b910461" name="MAME_0.185_Software_List_ROMs_non-merged/MAME_0.185_Software_List_ROMs_non-merged.zip/MAME%200.185%20Software%20List%20ROMs%20%28non-merged%29%2Fa5200%2Fpitfall2.zip" sha1="b051f0fb2e816787ab6eed0cb008b9f8cc9963dc" size="11073" />
			<title_clean>David Crane's Pitfall II - Lost Caverns</title_clean>
			<plot>You play Pitfall Harry searching for the Raj diamond, his niece Rhonda, and a variety of treasures somewhere in the Andes. Poisonous frogs, eels, scorpions, bats and other hazards get in the way.Pitfall II is the sequel to Pitfall!, the original platform game. Gameplay has remained pretty much the same, with each screen presenting a side view of obstacles to get past, and potentially treasures to collect. The landscape is more maze like, with a variety of paths and dead ends to search. Along the way there are checkpoints the player will encounter. When the player dies, Pitfall Harry will be sent back to the most recently crossed checkpoint.</plot>
			<year>1984</year>
			<genre>Action</genre>
			<studio>Activision</studio>
			<nplayers>1</nplayers>
			<mobygames_url>http://www.mobygames.com/game/atari-5200/pitfall-ii-lost-caverns</mobygames_url>
			<boxart1>iDQdCFR.jpg</boxart1>
			<boxart2>HmDfRtg.jpg</boxart2>
			<boxart3>baxpu2z.jpg</boxart3>
			<snapshot1>Pw3xWZd.gif</snapshot1>
			<snapshot2>2zDZh3b.gif</snapshot2>
			<snapshot3>bmjIN4O.gif</snapshot3>
			<snapshot4>tBFmtPO.gif</snapshot4>
			<snapshot5>ycotpkC.gif</snapshot5>
			<snapshot6>4oLWxaM.gif</snapshot6>
		</game>
		<game name="Defender">
			<description>Defender</description>
			<rom crc="bd52623b" name="MAME_0.185_Software_List_ROMs_non-merged/MAME_0.185_Software_List_ROMs_non-merged.zip/MAME%200.185%20Software%20List%20ROMs%20%28non-merged%29%2Fa5200%2Fdefender.zip" sha1="44f6dbf5013a70e646d5c5232981d517069fc449" size="9395" />
			<title_clean>Defender</title_clean>
			<plot>[CR][B]Overview:[/B][CR]Defender is a  side scrolling shoot 'em up, and one one of the first space shooters to feature the freedom to move left or right. Gameplay[CR]The player flies left or right looking for UFOs to shoot. An HUD located on the top of the screen indicates where the UFOs are located; the goal is to achieve as many points as possible.Defender has a wrap-around landscape, and that landscape contains as many as ten humanoids. Alien ships called Landers attempt to abduct these humanoids. If a Lander grabs a humanoid and carries it up to the top of the screen, the Lander and humanoid merge into a much more aggressive Mutant ship. If all of the humanoids are killed, the land at the bottom of the screen explodes and the player must fight in empty space. At this point, all the Landers become Mutants. Every fifth wave restores the humanoid count to ten, regenerating the planetary surface, if necessary.Defender had a fairly complicated control scheme for the time, with a lever for moving up and down and buttons for thrust, fire, reverse, smart bomb, and hyperspace. Most ports and even some emulated versions of Defender replace the thrust and reverse buttons in favor of a four-way joystick to control movement and direction.The game was programmed by  Eugene Jarvis and  Larry DeMar, who would later go on to form an external development company known as Vid Kidz.[CR]</plot>
			<releasedate>7/7/1982</releasedate>
			<year>1982</year>
			<genre>Action</genre>
			<studio>Atari</studio>
			<nplayers>1-2 Alt</nplayers>
			<perspective>Side-Scrolling</perspective>
			<rating>4.1</rating>
			<thegamesdb_id>5151</thegamesdb_id>
			<mobygames_url>http://www.mobygames.com/game/atari-5200/defender</mobygames_url>
			<giantbomb_url>http://www.giantbomb.com/defender/3030-5536/</giantbomb_url>
			<boxart1>tLrRP4p.jpg</boxart1>
			<boxart2>GJN9I5u.jpg</boxart2>
			<boxart3>K7ONAj3.jpg</boxart3>
			<snapshot1>aL6T0Yp.gif</snapshot1>
			<snapshot2>xgaahRS.gif</snapshot2>
			<snapshot3>hO7sgax.gif</snapshot3>
			<snapshot4>HHhHddK.gif</snapshot4>
			<snapshot5>tcFAmFG.gif</snapshot5>
			<snapshot6>nztPcfY.gif</snapshot6>
			<snapshot7>SHZ3rhn.jpg</snapshot7>
			<snapshot8>9w3BmKY.jpg</snapshot8>
			<snapshot9>uVqyd38.png</snapshot9>
			<snapshot10>jEW7h5t.png</snapshot10>
			<banner1>UtxJPRB.jpg</banner1>
			<clearlogo1>zwNDAvc.png</clearlogo1>
		</game>
		<game name="Dig Dug">
			<description>Dig Dug</description>
			<rom crc="6a687f9c" name="MAME_0.185_Software_List_ROMs_non-merged/MAME_0.185_Software_List_ROMs_non-merged.zip/MAME%200.185%20Software%20List%20ROMs%20%28non-merged%29%2Fa5200%2Fdigdug.zip" sha1="387a76ba5912251e2285b7722004ad75e9ede523" size="11895" />
			<title_clean>Dig Dug</title_clean>
			<plot>[CR][B]Overview:[/B][CR]  View zoomed image in  gallery for animation.     You play as Dig Dug (who is also known as    Taizo Hori in other games that he appears in), a  pump wielding spelunker who faces several enemies while he digs    underground. The object of each level (or board) is to clear it of all of the enemies before they kill you by walking to within a set distance and pushing the button to fill the up with air until they explode. Another more strategic way to dispatch your enemies would be to dig underneath    boulders that are located on each level and drop them on to to enemies that are below them. It could be argued that this was one of the first major acts of  violence  in a video game, but due to it's cartoon like nature it was probably overlooked at the time. The original game was released into arcades by Namco in 1982, and contained the standard (at the time) of 256 levels before you reached a    "kill screen" and the game either froze up or  reset itself. Another source of scoring points throughout the game is the inclusion of a fruit or item in the center of the screen that would appear after dropping two of the levels boulders. This mechanic is very similar to another Namco game series,    Pac-Man. The boulders did not have to drop on enemies for the fruits to appear however. The bonus items include :    Carrot,  Turnip, Zucchini (or Cucumber),    Eggplant,  Green Pepper,    Tomato,    Garlic,    Watermelon,    Pineapple, as well as the inclusion of a  Warship from Namco's    Galaxian.     [CR][B]Enemies:[/B][CR]PookaPooka: Best described as a round orange ball with aviator goggles, Pooka is the most common enemy that you will  face in the game. Not as overly aggressive as his counter part, he as well as Fygar still has the ability to pass through  the un-dug parts of the dirt in each level to attack you from any angle.  FygarFygar: A dragon-like creature, not only can he pass through the dirt and attack you but also has the ability to breathe fire, making him a decidedly more difficult and deadly enemy.[CR][B]Legacy:[/B][CR]Dig-Dug is considered to be a classic and has spawned many    sequels and has appeared on many    compilations and game download services since its initial release. The character of DIg-Dug also has a son named Susumu Hori ( that appears in the    Mr. Driller series), continuing the family legacy of digging to the depths of the earth.  Downloading and playing the demo of the XBLA version unlocks a Gamerpic. [CR]Critical Reception[CR]When the Game Boy version was released in 1993 Electronic Gaming Monthly awarded the game scores of 6,6,6, and 5.  They stated, "...the game play is intact and the graphics are decent for GB standards.  A few new features [are] thrown in for a little variety and you have a solid little GB cart that's great for long road trips".[CR]</plot>
			<releasedate>7/7/1983</releasedate>
			<year>1983</year>
			<genre>Action</genre>
			<studio>Atari</studio>
			<nplayers>1-2 Sim</nplayers>
			<perspective>3rd-Person</perspective>
			<rating>3.6</rating>
			<videoid>Pd6TTrVdm7s</videoid>
			<thegamesdb_id>5153</thegamesdb_id>
			<mobygames_url>http://www.mobygames.com/game/atari-5200/dig-dug</mobygames_url>
			<giantbomb_url>http://www.giantbomb.com/dig-dug/3030-2587/</giantbomb_url>
			<boxart1>hpsFfkS.jpg</boxart1>
			<boxart2>ilx1mpS.jpg</boxart2>
			<boxart3>xmFXC2u.jpg</boxart3>
			<snapshot1>OC7l9B8.jpg</snapshot1>
			<snapshot2>QUQ70Mj.gif</snapshot2>
			<snapshot3>nmNvt74.gif</snapshot3>
			<snapshot4>4Du4cip.gif</snapshot4>
			<snapshot5>IzaS3Mo.gif</snapshot5>
			<snapshot6>9HI7mv2.gif</snapshot6>
			<snapshot7>Ecmb8bj.jpg</snapshot7>
			<snapshot8>ehaEtba.jpg</snapshot8>
			<snapshot9>EuWybtR.jpg</snapshot9>
			<snapshot10>xWPUNde.jpg</snapshot10>
			<fanart1>BriZYM2.jpg</fanart1>
			<banner1>lLgLQky.jpg</banner1>
			<clearlogo1>4MInlDv.png</clearlogo1>
		</game>
		<game name="The Dreadnaught Factor">
			<description>The Dreadnaught Factor</description>
			<rom crc="460def2d" name="MAME_0.185_Software_List_ROMs_non-merged/MAME_0.185_Software_List_ROMs_non-merged.zip/MAME%200.185%20Software%20List%20ROMs%20%28non-merged%29%2Fa5200%2Fdfactor.zip" sha1="ea7b40ce1106378e1d409cab6634fb2e483ff238" size="7109" />
			<title_clean>The Dreadnaught Factor</title_clean>
			<plot>The Zorban Dreadnaughts are spaceships that are 140,000 feet long and weigh 970 megatons, making them the largest, most heavily armoured spaceships ever created. A fleet of these large battlecraft are now heading towards your home planet, and it is your job to stop them! The game is played from a side scrolling overhead point of view as your small but agile spaceship flies past the dreadnaughts. On each pass your spaceship makes, you need to try and bomb as many of the energy vents as possible. When all energy vents on a dreadnaught are destroyed, that dreadnaught will explode. Time is limited, though, and if you make too many passes to destroy the energy vents the dreadnaught will be within firing range of your home planet and will destroy it. Each of the dreadnaughts are heavily armed; guns, canons, missiles, and other weapons are located on each dreadnaught and will be trying their best to end your mission. Multiple skill levels are included which alter the number of dreadnaughts you must destroy, as well as their speed and firing capabilities.</plot>
			<releasedate>7/7/1984</releasedate>
			<year>1984</year>
			<genre>Action</genre>
			<studio>Activision</studio>
			<nplayers>1</nplayers>
			<perspective>3rd-Person</perspective>
			<rating>3.4</rating>
			<thegamesdb_id>5225</thegamesdb_id>
			<mobygames_url>http://www.mobygames.com/game/atari-5200/dreadnaught-factor</mobygames_url>
			<giantbomb_url>http://www.giantbomb.com/the-dreadnaught-factor/3030-16051/</giantbomb_url>
			<boxart1>ZgkvOho.jpg</boxart1>
			<boxart2>NyvdyqU.jpg</boxart2>
			<boxart3>07sOSXv.jpg</boxart3>
			<snapshot1>93Tl20n.gif</snapshot1>
			<snapshot2>02KmXCm.gif</snapshot2>
			<snapshot3>bNpTe9B.gif</snapshot3>
			<snapshot4>Iqf7pdn.gif</snapshot4>
			<snapshot5>DmLrcU6.gif</snapshot5>
			<clearlogo1>WkiVoFD.png</clearlogo1>
		</game>
		<game name="Final Legacy (Prototype)">
			<description>Final Legacy (Prototype)</description>
			<rom crc="d3bd3221" name="MAME_0.185_Software_List_ROMs_non-merged/MAME_0.185_Software_List_ROMs_non-merged.zip/MAME%200.185%20Software%20List%20ROMs%20%28non-merged%29%2Fa5200%2Fflegacy.zip" sha1="48625af4f3e9fe538dab2a0b463887fc8c6b138d" size="13245" />
			<title_clean>Final Legacy</title_clean>
			<plot>This is a battle on three fronts. You are the captain of the ship Legacy. Your ultimate goal is to destroy the Warmongers' missile bases but you must also protect your cities.[CR]You begin the game in command mode. You select your other modes with the joystick. Up for navigation, down for torpedo, left for sea-to-air and right for sea-to-land.[CR]Navigation[CR]In navigation mode, you will see an overhead map of the world. You will note that there is a black dot in a black circle. This is you and the circle represents your effective range. You move the circle about the screen to target ships or known missile bases or to refuel at a city. You use fuel only when you are in navigation mode. When you are within range, or if an enemy ships comes within your range, press the space bar to return to the command mode then change to the desired mode.[CR]Torpedo[CR]If you are within range of an enemy ship, switch to torpedo mode. In this mode, you will use the scanner at the bottom to line up your target. Move out of line to avoid a direct hit. Beware of war ship as they will chase you and have the most firepower. Hunter ships will also chase you. While their firepower is not as high as war ships, it is still fairly good. Intelligence ships have the weakest firepower and will not chase you. They can be found on the right side of the screen. If one is destroyed and there are any hidden missile bases, there is a eighty percent chance a hidden base will be revealed.[CR]Sea-to-land[CR]If you want to destroy a missile base or refuel, enter sea-to-land mode. To refuel, get near a city then enter this mode. When you are in sea-to-land mode, you will know you are within range if you see "Dock for refueling" on the screen. You then place the cross hairs on the base of the city and wait for refueling to complete, unless you or a city are under attack. Do not use the fire button to exit or you will fire on your city. To destroy a missile base, position your cross hairs using the scanner on the screen until you are on a missile launcher then fire. Be advised that when you fire on a missile base, they will shoot missiles at a city.[CR]Sea-to-air[CR]If a city is under attach, switch to this mode. You will control a weapons satellite. Use you joystick, or the trak-ball , if you plugged one into port 2, to aim at an incoming missile and press fire to blast it. If it gets past you but has not reached your city, you get a "Refocusing" message and the view switches to a short range view where you will get one more try.[CR]Be warned that ships can attack you no matter what mode you are in. On the easiest level, there are no hidden bases nor do you use fuel.[CR]The Atari 5200 version of this game was never released but is however mostly identical to the Atari 8-Bit version that was released.</plot>
			<releasedate>31/12/1987</releasedate>
			<year>1987</year>
			<genre>Flight Simulator, Shooter, Strategy</genre>
			<studio>Atari</studio>
			<nplayers>1</nplayers>
			<videoid>ncLHZgMoqgY</videoid>
			<thegamesdb_id>34471</thegamesdb_id>
			<giantbomb_url>http://www.giantbomb.com/final-legacy/3030-13789/</giantbomb_url>
			<boxart1>CSWCUUr.jpg</boxart1>
			<snapshot1>dUMxw2Y.jpg</snapshot1>
			<snapshot2>KTedZJL.jpg</snapshot2>
			<snapshot3>hTUcelG.jpg</snapshot3>
			<snapshot4>iF3YOCe.png</snapshot4>
			<snapshot5>anijGoW.jpg</snapshot5>
			<snapshot6>eW2JJsA.png</snapshot6>
			<snapshot7>9wMU7Ve.png</snapshot7>
			<snapshot8>G8iNfD0.png</snapshot8>
			<snapshot9>8aYCMfe.png</snapshot9>
		</game>
		<game name="Frisky Tom (Prototype)">
			<description>Frisky Tom (Prototype)</description>
			<rom crc="04b299a4" name="MAME_0.185_Software_List_ROMs_non-merged/MAME_0.185_Software_List_ROMs_non-merged.zip/MAME%200.185%20Software%20List%20ROMs%20%28non-merged%29%2Fa5200%2Ffriskyt.zip" sha1="69dcc8f59ca449f13dc896b4b29b534762d97064" size="9263" />
			<title_clean>Frisky Tom</title_clean>
			<plot>A prototype game that was never officially released for the Atari 5200, Frisky Tom is a port of the obscure Nichibutsu coin-op of the same name in which you play a plumber who must climb up and fix broken pipes to keep a steady stream of water flowing from the tank at the top of the screen to the reservoir at the bottom.  Unfortunately this house is infested with mice which roam the screen, gnawing through pipes and generally causing problems for our man Tom.[CR]Once a mouse gnaws through a pipe, you'll see the flow of water stop and a pipe piece will fall to the ground.  To repair the pipe Tom must pick up the fallen piece (you can hold two pieces a time), and put it back into the hole.  To get to where the holes are, Tom must carefully climb up and navigate the maze of pipes.  Although Tom can cross short gaps in the pipes, he'll need to go around the larger ones.  While climbing around on the pipes, Tom will run across several different kinds of mice. Each mouse has its own color and purpose.[CR]When the flow of water is interrupted, the timer in the reservoir will begin to count downward from 5000 at the rate of 100 points per second.  The only way to stop this countdown is to restore the water flow by fixing the pipes.  If the timer reaches zero, Tom will lose a life and play the current level over again.  If Tom is able to get enough water into the reservoir (keeping the timer above 1500), he'll be rewarded with a bonus intermission showing a woman taking a shower.[CR]- Excerpt from www.atariprotos.com</plot>
			<releasedate>4/7/1983</releasedate>
			<year>1983</year>
			<genre>Action</genre>
			<studio>Atari</studio>
			<nplayers>1</nplayers>
			<videoid>wswlpoL6wRc</videoid>
			<thegamesdb_id>34472</thegamesdb_id>
			<boxart1>mfWkHwv.jpg</boxart1>
			<snapshot1>LimftdN.jpg</snapshot1>
			<snapshot2>sv6Ziq5.jpg</snapshot2>
			<clearlogo1>yWskbKT.png</clearlogo1>
		</game>
		<game name="Frogger">
			<description>Frogger</description>
			<rom crc="ae7e3444" name="MAME_0.185_Software_List_ROMs_non-merged/MAME_0.185_Software_List_ROMs_non-merged.zip/MAME%200.185%20Software%20List%20ROMs%20%28non-merged%29%2Fa5200%2Ffrogger.zip" sha1="d9a695757f0494aee92a50ab8a49558745e0cedf" size="6049" />
			<title_clean>Frogger</title_clean>
			<plot>[CR][B]Overview:[/B][CR]Frogger is a top-down, multi-stage action game. The player controls frogs home, while avoiding obstacles. The arcade game's popularity lead to many ports, remakes, and sequels.[CR][B]Gameplay:[/B][CR]Frogger about to cross the road.  The objective in Frogger is controlling frogs home using a four-way joystick. Gameplay is timed, and successful completion requires navigating several contiguous stages in each level.First, the frog must cross a highway while avoiding various automobiles. Lanes of traffic operate in alternating directions, and at different speeds. Getting squashed by a vehicle causes the player to lose one life, and restart the level.A median separates the highway from a river. In later stages, the median is occupied by a snake which will also cause the player to lose a life if touched. The river contains alternating lanes of turtles and logs, moving in alternate directions, and at different speeds. The turtles move in groups of two or three, and every other group submerges regularly. The player must navigate over the turtles while above water to reach logs in various configurations, and repeat the process until reaching home.Timing is critical as the player navigates the frog into one of five home slots. Missing the slot, or reaching the edge of the screen before leaping home loses the player one life, and restarts the stage. Once a home slot is filled, the stage restarts, and play resumes until all home slots are filled, causing the next level to start.Score is kept as each frog progresses toward home, points are tallied. Additionally, optional bonus points are gained by rescuing a lady frog atop a log by hopping over her, and bringing her into a home slot without dying. Further bonus points are earned through catching briefly-appearing flies in home slots, and finishing stages early.Later stages present the player with additional challenges from faster moving obstacles, faster submersing turtles, alligators occupying home slots briefly, snakes moving along logs, and trickier log configurations.[CR][B]Legacy:[/B][CR]The popular 1990s show Seinfeld had an episode almost entirely dedicated to Frogger. In the episode George Costanza learns that a pizza place he visited frequently as a child is closing down which will lead to the unplugging of a Frogger arcade machine and the loss of his high score. At the end of the episode, from a top down view identical to the game, we see George maneuver the arcade cabinet through traffic to reach the other side of the street.[CR]</plot>
			<releasedate>7/7/1983</releasedate>
			<year>1983</year>
			<genre>Action</genre>
			<studio>Parker Brothers</studio>
			<nplayers>1-2 Alt</nplayers>
			<perspective>Top-Down</perspective>
			<thegamesdb_id>5156</thegamesdb_id>
			<mobygames_url>http://www.mobygames.com/game/atari-5200/frogger</mobygames_url>
			<giantbomb_url>http://www.giantbomb.com/frogger/3030-11903/</giantbomb_url>
			<boxart1>evixqog.jpg</boxart1>
			<boxart2>GN40HWt.jpg</boxart2>
			<boxart3>QFXM2BM.jpg</boxart3>
			<snapshot1>idBChhw.gif</snapshot1>
			<snapshot2>VO5N9BU.gif</snapshot2>
			<snapshot3>E5HiEHP.gif</snapshot3>
			<snapshot4>qNhRWmy.png</snapshot4>
			<snapshot5>LIPAKlu.png</snapshot5>
			<snapshot6>Sanq2NY.png</snapshot6>
			<snapshot7>5crR6UN.png</snapshot7>
			<snapshot8>XH9Ml2n.png</snapshot8>
			<snapshot9>lwnXYfL.png</snapshot9>
			<snapshot10>bBrYsud.png</snapshot10>
			<fanart1>fqrrZjC.jpg</fanart1>
			<clearlogo1>Fh1buQN.png</clearlogo1>
		</game>
		<game name="Frogger II: Threeedeep!">
			<description>Frogger II: Threeedeep!</description>
			<rom crc="0af19345" name="MAME_0.185_Software_List_ROMs_non-merged/MAME_0.185_Software_List_ROMs_non-merged.zip/MAME%200.185%20Software%20List%20ROMs%20%28non-merged%29%2Fa5200%2Ffrogger2.zip" sha1="3d815594cf674694b04bb0ff90bf635d7d402fc2" size="9039" />
			<title_clean>Frogger II: Threeedeep!</title_clean>
			<plot>In Frogger II, you need to guide your frog to safety in three different locations. Starting out underwater, reach the top of the pond while avoiding dangerous alligators and fish (you can ride a turtle for safety!). Once on top of the pond, hop across logs, birds, and even a whale to the life preserver trailing behind a tugboat. In the third location you have to hop across a flock of birds to reach a cloud at the top of the screen. Each frog has a time limit to safely reach one of the homes on each of the three screens. You move on to the next level when a frog has safely reached each of the homes on all screens.</plot>
			<releasedate>7/7/1984</releasedate>
			<year>1984</year>
			<genre>Action</genre>
			<studio>Parker Brothers</studio>
			<nplayers>1</nplayers>
			<perspective>Platform</perspective>
			<rating>4.2</rating>
			<thegamesdb_id>5157</thegamesdb_id>
			<mobygames_url>http://www.mobygames.com/game/atari-5200/frogger-ii-threeedeep</mobygames_url>
			<giantbomb_url>http://www.giantbomb.com/frogger-ii-threeedeep/3030-20434/</giantbomb_url>
			<boxart1>tsPJeBe.jpg</boxart1>
			<boxart2>2Z7ipsh.jpg</boxart2>
			<boxart3>I84Izb7.jpg</boxart3>
			<snapshot1>l1fEepF.gif</snapshot1>
			<snapshot2>q4K8lmw.gif</snapshot2>
			<snapshot3>hOOjDEB.gif</snapshot3>
			<snapshot4>zyuh9Oj.gif</snapshot4>
			<snapshot5>w6XNm7o.png</snapshot5>
			<snapshot6>xdrV2yG.png</snapshot6>
			<snapshot7>Ky64F7J.png</snapshot7>
			<snapshot8>2rdi14d.png</snapshot8>
			<snapshot9>eztZSXj.png</snapshot9>
			<snapshot10>S7S39fO.png</snapshot10>
			<clearlogo1>dHOgYDe.png</clearlogo1>
		</game>
		<game name="Galaxian">
			<description>Galaxian</description>
			<rom crc="3ef4a23f" name="MAME_0.185_Software_List_ROMs_non-merged/MAME_0.185_Software_List_ROMs_non-merged.zip/MAME%200.185%20Software%20List%20ROMs%20%28non-merged%29%2Fa5200%2Fgalaxian.zip" sha1="0df0d7f11d89e2c5b59cc9f98d67d98e203831aa" size="5943" />
			<title_clean>Galaxian</title_clean>
			<plot>[CR][B]Overview:[/B][CR]Galaxian (&#12462;&#12515;&#12521;&#12463;&#12471;&#12450;&#12531;) is an Arcade game that was developed by Namco and released in October 1979. It was published by Namco in Japan and imported to North America by Midway that December. A vertical scrolling shooter game in which the player controls a spaceship at the bottom of the screen, and shoots enemies descending in various directions, it was designed to compete with Taito's successful earlier game Space Invaders (which was released in the previous year, and also imported to the US by Midway).The game was a big hit for Namco upon its release, and has been a focus of competitive gaming ever since.It was ported to the Atari 2600, Atari 5200, ColecoVision, Bally Astrocade, Nintendo Famicom, and home computers.It spawned a successful sequel, Galaga, in 1981, and the lesser known Gaplus and Galaga '88 in 1984 and 1987 respectively, as well as many later ports and adaptations. Along with its immediate sequel, it was one of the most popular games during the golden age of Arcade video games.[CR][B]Description:[/B][CR]Galaxian expanded on the formula pioneered by Space Invaders. As in the earlier game, Galaxian features a horde of attacking aliens that exchanged shots with the player. In contrast to Space Invaders, Galaxianadded an element of drama by having the aliens periodically make kamikaze-like dives at the player's ship, the Galaxip. This made it the first game to feature enemies with individual personalities. The game's plot consists of a title screen that displayed the message "WE ARE THE GALAXIANS / MISSION: DESTROY ALIENS".Galaxian was very successful for Namco and introduced several "firsts". Although not the first color video game, Galaxian took RGB color graphics a step further with multi-colored animated sprites and explosions, different colored fonts for the score and high score, the vertical scrolling starfield, and graphic icons that show the number of lives left and how many stages the player had completed. It also features a crude theme song and more prominent background music/sound effects. These elements combine to create a look and feel that would set the standard for arcade games in the 1980s such as Pac-Man.[CR][B]Gameplay:[/B][CR]The objective is destroy endless 'waves' of enemies. The enemy ships are arranged in a formation at the top of the screen. At regular intervals enemy ships on the sides of the formation swoop down and shoot at the player. There are 4 different types of enemy ship, each type behaves differently on its attacking run.The player must destroy all ships in a wave to complete it. With a minor exception that one yellow ship may disappear after a bombing run and will appear as an extra yellow ship in the following wave. The yellow ships attack in a formation with two red ships, the order these three are destroyed determines the points awarded for destroying the yellow. The maximum is 800 points if the two reds are destroyed first. Once a wave has been completed a red flag is added to the bottom of the screen. When 10 flags are accumulated they are replaced by a larger flag.The player has 3 lives at the beginning of the game. A bonus life is awarded when the player reaches a score of 7000 points. Once all lives have been lost the game ends. The player can only have one shot on screen at one time. This means if the player misses he must wait until the shot leaves the top of the screen to fire again. This makes accuracy very important.High ScoreThe current world record score for Galaxian is 1,653,270 points.[CR]Development and Release[CR]The game was developed by Namco in 1979, and released in Japan that year. It was designed to build and improve upon the formula of Taito's game Space Invaders, which revolutionized the gaming industry upon its release a year earlier. Galaxian incorporated new technology into its dedicated arcade system board, the Namco Galaxian. Unlike Space Invaders, which was black &amp; white and featured enemies that could only move vertically and horizontally as they descended, Galaxian had a color screen and enemies that descended in patterns and came from various directions. The result was more complex and difficult game play.In 1980, Namco partnered with the American company Midway to release the game in North America. Midway had previously published Space Invaders in the market, but had to seek new foreign partners when Taito decided to market their games themselves.[CR]Reception of Ports[CR]Home Computing Weekly in 1983 gave the Spectrum version of Galaxian 3/5 stars describing it as a well-written version and praising the graphics as fast although flickery. Softline in 1983 criticized the Atari 8-bit version of the game for being shipped on cartridge, which raised its cost, and stated that "this game becomes tedious very quickly". Famicom Ts&#363;shin in 1995 scored the Game Boy version of the game a 24 out of 40.[CR][B]Legacy:[/B][CR]Galaxian has spawned several follow-up games. The most popular of these was its immediate successor, Galaga, which largely eclipsed its predecessor in popularity, introducing aliens attacking in intricate formations, multiple shots, and bonus stages. A third official sequel, Gaplus, was released in 1984. As with Galaga, this was a fixed shooter, with limited vertical movement. However, by 1984, the novelty of the Space Invaders formula had faded, and it was no longer successful. A fourth sequel, Galaga '88, was released in 1987, and imported to North America by Atari Games. Namco then released Galaxian 3 in 1990. A final sequel, Galaga Arrangement, was released as part of the Namco Classic Collection Vol. 1, in 1995.PortsThe original arcade version of Galaxian has been ported to many different systems. These include:Apple IIAtari 400/800Atari 2600Atari 5200Bally Astrocade (Galactic Invasion)Coleco VFD table topColecoVisionCommodore VIC-20Commodore 64DreamcastGame Boy (bundled with its direct successor, Galaga)IBM PCMobile JavaMSX (Europe and Japan only)NEC PC-8801Nintendo Famicom Disk System (Japan only)Sharp X1Virtual Console (Japan only)ZX SpectrumColeco also released stand-alone Mini-Arcade tabeletop versions of Galaxian, which, along with Pac-Man, Donkey Kong, and Frogger, sold three million units combined. A port for the Game Boy Color was planned, but never released.Moon Alien Part 2Nichibutsu released a modified version of this game for the arcades as Moon Alien Part 2. Besides the graphics, the only main difference between this and Galaxian is the inclusion of an energy meter that drains with every second the player spends clearing a wave. If the player doesn't clear the wave before running out of energy, the ship is destroyed.Arcade sequelsMain: Galaxian (franchise) Galaga (1981)Gaplus (1984)Galaga '88 (1987)Galaga Arrangement (1995) - released as part of Namco Classic Collection Vol. 1Galaxian was one of the most widely pirated motherboards during the early '80s. Numerous hacks were made of the game and featured slightly redesigned enemy characters and special bonus stages. The scrolling starfield and death explosion were still familiar as those from Galaxian, however. These hacks include: Galaxian Part 4, Galaxian Part X, Galaxian Turbo, and Super Galaxians.3D sequelsGalaxian&#179; (1990) - Galaxian&#179;: Project Dragoon (Theatre 6) for six players on two 110-inch RGB projectors - 18-foot-wide (5.5 m) screenAttack of the Zolgear (1994) - a ROM and laserdisc upgrade for Galaxian&#179; [CR]</plot>
			<releasedate>7/7/1982</releasedate>
			<year>1982</year>
			<genre>Action</genre>
			<studio>Atari</studio>
			<nplayers>1-2 Alt</nplayers>
			<perspective>3rd-Person</perspective>
			<rating>4.0</rating>
			<videoid>GSh528KGCfE</videoid>
			<thegamesdb_id>5158</thegamesdb_id>
			<mobygames_url>http://www.mobygames.com/game/atari-5200/galaxian</mobygames_url>
			<giantbomb_url>http://www.giantbomb.com/galaxian/3030-2445/</giantbomb_url>
			<boxart1>ftXC64j.jpg</boxart1>
			<boxart2>bM2pvlN.jpg</boxart2>
			<boxart3>CWZnLXB.jpg</boxart3>
			<boxart4>YPCATrF.jpg</boxart4>
			<snapshot1>zZsDfuN.gif</snapshot1>
			<snapshot2>mWJLQnc.gif</snapshot2>
			<snapshot3>0Gosjgb.gif</snapshot3>
			<snapshot4>SmBTHrT.gif</snapshot4>
			<snapshot5>yMaVjnJ.jpg</snapshot5>
			<snapshot6>fHeAS9p.jpg</snapshot6>
			<snapshot7>0woZ85r.jpg</snapshot7>
			<snapshot8>q83lvm1.jpg</snapshot8>
			<snapshot9>bwL37tX.jpg</snapshot9>
			<snapshot10>pb637wF.jpg</snapshot10>
			<banner1>p8GmTtv.jpg</banner1>
			<clearlogo1>Za02INn.png</clearlogo1>
		</game>
		<game name="Gorf">
			<description>Gorf</description>
			<rom crc="e955db74" name="MAME_0.185_Software_List_ROMs_non-merged/MAME_0.185_Software_List_ROMs_non-merged.zip/MAME%200.185%20Software%20List%20ROMs%20%28non-merged%29%2Fa5200%2Fgorf.zip" sha1="80926bb270ea66cb5cacc379de1fc16d8a3d814b" size="8101" />
			<title_clean>Gorf</title_clean>
			<plot>Gorf is a game similar to Space Invaders, alien vessels approach closer and closer in their threatening row formation.[CR]The game itself consists of four levels:[CR]1. The first level has you behind a defensive shield, defending against an alien attack. The level is a top-down view, with your ship &amp; shield on one side and the aliens on the other side;[CR]The second level is similar to the first, only your defensive shield is gone, and the enemies tend to swoop down over the level as opposed to those row formations. Bonus ships also tend to appear in this level;[CR]The third level is a change, and has you entering hyperspace. Your only goal is to survive to the end of your journey. The viewpoint switches from a top-down view to a behind-the-ship view and in effect you are heading "towards" your destination. Alien vessels flying in circular formation try to stop you;[CR]The fourth and final level is similar to the first again, with some key differences. You do not fight a wave of enemies, but a single one. A mothership with a glowing weak spot. Hitting the weak spot will instantly destroy it. The mothership also has that same shield that was yours in the first level.[CR]Finishing the game increases your rank and starts the game over at level 1 with a faster game speed for more challenge.</plot>
			<releasedate>7/7/1983</releasedate>
			<year>1983</year>
			<genre>Action</genre>
			<studio>CBS Electronics</studio>
			<nplayers>1-2 Sim</nplayers>
			<perspective>3rd-Person</perspective>
			<videoid>NH0mZ4UdiCc</videoid>
			<thegamesdb_id>5160</thegamesdb_id>
			<mobygames_url>http://www.mobygames.com/game/atari-5200/gorf</mobygames_url>
			<giantbomb_url>http://www.giantbomb.com/gorf/3030-13036/</giantbomb_url>
			<boxart1>u64YpuA.jpg</boxart1>
			<boxart2>EN8rYoQ.jpg</boxart2>
			<boxart3>p4az31b.jpg</boxart3>
			<snapshot1>q9CoOk4.jpg</snapshot1>
			<snapshot2>bAw1wHK.gif</snapshot2>
			<snapshot3>KK3X4YZ.gif</snapshot3>
			<snapshot4>So9DGJc.gif</snapshot4>
			<snapshot5>jhH7yYt.gif</snapshot5>
			<snapshot6>A8YczZs.gif</snapshot6>
			<snapshot7>uc2ggbZ.png</snapshot7>
			<snapshot8>ym4bYxS.png</snapshot8>
			<snapshot9>zSuy4PW.png</snapshot9>
			<snapshot10>d0iGle9.png</snapshot10>
			<banner1>mHSyddB.jpg</banner1>
			<clearlogo1>7RTkjxJ.png</clearlogo1>
		</game>
		<game name="Gremlins">
			<description>Gremlins</description>
			<rom crc="063ec2c4" name="MAME_0.185_Software_List_ROMs_non-merged/MAME_0.185_Software_List_ROMs_non-merged.zip/MAME%200.185%20Software%20List%20ROMs%20%28non-merged%29%2Fa5200%2Fgremlins.zip" sha1="f3c32b39580d589799dcead98bb206fbf3df0504" size="15130" />
			<title_clean>Gremlins</title_clean>
			<plot>Gremlins is an action game based on the Steven Spielberg movie of the same name. The game takes place just after midnight when there are Gremlins and Mogwai running around Billy's living room![CR]You control Billy from a 3rd person point of view. On each level, your goal is to catch all of the Mogwai and return them to their cage (located in the upper right corner of the screen) and to destroy all of the Gremlins with a sword. Each level has a time limit - at 6:00 am when the sun rises. You move on to the next level by completing your tasks or just surviving until 6:00, although more points are awarded for the former. You will also receive bonus points for each Mogwai returned to the cage. [CR]On many of the levels there will be various types of food lying about the screen. If a Mogwai eats any food, it will turn into a gremlin. There may also be  puddles of water; if a Gremlin or Mogwai runs into the water, it will split into two. Some levels also contain a refrigerator or popcorn machine which will throw food out onto the screen, or a television which will distract the Gremlins. [CR]You also begin the game with a limited number of flash cubes; if you get into trouble, you can use these to temporarily stun all of the Gremlins and Mogwai. As the levels progress gameplay becomes faster and the Gremlins and Mogwai more numerous.</plot>
			<releasedate>7/7/1984</releasedate>
			<year>1986</year>
			<genre>Action</genre>
			<studio>Atari</studio>
			<nplayers>1-2 Sim</nplayers>
			<perspective>Top-Down</perspective>
			<rating>4.5</rating>
			<videoid>Of4FjKRo024</videoid>
			<thegamesdb_id>5161</thegamesdb_id>
			<mobygames_url>http://www.mobygames.com/game/atari-5200/gremlins</mobygames_url>
			<giantbomb_url>http://www.giantbomb.com/gremlins/3030-15465/</giantbomb_url>
			<boxart1>328yQde.jpg</boxart1>
			<boxart2>RymWWAu.jpg</boxart2>
			<boxart3>Oax6a8L.jpg</boxart3>
			<snapshot1>yYwee4P.gif</snapshot1>
			<snapshot2>U1J83Cs.gif</snapshot2>
			<snapshot3>Dvacxe4.gif</snapshot3>
			<snapshot4>JPQsrR4.gif</snapshot4>
			<snapshot5>EQbinGn.gif</snapshot5>
			<snapshot6>0gG0nSu.gif</snapshot6>
			<snapshot7>dyPvAYz.png</snapshot7>
			<snapshot8>o4a7yL9.png</snapshot8>
			<snapshot9>oEIHBHt.png</snapshot9>
			<snapshot10>iD3SbkB.png</snapshot10>
			<banner1>3KJFsdA.jpg</banner1>
			<clearlogo1>A9JtVXg.png</clearlogo1>
		</game>
		<game name="Gyruss">
			<description>Gyruss</description>
			<rom crc="cfd4a7f9" name="MAME_0.185_Software_List_ROMs_non-merged/MAME_0.185_Software_List_ROMs_non-merged.zip/MAME%200.185%20Software%20List%20ROMs%20%28non-merged%29%2Fa5200%2Fgyruss.zip" sha1="d0d8650eb07d1679004d491360c2c041e37c61cd" size="12381" />
			<title_clean>Gyruss</title_clean>
			<plot>[CR][B]Overview:[/B][CR]Gyruss is a 1983 shoot 'em up created by Yoshiki Okamoto and Konami in which players take command of a ship trying to warp to Earth. Along the way, enemy spaceships, lasers, and meteors will appear and must be destroyed before the player can advance.[CR][B]Gameplay:[/B][CR]Upon starting the game, players will be greeted with the message "2 WARPS TO NEPTUNE". Each level means the player is one warp closer to reaching the planet. Killing all enemies that appear in the level will complete the warp. The opposing spaceships will fly towards the player's ship in a pattern, often curving around the tube perspective and flying back towards the center, where they will wait. Enemy ships who are not shot while waiting in the center will fly off screen and reappear flying out from the center. Completing all the warps will display a quick cutscene of the player ship zooming towards Neptune. Next, a small bonus round called the Change Stage will start. The ships in the Chance Stage will not shoot back, allowing the player to rack up points with ease.In the arcade version of Gyruss, gameplay remains the same as the player warps from Neptune to Uranus, then Saturn, Jupiter, Mars, and eventually Earth. The final level, "3 WARPS TO NEPTUNE", is extremely fast. Completing it restarts the game over at two warps to Neptune.In the NES version, the player starts at the edge of the Solar System, then warps to Neptune, Pluto, Uranus, Saturn, Jupiter, Mars, Earth, Venus, Mercury, and finishes the game at The Sun.PerspectiveThe ship sprites will shrink as they move farther down the 'tube'The most unique feature of Gyruss is the perspective: the field of play is a similar to a giant abstract tube with the player's ship flying through. Enemies will most often appear at the center of the 'tube' and fly outward to give the effect of rapid approach. On occasion, 'flocks' of enemy ships will fly out from the left or right side of the screen, breaking the tube perspective.PortsGyruss proved to be a bit of a success for Konami, and ports were soon made for the Atari 2600, Atari 5200, ColecoVision, Atari 8-bit, and Commodore 64. A port to the European ZX Spectrum was also planned, but later scrapped. In 2007, an Xbox Live Arcade port of Gyruss was released with updated sound and graphics. Gyruss has found its way onto several Konami compilations, such as the Playstation Konami Arcade Classics and Konami Collector's Series: Arcade Advanced for the Game Boy Advance. Gyruss is said to be coming to Microsoft's Game Room for the Xbox 360 and PC in July 2010.Differences between the NES remake and the Arcade versionIn 1988, Konami released Gyruss to The Famicom Disk System/ Nintendo Entertainment System under the Ultra Games label. This version was much more of a remake than a mere port. Along with a slight hint of story came improved art, new music, boss battles, more planets to warp to, added Chance Stages, and different power ups. A major difference in the story was that it featured Genghis Khan as a villain.[CR][B]Enemies:[/B][CR]Excerpt from the Atari 5200 Gyruss manual -Within each warp you'll face FOUR different formations of enemy planes. The formations might emerge from the center of the screen where the planes band together--or form off screen where they can create a surprise attack. In either case, shoot down as many planes within the formation as you can and don't let them hit your own ship. Planes fire missiles, too...your only option is to avoid them...or be shot down. After the last formation appears, all the planes NOT shot down will regroup in the center and attack again. They will continue to do so until you've eliminated the last one--unless, of course, one eliminates you first.BUT PLANES ARE NOT ALL YOU NEED TO WORRY ABOUT. THERE ARE SWIRLING AND DEADLY SATELLITES AND METEORS, TOO.There are several reoccurring types of enemies in Gyruss: enemy ships, asteroids, satellites, and laser generators.Enemy ships will fly in formation from either the center (giving the illusion of depth) or from the left and right side of the screen. They will then head back to the center of the screen, growing smaller in size as they get away from the player ship. Ships in the middle of the screen can still be shot at, and neglecting to do so will cause the enemy ship to fly away and reappear later.Asteroids are round, blue blobs that start in the middle of the screen and suddenly zoom past the player. Asteroids will never change position in the 'tube' and are easily avoided.Satellites will phase into view usually right in front of the player ship and follow it around for a time. The satellites include three sections, the blue triangles, and the spiky orange middle. Shooting the orange spiky ball in the middle will double the player's firepower.The final type of enemy in the arcade version of Gyruss are the laser generators. Each generator consists of two small blue circles with yellow energy pulsing between them. Similar to asteroids, lasers will never change position and moving out of the way is the simplest way of combating them. Another way to stop the threat of laser generators is to shoot one of the two small blue circles holding the laser beam in place. This will stop the beam from pulsing and destroy the circle the player shot at, but the other half will remain on the screen and fly past like an asteroid.Like many old arcade games, all enemies are on a set pattern and basic memorization is key for high scores.[CR][B]Trivia:[/B][CR]Gryuss makes a brief cameo in Grand Theft Auto: San Andreas.As with many Konami games, the Konami Code can be entered into the title screen of the NES remake, albeit backwards (A B A B right left right left down down up up).The main theme of Gyruss is a contemporary arrangement of Johan Sebastian Bach's Toccata and Fugue in D Minor.An even more fast-paced and electronic arrangement of the Gyruss theme can be found in Konami's Dance Dance Revolution: ULTRAMIX 2 under the name GYRUSS -FULL TILT-.According to TwinGalaxies, the highest score ever recorded for the arcade version of Gyruss was Michael Bangs's perfect score of 47,024,400.Gyruss creator Yoshiki Okamoto was fired after the release of the game due to financial disputes. He then joined Capcom where he would later produce 1942 and Street Fighter II.After making Gyruss, Yoshiki Okamoto created another classic shoot 'em up, Time Pilot.The Atari 2600 and Commodore 64 ports of Gyruss were released by Parker Brothers.According to an article in Electronic Gaming Monthly, a lifeform from the planet Gyruss is known as a Gyrussian.[CR]</plot>
			<releasedate>7/7/1984</releasedate>
			<year>1984</year>
			<studio>Parker Brothers</studio>
			<nplayers>1-2 Alt</nplayers>
			<rating>2.2</rating>
			<videoid>Tr00Yuy2rnE</videoid>
			<thegamesdb_id>5162</thegamesdb_id>
			<mobygames_url>http://www.mobygames.com/game/atari-5200/gyruss</mobygames_url>
			<giantbomb_url>http://www.giantbomb.com/gyruss/3030-18885/</giantbomb_url>
			<boxart1>rE5eGjv.jpg</boxart1>
			<boxart2>SlzeYJX.jpg</boxart2>
			<boxart3>MP9eRAN.jpg</boxart3>
			<snapshot1>RAaXgeN.gif</snapshot1>
			<snapshot2>9HwzBS2.gif</snapshot2>
			<snapshot3>HMP1ORo.gif</snapshot3>
			<snapshot4>UTWLRKN.gif</snapshot4>
			<snapshot5>Z2kMhz2.gif</snapshot5>
			<snapshot6>K4q9l1b.gif</snapshot6>
			<snapshot7>bj6tvDO.jpg</snapshot7>
			<snapshot8>AezlQWS.jpg</snapshot8>
			<snapshot9>KucOJw1.jpg</snapshot9>
			<snapshot10>fxcBVBx.jpg</snapshot10>
			<clearlogo1>8L2xHDl.png</clearlogo1>
		</game>
		<game name="H.E.R.O.">
			<description>H.E.R.O.</description>
			<rom crc="18a73af3" name="MAME_0.185_Software_List_ROMs_non-merged/MAME_0.185_Software_List_ROMs_non-merged.zip/MAME%200.185%20Software%20List%20ROMs%20%28non-merged%29%2Fa5200%2Fhero.zip" sha1="d286ecb6793a0dda9c9c68f6355dbe3ade6922f9" size="8532" />
			<title_clean>H.E.R.O.</title_clean>
			<plot>[CR][B]Overview:[/B][CR]  H.E.R.O. is a platforming game published and developed by                     Activision in 1984. It was originally developed for the                    Atari 2600 but ported to many other consoles already listed on this page. The name is speculated to mean "Helicopter Emergency Rescue Operation".[CR][B]Gameplay:[/B][CR]   The main objective of the game is to rescue trapped miners. You're equipped with a       heli-pack  allowing you to          fly around the level, as well as a               laser-beam to defend yourself from the game's various enemies (             bats,             snakes,            spiders, etc). You're also equipped with           dynamite, which you can use to kill  enemies or to destroy various walls blocking your way. It's possible to use your laser beam to disintegrate the wall as well without the risk of killing yourself, although it takes longer. There are      magma walls later in the game that kill you if you touch them, making it slightly harder to plant dynamite next to, or navigate through the caverns. When you die, you're returned to the same screen as the one you were just on, costing a life. There is a        power meter on the bottom of the screen that slowly drains indicating a time limit, making later levels fairly difficult due to their length. When the power meter is drained, you lose a life. Later levels often feature a raft the player can use to float across the water unharmed.  [CR]H.E.R.O. for Xbox 360 Game Room[CR]H.E.R.O. was included in the June 23rd, 2010 Game Pack release of   Game Room for the  Xbox 360.[CR]</plot>
			<releasedate>7/7/1984</releasedate>
			<year>1984</year>
			<genre>Action</genre>
			<studio>Activision</studio>
			<nplayers>1</nplayers>
			<perspective>3rd-Person</perspective>
			<rating>4.1</rating>
			<thegamesdb_id>5164</thegamesdb_id>
			<mobygames_url>http://www.mobygames.com/game/atari-5200/hero</mobygames_url>
			<giantbomb_url>http://www.giantbomb.com/hero/3030-4430/</giantbomb_url>
			<boxart1>6KFBt9S.jpg</boxart1>
			<boxart2>GNqlBTy.jpg</boxart2>
			<boxart3>2eTFsIz.jpg</boxart3>
			<snapshot1>k6NHHWM.gif</snapshot1>
			<snapshot2>zqnfNMz.gif</snapshot2>
			<snapshot3>NRF83rk.gif</snapshot3>
			<snapshot4>LoJ2CTi.gif</snapshot4>
			<snapshot5>UPUydN2.gif</snapshot5>
			<snapshot6>OJmigNl.png</snapshot6>
			<clearlogo1>TH1pAeK.png</clearlogo1>
		</game>
		<game name="James Bond">
			<description>James Bond</description>
			<rom crc="d9ae4518" name="MAME_0.185_Software_List_ROMs_non-merged/MAME_0.185_Software_List_ROMs_non-merged.zip/MAME%200.185%20Software%20List%20ROMs%20%28non-merged%29%2Fa5200%2Fjbond.zip" sha1="ae765943ae8d909b6ca6ff1560ba027adeeaa515" size="9887" />
			<title_clean>James Bond</title_clean>
			<plot>In James Bond 007 you control James Bond in his multi purpose craft. This craft can travel on both land and sea, can jump over danger, or fire at enemies on the many different levels. Each horizontally scrolling level in the game is loosely based on a different James Bond movie. The levels included are Diamonds Are Forever, The Spy Who Loved Me, Moonraker, and For Your Eyes Only. Each level has a variety of enemies trying to destroy you, and a unique goal that must be accomplished to continue on (for example, you may have to land on a hidden oil rig to stop Seraffino, or find Stromberg's undersea laboratory and destroy it). If you can complete all the missions, you win the game! Good luck, Mr. Bond.</plot>
			<year>1984</year>
			<genre>Action</genre>
			<studio>Parker Brothers</studio>
			<nplayers>1-2 Sim</nplayers>
			<mobygames_url>http://www.mobygames.com/game/atari-5200/james-bond-007_</mobygames_url>
			<boxart3>qwMhbZj.jpg</boxart3>
			<snapshot1>CE61TdM.gif</snapshot1>
			<snapshot2>pr6wpBl.gif</snapshot2>
			<snapshot3>Ea83ctd.gif</snapshot3>
			<snapshot4>6bcTexR.gif</snapshot4>
			<snapshot5>IOMwymx.gif</snapshot5>
			<snapshot6>1iOu0pS.gif</snapshot6>
		</game>
		<game name="Joust">
			<description>Joust</description>
			<rom crc="bfd30c01" name="MAME_0.185_Software_List_ROMs_non-merged/MAME_0.185_Software_List_ROMs_non-merged.zip/MAME%200.185%20Software%20List%20ROMs%20%28non-merged%29%2Fa5200%2Fjoust.zip" sha1="0f74125edac90ffd1274a128df2970c239348fb5" size="11759" />
			<title_clean>Joust</title_clean>
			<plot>[CR][B]Overview:[/B][CR]Released in 1982, this two-dimensional platform game played from a third-person perspective. The main character is a knight, but unlike medieval knights he rides a yellow flying ostrich. The object is to get to the next level , called a wave, without being defeated by enemy knights, who ride mounted upon flying vultures.[CR][B]Gameplay:[/B][CR]Jousting is hard work.The object of Joust is to defeat all of the other jousters on the stage. This can be done by making contact with them while the player's jouster's jousting spear is higher than the enemy's is. As long as this is the case when the player's jouster collides with an enemy, they will be defeated. To ensure that an enemy jouster will not return, however, it is necessary to pick up the egg that is dropped when they are defeated. If the egg isn't collected quickly, it will hatch into another jouster and another buzzard will quickly arrive to pick him up and return him to the fight.There are lava pits on either side of the island on the lowest level of the battleground. In the early stages these pits will be sealed so that falling into them is impossible, but eventually they will open up and become a hazard to both the player and the enemies. Living in the lava is a lava troll who will grab any character that flies too close to it, players and enemies, and attempt to drag them down into the lava. It is possible to escape the troll when caught by flying hard enough.An enemy pterodactyl appears if too much time elapses in a stage. The beast appears to be unbeatable, but it can actually be killed by stabbing it directly in its mouth when it is open. This is difficult however because the creature moves much faster than other enemies. It will also leave if all the other jousters on the stage are defeated.[CR]Ports[CR]Joust has appeared on nearly every popular gaming system to date in some form or another. Usually it is packaged into a "best of" package but more recently it has been sold stand-alone on popular download services such as Xbox Live Marketplace and on the PlayStation Network.Joust was ported and released on the Xbox 360 via the Xbox Live Marketplace. The game was unscaled to appear in HD and was sold for 400 Microsoft points or $5.Joust was also ported to the PlayStation 3 via the PlayStation Network, sold for $4.99 and published by Sony Online Entertainment.[CR]</plot>
			<releasedate>7/7/1983</releasedate>
			<year>1983</year>
			<genre>Action</genre>
			<studio>Atari</studio>
			<nplayers>1-2 Sim</nplayers>
			<perspective>3rd-Person</perspective>
			<rating>4.2</rating>
			<videoid>YKevASnO1hE</videoid>
			<thegamesdb_id>5167</thegamesdb_id>
			<mobygames_url>http://www.mobygames.com/game/atari-5200/joust</mobygames_url>
			<giantbomb_url>http://www.giantbomb.com/joust/3030-11689/</giantbomb_url>
			<boxart1>3hhcEn1.jpg</boxart1>
			<boxart2>ZyeJTU4.jpg</boxart2>
			<boxart3>aXWGdNT.jpg</boxart3>
			<snapshot1>AcNuFF0.gif</snapshot1>
			<snapshot2>AlZnDUd.gif</snapshot2>
			<snapshot3>7vRufvw.gif</snapshot3>
			<snapshot4>2AcuJmm.gif</snapshot4>
			<snapshot5>wMRp8Mg.gif</snapshot5>
			<snapshot6>Genn64g.gif</snapshot6>
			<snapshot7>r7Zwpuy.jpg</snapshot7>
			<snapshot8>icZpeJs.jpg</snapshot8>
			<snapshot9>50ge0vf.jpg</snapshot9>
			<snapshot10>obtKxb3.jpg</snapshot10>
			<banner1>LivaVWM.jpg</banner1>
			<clearlogo1>6RBMBuU.png</clearlogo1>
		</game>
		<game name="Jungle Hunt">
			<description>Jungle Hunt</description>
			<rom crc="2c676662" name="MAME_0.185_Software_List_ROMs_non-merged/MAME_0.185_Software_List_ROMs_non-merged.zip/MAME%200.185%20Software%20List%20ROMs%20%28non-merged%29%2Fa5200%2Fjungleh.zip" sha1="fa02ee04cfad90c6ccf9d9b984e3b7b3327fec12" size="12278" />
			<title_clean>Jungle Hunt</title_clean>
			<plot>[CR][B]Overview:[/B][CR]Jungle Hunt, a side-scrolling platformer released for arcades in 1982 and for the Atari 2600 in 1983, is a three phase platformer that puts the player in the shoes of a typical jungle survivalist, tasked with rescuing a lady from the hands of a group of bloodthirsty cannibals. The game was originally called Jungle King and featured Tarzan as the protagonist, but due to copyright issues over his use, it was changed to Jungle Hunt.The first level features vine swings of varying distances, where perfect timing is required to proceed.The second level is a side-scrolling swimming challenge that pits the explorer against crocodiles. Armed with a knife, the player can choose to avoid or stab, with extra points awarded for stabbing a crocodile with its mouth open.The last level is a side-scrolling boulder jump, with a voodoo doctor end boss. Boulders of different sizes, speeds and intervals enter from the right side of the screen, and the player must leap over them. As more boulders enter the screen, timing becomes critical. The end boss shakes from side to side and leaps very high in the air. Successful completion requires timing a run directly beneath the boss character as he leaps.Like many 2600 games, the game allows you to start back at the beginning to replay at a higher difficulty.[CR][B]Controls:[/B][CR]The home console version of the game was designed for use with the classic Atari 2600 joystick controller.Level 1: Stick moves character up and down on vine. Button initiates jump.Level 2: Stick moves character up down left right. Button stabs knife.Level 3: Stick moves Character left and right. Button jumps.[CR]</plot>
			<releasedate>7/7/1983</releasedate>
			<year>1983</year>
			<studio>Atari</studio>
			<nplayers>1-2 Sim</nplayers>
			<perspective>3rd-Person</perspective>
			<rating>3.5</rating>
			<videoid>ULTx81KjQYU</videoid>
			<thegamesdb_id>5169</thegamesdb_id>
			<mobygames_url>http://www.mobygames.com/game/atari-5200/jungle-hunt</mobygames_url>
			<giantbomb_url>http://www.giantbomb.com/jungle-hunt/3030-11421/</giantbomb_url>
			<boxart1>wx6RPvp.jpg</boxart1>
			<boxart2>I6rbYX8.jpg</boxart2>
			<boxart3>DmSmUdn.jpg</boxart3>
			<snapshot1>lKSss93.gif</snapshot1>
			<snapshot2>f74sNtU.gif</snapshot2>
			<snapshot3>qhGcQet.gif</snapshot3>
			<snapshot4>VstewjH.gif</snapshot4>
			<snapshot5>1YPTjA5.gif</snapshot5>
			<snapshot6>MldPttU.gif</snapshot6>
			<snapshot7>Q5nE1IC.gif</snapshot7>
			<snapshot8>y2nXvgV.jpg</snapshot8>
			<snapshot9>BDOygrT.jpg</snapshot9>
			<snapshot10>Crdf8t6.jpg</snapshot10>
			<banner1>vbZqpC2.jpg</banner1>
			<clearlogo1>VXvjWqR.png</clearlogo1>
		</game>
		<game name="K-Razy Shoot Out">
			<description>K-Razy Shoot Out</description>
			<rom crc="ee702214" name="MAME_0.185_Software_List_ROMs_non-merged/MAME_0.185_Software_List_ROMs_non-merged.zip/MAME%200.185%20Software%20List%20ROMs%20%28non-merged%29%2Fa5200%2Fkshoot.zip" sha1="c7eb2b4a46a197adfedf33c2ccc17d8424d681c4" size="5544" />
			<title_clean>K-Razy Shoot Out</title_clean>
			<plot>K-Razy Shootout is an arcade action game similar to Berzerk. You are in a maze filled with dangerous robots. Your goal is to shoot as many of the robots as you can to earn points. If you collide with a robot, robot fire, or the maze walls you lose a life. The game ends when all of your reserve lives have been lost. Each sector of the game has a timer bar; if you complete a sector while the bar is in the green or yellow section, bonus points are earned. If the timer runs out, you lose a life. Each sector will have one or more exits in the maze; you may exit a maze at any time, but if you leave before all of the robots are destroyed then you will have to go back two sectors.</plot>
			<releasedate>7/7/1982</releasedate>
			<year>1983</year>
			<genre>Action</genre>
			<studio>CBS Electronics</studio>
			<nplayers>1</nplayers>
			<perspective>3rd-Person</perspective>
			<rating>3.0</rating>
			<thegamesdb_id>5176</thegamesdb_id>
			<mobygames_url>http://www.mobygames.com/game/atari-5200/k-razy-shoot-out</mobygames_url>
			<giantbomb_url>http://www.giantbomb.com/k-razy-shootout/3030-9484/</giantbomb_url>
			<boxart1>vsgP7Vb.jpg</boxart1>
			<boxart2>yvntNKM.jpg</boxart2>
			<boxart3>lef7m8q.jpg</boxart3>
			<snapshot1>HGH7xQs.gif</snapshot1>
			<snapshot2>xUmMtso.gif</snapshot2>
			<snapshot3>fL19y3c.gif</snapshot3>
			<snapshot4>0jqNfpz.gif</snapshot4>
			<snapshot5>p2czbi8.gif</snapshot5>
			<snapshot6>P9DXPXt.gif</snapshot6>
			<snapshot7>PHRHDUL.jpg</snapshot7>
			<snapshot8>ImttMVA.jpg</snapshot8>
			<snapshot9>YvzjjMS.jpg</snapshot9>
			<snapshot10>uQ0QedF.jpg</snapshot10>
		</game>
		<game name="Kaboom!">
			<description>Kaboom!</description>
			<rom crc="420f5d0b" name="MAME_0.185_Software_List_ROMs_non-merged/MAME_0.185_Software_List_ROMs_non-merged.zip/MAME%200.185%20Software%20List%20ROMs%20%28non-merged%29%2Fa5200%2Fkaboom.zip" sha1="a80f876a89a8ceacc71da5d9c02b546970b17730" size="3343" />
			<title_clean>Kaboom!</title_clean>
			<plot>[CR][B]Overview:[/B][CR]Kaboom! is a single-screen action game, where the player catches bombs in a series of three buckets. With a gameplay style somewhat similar to Breakout, the player uses a paddle (2600 version) or joystick (5200 version) to control the action.[CR][B]Gameplay:[/B][CR][B]Gameplay:[/B] takes place on a single screen. The Mad Bomber, at the top of the screen glides left and right while dropping bombs. The player controls a series of three buckets, which are used to catch the bombs before they land at the bottom of the screen. As gameplay progresses, the Mad Bomber moves and drops bombs more rapidly, increasing difficulty. Points are scored on a sliding scale; the more groups of bombs caught, the more points are awarded - 8 groups giving the maximum multiplier. Each bomb group comes faster, and has more bombs than the prior.DifficultyThe difficulty switches control the width of the buckets. The 'B' level difficulty decreases the bucket size to less than half of the 'A' level difficulty. The difficulty does not affect scoring.Missed BombsIf the player misses a bomb, the score multiplier is reset, and the player loses a bucket, increasing the challenge on subsequent attempts. Gameplay resumes one bomb set prior to the current bomb set, but with half as many bombs to catch. When all buckets are gone, the game is over. Scoring 1000 points earns the player a new bucket, with a maximum of three earned buckets. Earned buckets may not be stockpiled; a player must earn 1000 points subsequent to losing a bucket to gain a new one. Because missed bombs lower the difficulty, a high level strategy is to purposely miss a bomb around the 900 mark, if successful the player will be easily able to regain an extra bucked while at the same time slowing the onslaught of bombs.ModesThe Atari 2600 version of Kaboom! features 2-player alternating play, with independent difficulty selection. The 5200 version additionally supports a mode whereby players alternate between controlling the buckets, and the Mad Bomber.[CR][B]Trivia:[/B][CR]Like all Activision releases of this era, the box, manual and cartridge label all feature the name of the designer of that particular game. In this case, Larry Kaplan. Additionally, Larry Kaplan provided several gameplay tips at the back of the instruction manual.The mad bomber has a "sad face" while dropping bombs, but a "happy face" if one gets by the player. A score of 10,000 points leads to an easter-egg: a surprised face, regardless of the action.As with many Activision games, a patch was available for excellent gameplay. Providing activision with a photograph of a score of 3000 or better would get that player a free "Bucket Brigade" patch.Activision released an LCD keychain version of the game in the early 1990s. [CR]</plot>
			<releasedate>7/7/1983</releasedate>
			<year>1983</year>
			<genre>Action</genre>
			<studio>Activision</studio>
			<nplayers>1-2 Sim</nplayers>
			<perspective>3rd-Person</perspective>
			<rating>2.8</rating>
			<thegamesdb_id>5170</thegamesdb_id>
			<mobygames_url>http://www.mobygames.com/game/atari-5200/kaboom</mobygames_url>
			<giantbomb_url>http://www.giantbomb.com/kaboom/3030-9094/</giantbomb_url>
			<boxart1>fFyiiFt.jpg</boxart1>
			<boxart2>qcFpUuL.jpg</boxart2>
			<boxart3>U3pxH23.jpg</boxart3>
			<snapshot1>gNdauAp.gif</snapshot1>
			<snapshot2>IyoIWwN.gif</snapshot2>
			<snapshot3>4aNvwUk.gif</snapshot3>
			<snapshot4>Fdq3V46.png</snapshot4>
			<snapshot5>ccWODrm.png</snapshot5>
			<snapshot6>VIjNv0H.png</snapshot6>
			<snapshot7>LYAGDk4.png</snapshot7>
			<snapshot8>qEXdFkp.png</snapshot8>
			<snapshot9>b1hQMnh.png</snapshot9>
			<snapshot10>SQg4wUD.png</snapshot10>
		</game>
		<game name="Kangaroo">
			<description>Kangaroo</description>
			<rom crc="ecfa624f" name="MAME_0.185_Software_List_ROMs_non-merged/MAME_0.185_Software_List_ROMs_non-merged.zip/MAME%200.185%20Software%20List%20ROMs%20%28non-merged%29%2Fa5200%2Fkangaroo.zip" sha1="c3dbeed7adc0e282bf76332ab5a3209550e26d02" size="10015" />
			<title_clean>Kangaroo</title_clean>
			<plot>Kangaroo, released in 1983 and then again with silver box label in 1988, was the story of a mother kangaroo searching for her kidnapped baby.  The game utilized the Atari 2600 joystick to help mother maneuver, "Donkey Kong" type level designs.  Every different direction on the joystick would send mother ducking or leaping from ledges or to collect scattered fruit for points.  The red button on the joystick controlled her "boxing," which was frequently needed to fight of the onslaught of evil monkeys bent on keeping baby kangaroo kidnapped.  The game was remembered as being especially difficult as you start the game with 3 lives and no continues.Kangaroo is another gem by yesterday's standards, but remains a formidable challenge to any newcomer to the games design.In one of the levels that broke with the game's usual ascent format, your joey is on top of a column of monkeys that you must punch repeatedly in order to knock each monkey out from other the platform your joey is on.  You punch the HELL out of those monkeys, I can tell you.The game uses Stephen Foster's song "O! Suzanna!" to signal level completion (when your little joey says MOM in big letters after you rescue him or her).  When ringing the bell to bring in the next selection of fruit, you hear the Westminster Quarters song (often heard in college campuses). As you get closer to the top of each level a gorilla will come out and want to box you.  It's best to avoid him and keep going till you reach the top.[CR]</plot>
			<releasedate>7/7/1983</releasedate>
			<year>1983</year>
			<genre>Action</genre>
			<studio>Atari</studio>
			<nplayers>1-2 Sim</nplayers>
			<perspective>3rd-Person</perspective>
			<rating>3.0</rating>
			<thegamesdb_id>5171</thegamesdb_id>
			<mobygames_url>http://www.mobygames.com/game/atari-5200/kangaroo</mobygames_url>
			<giantbomb_url>http://www.giantbomb.com/kangaroo/3030-11432/</giantbomb_url>
			<boxart1>JfGNHYZ.jpg</boxart1>
			<boxart2>GREMPSe.jpg</boxart2>
			<boxart3>9s1BTB7.jpg</boxart3>
			<snapshot1>HDkiysn.gif</snapshot1>
			<snapshot2>0pBFTjQ.gif</snapshot2>
			<snapshot3>6sEjDqT.gif</snapshot3>
			<snapshot4>xoyhSxV.gif</snapshot4>
			<snapshot5>C0kIHYn.png</snapshot5>
			<snapshot6>VmuJihC.png</snapshot6>
			<snapshot7>O8w92Cc.jpg</snapshot7>
			<snapshot8>YEBjJuk.jpg</snapshot8>
			<snapshot9>L8YBUGD.png</snapshot9>
			<snapshot10>MV66Jkg.png</snapshot10>
			<banner1>Oc1h00U.jpg</banner1>
			<clearlogo1>a6MEdHJ.png</clearlogo1>
		</game>
		<game name="Keystone Kapers">
			<description>Keystone Kapers</description>
			<rom crc="8fe3bb2c" name="MAME_0.185_Software_List_ROMs_non-merged/MAME_0.185_Software_List_ROMs_non-merged.zip/MAME%200.185%20Software%20List%20ROMs%20%28non-merged%29%2Fa5200%2Fkeykaper.zip" sha1="9f31c85a13e919135438590601e33bef11a8df8a" size="6439" />
			<title_clean>Keystone Kapers</title_clean>
			<plot>The notorious thief Harry Hooligan is on the loose! You play the part of Officer Keystone Kelly, sent in to capture Harry. Harry is trapped in a four story mall, and is running as fast as he can to reach the exit at the top. Your job is to catch up to him and send him to prison. You will need to use either the escalators at the end of each floor, or the elevator in the middle to go from floor to floor. The escalators may be further away, but the elevator moves pretty slowly so you will need to decide which route will be faster in getting you closer to your goal. If Harry can make it to the top before you catch him, you will have to retry that level. Harry has no intention of letting you catch him easily, and is hurling everything he can find in an attempt to slow you down. Shopping carts, bouncing balls, biplanes, and more will all be flying past on the screen and will either slow you down or send you back to the beginning if you get hit. As the levels progress, Harry will run faster and faster, and more objects will be tossed your way to duck and jump over.</plot>
			<releasedate>7/7/1984</releasedate>
			<year>1984</year>
			<genre>Action</genre>
			<studio>Activision</studio>
			<nplayers>1</nplayers>
			<perspective>3rd-Person</perspective>
			<rating>4.2</rating>
			<thegamesdb_id>5172</thegamesdb_id>
			<mobygames_url>http://www.mobygames.com/game/atari-5200/keystone-kapers</mobygames_url>
			<giantbomb_url>http://www.giantbomb.com/keystone-kapers/3030-4423/</giantbomb_url>
			<boxart1>jPQDsKM.jpg</boxart1>
			<boxart2>uTxj5HE.jpg</boxart2>
			<boxart3>ZAR1PCQ.jpg</boxart3>
			<snapshot1>gUhAdxH.gif</snapshot1>
			<snapshot2>FbTQ9XP.gif</snapshot2>
			<snapshot3>mGkNEeK.gif</snapshot3>
			<snapshot4>UerOIFm.gif</snapshot4>
			<snapshot5>HIxnHuu.gif</snapshot5>
			<snapshot6>z4VL3dv.png</snapshot6>
			<snapshot7>cx4ZADD.png</snapshot7>
			<snapshot8>KyLTlCQ.png</snapshot8>
			<snapshot9>Tx70peH.png</snapshot9>
			<snapshot10>B7Sy3IM.png</snapshot10>
			<clearlogo1>OKWUR2M.png</clearlogo1>
		</game>
		<game name="The Last Starfighter (Prototype)">
			<description>The Last Starfighter (Prototype)</description>
			<rom crc="83517703" name="MAME_0.185_Software_List_ROMs_non-merged/MAME_0.185_Software_List_ROMs_non-merged.zip/MAME%200.185%20Software%20List%20ROMs%20%28non-merged%29%2Fa5200%2Flaststar.zip" sha1="4046f60602254a7d86d2a6efd1a330455eaec119" size="12885" />
			<title_clean>The Last Starfighter</title_clean>
			<plot>"Greetings Starfighter. You have been recruited by the Star League to defend the Frontier against Xur and the Ko-Dan armada."[CR]It's not just a tag line, it's also the instructions!  Yes, you've been recruited to help the Star League destroy Xur and his forces once and for all.  To accomplish this, you'll have to travel to the Procyon system and destroy the Ko-Dan in their own galaxy.  However, while you're off playing cowboy in a distant galaxy, the Ko-Dan armada are planning their own attack on your home system of Celos IV.  So not only must you defeat the whole Ko-Dan empire single handed, you must also defend your galaxy at the same time.  Accomplishing both tasks at once is all about strategy, sharp shooting, and a little luck. [CR]The Last Starfighter is based on the 80s movie. Unfortunately despite being finished it wasn't released for the Atari 5200. However it does exist in prototype form and was eventually officially released for the Atari XE/XL as Star Raiders II with some minor changes. Also an arcade version was supposed to be released but was canned as well. On top of all that this game wasn't even originally The Last Starfighter and instead was originally called Orbiter that was retooled. Quite a history for a prototype!</plot>
			<releasedate>8/5/1984</releasedate>
			<year>1984</year>
			<genre>Flight Simulator, Shooter</genre>
			<studio>Atari</studio>
			<videoid>eKYToZkShSA</videoid>
			<thegamesdb_id>32354</thegamesdb_id>
			<boxart1>lmjZW58.jpg</boxart1>
			<boxart2>Ik0LQFQ.jpg</boxart2>
		</game>
		<game name="Looney Tunes Hotel (Prototype)">
			<description>Looney Tunes Hotel (Prototype)</description>
			<rom crc="84df4925" name="MAME_0.185_Software_List_ROMs_non-merged/MAME_0.185_Software_List_ROMs_non-merged.zip/MAME%200.185%20Software%20List%20ROMs%20%28non-merged%29%2Fa5200%2Flooneyh.zip" sha1="bc4a536616ac45689b3ad790f6b1394ebbd8cc7e" size="9446" />
			<title_clean>Looney Tunes Hotel</title_clean>
			<plot>Looney Tunes Hotel was a nearly completed video game that was going to be released for the Atari 5200. Players were to play on a set of hotels, but Atari never got to finishing the game.</plot>
			<genre>Platform, Stealth</genre>
			<studio>Atari</studio>
			<thegamesdb_id>32355</thegamesdb_id>
			<giantbomb_url>http://www.giantbomb.com/looney-tunes-hotel/3030-30695/</giantbomb_url>
			<boxart1>MNMCKqb.jpg</boxart1>
		</game>
		<game name="Mario Bros.">
			<description>Mario Bros.</description>
			<rom crc="873742f1" name="MAME_0.185_Software_List_ROMs_non-merged/MAME_0.185_Software_List_ROMs_non-merged.zip/MAME%200.185%20Software%20List%20ROMs%20%28non-merged%29%2Fa5200%2Fmario.zip" sha1="a293b6b06050e11029d97137f2b1b36059567273" size="12345" />
			<title_clean>Mario Bros.</title_clean>
			<plot>[CR][B]Overview:[/B][CR]Mario Bros. is the first in a long line of Mario Bros. titles, although its differences from the later games are significant.[CR]Comparison to other Mario Games[CR]Mario Bros. FirstsMario - initially called Jumpman - was introduced in Nintendo's first Donkey Kong video game. There, his only offensive ability was the hammer which, like Pac-Man's power pellets, were limited in number and duration. Here, Mario has an ongoing offensive power, one that he would use throughout the sequels, that of jumping under a thing that is standing on a ledge above. While this is usually an optional attack in the later games, for Mario Bros. it's vital for finishing a given stage. Punching underneath a monster flips it over or changes its color (in lieu of flipping it over). Only when upside down is a monster safe to touch. Should Mario touch a monster, he actually boots it into the water at the bottom of the screen, scoring points and defeating the enemy. Other firsts which would find their way into later Mario Bros. titles:This game was the first appearance of the iconic turtle enemy called the Shell Creeper, later dubbed the Koopa Troopa. Mario could not, however, jump on their backs as he could later, even though the Shell Creepers and Koopa Troopas look nearly identical.Shining sewer pipes, too, made their first appearance. This time they serve as monster dispensers, and reminders that game takes place in a sewer.Many things fall into the sewers, including baby turtles which grow up to be Shell Creepers, but another iconic thing that might get lost in a storm drain is a coin. Thus, coins are brought in as extra scoring items every time an enemy is killed. If Mario picks them up before they reach the bottom of the screen, the player gets extra points.The POW block, used to flip all the monsters over who are currently standing on a surface, is later employed in other Super Mario games (though its "zapper-like" abilities are changed).Fireballs also make an appearance, looking a bit more like the fireballs Mario and Luigi throw when they've picked up a flower in Super Mario Bros., but fireballs in this game are enemies.And last, but not least, the simultaneous two-player mode introduces Luigi, a swapped-palette Mario.Elements Unique to Mario Bros.Many elements in Mario Bros. did not get picked up for later installments of the Mario Bros. series. Other enemies, such as the hopping Fighter Flies, ice-patch creating Slipice blobs, and crabby Sidesteppers are seen nowhere else. Neither is the complex punching-under-then-hopping-up-to-kill-the-monster mechanic, although there are certain situations in later games where this is a viable tactic. Touching an enemy when it isn't supine brings instant death, and possibly the most notable difference is that the game is largely defensive. In Donkey Kong before it, and all Super Mario games after, Mario as a player character is largely the mover, moving the game from scene to scene. Here Mario and Luigi defend territory until they win - the scenery eventually changes, but only slightly.[CR]</plot>
			<releasedate>7/7/1983</releasedate>
			<year>1983</year>
			<genre>Action</genre>
			<studio>Atari</studio>
			<nplayers>1-2 Alt</nplayers>
			<perspective>3rd-Person</perspective>
			<rating>2.9</rating>
			<thegamesdb_id>5178</thegamesdb_id>
			<mobygames_url>http://www.mobygames.com/game/atari-5200/mario-bros</mobygames_url>
			<giantbomb_url>http://www.giantbomb.com/mario-bros/3030-19726/</giantbomb_url>
			<boxart1>tQVvlWW.jpg</boxart1>
			<boxart2>UBv7vBE.jpg</boxart2>
			<boxart3>rrl7vYb.jpg</boxart3>
			<snapshot1>AmXnsWl.gif</snapshot1>
			<snapshot2>7uKrwBn.gif</snapshot2>
			<snapshot3>KLijaPm.gif</snapshot3>
			<snapshot4>OEUJ5oA.gif</snapshot4>
			<snapshot5>AePzv5h.gif</snapshot5>
			<snapshot6>CAcvNYp.gif</snapshot6>
			<snapshot7>Tseed5i.png</snapshot7>
			<snapshot8>SEjtiSN.png</snapshot8>
			<snapshot9>N3GD6wc.png</snapshot9>
			<snapshot10>Jq3ixW7.png</snapshot10>
			<fanart1>Ucg8V0g.jpg</fanart1>
			<banner1>izB3IiK.jpg</banner1>
			<clearlogo1>RAHENNm.png</clearlogo1>
		</game>
		<game name="Meebzork (Prototype)">
			<description>Meebzork (Prototype)</description>
			<rom crc="9fb13411" name="MAME_0.185_Software_List_ROMs_non-merged/MAME_0.185_Software_List_ROMs_non-merged.zip/MAME%200.185%20Software%20List%20ROMs%20%28non-merged%29%2Fa5200%2Fmeebzork.zip" sha1="ff0f1d9ed0ae45e3c81b252f3d0a335e03b0aa4b" size="15097" />
			<title_clean>Meebzork</title_clean>
			<plot>An unfinished prototype game that was originally planned as a shooter but the last available version ends up being more an action/adventure game. There is an early build available of the shooter as well.[CR]You are a warrior named Meebzork who can practice or play through 6 different levels (not including another level that was going to be after you completed a board and would allow you to choose a next one). All 6 levels are different in what they require. While unfinished and unpolished you can see a lot of potential.</plot>
			<releasedate>16/11/1983</releasedate>
			<year>1983</year>
			<genre>Adventure</genre>
			<studio>Atari</studio>
			<nplayers>1</nplayers>
			<videoid>adxE-tHynl0</videoid>
			<thegamesdb_id>34485</thegamesdb_id>
			<boxart1>hobp38S.jpg</boxart1>
		</game>
		<game name="MegaMania">
			<description>MegaMania</description>
			<rom crc="240a1e1a" name="MAME_0.185_Software_List_ROMs_non-merged/MAME_0.185_Software_List_ROMs_non-merged.zip/MAME%200.185%20Software%20List%20ROMs%20%28non-merged%29%2Fa5200%2Fmegmania.zip" sha1="f5512460c6b6d3a1baa0b23adf6a3a37fe308eb3" size="6059" />
			<title_clean>MegaMania</title_clean>
			<plot>[CR][B]Overview:[/B][CR]Megamania is an Atari 2600 shoot em up game released in 1982 by Activision. It was designed by Steve Cartwright, and was later ported to Atari 8-bit and Atari 5200, with some minor interface/graphical improvements, by Glyn Anderson. Insofar as the game has a plot, it takes place in a Space Nightmare, brought on by the protagonist, a pilot on an intergalactic space cruiser, consuming two pepperoni pizzas and a quart of chocolate mint ice cream. [CR][B]Gameplay:[/B][CR] Megamania is a fairly traditional shoot em up.The player controls a spaceship visually similar to the Starship Enterprise armed with a laser cannon. A time restraint in the form of an contiuously dwindling energy bar is displayed on the bottom of the screen, and when this runs out, the player loses one of his three initial ships. The ship can be moved left and right, and shoot, and that is the full extent of the player's control of it.  As usual with Atari 2600 games, the game has several gameplay modes; the player can select to have missiles that follow the sideways motion of the spaceship, or missiles that fire straight, independent of the spaceship. The game's enemies feature a typically early 80s variety of random foodstuffs and geometric shapes, which come at your space ship in increasingly intricate patterns as you progress through the levels.  Scoring is performed by killing enemies, and the points awarded for each kill increase from level to level. The player is also awarded for finishing levels quickly, as the remaining energy bar is also tallied into the score. Should the total score exceed 999.999 points, the game crashes, as a result of a programming error.  The lyrics to the theme song bear mentioning. It was performed by The Tubes, a San Fransisco-based rock band. "Mega! Megamania. Megamania!! It's gonna drive you insane. You've got to shoot to survive, you've got to run to stay alive! You may regret it, the day you get it- It's never gonna let you alone!"[CR]</plot>
			<releasedate>7/7/1983</releasedate>
			<year>1983</year>
			<genre>Action</genre>
			<studio>Activision</studio>
			<nplayers>1-2 Sim</nplayers>
			<perspective>3rd-Person</perspective>
			<rating>3.5</rating>
			<thegamesdb_id>5179</thegamesdb_id>
			<mobygames_url>http://www.mobygames.com/game/atari-5200/megamania</mobygames_url>
			<giantbomb_url>http://www.giantbomb.com/megamania/3030-9694/</giantbomb_url>
			<boxart1>hXc3HTX.jpg</boxart1>
			<boxart2>EnDW8bV.jpg</boxart2>
			<boxart3>PZD6gQA.jpg</boxart3>
			<snapshot1>eFXUldW.gif</snapshot1>
			<snapshot2>ffIXciN.gif</snapshot2>
			<snapshot3>IZNKKBZ.gif</snapshot3>
			<snapshot4>xKg62UA.gif</snapshot4>
			<snapshot5>fHbyP8n.gif</snapshot5>
			<snapshot6>6FIkQq9.png</snapshot6>
			<snapshot7>ptoini9.png</snapshot7>
			<snapshot8>RBSNSi2.png</snapshot8>
			<snapshot9>9mvUDwn.png</snapshot9>
			<snapshot10>PjtziN8.png</snapshot10>
		</game>
		<game name="Meteorites">
			<description>Meteorites</description>
			<rom crc="ab8e035b" name="MAME_0.185_Software_List_ROMs_non-merged/MAME_0.185_Software_List_ROMs_non-merged.zip/MAME%200.185%20Software%20List%20ROMs%20%28non-merged%29%2Fa5200%2Fmeteorit.zip" sha1="32d86a381feff43149b66336dcc4ba2523273228" size="7326" />
			<title_clean>Meteorites</title_clean>
			<plot>Meteorites is an arcade action game featuring gameplay similar to Asteroids. You control a spaceship surrounded by numerous asteroids; your goal is to destroy them! Each time you shoot an asteroid, it will break up into smaller asteroids. Eventually the pieces will be small enough that you can destroy them. When you have destroyed all of the asteroids, you will move on to the next, more difficult level. To make the game more difficult, a flying saucer will also appear from time to time and try to shoot your spaceship. To get out of trouble quickly, your spaceship also may enter hyperspace transporting you to a new location on the screen. Be careful, though, sometimes the new location is worse than the one you left!</plot>
			<releasedate>7/7/1983</releasedate>
			<year>1983</year>
			<genre>Action</genre>
			<studio>Electra Concepts International Corp.</studio>
			<nplayers>1-2 Sim</nplayers>
			<perspective>3rd-Person</perspective>
			<rating>2.5</rating>
			<thegamesdb_id>5180</thegamesdb_id>
			<mobygames_url>http://www.mobygames.com/game/atari-5200/meteorites</mobygames_url>
			<giantbomb_url>http://www.giantbomb.com/meteorites/3030-20114/</giantbomb_url>
			<boxart1>GfwxWQx.jpg</boxart1>
			<boxart2>uI3A6Py.jpg</boxart2>
			<snapshot1>XluPoZU.gif</snapshot1>
			<snapshot2>lDNYwgV.gif</snapshot2>
			<snapshot3>ZCwVIcw.gif</snapshot3>
			<snapshot4>JL7IX7a.gif</snapshot4>
			<snapshot5>8YtayzI.png</snapshot5>
			<snapshot6>opDFOtn.png</snapshot6>
			<snapshot7>ZJfxijg.png</snapshot7>
			<banner1>6q7wqN3.jpg</banner1>
			<clearlogo1>stQslZZ.png</clearlogo1>
		</game>
		<game name="Microgammon SB (Prototype)">
			<description>Microgammon SB (Prototype)</description>
			<rom crc="931a454a" name="MAME_0.185_Software_List_ROMs_non-merged/MAME_0.185_Software_List_ROMs_non-merged.zip/MAME%200.185%20Software%20List%20ROMs%20%28non-merged%29%2Fa5200%2Fmicrogam.zip" sha1="2f152a857a8a58d602b3c717612d9744423ee495" size="6430" />
			<title_clean>Microgammon SB</title_clean>
			<plot>Microgammon SB originally started out as an Apple IIe game.  According to programmer Steve Baker, he had originally developed the game for the Apple when he decided to port it to the Atari 5200.  Since the 5200 possessed a high resolution mode that was on par with the Apple's, the conversion was pretty straightforward.  However one side effect of using the 5200's high-res mode was that the graphics were in black &amp; white only.  However most players find that this really doesn't distract much from the game since it uses black and white pieces anyway.</plot>
			<releasedate>15/8/1983</releasedate>
			<year>1983</year>
			<genre>Strategy</genre>
			<studio>Atari</studio>
			<nplayers>1-2 Alt</nplayers>
			<ESRB>E - Everyone</ESRB>
			<thegamesdb_id>34486</thegamesdb_id>
			<boxart1>vpS2YDL.png</boxart1>
		</game>
		<game name="Millipede (Prototype)">
			<description>Millipede (Prototype)</description>
			<rom crc="969cfe1a" name="MAME_0.185_Software_List_ROMs_non-merged/MAME_0.185_Software_List_ROMs_non-merged.zip/MAME%200.185%20Software%20List%20ROMs%20%28non-merged%29%2Fa5200%2Fmilliped.zip" sha1="1243a8ecfc02a74ae4e1f4fcda38502776f45cb0" size="11661" />
			<title_clean>Millipede</title_clean>
			<plot>An unreleased prototype conversion of the arcade game Millipede. It was completed but never released due to Atari abandoning the 5200 near it's completion.[CR]The goal is to survive wave after wave of various insects while trying to destroy a Millipede that makes its way down the screen towards your player. While very similar to Centipede it adds quite a few new quirks such as new insects to contend with and DDT bombs that when shot will destroy what is around them.</plot>
			<releasedate>31/1/1984</releasedate>
			<year>1984</year>
			<genre>Shooter</genre>
			<studio>Atari</studio>
			<nplayers>1-2 Alt</nplayers>
			<videoid>vgg8OHjPito</videoid>
			<thegamesdb_id>34487</thegamesdb_id>
			<boxart1>rlTIpTl.jpg</boxart1>
			<snapshot1>5creoF7.jpg</snapshot1>
			<snapshot2>Usl9PwP.jpg</snapshot2>
		</game>
		<game name="Miner 2049er">
			<description>Miner 2049er</description>
			<rom crc="7df1adfb" name="MAME_0.185_Software_List_ROMs_non-merged/MAME_0.185_Software_List_ROMs_non-merged.zip/MAME%200.185%20Software%20List%20ROMs%20%28non-merged%29%2Fa5200%2Fmine2049.zip" sha1="0564b1867a0b570d66dfcbc11adc3e51a2c6f28c" size="12546" />
			<title_clean>Miner 2049er</title_clean>
			<plot>You play the part of Bounty Bob, and it is your mission to explore every inch of an abandoned mine. As you walk over floor sections in the mine, the floor will change color. When all of the floor sections have been changed in color, you can move on to the next, more challenging level. To reach all of the floor sections, you will need to figure out how to get there! You can jump (be careful not to fall too far though, or you will be squished), climb up and down ladders, and use different transportation devices that can be found on the levels (such as an elevator, slides, a springboard, or a canon!) Wandering around the mine are numerous radioactive creatures which get in Bounty Bobs way. Also scattered throughout the mines are various artifacts left behind; if Bounty Bob collects one of these, the creatures will temporarily become vulnerable. If Bounty Bob runs into one of the creatures in this state the creature will be destroyed, but if he runs into a creature while it is glowing Bounty Bob will be destroyed! There is a total of ten different levels, and to complete them all you will need quick reflexes as well as figure out a unique strategy for each level.</plot>
			<releasedate>7/7/1983</releasedate>
			<year>1983</year>
			<genre>Action</genre>
			<studio>Big Five Software</studio>
			<nplayers>1-2 Sim</nplayers>
			<perspective>Platform</perspective>
			<rating>5.0</rating>
			<thegamesdb_id>5181</thegamesdb_id>
			<mobygames_url>http://www.mobygames.com/game/atari-5200/miner-2049er</mobygames_url>
			<giantbomb_url>http://www.giantbomb.com/miner-2049er/3030-14533/</giantbomb_url>
			<boxart1>0KZNNLu.jpg</boxart1>
			<boxart2>n0U0xv2.jpg</boxart2>
			<boxart3>vS69w9x.jpg</boxart3>
			<boxart4>70hZMmy.jpg</boxart4>
			<snapshot1>RzTVlx6.gif</snapshot1>
			<snapshot2>v2cftta.gif</snapshot2>
			<snapshot3>zqvrOgN.gif</snapshot3>
			<snapshot4>ftBRRg7.gif</snapshot4>
			<snapshot5>awEQJud.gif</snapshot5>
			<snapshot6>rCX9xq7.gif</snapshot6>
			<snapshot7>Sgg6AjH.gif</snapshot7>
			<snapshot8>Em5wWKZ.gif</snapshot8>
			<snapshot9>5Ue3qpc.gif</snapshot9>
			<snapshot10>dFkfT8g.png</snapshot10>
			<clearlogo1>uDzVLVQ.png</clearlogo1>
		</game>
		<game name="Miniature Golf (Prototype)">
			<description>Miniature Golf (Prototype)</description>
			<rom crc="c597c087" name="MAME_0.185_Software_List_ROMs_non-merged/MAME_0.185_Software_List_ROMs_non-merged.zip/MAME%200.185%20Software%20List%20ROMs%20%28non-merged%29%2Fa5200%2Fminigolf.zip" sha1="ef4d3ee7b4da2ef79c6f4d0d1833f10c1eb7725e" size="7032" />
			<title_clean>Miniature Golf</title_clean>
			<plot>Unreleased prototype game by Steve Baker for the Atari 5200. However it was completed and is fully playable. Due to the Hi-Res mode used the game has some odd choices for colors but other than that is quite well done and simulates Miniature Golf very well. [CR]Control is handled entirely by the keypad, so the non-centering 5200 joystick doesn't hinder the gameplay.  Pushing the # and * keys changes the direction the ball will be hit (represented by an arrow) and the 1-9 keys are used to indicate the power of the swing (1=lowest and 9=highest).</plot>
			<releasedate>10/2/1983</releasedate>
			<year>1983</year>
			<genre>Sports</genre>
			<studio>Atari</studio>
			<nplayers>1-2 Alt</nplayers>
			<videoid>gNJuO19kEgM</videoid>
			<thegamesdb_id>34488</thegamesdb_id>
			<boxart1>FxqUCK1.jpg</boxart1>
			<snapshot1>WkLBUZp.jpg</snapshot1>
			<snapshot2>B8PN0FW.jpg</snapshot2>
		</game>
		<game name="Missile Command">
			<description>Missile Command</description>
			<rom crc="44d3ff6f" name="MAME_0.185_Software_List_ROMs_non-merged/MAME_0.185_Software_List_ROMs_non-merged.zip/MAME%200.185%20Software%20List%20ROMs%20%28non-merged%29%2Fa5200%2Fmissile.zip" sha1="5c8ec22e131810ccac08066ca96e9944ccfa4ecb" size="4883" />
			<title_clean>Missile Command</title_clean>
			<plot>[CR][B]Gameplay:[/B][CR]In Missile Command you control three missile turrets and protect six cities from incoming nuclear missiles. When you lose all of your cites, then it's game over, and the game doesn't end until you lose and the inhabitants of the cities are killed. The original arcade release had you using a trackball to move a cursor around the screen, with the press of one of three buttons you could fire a missle from the appropriate missile turret. Each missile turret has 10 missiles per level, however your missiles have a wide explosion range, letting you destroy multiple incoming missiles with one blast. The game has a set number of incoming missiles per level, and as you go up in level, the number of incoming missiles increases, therefore increasing the difficulty. The overall goal of the game, like many games from the 70's and 80's is to get the highest  High Score. Bugs &amp; GlitchesThe original version has a bug that happens once you get to 810,000 points. You get awarded with 150 extra cities, making it possible to play the game for several more hours.StrategiesAfter getting up to the 255th and 256th stages (known as the 0x stages) the scoring increases by 256 times, but the speed of the missiles also becomes accelerated. Expert players have been known to score over 1 million points, enabling some players to reach up to 2,800,000 points. The scoring system was primitive enough at the time where it would only show six-digits, so their 2,800,000 showed up as 800,000. After getting past the 256th stage, the game reverts back to the original speed from stage 1, but keeps your point total and your extra cities, making it possible to keep playing the game in a giant loop. [CR]Remakes[CR]Missile Command was originally released in  arcades in 1980 and ported to the  Atari 2600, from there it was made on the  Atari 5200 and the  Atari 8-bit, as well as other consoles. The game became so incredibly popular, that over the years it has been remade by various companies under different names, and sometimes even slightly different graphics. A few examples of these are  Commando Raid,  Lunar Command, and  Condition Red.[CR]</plot>
			<releasedate>7/7/1982</releasedate>
			<year>1982</year>
			<genre>Action</genre>
			<studio>Atari</studio>
			<nplayers>1-2 Alt</nplayers>
			<perspective>3rd-Person</perspective>
			<rating>3.8</rating>
			<thegamesdb_id>5182</thegamesdb_id>
			<mobygames_url>http://www.mobygames.com/game/atari-5200/missile-command_</mobygames_url>
			<giantbomb_url>http://www.giantbomb.com/missile-command/3030-4062/</giantbomb_url>
			<boxart1>CVP2ctQ.jpg</boxart1>
			<boxart2>BvMnMr7.jpg</boxart2>
			<boxart3>smi5BQC.jpg</boxart3>
			<snapshot1>KLK7gQZ.gif</snapshot1>
			<snapshot2>jkJQzof.gif</snapshot2>
			<snapshot3>75UWkJx.gif</snapshot3>
			<snapshot4>0VpGLsf.gif</snapshot4>
			<snapshot5>XCs92rp.gif</snapshot5>
			<snapshot6>UuiWKvV.gif</snapshot6>
			<snapshot7>3MUPV0q.jpg</snapshot7>
			<snapshot8>HOG7fuH.jpg</snapshot8>
			<snapshot9>chhQWax.jpg</snapshot9>
			<snapshot10>UiMy5U1.jpg</snapshot10>
			<banner1>FdTGxaN.jpg</banner1>
			<clearlogo1>gQFiRJh.png</clearlogo1>
		</game>
		<game name="Montezuma's Revenge">
			<description>Montezuma's Revenge</description>
			<rom crc="2a640143" name="MAME_0.185_Software_List_ROMs_non-merged/MAME_0.185_Software_List_ROMs_non-merged.zip/MAME%200.185%20Software%20List%20ROMs%20%28non-merged%29%2Fa5200%2Fmontezum.zip" sha1="7e2a05625598c7e6615f969aa695e64315cd9846" size="9957" />
			<title_clean>Montezuma's Revenge</title_clean>
			<plot>[CR][B]Overview:[/B][CR]In Montezuma's Revenge, players control Panama Joe in this exploration platformer.The player has a five-slot inventory shown at the upper left of the screen. Throughout the game, players can collect several items; color-coded keys, swords that defeat skulls, scepters that grant temporary invincibility, and torches that light up dark levels.Levels are sometimes variations on previous levels. For instance, Level 3 is very similar to Level 1, except with a couple of minor changes that make the level more challenging.On dark levels, none of the platforms ladders or chains are visible until the player finds a torch. This requires blind exploration, based on the general layout of previous levels, before locating the torch and revealing the platforms for the rest of the level. However, the last level of the game is entirely dark and no torches are available.Between levels, the player falls through areas populated only by gold bars and chains. The player needs to grab the chain before the end of the bonus area to land safely at the beginning of the next level. [CR]</plot>
			<releasedate>7/7/1983</releasedate>
			<year>1983</year>
			<genre>Action</genre>
			<studio>Parker Brothers</studio>
			<nplayers>1</nplayers>
			<perspective>Platform</perspective>
			<rating>3.0</rating>
			<thegamesdb_id>5183</thegamesdb_id>
			<mobygames_url>http://www.mobygames.com/game/atari-5200/montezumas-revenge</mobygames_url>
			<giantbomb_url>http://www.giantbomb.com/montezumas-revenge/3030-4619/</giantbomb_url>
			<boxart1>5aHnDyA.jpg</boxart1>
			<boxart2>FUA3Af6.jpg</boxart2>
			<boxart3>1ZpT9BS.jpg</boxart3>
			<snapshot1>h8eXXIJ.gif</snapshot1>
			<snapshot2>XsedWbi.gif</snapshot2>
			<snapshot3>8rMuAG7.gif</snapshot3>
			<snapshot4>EMOJFs3.gif</snapshot4>
			<snapshot5>qtVYkEM.gif</snapshot5>
			<snapshot6>3UifNGp.jpg</snapshot6>
			<snapshot7>bXbzAjQ.jpg</snapshot7>
			<snapshot8>hfGMOvb.jpg</snapshot8>
			<snapshot9>VDWHjRM.jpg</snapshot9>
			<snapshot10>RaEM3To.jpg</snapshot10>
			<clearlogo1>06ECbKK.png</clearlogo1>
		</game>
		<game name="Moon Patrol">
			<description>Moon Patrol</description>
			<rom crc="d0b2f285" name="MAME_0.185_Software_List_ROMs_non-merged/MAME_0.185_Software_List_ROMs_non-merged.zip/MAME%200.185%20Software%20List%20ROMs%20%28non-merged%29%2Fa5200%2Fmpatrol.zip" sha1="02dd5b9278c06ae8cbb6dacc094e238fbacf08d2" size="12039" />
			<title_clean>Moon Patrol</title_clean>
			<plot>[CR][B]Overview:[/B][CR]Moon Patrol is an arcade game originally released in 1982 by Irem and later licensed for release in North America by Williams (Midway). It is a side-scrolling shooter that puts players at the controls of a six-wheeled moon rover that can jump and shoot. The goal is to move through the entire course as quickly as possible while shooting enemies for additional points. Cannons are mounted on the front and top of the vehicle, and both fire simultaneously when the fire button is pressed. Rocks, mines, and pits in the course prevent you from just holding to the right for maximum speed. Rocks and mines can be shot, but pits must be jumped. Some enemies fire shots that create new pits in the course, forcing players to react quickly.The course is broken up into multiple checkpoints, each denoted by a letter. Some checkpoints ("E," for example) cause the game to stop, check your time, award bonus points for fast movement, and send you on your way. When the end is reached, a further bonus is awarded and the player returns to the first checkpoint.As with many games of its era, Moon Patrol was ported around to several different home platforms.[CR]Television Reference[CR]On the popular T.V. show, Psych, the episode tuesday the 17th, you can hear a direct reference to Moon Patrol and actully see gameplay.[CR]</plot>
			<releasedate>7/7/1983</releasedate>
			<year>1983</year>
			<genre>Action</genre>
			<studio>Atari</studio>
			<nplayers>1-2 Alt</nplayers>
			<perspective>Side-Scrolling</perspective>
			<rating>4.5</rating>
			<ESRB>E - Everyone</ESRB>
			<videoid>HBOKWCpwGfM</videoid>
			<thegamesdb_id>5184</thegamesdb_id>
			<mobygames_url>http://www.mobygames.com/game/atari-5200/moon-patrol</mobygames_url>
			<giantbomb_url>http://www.giantbomb.com/moon-patrol/3030-11205/</giantbomb_url>
			<boxart1>TgYw2iH.jpg</boxart1>
			<boxart2>EVU8Y4M.jpg</boxart2>
			<boxart3>MVPp0zk.jpg</boxart3>
			<snapshot1>vZ43eTF.gif</snapshot1>
			<snapshot2>GdScIhl.gif</snapshot2>
			<snapshot3>SXteTwF.gif</snapshot3>
			<snapshot4>tRQxBsO.gif</snapshot4>
			<snapshot5>JiJsUpa.gif</snapshot5>
			<snapshot6>XQ6IoAg.gif</snapshot6>
			<snapshot7>wSGeQaa.gif</snapshot7>
			<snapshot8>td0BLPl.gif</snapshot8>
			<snapshot9>Cl9Xa70.png</snapshot9>
			<snapshot10>rtcSJEw.png</snapshot10>
			<banner1>pDVgfMt.jpg</banner1>
			<clearlogo1>VYcJNGi.png</clearlogo1>
		</game>
		<game name="Mountain King">
			<description>Mountain King</description>
			<rom crc="0f24243c" name="MAME_0.185_Software_List_ROMs_non-merged/MAME_0.185_Software_List_ROMs_non-merged.zip/MAME%200.185%20Software%20List%20ROMs%20%28non-merged%29%2Fa5200%2Fmking.zip" sha1="2e7ae57260624d1f5710d445a0936f0c280a6655" size="6571" />
			<title_clean>Mountain King</title_clean>
			<plot>Deep within a multi platformed diamond mine is a valuable crown. Your goal is to locate and retrieve the crown, then make it to the top of the mine alive! There are several steps that need to be completed before you can retrieve the crown. First you need to collect enough diamonds to earn 1,000 points. After you have enough points, you need to locate the flame spirit which is hidden somewhere within the mine. Since the mine is rather dark, you carry a flashlight with you which can be used to locate objects (such as treasure chests full of diamonds and the flame spirit.) Once you have the flame spirit, you need to find the entrance to the temple the crown is in. Offer the flame spirit to the skull spirit guarding the entrance, and you can get in and take the crown. Once you have the crown, you need to make it to the top of the mine before time runs out. To make this task more challenging, numerous cave bats fly around which can steal the crown. If this happens, you need to begin again! At the very bottom of the mine is a deadly spider; if you're not careful while exploring this region of the mine, you could become caught in it's web and be eaten. Each level has a time limit, and the more levels you complete the shorter the time limit becomes!</plot>
			<releasedate>7/7/1983</releasedate>
			<year>1983</year>
			<genre>Action</genre>
			<studio>CBS Electronics</studio>
			<nplayers>1</nplayers>
			<perspective>3rd-Person</perspective>
			<rating>3.5</rating>
			<thegamesdb_id>5185</thegamesdb_id>
			<mobygames_url>http://www.mobygames.com/game/atari-5200/mountain-king</mobygames_url>
			<giantbomb_url>http://www.giantbomb.com/mountain-king/3030-16323/</giantbomb_url>
			<boxart1>alAlqky.jpg</boxart1>
			<boxart2>0N1gNJ5.jpg</boxart2>
			<boxart3>mKHehDY.jpg</boxart3>
			<snapshot1>gTawFvs.gif</snapshot1>
			<snapshot2>curCKvi.gif</snapshot2>
			<snapshot3>1qvLLSm.gif</snapshot3>
			<snapshot4>TVT7Ieu.gif</snapshot4>
			<snapshot5>xlucbW5.png</snapshot5>
			<snapshot6>TBg2iYZ.png</snapshot6>
			<snapshot7>uPyQDNf.png</snapshot7>
			<snapshot8>CssVx6b.png</snapshot8>
			<snapshot9>LMXfrWt.png</snapshot9>
			<snapshot10>Ubpd6qu.png</snapshot10>
			<clearlogo1>Ok2m3e6.png</clearlogo1>
		</game>
		<game name="Mr. Do!'s Castle">
			<description>Mr. Do!'s Castle</description>
			<rom crc="aa55f9be" name="MAME_0.185_Software_List_ROMs_non-merged/MAME_0.185_Software_List_ROMs_non-merged.zip/MAME%200.185%20Software%20List%20ROMs%20%28non-merged%29%2Fa5200%2Fdocastle.zip" sha1="002e6f8c7533b03f8041e7f1896589c0ab0e17a6" size="6825" />
			<title_clean>Mr. Do!'s Castle</title_clean>
			<plot>Mr. Do!'s Castle is an action platform game which has you in a castle consisting of several floors, each of which contain a variety of blocks. You control Mr. Do! the clown who has a hammer which can be used to knock out the blocks in the floor. Wandering throughout the castle are deadly unicorns which are constantly trying to catch you. Your goal is to earn as many points as possible and to progress through the increasingly difficult castles. [CR]There are two ways to complete a castle; you can either destroy all of the deadly unicorns by crushing them with blocks, or you can knock out all of the blocks which have a cherry symbol on them. In addition to the cherry blocks, there are three blocks with a key. If all three key blocks are knocked out, the door on the roof of the castle unlocks. If you make it to the door, all of the unicorns will temporarily become harmless and will contain a letter. If you hit a letter unicorn, you will earn a letter in the word EXTRA. Spell the complete word, and you will earn an extra life. [CR]The last type of block you'll encounter has a skull on it. If you knock out two skull blocks, all of the blocks between them will also be knocked out and replaced with a bridge. As the castles progress, the castle layout will become trickier and the unicorns become faster and more numerous.</plot>
			<releasedate>7/7/1984</releasedate>
			<year>1984</year>
			<genre>Action</genre>
			<studio>Parker Brothers</studio>
			<nplayers>1</nplayers>
			<perspective>3rd-Person</perspective>
			<rating>3.3</rating>
			<thegamesdb_id>5187</thegamesdb_id>
			<mobygames_url>http://www.mobygames.com/game/atari-5200/mr-dos-castle</mobygames_url>
			<giantbomb_url>http://www.giantbomb.com/mr-dos-castle/3030-1105/</giantbomb_url>
			<boxart1>1mxQcg6.jpg</boxart1>
			<boxart2>bvlZqb9.jpg</boxart2>
			<boxart3>WV22VRg.jpg</boxart3>
			<snapshot1>Yer07kW.gif</snapshot1>
			<snapshot2>lK0jHrl.gif</snapshot2>
			<snapshot3>0yJSrCx.gif</snapshot3>
			<snapshot4>BvAWn3d.gif</snapshot4>
			<snapshot5>rryNYzd.png</snapshot5>
			<snapshot6>Vd2hC0Q.png</snapshot6>
			<snapshot7>SSTzka4.png</snapshot7>
			<snapshot8>H6S34jC.png</snapshot8>
			<snapshot9>bZ7E5V5.png</snapshot9>
			<snapshot10>JQiwOLw.png</snapshot10>
			<clearlogo1>mYGOHS8.png</clearlogo1>
		</game>
		<game name="Pengo">
			<description>Pengo</description>
			<rom crc="e4f8ba8c" name="MAME_0.185_Software_List_ROMs_non-merged/MAME_0.185_Software_List_ROMs_non-merged.zip/MAME%200.185%20Software%20List%20ROMs%20%28non-merged%29%2Fa5200%2Fpengo.zip" sha1="19ff7622dbbc2915e3e98d8d966340e7e893ff34" size="10945" />
			<title_clean>Pengo</title_clean>
			<plot>[CR][B]Overview:[/B][CR]The player controls Pengo the penguin attempting to navigate an ice world full of enemies called Sno-Bees. Pressing the lone action button while facing an ice block will cause Pengo to push forward the block, which will slide until it hits a wall or another ice block. The ice block will also crush any Sno-Bees in the line of trajectory. Crushing multiple Sno-Bees at once will increase the number of points awarded.There are a total of sixteen levels, which repeat in order after completing the sixteenth level.As the player dispatches enemies, new Sno-Bees hatch from eggs located within other ice blocks within the level. Eggs can be eliminated by crushing the ice blocks that contain them. At the beginning of each new level, the ice blocks with eggs within them will momentarily flash a color showing the level of Sno-Bee inside. Pengo can briefly stun Sno-Bees by pushing a side wall, causing the water to ripple. This stun will only effect adjacent Sno-Bees to the player character. When stunned the Sno-Bees can be run over by Pengo. Each level ends when all Sno-Bees have been eliminated.Diamond blocks located within the level are unbreakable. When diamond blocks are oriented into a vertical or horizontal line the player is awarded 5,000 to 10,000 bonus points depending on whether the line is against a wall or not. The alignment of the diamond blocks will also temporarily stun all Sno-Bees within the level.When 60 seconds have elapsed in a round without the player dying, the game enters into a sudden death mode; the music speeds up and the movement speed of the Sno-Bees increases.ScoringThe points award for crushing Sno-Bees is dependant on the number crushed in one push of an ice block:400 points for 1 Sno-Bee1,600 points for 2 Sno-Bees3,200 points for 3 Sno-Bees6,400 points for 4 Sno-Bees100 points for walking over a stunned Sno-Bee10,000 points for aligning the three diamond blocks together if at least one is not touching a wall, but only 5,000 if all are against the walls.30 pointe for crushing an ice block or 500 points if the ice block contains a Sno-Bee egg.A bonus is awarded for time left after completion of a round:5,000 points for under 20 seconds2,000 points for between 20&#8211;29 seconds1,000 points for between 30&#8211;39 seconds500 points for between 40&#8211;49 seconds10 points for between 50&#8211;59 seconds0 points for 60 seconds or moreAn extra life is awarded at 30,000 pointsWorld Record High ScoreAccording to Twin Galaxies the world record score for Pengo is held by Rodney Day from Canberra, Australia. His score of 1,110,370 points was set on August 13, 1983.Easter EggThe credits can be displayed by holding both joysticks up, pressing both action buttons and pressing one start game button at the same time while the game is in "Attract Mode"[CR]</plot>
			<releasedate>7/7/1983</releasedate>
			<year>1983</year>
			<genre>Action</genre>
			<studio>Atari</studio>
			<nplayers>1-2 Sim</nplayers>
			<perspective>Top-Down</perspective>
			<rating>4.2</rating>
			<thegamesdb_id>5191</thegamesdb_id>
			<mobygames_url>http://www.mobygames.com/game/atari-5200/pengo</mobygames_url>
			<giantbomb_url>http://www.giantbomb.com/pengo/3030-4196/</giantbomb_url>
			<boxart1>Qlt644F.jpg</boxart1>
			<boxart2>PGvKXBK.jpg</boxart2>
			<boxart3>hfChPem.jpg</boxart3>
			<snapshot1>9TE3Msz.gif</snapshot1>
			<snapshot2>NLLh9V0.gif</snapshot2>
			<snapshot3>faqR4dQ.gif</snapshot3>
			<snapshot4>nCkrgJf.png</snapshot4>
			<snapshot5>LGBGPlr.png</snapshot5>
			<snapshot6>OT9xBaG.png</snapshot6>
			<snapshot7>A6u0wjA.png</snapshot7>
			<snapshot8>PpvFYjF.png</snapshot8>
			<snapshot9>PTPqqpz.png</snapshot9>
			<snapshot10>abJRYC6.jpg</snapshot10>
			<banner1>L8MMW6D.jpg</banner1>
			<clearlogo1>KsuscPx.png</clearlogo1>
		</game>
		<game name="Pitfall!">
			<description>Pitfall!</description>
			<rom crc="b2887833" name="MAME_0.185_Software_List_ROMs_non-merged/MAME_0.185_Software_List_ROMs_non-merged.zip/MAME%200.185%20Software%20List%20ROMs%20%28non-merged%29%2Fa5200%2Fpitfall.zip" sha1="d1c7dc3de097a4bfab82235acec69a97e6e05f18" size="5743" />
			<title_clean>Pitfall!</title_clean>
			<plot>[CR][B]Gameplay:[/B][CR]A shortcut!Pitfall! is a 2D platforming adventure where the player has to find 32 treasures within a time limit of 20 minutes. Players control the character Pitfall Harry and have to guide him through a dense forest filled with deadly obstacles such as snakes, scorpions, rolling logs, alligator infested swamps, and bottomless pits.The game had many basic gameplay elements that are now common in all platformers. Harry had the ability to jump, swing, climb ladders and run left or right on the screen. The game places Harry on the left side of the screen by default, but a player could choose to tackle the jungle by going right on the screen. The game also had many secret passages which could be used as shortcuts.[CR]Release History[CR]Pitfall! was created in 1982 by Activision employee David Crane. The game was a technical achievement in that it had multiple animated sprites of varying colors with no flickering. Pitfall! introduced the basic concept of having a character jump around to avoid obstacles and collect items, which is now the basis for all platformers. The game was a massive success on the Atari 2600 and had ports for numerous game systems afterwards.The character in the game is lovingly referred to as Pitfall Harry.[CR][B]Fun Facts:[/B][CR]Pitfall! was used in an episode of South Park in which Father Maxy had to traverse a series of levels (with himself being the main character) to retrieve a lost scroll hidden in the catacombs of The Vatican.In 1982, then-unknown actor Jack Black was in a Pitfall! commercial.Actor Bruce Campbell of Evil Dead fame would eventually play the voice of Pitfall Harry in the Playstation version of the game.When Pitfall! was originally sold, anyone who scored above 20,000 points could send Activision a picture of his or her television screen to receive a Pitfall Harry's Explorers' Club patch.In Marvel Ultimate Alliance, the player must complete a game of Pitfall! using their own character in order to proceed in a mission.In Call Of Duty: Black Ops II: this game is playable through a secret in the Nuketown 2025 map.[CR]</plot>
			<releasedate>7/7/1984</releasedate>
			<year>1984</year>
			<genre>Action</genre>
			<studio>Activision</studio>
			<nplayers>1</nplayers>
			<perspective>Platform</perspective>
			<rating>3.7</rating>
			<thegamesdb_id>5192</thegamesdb_id>
			<mobygames_url>http://www.mobygames.com/game/atari-5200/pitfall</mobygames_url>
			<giantbomb_url>http://www.giantbomb.com/pitfall/3030-10014/</giantbomb_url>
			<boxart1>pxNS5mw.jpg</boxart1>
			<boxart2>0OhcVCT.jpg</boxart2>
			<snapshot1>yDL5u4z.jpg</snapshot1>
			<snapshot2>Hh64h4M.png</snapshot2>
			<snapshot3>F0TLz0Q.png</snapshot3>
			<snapshot4>V1zy2dE.png</snapshot4>
			<snapshot5>VNBfOda.png</snapshot5>
			<snapshot6>DnoSEDo.png</snapshot6>
			<snapshot7>2HMbe3J.png</snapshot7>
			<snapshot8>Rnmyafp.png</snapshot8>
			<snapshot9>yCJXLJX.png</snapshot9>
			<snapshot10>rwlu5Xm.png</snapshot10>
			<fanart1>HFyDcMI.jpg</fanart1>
			<banner1>sY6SZmG.jpg</banner1>
			<clearlogo1>D7gUz9Y.png</clearlogo1>
		</game>
		<game name="Pole Position">
			<description>Pole Position</description>
			<rom crc="abc2d1e4" name="MAME_0.185_Software_List_ROMs_non-merged/MAME_0.185_Software_List_ROMs_non-merged.zip/MAME%200.185%20Software%20List%20ROMs%20%28non-merged%29%2Fa5200%2Fpolepos.zip" sha1="d504764c5894ee99c0b5e2024cbe833ebba3ab17" size="11884" />
			<title_clean>Pole Position</title_clean>
			<plot>Pole Position is the conversion of the arcade racing game. Enter the Grand Prix, race against other racing cars to achieve the highest score possible in the shortest amount of time.[CR]Before the player can enter the Grand Prix, the player must first qualify by competing in the Qualifying Lap within 73 seconds or less. If the player however, does not qualify in the Qualifying Lap, the player may continue to race until the Race Timer runs after 90 seconds. The player will score 50 point per 5 meters and additionally 50 points for every racing car passed. When the time runs out - Game Over. The player will have to restart the Qualifying Lap.[CR]Qualifying will enable the player to start in one of the eight available positions. The faster the lap time was, the better the starting position in addition to bonus score points. The number one starting position, is the Pole Position.[CR]During the Grand Prix, the player will compete against the Race Timer as well as against other racing cars. If the player fails to beat the Race Timer in any lap, the player drops out of the race - Game Over. Completing the race by reaching finishing line will grant the player 200 points per each second left on the Race Timer, bonus score for distance covered, and passing bonus points.[CR][B]Scoring:[/B][CR]1. Every 5 meters driven: 50 points[CR]Passing Car Bonus: 50 points per racing car[CR]Time Bonus: 200 points per second left on the Race Timer[CR]Positions[CR]1. Pole Position - Lap Time: 58"50 seconds - 4,000 points[CR]2nd Position - Lap Time: 60"00 seconds - 2,000 points[CR]3rd Position - Lap Time: 62"00 seconds - 1,400 points[CR]4th Position - Lap Time: 64"00 seconds - 1,000 points[CR]5th Position - Lap Time: 66"00 seconds - 800 points[CR]6th Position - Lap Time: 68"00 seconds - 600 points[CR]7th Position - Lap Time: 70"00 seconds - 400 points[CR]8th Position - Lap Time: 73"00 seconds - 200 points</plot>
			<releasedate>7/7/1983</releasedate>
			<year>1983</year>
			<genre>Driving, Racing</genre>
			<studio>Atari</studio>
			<nplayers>1</nplayers>
			<perspective>3rd-Person</perspective>
			<rating>3.8</rating>
			<videoid>kdXNpEUT54o</videoid>
			<thegamesdb_id>5194</thegamesdb_id>
			<mobygames_url>http://www.mobygames.com/game/atari-5200/pole-position</mobygames_url>
			<giantbomb_url>http://www.giantbomb.com/pole-position/3030-10087/</giantbomb_url>
			<boxart1>fEctLhW.jpg</boxart1>
			<boxart2>nxYfd04.jpg</boxart2>
			<boxart3>zml2Qdf.jpg</boxart3>
			<snapshot1>RjuKnOk.gif</snapshot1>
			<snapshot2>6AIWETf.gif</snapshot2>
			<snapshot3>hMOolUq.gif</snapshot3>
			<snapshot4>KZwu0Yc.gif</snapshot4>
			<snapshot5>TliP6Db.gif</snapshot5>
			<snapshot6>JDbQaSt.png</snapshot6>
			<snapshot7>BxUeqB6.jpg</snapshot7>
			<snapshot8>Q20MReL.jpg</snapshot8>
			<snapshot9>nB8Cb9i.jpg</snapshot9>
			<snapshot10>NoAtupM.png</snapshot10>
			<banner1>7VBEQWV.jpg</banner1>
			<clearlogo1>VjyflaK.png</clearlogo1>
		</game>
		<game name="Popeye">
			<description>Popeye</description>
			<rom crc="a18a9a40" name="MAME_0.185_Software_List_ROMs_non-merged/MAME_0.185_Software_List_ROMs_non-merged.zip/MAME%200.185%20Software%20List%20ROMs%20%28non-merged%29%2Fa5200%2Fpopeye.zip" sha1="e615aaa0c1d56ac83b91f6087970fa708d6433bf" size="12126" />
			<title_clean>Popeye</title_clean>
			<plot>[CR][B]Overview:[/B][CR]Popeye must catch hearts, musical notes, or letter from the word "HELP" that his girlfriend Olive Oyl, who is located at the top of the screen, is tossing down. These items slowly floating items descend to the bottom of the screen and eventually 'break' unless Popeye can collect them.Popeye's nemesis, Bluto, pursues him throughout each of the repeating three stages. The Sea Hag also appears to hurl bottles, etc. at our hero. Sweet Pea and Wimpy also make appearances but only serve to provide opportunities to score more points.The three stages consist of the dock level, the street level, and the ship level. Difficulty increases each time the player completes the set of stages. Controls consist of an 8-way joystick and a 'punch' button.[CR]History &amp; Design[CR] Original Arcade CabinetPopeye was released by Nintendo in 1982. Its cabinet is the same design as the earlier more recognizable Donkey Kong and the later Donkey Kong Jr. cabinets. A cocktail table version was also released. The game was designed by Genyo Takeda and a young upstart designer named Shigeru Miyamoto. The Popeye characters were originally going to be used for Donkey Kong, but Nintendo decided to go with an original character creation that evolved into the iconic Mario. The CPU was a Z80 Chip running at 4MHz. Sound was produced using a AY8910 chip running at 2MHz. [CR][B]Gameplay:[/B][CR] Three Stages of PopeyeTHE DOCK STAGE - Popeye must catch 24 hearts that Olive Oyl tosses down one at a time. The HUD displays how many hearts the player has collected. If a heart reaches the bottom of the screen, the player will lose a life if he doesn't retrieve the breaking heart after about 10 seconds.Bluto chases Popeye throughout the stage. There are two ways he can be temporarily disposed of. One is by punching the signature can of spinach that will periodically appear on the sides of the screen. Once the can is punched, Popeye gets stong and turns red for about 10 seconds and has the ability to punch Bluto, sending him bouncing across the screen and into the sea. Catching hearts while in this 'red mode' will also net double points. The player will get 3000 points knocking out Bluto but he will shortly climb back out and continue his pursuit. The second way he can be incapacitated is by hitting a punching bag that dislodges a bucket. If timed right, the bucket will fall on Bluto's head giving the player 2000 points and some time to grabs some more hearts before he eventually pulls the bucket off.Both Bluto and the Sea Hag like to throw bottles at Popeye. These bottles can be broken by punching them. Bluto throws his bottles in groups of four and the Sea Hag will periodically show up on the side of the screen, throw one and disappear. Sometimes there will will be one on each side and they'll simultaneously throw a bottle, attempting to 'sandwich' Popeye between them is he isn't fast enough with his punches. Bluto can also jump up to a higher level or reach down to a lower level to knock Popeye out. Players should take caution when passing Bluto directly above or below him.THE STREET STAGE - This stage is similar to the first but features a different level layout and Olive throws musical notes instead of hearts. There is also a seesaw located in the lower left corner that, if timed right, allows Popeye to be launched in the air, thanks to Wimpy standing on the other end. Once in the air, Popeye can touch Sweet Pea for a point bonus who is floating above with a balloon.THE SHIP STAGE - The final stage features similar gameplay with two different features. One is there is a sliding platform at the top. Second each time Popeye catches one of the H-E-L-P letters that Olive tosses him, a ladder step will appear. Once enough letters are caught and the ladder is completed, Popeye can climb up and rescue Olive. The Sea Hag's pet vulture will also come out on the left side of the screen. Popeye can punch it continuously for points.Once Popeye rescues Olive, players are treated to a short intermission where Popeye's theme song is played while his face appears on the screen, blowing his signature "toot, toot" on his pipe. Players are then returned to the first stage again with increased difficulty. The Sea Hag now send bouncing skulls at Popeye, which are more difficult to punch. They will also fall down from an above level and knock him on the head if he is walking directly below.[CR]Ports[CR]Popeye was ported to several popular home consoles in subsequent years including the Atari 2600 and 5200, Intellivision, Colecovision, Odyssey2, and eventually came full circle releasing on the Nintendo Entertainment System (NES). Ports to computer systems included the Texas Instruments TI-99, Atari XL, and Commodore 64. A mobile phone version was also released in 2008.[CR]</plot>
			<releasedate>7/7/1984</releasedate>
			<year>1984</year>
			<genre>Action</genre>
			<studio>Parker Brothers</studio>
			<nplayers>1</nplayers>
			<perspective>3rd-Person</perspective>
			<thegamesdb_id>5195</thegamesdb_id>
			<mobygames_url>http://www.mobygames.com/game/atari-5200/popeye</mobygames_url>
			<giantbomb_url>http://www.giantbomb.com/popeye/3030-14419/</giantbomb_url>
			<boxart1>u6QJbxG.jpg</boxart1>
			<boxart2>ugf8KUJ.jpg</boxart2>
			<boxart3>lmaS60K.jpg</boxart3>
			<snapshot1>X1c1dCn.gif</snapshot1>
			<snapshot2>mgHzqR6.gif</snapshot2>
			<snapshot3>ht9lnXQ.gif</snapshot3>
			<snapshot4>Ipu1lMz.png</snapshot4>
			<snapshot5>Zvewv5A.png</snapshot5>
			<snapshot6>1dQ11w7.png</snapshot6>
			<snapshot7>CrRGtT9.png</snapshot7>
			<snapshot8>XvQaXsa.png</snapshot8>
			<snapshot9>EanGp89.jpg</snapshot9>
			<snapshot10>GFYdCad.jpg</snapshot10>
			<banner1>Jh2xoEv.jpg</banner1>
			<clearlogo1>n9Ve9Rx.png</clearlogo1>
		</game>
		<game name="Q*bert">
			<description>Q*bert</description>
			<rom crc="3fe4a401" name="MAME_0.185_Software_List_ROMs_non-merged/MAME_0.185_Software_List_ROMs_non-merged.zip/MAME%200.185%20Software%20List%20ROMs%20%28non-merged%29%2Fa5200%2Fqbert.zip" sha1="e6966bde5cd4167020c9d21bab613af1648b4d75" size="6116" />
			<title_clean>Q*bert</title_clean>
			<plot>[CR][B]Gameplay:[/B][CR]The goal of Q*Bert is to navigate Q*Bert around an isometric pyramid structure. Each hop on a cube of the pyramid changes the color of its surface. The game will specify what color the entire pyramid must be changed to in order to advance. Multicolored discs alongside the pyramid allow for a quick getaway, but disappear once used.[CR]Arcade Cabinet[CR]The game designers wanted to add the sound of Q*Bert hitting the ground after falling off of the pyramid, so a pinball "knocker" (the solenoid that alerts the player that they've won a free game) was incorporated into the cabinet.[CR][B]Enemies:[/B][CR]The most common foe Q*Bert will encounter is Coily the snake, who hops down the pyramid structure. Once he reaches the bottom, he "uncoils" and chases after Q*Bert until he finishes the level or is killed. Red balls also bounce down the pyramid structure that Q*Bert must avoid. Slick and Sam are two more enemies that run around the structure changing the colors of the pyramid back to their original colors, slowing Q*Bert's progress. Unlike the other enemies in the game, Q*Bert can get rid of Slick and Sam by jumping on them.[CR]Other Versions[CR]Faster Harder More Challenging Q*Bert was to be the tougher successor to the original game. Changes, such as moving multicolored discs, lived up to the name, but the product was canceled before being released.[CR]</plot>
			<releasedate>7/7/1983</releasedate>
			<year>1983</year>
			<genre>Action</genre>
			<studio>Parker Brothers</studio>
			<nplayers>1-2 Sim</nplayers>
			<perspective>3rd-Person</perspective>
			<rating>4.0</rating>
			<videoid>D62C-u7gz-o</videoid>
			<thegamesdb_id>5196</thegamesdb_id>
			<mobygames_url>http://www.mobygames.com/game/atari-5200/qbert</mobygames_url>
			<giantbomb_url>http://www.giantbomb.com/qbert/3030-20782/</giantbomb_url>
			<boxart1>jPnKp8l.jpg</boxart1>
			<boxart2>dy1hzkT.jpg</boxart2>
			<boxart3>XJFBDic.jpg</boxart3>
			<snapshot1>LYs5Ojc.gif</snapshot1>
			<snapshot2>7yy5JSa.gif</snapshot2>
			<snapshot3>4JSgHQj.gif</snapshot3>
			<snapshot4>sD84UfB.gif</snapshot4>
			<snapshot5>g50Gvom.gif</snapshot5>
			<fanart1>tzft0ul.jpg</fanart1>
			<clearlogo1>7iD7FkA.png</clearlogo1>
		</game>
		<game name="Qix">
			<description>Qix</description>
			<rom crc="aea6d2c2" name="MAME_0.185_Software_List_ROMs_non-merged/MAME_0.185_Software_List_ROMs_non-merged.zip/MAME%200.185%20Software%20List%20ROMs%20%28non-merged%29%2Fa5200%2Fqix.zip" sha1="786cdf54d1625e0d3ea8814506fdeeba5e4ece48" size="7401" />
			<title_clean>Qix</title_clean>
			<plot>[CR][B]Overview:[/B][CR]In QIX, the objective is to fence in a large majority of the play field and defeat the QIX. Players must close in the large enemy, the QIX, in a closed space without it touching the player or the lines drawn by the player. Every time the player creates a closed space, they are awarded points and the space becomes solid so the QIX can no longer pass through it. Other enemies besides the QIX exist in the form of Sparx. The Sparx moves on the lines that the player draws and can defeat the player in the same way as the QIX.QIX was originally released in arcades in 1981 but Taito ported the game to a large variety of consoles such as the Atari 5200, Atari 400/800, Apple II, Commodore 64, DOS, Amiga (with new graphics), Apple IIGS, NES, and Atari Lynx. Nintendo also developed a Game Boy version that featured Mario, Luigi, and Princess Peach.[CR]</plot>
			<releasedate>7/7/1982</releasedate>
			<year>1982</year>
			<genre>Action</genre>
			<studio>Atari</studio>
			<nplayers>1-2 Sim</nplayers>
			<perspective>Top-Down</perspective>
			<rating>3.8</rating>
			<thegamesdb_id>5197</thegamesdb_id>
			<mobygames_url>http://www.mobygames.com/game/atari-5200/qix</mobygames_url>
			<giantbomb_url>http://www.giantbomb.com/qix/3030-6136/</giantbomb_url>
			<boxart1>gdWxzVb.jpg</boxart1>
			<boxart2>FqMer12.jpg</boxart2>
			<boxart3>phANzqu.jpg</boxart3>
			<snapshot1>bEU8TkC.jpg</snapshot1>
			<snapshot2>Fj7EjY1.gif</snapshot2>
			<snapshot3>bFoeWvE.gif</snapshot3>
			<snapshot4>vgRWQoh.gif</snapshot4>
			<snapshot5>at4M7Mq.gif</snapshot5>
			<snapshot6>LimAqc7.gif</snapshot6>
			<snapshot7>8coYQAa.gif</snapshot7>
			<snapshot8>3HFTjMZ.jpg</snapshot8>
			<snapshot9>42CLuYc.jpg</snapshot9>
			<snapshot10>FfCQ9PM.png</snapshot10>
			<banner1>NdimAd9.jpg</banner1>
			<clearlogo1>nppCGNN.png</clearlogo1>
		</game>
		<game name="Quest for Quintana Roo">
			<description>Quest for Quintana Roo</description>
			<rom crc="b5f3402b" name="MAME_0.185_Software_List_ROMs_non-merged/MAME_0.185_Software_List_ROMs_non-merged.zip/MAME%200.185%20Software%20List%20ROMs%20%28non-merged%29%2Fa5200%2Fquintana.zip" sha1="17a41c5f9a32f8a71939cfaa0e96807b951aedad" size="11280" />
			<title_clean>Quest for Quintana Roo</title_clean>
			<plot>You are Yucatan Sam on a quest to explore the temple of Quintana Roo. Your goal is to find the vault which is hidden somewhere within and return with the treasure that is inside. You begin your quest outside the temple; climb your way up the side of the temple in order to get inside. Poisonous snakes and deadly lightning bolts will block your progress here. Once inside the temple, you have a limited air supply so you need to explore quickly. Hidden in various rooms of the temple are numerous keys which are needed to unlock the vault. The keys and some other useful items are hidden in secret rooms which you need to locate by using your trusty pick axe or the flasks of acid you carry. To help figure out which rooms may contain hidden objects, you carry a geiger counter with you;  the higher the reading, the closer you are to something of interest! The rooms you'll be exploring are guarded by snakes, spiders, and even mummies! To deal with these enemies you carry a gun, and you can also use the acid flasks against them (ammo is limited, so use it wisely). If you are successful in your mission, you may receive a secret code which can be used to begin the game at later levels. Good luck!</plot>
			<releasedate>7/7/1984</releasedate>
			<year>1984</year>
			<genre>Action, Adventure</genre>
			<studio>Sunrise Software</studio>
			<nplayers>1</nplayers>
			<perspective>3rd-Person</perspective>
			<rating>2.5</rating>
			<thegamesdb_id>5198</thegamesdb_id>
			<mobygames_url>http://www.mobygames.com/game/atari-5200/quest-for-quintana-roo</mobygames_url>
			<giantbomb_url>http://www.giantbomb.com/quest-for-quintana-roo/3030-1841/</giantbomb_url>
			<boxart1>1av4LQV.jpg</boxart1>
			<boxart2>jffsb9y.jpg</boxart2>
			<boxart3>ZbFh0jv.jpg</boxart3>
			<snapshot1>sKUsR9j.gif</snapshot1>
			<snapshot2>vPSNXPr.gif</snapshot2>
			<snapshot3>uZzQxez.gif</snapshot3>
			<snapshot4>3EsrqiR.gif</snapshot4>
			<snapshot5>itzDAt5.gif</snapshot5>
			<snapshot6>fvzXb4u.gif</snapshot6>
			<snapshot7>evU1gme.png</snapshot7>
			<snapshot8>bopDWjS.png</snapshot8>
			<snapshot9>sfxqBIe.png</snapshot9>
			<banner1>wpDufUz.jpg</banner1>
			<clearlogo1>nggop89.png</clearlogo1>
		</game>
		<game name="RealSports Baseball">
			<description>RealSports Baseball</description>
			<rom crc="44166592" name="MAME_0.185_Software_List_ROMs_non-merged/MAME_0.185_Software_List_ROMs_non-merged.zip/MAME%200.185%20Software%20List%20ROMs%20%28non-merged%29%2Fa5200%2Frsbaseb.zip" sha1="a94d06739fa19453fa586a836eaacae11fe93989" size="17382" />
			<title_clean>RealSports Baseball</title_clean>
			<plot>Baseball is an action game which can be played by two players or one player against the computer. The game allows you to bunt the ball or try for a homerun, steal bases, and throw several types of pitches from a fast ball to a curve ball. Several game variations are included which allow you to select whether the home or visiting team is at bat first, and whether or not a player can swing only at pitches that are a strike, or they can swing at any pitch.</plot>
			<releasedate>7/7/1983</releasedate>
			<year>1983</year>
			<genre>Action, Sports</genre>
			<studio>Atari</studio>
			<nplayers>1-2 Sim</nplayers>
			<perspective>3rd-Person</perspective>
			<rating>3.5</rating>
			<thegamesdb_id>5200</thegamesdb_id>
			<mobygames_url>http://www.mobygames.com/game/atari-5200/realsports-baseball</mobygames_url>
			<giantbomb_url>http://www.giantbomb.com/realsports-baseball/3030-3020/</giantbomb_url>
			<boxart1>hP1Hymu.jpg</boxart1>
			<boxart2>gTIYZaq.jpg</boxart2>
			<boxart3>XaJ6ujk.jpg</boxart3>
			<snapshot1>DbxzMOP.gif</snapshot1>
			<snapshot2>fvCHR8h.gif</snapshot2>
			<snapshot3>kJJGFga.gif</snapshot3>
			<snapshot4>oGzmJAv.gif</snapshot4>
			<snapshot5>I3CHsRU.jpg</snapshot5>
			<snapshot6>JTkrbag.jpg</snapshot6>
			<snapshot7>KCinu7a.jpg</snapshot7>
			<snapshot8>pXqa3yk.jpg</snapshot8>
			<snapshot9>K4rQf62.jpg</snapshot9>
			<snapshot10>tdxrdT9.png</snapshot10>
			<banner1>lt1cHhX.jpg</banner1>
		</game>
		<game name="RealSports Basketball (19831216)">
			<description>RealSports Basketball (19831216)</description>
			<rom crc="dd217276" name="MAME_0.185_Software_List_ROMs_non-merged/MAME_0.185_Software_List_ROMs_non-merged.zip/MAME%200.185%20Software%20List%20ROMs%20%28non-merged%29%2Fa5200%2Frsbasket.zip" sha1="9b21ac7fec8d556585c6970231318ef1f501b2b5" size="9586" />
			<title_clean>RealSports Basketball</title_clean>
			<plot>If you enjoyed  RealSports Baseball, you may also enjoy  Thwocker.[CR]</plot>
			<releasedate>27/5/1983</releasedate>
			<year>1983</year>
			<genre>Action, Sports</genre>
			<studio>Atari</studio>
			<nplayers>1-2 Alt</nplayers>
			<perspective>3rd-Person</perspective>
			<rating>3.5</rating>
			<ESRB>E - Everyone</ESRB>
			<thegamesdb_id>22377</thegamesdb_id>
			<mobygames_url>http://www.mobygames.com/game/atari-5200/realsports-baseball</mobygames_url>
			<giantbomb_url>http://www.giantbomb.com/realsports-baseball/3030-3020/</giantbomb_url>
			<boxart1>eD7rjWD.jpg</boxart1>
			<boxart2>gTIYZaq.jpg</boxart2>
			<boxart3>XaJ6ujk.jpg</boxart3>
			<snapshot1>QX2s9eK.jpg</snapshot1>
			<snapshot2>Fil7Vov.jpg</snapshot2>
			<snapshot3>xG2PVE6.jpg</snapshot3>
			<snapshot4>pvZ3QfI.jpg</snapshot4>
			<snapshot5>I3CHsRU.jpg</snapshot5>
			<snapshot6>JTkrbag.jpg</snapshot6>
			<snapshot7>KCinu7a.jpg</snapshot7>
			<snapshot8>pXqa3yk.jpg</snapshot8>
			<snapshot9>K4rQf62.jpg</snapshot9>
			<snapshot10>tdxrdT9.png</snapshot10>
		</game>
		<game name="RealSports Basketball (Prototype, 19831031)">
			<description>RealSports Basketball (Prototype, 19831031)</description>
			<rom crc="c90196fa" name="MAME_0.185_Software_List_ROMs_non-merged/MAME_0.185_Software_List_ROMs_non-merged.zip/MAME%200.185%20Software%20List%20ROMs%20%28non-merged%29%2Fa5200%2Frsbasket1.zip" sha1="9edb066a37ca7657979952c946ab89be7926f4f8" size="9396" />
			<title_clean>RealSports Basketball</title_clean>
			<plot>If you enjoyed  RealSports Baseball, you may also enjoy  Thwocker.[CR]</plot>
			<releasedate>27/5/1983</releasedate>
			<year>1983</year>
			<genre>Action, Sports</genre>
			<studio>Atari</studio>
			<nplayers>1-2 Alt</nplayers>
			<perspective>3rd-Person</perspective>
			<rating>3.5</rating>
			<ESRB>E - Everyone</ESRB>
			<thegamesdb_id>22377</thegamesdb_id>
			<mobygames_url>http://www.mobygames.com/game/atari-5200/realsports-baseball</mobygames_url>
			<giantbomb_url>http://www.giantbomb.com/realsports-baseball/3030-3020/</giantbomb_url>
			<boxart1>bjoGCeg.jpg</boxart1>
			<boxart2>gTIYZaq.jpg</boxart2>
			<boxart3>XaJ6ujk.jpg</boxart3>
			<snapshot1>QX2s9eK.jpg</snapshot1>
			<snapshot2>Fil7Vov.jpg</snapshot2>
			<snapshot3>xG2PVE6.jpg</snapshot3>
			<snapshot4>pvZ3QfI.jpg</snapshot4>
			<snapshot5>I3CHsRU.jpg</snapshot5>
			<snapshot6>JTkrbag.jpg</snapshot6>
			<snapshot7>KCinu7a.jpg</snapshot7>
			<snapshot8>pXqa3yk.jpg</snapshot8>
			<snapshot9>K4rQf62.jpg</snapshot9>
			<snapshot10>tdxrdT9.png</snapshot10>
		</game>
		<game name="RealSports Basketball (Prototype, 19821105)">
			<description>RealSports Basketball (Prototype, 19821105)</description>
			<rom crc="0f996184" name="MAME_0.185_Software_List_ROMs_non-merged/MAME_0.185_Software_List_ROMs_non-merged.zip/MAME%200.185%20Software%20List%20ROMs%20%28non-merged%29%2Fa5200%2Frsbasket2.zip" sha1="2b43f74db4833272d2048de8fa32b857af8e090f" size="4485" />
			<title_clean>RealSports Basketball</title_clean>
			<plot>If you enjoyed  RealSports Baseball, you may also enjoy  Thwocker.[CR]</plot>
			<releasedate>27/5/1983</releasedate>
			<year>1983</year>
			<genre>Action, Sports</genre>
			<studio>Atari</studio>
			<nplayers>1-2 Alt</nplayers>
			<perspective>3rd-Person</perspective>
			<rating>3.5</rating>
			<ESRB>E - Everyone</ESRB>
			<thegamesdb_id>22377</thegamesdb_id>
			<mobygames_url>http://www.mobygames.com/game/atari-5200/realsports-baseball</mobygames_url>
			<giantbomb_url>http://www.giantbomb.com/realsports-baseball/3030-3020/</giantbomb_url>
			<boxart1>bjoGCeg.jpg</boxart1>
			<boxart2>gTIYZaq.jpg</boxart2>
			<boxart3>XaJ6ujk.jpg</boxart3>
			<snapshot1>QX2s9eK.jpg</snapshot1>
			<snapshot2>Fil7Vov.jpg</snapshot2>
			<snapshot3>xG2PVE6.jpg</snapshot3>
			<snapshot4>pvZ3QfI.jpg</snapshot4>
			<snapshot5>I3CHsRU.jpg</snapshot5>
			<snapshot6>JTkrbag.jpg</snapshot6>
			<snapshot7>KCinu7a.jpg</snapshot7>
			<snapshot8>pXqa3yk.jpg</snapshot8>
			<snapshot9>K4rQf62.jpg</snapshot9>
			<snapshot10>tdxrdT9.png</snapshot10>
		</game>
		<game name="RealSports Football">
			<description>RealSports Football</description>
			<rom crc="4336c2cc" name="MAME_0.185_Software_List_ROMs_non-merged/MAME_0.185_Software_List_ROMs_non-merged.zip/MAME%200.185%20Software%20List%20ROMs%20%28non-merged%29%2Fa5200%2Frsfootb.zip" sha1="a0dbd654ed3ba2583ca175a1356924d9529884df" size="10481" />
			<title_clean>RealSports Football</title_clean>
			<plot>Football is an action football game for two players or one player against the computer.  The game is played from a top down point of view of the field which scrolls to follow the action. There is a variety of offensive and defensive plays that can be called, along with several skill levels for each player. Each game will last for one fifteen minute quarter, whichever team has the most points at the end wins!</plot>
			<releasedate>7/7/1982</releasedate>
			<year>1982</year>
			<genre>Sports</genre>
			<studio>Atari</studio>
			<nplayers>1-2 Sim</nplayers>
			<perspective>3rd-Person</perspective>
			<rating>1.4</rating>
			<thegamesdb_id>5205</thegamesdb_id>
			<mobygames_url>http://www.mobygames.com/game/atari-5200/realsports-football</mobygames_url>
			<giantbomb_url>http://www.giantbomb.com/realsports-football/3030-12360/</giantbomb_url>
			<boxart1>1SCP9gT.jpg</boxart1>
			<boxart2>iDwM4wV.jpg</boxart2>
			<boxart3>2W9sQjH.jpg</boxart3>
			<snapshot1>f32ZPlD.gif</snapshot1>
			<snapshot2>8HWn06o.gif</snapshot2>
			<snapshot3>Y3F1rch.gif</snapshot3>
			<snapshot4>HLudo07.gif</snapshot4>
			<snapshot5>Q2tDVVZ.jpg</snapshot5>
			<snapshot6>yybHPxp.jpg</snapshot6>
			<snapshot7>vyBaQW6.jpg</snapshot7>
			<snapshot8>kQYdmJR.jpg</snapshot8>
			<snapshot9>EauTtMM.jpg</snapshot9>
			<banner1>1k891tc.jpg</banner1>
		</game>
		<game name="RealSports Soccer">
			<description>RealSports Soccer</description>
			<rom crc="ecbd1853" name="MAME_0.185_Software_List_ROMs_non-merged/MAME_0.185_Software_List_ROMs_non-merged.zip/MAME%200.185%20Software%20List%20ROMs%20%28non-merged%29%2Fa5200%2Frssoccer.zip" sha1="c911cc914f3923d5aeb1a897e6dc4a551a9a53da" size="7074" />
			<title_clean>RealSports Soccer</title_clean>
			<plot>The game is played from an angled overhead point of view of the field which scrolls to follow the action. If your team has the ball, you control whichever player is currently dribbling the ball, otherwise you can control any one player at a time while the computer controls the rest of your team. Various time lengths can be selected for each game, you can kick the ball low, medium or high, and there are throw-ins, corner kicks, goal kicks. When playing against the computer several different skill levels are available.</plot>
			<releasedate>7/7/1982</releasedate>
			<year>1982</year>
			<genre>Sports</genre>
			<studio>Atari</studio>
			<nplayers>1-2 Sim</nplayers>
			<perspective>3rd-Person</perspective>
			<rating>2.4</rating>
			<videoid>O4tmBJ26Kjc</videoid>
			<thegamesdb_id>5206</thegamesdb_id>
			<mobygames_url>http://www.mobygames.com/game/atari-5200/realsports-soccer</mobygames_url>
			<giantbomb_url>http://www.giantbomb.com/realsports-soccer/3030-17190/</giantbomb_url>
			<boxart1>B8juLhI.jpg</boxart1>
			<boxart2>0VbDNNR.jpg</boxart2>
			<boxart3>xLi1Ur2.jpg</boxart3>
			<boxart4>8PIXfZh.jpg</boxart4>
			<snapshot1>cOOarVQ.gif</snapshot1>
			<snapshot2>wdP5Fxw.gif</snapshot2>
			<snapshot3>xnccYCM.gif</snapshot3>
			<snapshot4>GeNdcdT.gif</snapshot4>
			<snapshot5>G3AmIuU.png</snapshot5>
			<snapshot6>fm7HQiP.png</snapshot6>
			<snapshot7>cknczjz.png</snapshot7>
			<snapshot8>iu4vIHc.jpg</snapshot8>
			<snapshot9>MvWBQIh.png</snapshot9>
			<banner1>fdjT1NA.jpg</banner1>
		</game>
		<game name="RealSports Tennis">
			<description>RealSports Tennis</description>
			<rom crc="10f33c90" name="MAME_0.185_Software_List_ROMs_non-merged/MAME_0.185_Software_List_ROMs_non-merged.zip/MAME%200.185%20Software%20List%20ROMs%20%28non-merged%29%2Fa5200%2Frstennis.zip" sha1="2e6c7472e37926cdfd3d855a4bd37a18fa83d8cf" size="6527" />
			<title_clean>RealSports Tennis</title_clean>
			<plot>Realsports Tennis is a tennis game for two players or one player against the computer. The game follows standard tennis rules, and allows you to hit forehand or backhand shots to all areas of the court as well as serves and lobs. You can play a game of singles or doubles, and multiple skill levels are included.</plot>
			<releasedate>7/7/1983</releasedate>
			<year>1983</year>
			<genre>Sports</genre>
			<studio>Atari</studio>
			<nplayers>1-2 Sim</nplayers>
			<perspective>3rd-Person</perspective>
			<rating>2.1</rating>
			<thegamesdb_id>5207</thegamesdb_id>
			<mobygames_url>http://www.mobygames.com/game/atari-5200/realsports-tennis</mobygames_url>
			<giantbomb_url>http://www.giantbomb.com/realsports-tennis/3030-17776/</giantbomb_url>
			<boxart1>RUNZkUw.jpg</boxart1>
			<boxart2>01KIx5E.jpg</boxart2>
			<boxart3>w7NQRZV.jpg</boxart3>
			<snapshot1>dzPTTxF.gif</snapshot1>
			<snapshot2>JgIls6l.gif</snapshot2>
			<snapshot3>RbUv50E.gif</snapshot3>
			<snapshot4>ggD7Xgy.jpg</snapshot4>
			<snapshot5>ufMhziP.jpg</snapshot5>
			<snapshot6>9lvTFrP.jpg</snapshot6>
			<snapshot7>oyipk6c.jpg</snapshot7>
			<snapshot8>gGF6tcr.jpg</snapshot8>
			<snapshot9>T8IgXvR.jpg</snapshot9>
			<banner1>3vCBw7i.jpg</banner1>
		</game>
		<game name="Rescue on Fractalus!">
			<description>Rescue on Fractalus!</description>
			<rom crc="762c591b" name="MAME_0.185_Software_List_ROMs_non-merged/MAME_0.185_Software_List_ROMs_non-merged.zip/MAME%200.185%20Software%20List%20ROMs%20%28non-merged%29%2Fa5200%2Ffractal.zip" sha1="9253d7286cf87999474b37df242ba23b4358ef4a" size="24381" />
			<title_clean>Rescue on Fractalus!</title_clean>
			<plot>Fractal LandscapeRescue on Fractalus was the result of Lucasfilm -- having just recently completed the original Star Wars movie trilogy -- deciding it wanted to get into the video game market. Partnered with Atari, Lucasfilm Computer Division Games Group (later renamed LucasArts Entertainment Company) released two games, Rescue on Fractalus and Ballblazer. Rescue on Fractalus is regarded as one of the most innovative games developed for the 5200, combining space flight simulation, shooting, and a healthy dose of strategy. It is also known for using fractal geometry for the ground terrain.When Jaggis AttackThe gameplay consists of flying down to the planet of Fractalus in your Valkyrie space fighter to rescue stranded pilots. This is complicated by the presence of an evil alien race, the Jaggis. Jaggis are intent on destroying you and have put in gun turrets, kamikaze space ships, as well as fake stranded pilots. The fake pilots will run up to your ship disguised in a human spacesuit, and then attempt to crash through the cockpit to destroy you. If you were unlucky enough to open your ship's doors to a disguised Jaggi, it will attack from within, forcing you to take off into space to suffocate it.The disguised Jaggi popping up in front of the cockpit could be startling, leading to the claim that Rescue on Fractalus was the first game to truly scare the player.Lucasfilm Computer Division Games GroupOnce you have rescued at least half of the required quota of downed pilots, your mother ship will appear and allow you to refuel and repair, however the level will not end until enough pilots have been rescued.The nickname for the alien race Jaggi, was a reference to the jagged pixel edges the non-anti-aliased graphics required on the early Atari hardware. An early working title of the project was "Behind Jagged Lines". Loren Carpenter programmed the fractal mountains in this game after using fractals in the computer generated imagery for "The Genesis Effect" in the movie Star Trek 2: The Wrath of Khan.Rescue on Fractalus was programmed by David Fox, Loren Carpenter, Charlie Kellner, Peter Langston, Gary Winnick, and David Levine.[CR]</plot>
			<releasedate>7/7/1984</releasedate>
			<year>1986</year>
			<genre>Action</genre>
			<studio>Atari</studio>
			<nplayers>1</nplayers>
			<perspective>1st-Person</perspective>
			<rating>2.7</rating>
			<thegamesdb_id>5208</thegamesdb_id>
			<mobygames_url>http://www.mobygames.com/game/atari-5200/rescue-on-fractalus</mobygames_url>
			<giantbomb_url>http://www.giantbomb.com/rescue-on-fractalus/3030-841/</giantbomb_url>
			<boxart1>7wIGrpA.jpg</boxart1>
			<boxart2>oLplJzv.jpg</boxart2>
			<boxart3>qjQP7z3.jpg</boxart3>
			<snapshot1>BBmOwit.gif</snapshot1>
			<snapshot2>69THlEe.gif</snapshot2>
			<snapshot3>J6xwpKd.gif</snapshot3>
			<snapshot4>Du6MYRb.gif</snapshot4>
			<snapshot5>KEelNAz.gif</snapshot5>
			<snapshot6>bzYe9sQ.gif</snapshot6>
			<snapshot7>781kxQa.gif</snapshot7>
			<snapshot8>Z0shj9U.jpg</snapshot8>
			<snapshot9>wn3idtO.jpg</snapshot9>
			<banner1>KvP7Ojx.jpg</banner1>
		</game>
		<game name="River Raid">
			<description>River Raid</description>
			<rom crc="09fc7648" name="MAME_0.185_Software_List_ROMs_non-merged/MAME_0.185_Software_List_ROMs_non-merged.zip/MAME%200.185%20Software%20List%20ROMs%20%28non-merged%29%2Fa5200%2Friveraid.zip" sha1="ce9bd3b0847c5e187c3e8f667c8f5ea771c49965" size="6450" />
			<title_clean>River Raid</title_clean>
			<plot>[CR][B]Overview:[/B][CR]Programmed entirely by  Carol Shaw (one of the first female game designers), River Raid puts the player in control of a fighter jet tasked with flying over a river from a  top-down, vertical perspective, shooting enemy vehicles like news helicopters, planes, and civilian cargo ships. Other than dodging enemy vehicles, your primary concern is your jet's fuel level, which slowly depletes over time, and can be replenished by flying over fuel pads found throughout the environment, however shooting a fuel tank will also boost your score by several points, making whether or not to fuel up or go for the points somewhat of a strategic decision. Inexplicably, the plane will also explode if it flies over land. While River Raid features the forced movement common in scrolling shooters, you can affect the speed of the scroll with your jet by pressing either up or down on the control stick.[CR][B]Reception:[/B][CR]River Raid was the first video game in history to be listed by the German Federal Department for Media Harmful to Young Persons, cited for "its intent to compromise the minds of children by forcing a paramilitaristic [sic] education upon them, and the playing of which caused cramps, anger, headaches and aggressiveness". The Department finally admitted that River Raid was harmless in 2002.[CR]</plot>
			<releasedate>7/7/1983</releasedate>
			<year>1983</year>
			<genre>Action</genre>
			<studio>Activision</studio>
			<nplayers>1-2 Sim</nplayers>
			<perspective>Top-Down</perspective>
			<rating>3.4</rating>
			<thegamesdb_id>5209</thegamesdb_id>
			<mobygames_url>http://www.mobygames.com/game/atari-5200/river-raid</mobygames_url>
			<giantbomb_url>http://www.giantbomb.com/river-raid/3030-10516/</giantbomb_url>
			<boxart1>vJJ1KZP.jpg</boxart1>
			<boxart2>LbG7cXe.jpg</boxart2>
			<boxart3>wvpUL7e.jpg</boxart3>
			<snapshot1>RwCgOJV.gif</snapshot1>
			<snapshot2>nizThAk.gif</snapshot2>
			<snapshot3>28wg0Eg.gif</snapshot3>
			<snapshot4>MSKqKv4.gif</snapshot4>
			<snapshot5>xo47x1p.jpg</snapshot5>
			<snapshot6>s9IMwXe.png</snapshot6>
			<snapshot7>r7sUKqW.png</snapshot7>
			<snapshot8>U3vgOlZ.png</snapshot8>
			<snapshot9>H7TVUiU.png</snapshot9>
			<snapshot10>Rimm0SL.png</snapshot10>
			<clearlogo1>WWH0afE.png</clearlogo1>
		</game>
		<game name="Road Runner (Prototype)">
			<description>Road Runner (Prototype)</description>
			<rom crc="a97606ab" name="MAME_0.185_Software_List_ROMs_non-merged/MAME_0.185_Software_List_ROMs_non-merged.zip/MAME%200.185%20Software%20List%20ROMs%20%28non-merged%29%2Fa5200%2Froadrun.zip" sha1="0a7aaef5b0ede927cea13e724906207e1db48068" size="7659" />
			<title_clean>Road Runner</title_clean>
			<plot>An unreleased prototype game staring the popular Road Runner cartoon character. Thought to have been based on perhaps a port of the arcade game Locomotion before being re skinned with Roadrunner and Wiley E Coyote.[CR]At the start of each level a birdseed truck will weave its way through the maze dropping off piles of birdseed as it goes.  The goal of Roadrunner is to move the tiles around so Wiley Coyote eats as much birdseed as he can before the Roadrunner gets it.  Each tile contains a portion of the road which Wiley and the Roadrunner walk on, by sliding the tiles around you can make paths leading to the piles of birdseed or to the tunnels on the side of the board.  The tunnels connect one side of the screen to the other, and can be useful for warping across the screen.  Unfortunately some of these tunnel entrances are really just painted on, so if Wiley attempts to enter one he'll knock himself out.  The only way to tell if a tunnel is real is to watch the Roadrunner and see which tunnels he takes.[CR]Wiley can die if he either runs off the end of the tile or runs into a false tunnel.  The Roadrunner appears to be able to back up from dead end track pieces and tunnels so he is impossible to kill, but you can trap him on two dead end pieces and complete the level at your leisure.  Once all the birdseed is gone the game moves to the next level.  If you happen to run into the Roadrunner you will score 10 points, and you the Roadrunner will be transported back to your starting points.  Wiley also scores 35 points for each tile he crosses, and 50 points for each pile of birdseed he collects.[CR]- Excerpt from AtariProtos.com</plot>
			<releasedate>3/6/1983</releasedate>
			<year>1983</year>
			<genre>Action, Puzzle</genre>
			<studio>Atari</studio>
			<nplayers>1</nplayers>
			<videoid>hBz7-YfqosA</videoid>
			<thegamesdb_id>34489</thegamesdb_id>
			<boxart1>ERqFxAC.jpg</boxart1>
			<snapshot1>gMr51VO.jpg</snapshot1>
			<snapshot2>38epbDu.jpg</snapshot2>
		</game>
		<game name="Robotron: 2084">
			<description>Robotron: 2084</description>
			<rom crc="4252abd9" name="MAME_0.185_Software_List_ROMs_non-merged/MAME_0.185_Software_List_ROMs_non-merged.zip/MAME%200.185%20Software%20List%20ROMs%20%28non-merged%29%2Fa5200%2Frobotron.zip" sha1="9175e6daca58102ac8b9729d7b0336cf09977d12" size="10950" />
			<title_clean>Robotron: 2084</title_clean>
			<plot>[CR][B]Overview:[/B][CR]Robotron: 2084 is often credited as a major inspiration for more recent eight-way directional shooters (though there were earlier dual-stick shooters such as Gun Fight and Sheriff). Although the game is fairly simple, the variety of enemies and strategies is notable. Current popular games, such as Geometry Wars, Everyday Shooter, and Super Stardust HD, all borrow their basic gameplay elements from Robotron.[CR][B]Gameplay:[/B][CR]ControlsRobotron: 2084 is a top-down eight-way directional shooter, meaning that two separate control sticks are used. The left stick controls the movement of the character, while the right stick controls the direction of the shooting. While this is a style of gameplay fairly common in more recent shooter games, this was not the case the time of the game's creation.ObjectEnemies appear in "waves," which function as the game's stages. The object of each wave is to destroy all of the enemies on the screen. However, each level also has a certain number of civilians. Saving civilians, while not necessary to advance to the next wave, will greatly increase the number of points the player can acquire. In the vein of most arcade games, the object of the game is to obtain as many points as possible.There is a fairly large variety of enemies within the game. The first type merely advance toward the player, but those in the later levels have more complex attacks which are difficult to avoid. The speed of the game also increases the longer the player is in the wave. The speed does reset if the player loses a life, however. The game resets after 255 waves back to wave 1.Every 5 waves, the player encounters a screen filled with a greatly increased number of humans to save. It is in these waves that the greatest number of points can be acquired. The human civiilans are hunted down in the game by the 'hulk' enemy. However, a glitch in the original programming means that these 'hulks' will all gravitate toward a single civilian, largely ignoring all the others. If this single human can be kept alive, then it is possilbe to collect a much greater number of the others, and achieve a dramatically increased score in the process. This feature was essentially a bug in the game, but ultimately gave rise to a key tactic in playing the game.[CR]</plot>
			<releasedate>7/7/1983</releasedate>
			<year>1983</year>
			<genre>Action</genre>
			<studio>Atari</studio>
			<nplayers>1-2 Sim</nplayers>
			<perspective>3rd-Person</perspective>
			<rating>3.9</rating>
			<thegamesdb_id>5210</thegamesdb_id>
			<mobygames_url>http://www.mobygames.com/game/atari-5200/robotron-2084</mobygames_url>
			<giantbomb_url>http://www.giantbomb.com/robotron-2084/3030-11233/</giantbomb_url>
			<boxart1>SjreYGB.jpg</boxart1>
			<boxart2>cjO17IQ.jpg</boxart2>
			<boxart3>75n7ZhI.jpg</boxart3>
			<snapshot1>hzIoSGc.gif</snapshot1>
			<snapshot2>1FmeOvO.gif</snapshot2>
			<snapshot3>cWiER5h.gif</snapshot3>
			<snapshot4>BSQt1K4.gif</snapshot4>
			<snapshot5>FYrbc9s.gif</snapshot5>
			<snapshot6>bbXmaEu.png</snapshot6>
			<snapshot7>81ZXIzp.png</snapshot7>
			<snapshot8>yvkLA2f.png</snapshot8>
			<snapshot9>cVeXPNU.png</snapshot9>
			<snapshot10>2jcM5N0.png</snapshot10>
			<banner1>cT0Wrz6.jpg</banner1>
			<clearlogo1>zq1zq04.png</clearlogo1>
		</game>
		<game name="Space Dungeon">
			<description>Space Dungeon</description>
			<rom crc="b68d61e8" name="MAME_0.185_Software_List_ROMs_non-merged/MAME_0.185_Software_List_ROMs_non-merged.zip/MAME%200.185%20Software%20List%20ROMs%20%28non-merged%29%2Fa5200%2Fspcedngn.zip" sha1="127ed1c31c3e85d10212eee7b9e6d71aef7dd891" size="10866" />
			<title_clean>Space Dungeon</title_clean>
			<plot>Space Dungeon is an arcade style shooter. You control a spaceship within the space dungeon which consists of numerous rooms. Located throughout are treasures, and your goal is to collect as many of these treasures as you can and then proceed to the dungeons exit (called "collect bonus"). You don't need to collect every treasure to complete a level, but more bonus points are earned the more treasures you collect. Many of the rooms contain dangerous enemies, including death squares, guards, enforcers, pikers, and more. To fight off the enemies, your spaceship is equipped with a laser which can fire in eight different directions. To help find your way around, a map at the top of the screen will indicate where you are, where you've been, and what rooms visited so far still have enemies in them. Also located in the dungeons is a thief; the thief has the same goal as you, and will try to steal the treasures before you can. The thief can't be destroyed, but shooting it will cause it to drop any treasures it may be carrying. If you lose a spaceship at any point by crashing into an enemy or enemy fire, you will be sent back to the starting location and all the treasure you were carrying will be left in the room where you died. The game ends when you have lost all of your reserve spaceships.</plot>
			<releasedate>7/7/1983</releasedate>
			<year>1983</year>
			<genre>Action</genre>
			<studio>Atari</studio>
			<nplayers>1-2 Sim</nplayers>
			<perspective>3rd-Person</perspective>
			<rating>3.8</rating>
			<thegamesdb_id>5213</thegamesdb_id>
			<mobygames_url>http://www.mobygames.com/game/atari-5200/space-dungeon</mobygames_url>
			<giantbomb_url>http://www.giantbomb.com/space-dungeon/3030-19413/</giantbomb_url>
			<boxart1>4P4qw9D.jpg</boxart1>
			<boxart2>cwdaYcz.jpg</boxart2>
			<boxart3>JXKFdGO.jpg</boxart3>
			<snapshot1>nJCNWvh.gif</snapshot1>
			<snapshot2>cueHu0e.gif</snapshot2>
			<snapshot3>wZNon8d.gif</snapshot3>
			<snapshot4>ZygjUT5.gif</snapshot4>
			<snapshot5>oN3fFyf.gif</snapshot5>
			<snapshot6>eWgYqYN.gif</snapshot6>
			<snapshot7>CS1FcWf.gif</snapshot7>
			<snapshot8>DL0mcRO.png</snapshot8>
			<snapshot9>eBNCh2O.png</snapshot9>
			<snapshot10>so9gWLb.png</snapshot10>
			<banner1>RqatqzY.jpg</banner1>
		</game>
		<game name="Space Invaders">
			<description>Space Invaders</description>
			<rom crc="de5c354a" name="MAME_0.185_Software_List_ROMs_non-merged/MAME_0.185_Software_List_ROMs_non-merged.zip/MAME%200.185%20Software%20List%20ROMs%20%28non-merged%29%2Fa5200%2Fspaceinv.zip" sha1="cf411db770217b5af5fcfa32725cc587a8b9e710" size="5614" />
			<title_clean>Space Invaders</title_clean>
			<plot>[CR][B]Overview:[/B][CR]One of the earliest shooting games, Space Invaders was released by Taito in Japan on June 19, 1978. Gameplay involves attempting to defeat waves of aliens cascading down from the top of the screen with a laser cannon that moves along a fixed horizontal axis. The only goal is to earn as many points as possible. Designer Tomohiro Nishikado was in charge of planning, graphic design, and programming for the game and drew creative inspiration from such diverse sources as Gun Fight, Breakout, The War of the Worlds, and Star Wars. The game&#8217;s development cycle lasted for one year, during which Nishikado created custom hardware and software. The game achieved massive popularity upon its release (leading to a temporary shortage of one hundred yen coins in Japan), and helped usher in the golden age of arcade video games (circa 1978-1984).Space Invaders sold over 400,000 arcade cabinets worldwide and grossed around $3.8 billion in revenue by 1982, equivalent to over $13 billion in 2014, making it the highest-grossing video game of all time.[CR][B]Gameplay:[/B][CR]Arcade (cabaret/cocktail) versionGameplay in Space Invaders is relatively simple. The player controls a small ship that can only move laterally across the bottom of the screen and fires vertically. Five rows of eleven aliens each advance slowly from one side of the screen to the other, dropping down one space and reversing direction when they reach either side. The player&#8217;s task is to acquire points by eliminating enemies and to destroy all of the aliens before they reach the bottom of the screen and complete their &#8220;invasion.&#8221; As aliens are destroyed, the speed of the remaining enemies increases, as does the tempo of the music. Once all of the enemies are destroyed, the wave resets and the difficulty increases (a cycle that can continue indefinitely).The Invaders constantly shoot back at the player as they advance from side to side across the screen. To help avoid their attacks, the player can hide behind a number of destructible barriers or &#8220;bunkers&#8221; near the bottom of the screen (four in the original version). Occasionally a &#8220;mystery ship&#8221; will appear near the top of the screen and move quickly from one side to the other while making a distinctive klaxon noise. Destroying it rewards the player with a sizeable point bonus.[CR]Development[CR]While working for the Taito Corporation, designer Nishikado was inspired to create Space Invaders by an early Taito electro-mechanical game called Space Monsters, and by the Atari arcade game Breakout. The game was planned to have tanks, planes, and battleships as enemies, but Nishikado was not happy with their onscreen movements. He considered making the enemies human (which would have been easier to animate), but scrapped the idea since he thought it would be immoral for players to shoot them. After he saw a magazine featuring the 1977 film Star Wars, he decided to use a space theme, and based his alien enemies on the squid-like antagonists from the 1953 movie version of The War of the Worlds.Upright cabinetDue to the limitations of 1970s microprocessors, Nishikado was forced to design and build his own hardware and development tools. The arcade board he put together contained a variety of both Japanese and American components. It used an Intel 8080 central processing unit (designed by American and Japanese engineers), which could output raster graphics on a CRT monitor, but was slow when it came to drawing sprite graphics, so a dedicated Fujitsu MB14241 video shifter (an early example of a graphics chip) was used to accelerate the drawing of sprite graphics to a bitmap framebuffer. Monaural sound was hosted by a combination of analogue circuitry and a Texas Instruments SN76477 sound chip. The system that he put together is now known as the Taito 8080 arcade system board.In spite of his efforts, Nishikado was unable to program the game exactly as he wanted. The hardware that he had assembled was not powerful enough to display graphics in color and the enemies moved slower than he had intended. Fortunately he discovered that the more enemies that were removed from play, the faster the processor could render those that remained. Rather than attempt to design the game to compensate for the speed increase, he opted to leave it in as a challenging gameplay mechanic.It was originally released in Japan by Taito as a cocktail cabinet, with monochrome graphics enhanced by a rainbow-colored cellophane overlay to simulate color graphics. Taito and American licence-holder Bally/Midway then created an upright cabinet that used strips of orange and green cellophane applied to the screen to simulate color graphics, though this version only simulated several colors (compared to Taito's original cocktail version simulating a wider range of colors). Both the Japanese and American upright cabinets also included a painted backdrop of a lunar surface and a starscape, and cabinet art featuring large humanoid creatures that bore little resemblance to the in-game enemies. Nishikado claims that this was due to the artist basing his interpretation on the game&#8217;s original title, Space Monsters.[CR]Impact and Legacy[CR]Soon after its release in Japan, Space Invaders became a huge success, completely taking over certain arcades and earning Taito a tidy profit. By the end of 1978, Taito had installed 100,000 machines across the country and grossed over $600 million dollars. An oft-quoted urban legend states that there was a shortage of 100-yen coins&#8212;and subsequent production increase&#8212;in Japan attributed to the game. By 1980, 300,000 cabinets had been sold in Japan and an additional 60,000 in the United States. By 1981, Space Invaders had made Taito more than $1 billion, and continued to gross an average of $600 million per year, through to 1982, by which time it had grossed $2 billion in quarters (equivalent to $4.6 billion in 2011). This made it the best-selling video game and highest-grossing entertainment product of its time, surpassing the then highest-grossing film Star Wars, which had grossed $486 million in movie tickets.Atari 2600 versionThe 1980 Atari 2600 version represented the first official licensed port of an arcade game to a home console, and and became the first "killer app" for video game consoles by quadrupling sales of the 2600. It sold over two million units in its first year on sale as a home console game, becoming the first title to sell over a million cartridges. Ports were also released for the Atari 8-bit computer line and the Atari 5200, as well as the Nintendo Entertainment System, Game Boy and SNES. Numerous unofficial clones were made as well, such as the popular computer games Super Invader (1979) and TI Invaders (1981).Game designer Shigeru Miyamoto considered Space Invaders a game that revolutionized the video game industry; he was never interested in video games before seeing it. Hideo Kojima also described it as the first video game that impressed him and got him interested in video games. Several publications ascribed the expansion of the video game industry from a novelty into a global industry to the success of the game. Edge magazine attributed the shift of video games from bars and arcades to more mainstream locations like restaurants and department stores to Space Invaders. Its popularity was such that it was the first game where an arcade machine's owner could make up for the cost of the machine in under one month, or in some places within one week.Technology journalist Jason Whittaker credited the game's success to ending the video game crash of 1977, which had earlier been caused by Pong clones flooding the market, and beginning the golden age of video arcade games.According to The Observer, the home console versions were popular and encouraged users to learn programming; many who later became industry leaders. 1UP stated that Space Invaders showed that video games could compete against the major entertainment media at the time: movies, music, and television IGN attributed the launch of the arcade phenomenon in North America in part to Space Invaders. Electronic Games credited the game's success as the impetus behind video gaming becoming a rapidly growing hobby and as "the single most popular coin-operated attraction of all time." Game Informer considered it, along with Pac-Man, one of the most popular arcade games that tapped into popular culture and generated excitement during the golden age of arcades.IGN listed it as one of the "Top 10 Most Influential Games" in 2007, citing the source of inspiration to video game designers and the impact it had on the shooting genre. 1UP ranked it at No. 3 in its list of "The 60 Most Influential Games of All Time," stating that, in contrast to earlier arcade games which "were attempts to simulate already-existing things," Space Invaders was "the first video game as a video game, instead of merely a playable electronic representation of something else." In 2008, Guinness World Records listed it as the top-rated arcade game in technical, creative, and cultural impact.As one of the earliest shooting games, it set precedents and helped pave the way for future titles and for the shooting genre. Space Invaders popularized a more interactive style of gameplay with the enemies responding to the player controlled cannon's movement, and was the first video game to popularize the concept of achieving a high score, being the first to save the player's score. While earlier shooting games allowed the player to shoot at targets, Space Invaders was the first in which targets could fire back at the player. It was also the first game where players were given multiple lives, had to repel hordes of enemies, could take cover from enemy fire, and use destructible barriers,in addition to being the first game to use a continuous background soundtrack, with four simple diatonic descending bass notes repeating in a loop, which was dynamic and changed pace during stages, like a heartbeat sound that increases pace as enemies approached.It also introduced the concept of a difficulty curve, with the aliens moving faster as the player kills more of them, making the game more difficult as it progresses. The game's concept of scaling difficulty became the basis for modern single-player video gaming.Cited by influential creators like Shigeru Miyamoto and Hideo Kojima as a major inspiration, Space Invaders revolutionized the industry following the video game crash of 1977 (brought on by a glut of Pong clones on the market and the departure of manufacturers like RCA and Fairchild). Proving that video games were capable of competing with movies, music and television, Space Invaders has since become recognized as one of the most influential games ever released. It was one of the first games to utilize the concept of a &#8220;high score,&#8221; and was the first to save the player&#8217;s score. It was the first shooter that allowed enemies to shoot back at the player, the first to give the player multiple lives and provide destructible cover against enemy fire. Its success effectively launched an entire genre of space shooters, including Atari&#8217;s Asteroids, Williams&#8217; Defender, and Namco&#8217;s Galaxian series.It moved the gaming industry away from Pong-inspired sports games grounded in real-world situations towards action games involving fantastical situations. Whittaker commented that Space Invaders helped action games become the most dominant genre on both arcades and consoles, through to contemporary times. Guinness World Records considered Space Invaders one of the most successful arcade shooting games by 2008. In describing it as a "seminal arcade classic", IGN listed it as the number eight "classic shoot 'em up". Space Invaders set the template for the shoot 'em up genre. Its worldwide success created a demand for a wide variety of science fiction games, inspiring the development of arcade games, such as Atari's Asteroids, Williams Electronic's Defender, and Namco's Galaxian and Galaga, which were modeled after Space Invaders' gameplay and design. This influence extends to most shooting games released to the present day, including first-person shooters such as Wolfenstein, Doom, Halo, and Call of Duty. Space Invaders also had an influence on early computer dungeon crawl games such as Dungeons of Daggorath, which used similar heartbeat sounds to indicate player health. Space Invaders' concept of a gradually increasing difficulty level also revolutionized the gaming industry.Remakes and sequelsSpace Invaders '95, one of many sequelsRecent ports and remakes include Space Invaders Anniversary, released in 2003 for the PlayStation 2 and including nine variants of the core game. Space Invaders, Space Invaders Part II and Return of the Invaders were featured in the arcade compilation Taito Legends (released in 2005), and Space Invaders '91, Space Invaders '95, and Space Invaders DX were featured in Taito Legends 2 (released in 2006). A remake of the game called Space Invaders Extreme was released for the PSP and Nintendo DS in 2008 and on Xbox Live Arcade in 2009. A second remake, Space Invaders Infinity Gene, was released in 2009 on PlayStation Network, Xbox Live Arcade, and iOS devices. [CR]</plot>
			<releasedate>7/7/1982</releasedate>
			<year>1982</year>
			<genre>Action</genre>
			<studio>Atari</studio>
			<nplayers>1-2 Alt</nplayers>
			<perspective>3rd-Person</perspective>
			<rating>3.9</rating>
			<videoid>qBDW3IervjI</videoid>
			<thegamesdb_id>5214</thegamesdb_id>
			<mobygames_url>http://www.mobygames.com/game/atari-5200/space-invaders-</mobygames_url>
			<giantbomb_url>http://www.giantbomb.com/space-invaders/3030-5099/</giantbomb_url>
			<boxart1>W2CWo9M.jpg</boxart1>
			<boxart2>QjWFf4g.jpg</boxart2>
			<boxart3>mEgGmJK.jpg</boxart3>
			<snapshot1>umXa44s.gif</snapshot1>
			<snapshot2>5OYrcRP.gif</snapshot2>
			<snapshot3>utjfmrb.gif</snapshot3>
			<snapshot4>aasToVP.gif</snapshot4>
			<snapshot5>OOQlN3X.gif</snapshot5>
			<snapshot6>UXyXmsE.gif</snapshot6>
			<snapshot7>jV50Lhk.jpg</snapshot7>
			<snapshot8>PFAV9y7.jpg</snapshot8>
			<snapshot9>Y7CwWzv.jpg</snapshot9>
			<snapshot10>9lsjQIg.jpg</snapshot10>
			<banner1>8IxBzei.jpg</banner1>
			<clearlogo1>PJXNclh.png</clearlogo1>
		</game>
		<game name="Space Shuttle - A Journey Into Space">
			<description>Space Shuttle - A Journey Into Space</description>
			<rom crc="387365dc" name="MAME_0.185_Software_List_ROMs_non-merged/MAME_0.185_Software_List_ROMs_non-merged.zip/MAME%200.185%20Software%20List%20ROMs%20%28non-merged%29%2Fa5200%2Fshuttle.zip" sha1="5ae20e767d9819fe601f3b1ea6d4506ae2f2ceef" size="11733" />
			<title_clean>Space Shuttle - A Journey Into Space</title_clean>
			<plot>Space Shuttle is a simulation game where you are the pilot of space shuttle Discovery. Your goal is to launch the Discovery, establish an orbit around the Earth, open the cargo bay doors and recover a satellite to perform repairs, and finally land the Discovery successfully, all while using as little fuel as possible. Each time the complete mission is accomplished, it will then repeat at a higher difficulty level (in the higher difficulty levels the satellite has a more erratic flight path). The game is played from a first person perspective in the space shuttle cockpit where you can control everything from the shuttles engines to cargo bay doors. When the game is over you will be given a ranking which is based on the number of successful dockings and the amount of fuel that was used. In addition to the full flight mode, two easier game variations (autosimulator and simulator mode) are included. The autosimulator mode is the easiest; the computer will control the flight (you can take over at any point you wish) and the controls are simplified. The simulation mode is closer to the full game, however you have an unlimited amount of fuel so there is no time pressure, and the computer will help compensate for inaccurate maneuvering.</plot>
			<releasedate>7/7/1983</releasedate>
			<year>1983</year>
			<genre>Simulation</genre>
			<studio>Activision</studio>
			<nplayers>1</nplayers>
			<perspective>1st-Person</perspective>
			<thegamesdb_id>5215</thegamesdb_id>
			<mobygames_url>http://www.mobygames.com/game/atari-5200/space-shuttle-a-journey-into-space</mobygames_url>
			<giantbomb_url>http://www.giantbomb.com/space-shuttle-a-journey-into-space/3030-11469/</giantbomb_url>
			<boxart1>zx7dzNz.jpg</boxart1>
			<boxart2>2AZ1g1H.jpg</boxart2>
			<boxart3>gGUDpq0.jpg</boxart3>
			<snapshot1>i4VLMvo.gif</snapshot1>
			<snapshot2>1NEf5tj.gif</snapshot2>
			<snapshot3>fmZIJBH.gif</snapshot3>
			<banner1>ul4oHVE.jpg</banner1>
		</game>
		<game name="Spitfire (Prototype)">
			<description>Spitfire (Prototype)</description>
			<rom crc="3c311303" name="MAME_0.185_Software_List_ROMs_non-merged/MAME_0.185_Software_List_ROMs_non-merged.zip/MAME%200.185%20Software%20List%20ROMs%20%28non-merged%29%2Fa5200%2Fspitfire.zip" sha1="688133761c462d6865bf673ed298b4d828120940" size="11168" />
			<title_clean>Spitfire</title_clean>
			<plot>Of all the prototypes that have passed through my hands over the years, Spitfire is definitely one of the strangest.  Part Zaxxon and part Star Raiders, Spitfire appears to have been Atari's first attempt into the realm of 3D shooters.  While the current known prototype may not be very complete (approx. 50%), it shows that the 5200 was indeed capable of 3D graphics.[CR]According to the dictionary, a Spitfire is a plane from World War II.  From the name of the game one would expect at WWII simulation game, but instead Spitfire is actually a Zaxxon style game with some elements of Star Raiders thrown in.  From the first screen it's obvious that the programmer was keen on 3D as all the text is in the same 3D style.  After selecting a skill level (0-2) with the * key, you are presented with the game map.[CR]The game map appears as a grid of 20x13 octagons (that's 260 octagons!).  While this may look a bit overwhelming, only the first three rows of octagons are ever used.  While the units may be spaced out over the map, this doesn't make any difference since your target is selected with the * key (perhaps you may have had to fly to your target in later versions?).  After selecting a target its statistics will be displayed in the status bar at the bottom of the screen.  In addition to the size of the target (Very Small, Small, Large, or Very Large), the status bar displays the possible elements on that target.</plot>
			<releasedate>1/1/1983</releasedate>
			<year>1983</year>
			<genre>Shooter</genre>
			<studio>Atari</studio>
			<nplayers>1</nplayers>
			<ESRB>E - Everyone</ESRB>
			<thegamesdb_id>37037</thegamesdb_id>
			<boxart1>ytHSL6T.png</boxart1>
		</game>
		<game name="Sport Goofy (Prototype)">
			<description>Sport Goofy (Prototype)</description>
			<rom crc="73b5b6fb" name="MAME_0.185_Software_List_ROMs_non-merged/MAME_0.185_Software_List_ROMs_non-merged.zip/MAME%200.185%20Software%20List%20ROMs%20%28non-merged%29%2Fa5200%2Fsprtgoof.zip" sha1="5f0354d8792d652313e5a0fa5d395e091c801d97" size="9483" />
			<title_clean>Sport Goofy</title_clean>
			<plot>An unreleased prototype for the Atari 5200. You take control of goofy as he competes in two events, the Marathon Dive and the Pogo Pop.[CR]The Marathon Dive is a game in which you must guide Goofy up a series of platforms so he can reach the diving platform and jump off before the timer runs out.  As Goofy climbs up the platforms he must avoid little armored tanks, which will chase Goofy around.  Thankfully these tanks can't jump, reverse direction, or use the ladders, so they can be avoided by jumping over them or leading them into a hole (which will cause them to fall down to the next level).  Also hindering Goofy's progress are large gaps in the platforms which must be carefully jumped over.  If Goofy falls through a hole he'll fall down one level but is otherwise unharmed, however if he is hit by a tank he'll loose a life.[CR]If Goofy makes it to the top of the platform he will run off the end, making it about halfway across the screen before realizing that he's running in mid-air.  Now Goofy will begin to fall, and you must guide him down to the little floating platform below.  However the floating platform is constantly moving in an erratic fashion, so hitting it can be tough.  If you successfully reach the platform, Goofy will smash into it and have his parachute open a second too late (in typical cartoon fashion).  If you miss the platform Goofy will fall into the water and drown (I guess he doesn't know how to swim).  As the levels progress the tanks will begin to move faster and faster, the diving platform has more holes in it, and the floating platform moves more erratically.  Eventually the difficulty will wrap around however, and the game will get very easy again.[CR]Pogo Pop takes place on a series of squares where Goofy bounces up and down on a pogo stick in an effort to touch every tile.  This may sound easy but there's a catch, every time you jump one of the tiles disappears, so the tile that was below you may not be there when you land.  As the levels progress the frequency of the tiles disappearing increases, making it harder and harder not to fall through the floor.  [CR]While you're jumping on tiles you can attempt to pop the Mickey Mouse balloons floating above you for extra points.  The balloons come in several different colors and are worth a varying amount of points.</plot>
			<releasedate>15/6/1983</releasedate>
			<year>1983</year>
			<genre>Action, Sports</genre>
			<studio>Atari</studio>
			<nplayers>1-2 Alt</nplayers>
			<videoid>khYbKE34oqU</videoid>
			<thegamesdb_id>34490</thegamesdb_id>
			<boxart1>Z52MMTf.jpg</boxart1>
			<snapshot1>5RoAXnw.jpg</snapshot1>
			<snapshot2>wpV9fCK.jpg</snapshot2>
		</game>
		<game name="Star Raiders">
			<description>Star Raiders</description>
			<rom crc="7d819a9f" name="MAME_0.185_Software_List_ROMs_non-merged/MAME_0.185_Software_List_ROMs_non-merged.zip/MAME%200.185%20Software%20List%20ROMs%20%28non-merged%29%2Fa5200%2Fstarraid.zip" sha1="57dfc22c9805555f957ed51a2dc7bf35ad00c9d9" size="7287" />
			<title_clean>Star Raiders</title_clean>
			<plot>[CR][B]Overview:[/B][CR]Doug Neubauer, one of the designers of a new Input/Output system which allowed for dynamic sound channels, created a game demo for the Atari 8-Bit computer, to demonstrate the new device. As Spacewar! before, the demo spawned a full standalone game: Star Raiders.Doug based the game on the text and primitive graphics based Star Trek games, where players would warp to a sector of space, eliminate enemies there, and warp to a new sector, defending starbases from attack and keeping an eye on your fuel. Star Raiders iterated upon this formula with action game trappings, adding 3D, real-time combat to Star Trek's strategic map-based view.Neubauer states that it was the first game to use 3-D algorithms which computed positions on all three axes. He explains why explosions in the game tend to slow it down: it took a lot of processing power then to guess the trajectory of the little particles that floated away from the destroyed target. In addition, he states:Today, of course, it's trivial, but back then it was state of the art. The game code is built up of modules: movement, control, collision detection, audio, photon firing, Zylon brain and console monitor. Special modules for galactic charts (and enemy strategy on charts) were included, along with a module for the long-range scanner.Atari 5200 OverlayThe game's success would prove to be a driving force behind Atari 8-bit sales, leading to contemporary ports to then-current Atari consoles. Due to the complexity of controls and gameplay, the Atari Touchpad controller was included in the 2600 release, with an overlay for Star Raiders - which would remain the sole game specifically designed for the controller. The Atari 5200's standard controller includes a keypad, so an overlay was supplied. Though keypads and overlays brought the gameplay closer to the Atari 8-Bit original, the game was simplified in various ways for both console releases.Solaris, also developed by Neubauaer, is a direct sequel, as is Star Raiders II, which Neubauaer was not involved in.Star Raiders' success would similarly lead to the first-person spaceflight combat genre's popularity, inspiring the seminal Elite, which in turn spawned games such as Wing Commander.[CR][B]Gameplay:[/B][CR]The main interface Gameplay begins by choosing one of four difficulty levels. Higher difficulty results in more frequent, and more dangerous enemies. The objective is to obtain the highest game ranking, "Star Commander Class 1". The lowest possible ranking is "Galactic Cook Class 5". Rank is determined via a number of factors including energy used, damage taken, enemies killed, and more.Star Raiders features a complex series of options for controlling the ship, engaging in combat, and managing energy. The screen is divided into two parts: The majority of the screen is a 3D real-time combat field. Centered is a crosshair which indicates weapon trajectory, and view orientation. Switching from fore to aft view changes the crosshair to a dash to indicate a rear-facing perspective.A heads-up display on the lower right includes targeting data: proximity, and lock-on assistance.The lower portion of the screen features a display including:V: The ship's current velocityK: Enemy killsE: Energy units remaining out of 9999 possibleT / C: Tracking or Attack computer status&#920; (theta): Horizontal coordinate with respect to current targeted enemy&#934; (phi): Vertical coordinate with respect to current targeted enemyR: Absolute distance to target (negative is behind ship)In addition to the on-screen display, a variety of control options are available to the player using keyboard input (Original Atari 8-Bit version), the included touchpad controller (Atari 2600) or the Atari 5200 controller. The Atari 8-Bit version has the most complete set of controls, while the console versions are simplified in various ways.Selecting a number between 0 and 9 sets the speed of the shipA/F Sets the current view to aft or fore, as indicated by the shape of the crosshair. Controls reverse for aft viewC/M Toggles the computer between Attack Control (the current status is indicated on the heads-up display) or manual targetingG Brings up the Galactic ChartH Engages HyperwarpL Engages the Long Range Sector ScanS Engages shieldsT Engages Tracking ModeP Pauses the gameThe Galactic ChartThe Galactic ChartThe Galactic Chart is a strategic map representing all sectors (individual grid cells) in the galaxy, and is where the player assesses threats on star bases, determines the direction and cost of hyperwarp jumps, and can review the Star Date and damage to Star Cruiser 7.EnemiesA number of dashes in a sector represents the number of Zylon enemies in that sector, from 1 to 4. A sector with a single dash may have 1 or 2 enemies. Speed is inversely proportional to the number of enemies, so thinning an enemy fleet also increases the speed of that enemy fleet, adding strategic decision making to engagement. The Targets indicator displays the number of targets in the sector that the cursor is currently hovering over.StarbasesThe star burst symbols represent stationary star bases, where the player repairs and refueles. Should all of them be destroyed, the game is lost, but every one lost results in a major reduction score, thereby reducing the player's final rank at the conclusion of the game.If a star base is surrounded, time is counting down before the Zylon fleet will destroy it. Every 50 time units that pass mean Zylons may move, and before too many more, should a base be surrounded, it will be destroyed. Should two bases be surrounded, only one will be the target, although it's up to the player to figure out which one is the intended target.HyperwarpA cursor, which looks like a photon bolt at long distance, helps the player plan where the ship is going to move on the Galactic Chart. As the player moves the cursor, the Warp Energy indicator will increase, showing the fuel drain of a given jump, from the sector the player is currently in to the target sector. After a certain amount, the energy drain jumps up dramatically. Whether or not this is planned, should the ship's course deviate too much away from the ship's start position, this fuel penalty will occur.Damage ControlThe letters following 'DC' represent the different functions which are vulnerable to damage. The letters turn yellow when a system is damaged, and pink when destroyed:P: Photons. Damage to this system means that one of the two photon torpedo emitters are down.E: Engines. Engines are a vital system when pursuing evasive targets, and when maneuvering to dock with a star base. Hyperspace engines cannot be damaged and are independent of the vulnerable Engine systems. Damage to the engines means that velocity is substandard, and also varies wildly from second to second, creating a violent stop-start effect past a certain velocity. Low velocities are relatively predictable, but high ones can often make the player overshoot the target during star base docking and pursuit maneuvers.S: Shields. If the shields are off, any hit by Zylon fire or asteroids instantly obliterate the ship. While on, shields lose energy when struck, and in higher difficulty levels, this hit usually results in damage or destruction of a subsystem. Should shields be damaged, they flash on and off at a random rate. While on, they provide protection like normal shields. While off, they leave the craft vulnerable, but they still cost energy to maintain. Destroyed shields leave the ship completely vulnerable, but still cost to leave them activated.C: Attack Computer. The attack computer is a power-draining system which includes target tracking, crosshair placement, and guided photon attacks during lock-ons. Damage to this subsystem removes the attack computer from the screen, although it still drains energy until turned off. Destruction of the system results in a frozen range finder, necessitating use of the long range sector scan for target tracking, should the enemy not be aggressive.L: Long Range Sector Scan. The sector scan helps the player locate all enemies in the sector, even when the game limits combat to two opponents at a time. Although difficult, combat kills can be achieved through this screen. Asteroids also show up on the sector scan. Damage to the sector scan results in a double image. Destruction of the system results in complete loss of functionality.R: Sub-space Radio. This is the system that keeps track of enemy movement, and informs the player of Zylons' star base surrounding and destruction. Should the radio be damaged, players will not reliably receive messages that a star base is surrounded or destroyed. In addition, the Galactic Chart is frozen in the last enemy/star base layout the player saw. The cursor still functions, but the only way a player can tell how many targets are in a given sector is with the target indicator at the bottom of the galactic chart screen.Long Range Sector ScanLong Range Scan The Long Range Sector Scan screen is a subset of the main screen, displaying the contents of the current sector. The player can pilot the craft, aim and fire photon torpedoes (forward only), and accelerate into hyperspace, though less quickly than from the Galactic Chart.Any asteroids, photon torpedoes, debris, Zylons, star bases, or refuel-and-repair craft in the sector are displayed as dark dashes. They will be in a sphere around the spaceship (represented in the center of the screen, with fore pointing up, and aft pointing down). Due to the similarity of all objects, the player must deduce the identity of an object based on movement pattern.Star Base Docking and DestructionDocking procedure Docking with a star base restores a ship's energy count to a full 9999, and repairs all damage. Every time a player docks, the score drops by a small amount, which in turn affects the final player ranking.The player must navigate the saucer-like star base within the cross hairs, and the attack computer should has the base in full lock. Proper distance and orientation are necessary to activate the star base docking procedure. When at the proper distance, a message will come up telling the player that the procedure has begun. Moving the ship aborts the sequence. Once docked, the ship is instantly repaired and refueled, and can now leave the sector.If a player is in a star base sector when it is destroyed, Zylons will instantly be in the sector. A player can destroy a star base with torpedoes.Hyperwarp JumpIn Hyperwarp Hyperwarp moves the player from one sector to another quickly, and costs fuel. Engaging hyperwarp is possible within the Galactic Map, the Long Range Sensor Scan, or on the main combat screen. While in hyperwarp, photon torpedoes no longer function, and at higher velocities, enemy photons will not be able to harm the player, making it a useful tactic to disengage from combat. The faster the ship is moving, the more quickly hyperwarp engages. In the center of the screen a small cross symbol will appear. The closer to the center this cross is, the closer to the center of the reference point on the Galactic Chart the ship will go.Hyperspace engines will always work given enough fuel. The galactic chart allows the player to change the point of reference that the center of the screen represents.When leaving hyperspace, the player can fire photons again.[CR]Cultural Notes[CR]Star Raiders was released during a revival of science fiction which followed the first Star Wars film. It also seemed strongly influenced by the original Star Trek series, which was still present in the public mindset. Faster than light travel was referred to as hyperwarp, warp being a staple term in Star Trek's faster than light travel, and the weapons both players and Zylons use are photons, referred to sometimes as photon torpedoes, one of the main weapons in the Star Trek franchise. It may also be relevant to note that early games that featured Star Trek were often of similar design, where the player commands a Federation starship, warping from sector to sector to defend star bases from marauding enemies, keeping an eye on the fuel gauge and taking damage to ship subsystems.Another subtle Star Trek reference seems to have been in the design of the Zylon cruiser. As it draws close, one notices a bump between the two curved arches that point downward from the ship's middle. This close-up view could be seen to look like the head-on view of the classic Klingon Cruiser design.References don't seem to stop at Star Trek, though. Star Wars was referenced by the Zylon fighter, which closely resembled the TIE-fighters used by the Galactic Empire.  [CR]</plot>
			<releasedate>7/7/1982</releasedate>
			<year>1982</year>
			<genre>Action, Strategy</genre>
			<studio>Atari</studio>
			<nplayers>1</nplayers>
			<perspective>1st-Person</perspective>
			<rating>3.6</rating>
			<thegamesdb_id>5217</thegamesdb_id>
			<mobygames_url>http://www.mobygames.com/game/atari-5200/star-raiders</mobygames_url>
			<giantbomb_url>http://www.giantbomb.com/star-raiders/3030-730/</giantbomb_url>
			<boxart1>7Tf5qsq.jpg</boxart1>
			<boxart2>M5D92Nk.jpg</boxart2>
			<boxart3>G8tZ16s.jpg</boxart3>
			<boxart4>XfS2JKJ.jpg</boxart4>
			<snapshot1>uRqxKeR.gif</snapshot1>
			<snapshot2>jgrNszw.gif</snapshot2>
			<snapshot3>oKgPR7g.gif</snapshot3>
			<snapshot4>BBEBKPB.gif</snapshot4>
			<snapshot5>PnZjtt3.gif</snapshot5>
			<snapshot6>g3in1GA.gif</snapshot6>
			<snapshot7>Z8qLSFT.gif</snapshot7>
			<snapshot8>6SW0AIk.png</snapshot8>
			<snapshot9>hijtSvM.png</snapshot9>
			<snapshot10>9ZT3ubE.png</snapshot10>
			<banner1>B1iGlrm.jpg</banner1>
		</game>
		<game name="Star Trek">
			<description>Star Trek</description>
			<rom crc="69f23548" name="MAME_0.185_Software_List_ROMs_non-merged/MAME_0.185_Software_List_ROMs_non-merged.zip/MAME%200.185%20Software%20List%20ROMs%20%28non-merged%29%2Fa5200%2Fstartrek.zip" sha1="19801454ab86f2a5cf691fcd577a71ad2b8dc7d5" size="10436" />
			<title_clean>Star Trek</title_clean>
			<plot>Star Trek: Strategic Operations Simulator is an arcade action game where you take control of the Starship Enterprise. Your mission is to save the Federation from NOMAD! Before you get a chance at destroying NOMAD, you'll have to battle your way through ten levels (each consisting of multiple rounds). In each round you may encounter Klingon fighters, deadly anti-matter saucers, asteroid fields, and deadly meteors, all of which are capable of depleting the Enterprises energy. The game ends when your energy supply has completely run out. To fight these dangers, the Enterprise is equipped with an unlimited supply of phasers and a limited supply of photon torpedoes. Each round also contains one or more starbases; if you dock at a starbase, some of your supplies (such as energy and torpedoes) will be replenished. The game is played from two points of view; the top of the screen contains a third person view of the Enterprise (along with the ships gauges), and on the bottom of the screen is a first person point of view </plot>
			<year>1983</year>
			<genre>Action</genre>
			<studio>Sega</studio>
			<nplayers>1</nplayers>
			<mobygames_url>http://www.mobygames.com/game/atari-5200/star-trek-strategic-operations-simulator</mobygames_url>
			<boxart1>oHNTlRQ.jpg</boxart1>
			<boxart2>NxgbdYq.jpg</boxart2>
			<boxart3>Yf33O82.jpg</boxart3>
			<snapshot1>zl3OZWe.gif</snapshot1>
			<snapshot2>uJ3oUCQ.png</snapshot2>
			<snapshot3>C9bxSeS.png</snapshot3>
			<snapshot4>mxRndnY.png</snapshot4>
			<snapshot5>9KhZihl.png</snapshot5>
			<snapshot6>xp5frw2.png</snapshot6>
			<snapshot7>hwgdhRa.png</snapshot7>
			<snapshot8>l3wu5l3.png</snapshot8>
		</game>
		<game name="Star Wars - Return of the Jedi - Death Star Battle">
			<description>Star Wars - Return of the Jedi - Death Star Battle</description>
			<rom crc="0675f0a5" name="MAME_0.185_Software_List_ROMs_non-merged/MAME_0.185_Software_List_ROMs_non-merged.zip/MAME%200.185%20Software%20List%20ROMs%20%28non-merged%29%2Fa5200%2Fjedidsb.zip" sha1="bf77048abc36ba2cba5eeeac812802d6a0eba891" size="6460" />
			<title_clean>Star Wars - Return of the Jedi - Death Star Battle</title_clean>
			<plot>[CR][B]Overview:[/B][CR]Star Wars: Return of the Jedi - Death Star Battle released in 1983 by Parker Brothers put you at the helm of the Millennium Falcon on a quest to destroy the Galactic Empires battle station.  The game was based on two different scenarios.  In the first sequence you fought through swarms of Tie-fighters and worked to lower the force field surrounding the Death Star.  As you battled the force field would lower giving you a few moments to scramble through the opening to begin sequence two.  In sequence two, you are faced with more Tie-fighters and the "under construction" Death Star itself.  During the second sequence, the Death Star is constantly having more portions put together to complete its construction and thus making the powerful world destroying super laser operational.  The game charges you with keeping Tie-fighters at bay while successfully chipping away at the outer layers of the Death Star, exposing the laser.  Once you destroy the laser, and Death Star, you complete the level and basically replay the game at higher difficulty.[CR][B]Gameplay:[/B]   [CR]The Atari 2600 version of the game uses the familiar joystick that controls the Falcon in all directions.  The red button fires lasers from the ship. [CR]</plot>
			<releasedate>7/7/1983</releasedate>
			<year>1983</year>
			<genre>Action</genre>
			<studio>Parker Brothers</studio>
			<nplayers>1</nplayers>
			<perspective>3rd-Person</perspective>
			<rating>1.6</rating>
			<thegamesdb_id>35937</thegamesdb_id>
			<mobygames_url>http://www.mobygames.com/game/atari-5200/star-wars-return-of-the-jedi-death-star-battle</mobygames_url>
			<giantbomb_url>http://www.giantbomb.com/star-wars-return-of-the-jedi-death-star-battle/3030-19947/</giantbomb_url>
			<boxart1>wOtfo0v.jpg</boxart1>
			<boxart2>pGYMKNy.jpg</boxart2>
			<boxart3>9EGdARN.jpg</boxart3>
			<snapshot1>ArnIjiH.gif</snapshot1>
			<snapshot2>2tNBIxe.gif</snapshot2>
			<snapshot3>W6JXZMt.gif</snapshot3>
			<snapshot4>KM6Heje.gif</snapshot4>
			<snapshot5>ANTch15.png</snapshot5>
		</game>
		<game name="Star Wars - The Arcade Game">
			<description>Star Wars - The Arcade Game</description>
			<rom crc="75f566df" name="MAME_0.185_Software_List_ROMs_non-merged/MAME_0.185_Software_List_ROMs_non-merged.zip/MAME%200.185%20Software%20List%20ROMs%20%28non-merged%29%2Fa5200%2Fstarwars.zip" sha1="ab676ffe054b23bdd43cee2498afefaabbf9355b" size="11385" />
			<title_clean>Star Wars - The Arcade Game</title_clean>
			<plot>Based on the original Star Wars film, this game had players reliving the climactic assault on the Death Star in the Battle of Yavin. Players fly their X-Wing through three stages to destroy the Death Star. After that, they attack it again at a higher difficulty until they get a game over.The  cockpit version of the game The arcade game had two different kinds of cabinets: a traditional stand-up cabinet like most arcade games, and also a sit down cockpit version similar to what you'd see in driving games. The controller was an analog yoke which offered a high level of precision when aiming the on screen reticle to attack various targets.Attacking TIEs in level 1The gameplay was split into three sections. In the first section, you approach the Death Star in what is essentially a rail shooter. In this section, players do not have control of where their ship flies. TIE Fighters shoot "fireballs" at players, which can then be shot down to avoid taking damage. Players can also shoot Darth Vader's TIE Advanced for a large bonus, but it is not possible to destroy his ship.The Death Star's surfaceIn the next section, players skim the surface of the Death Star to attack turrets and towers. In this section, players have full control of where they fly and must weave in between the towers while also shooting them down. Each tower they destroy offers a much higher point bounty than the one before it, and a bonus is awarded to players who can destroy all of the towers before time runs out. This section of the game is skipped on level 1.The Trench RunThe final section of the game recreates the climactic trench run. Turrets shoot more fireballs at the player while they navigate the trench. Players can fire at the turrets and fireballs to help defend themselves, but will receive a huge bonus if they are able to "Use the Force" to fly through the trench without firing any shots. At the end of the level, the player must fire a proton torpedo at the exhaust port to win the game and start again on the next difficulty. Depending on the arcade machine's dip switches, bonus shields are sometimes awarded for the next round.[CR]</plot>
			<releasedate>31/5/1983</releasedate>
			<year>1983</year>
			<genre>Action</genre>
			<studio>Parker Brothers</studio>
			<nplayers>1</nplayers>
			<videoid>iWYjXnP8aw4</videoid>
			<thegamesdb_id>5220</thegamesdb_id>
			<mobygames_url>http://www.mobygames.com/game/atari-5200/star-wars</mobygames_url>
			<giantbomb_url>http://www.giantbomb.com/star-wars/3030-29838/</giantbomb_url>
			<boxart1>eVYDtvx.jpg</boxart1>
			<boxart2>CZEPYMH.jpg</boxart2>
			<boxart3>cQVju0f.jpg</boxart3>
			<snapshot1>0WJR0BG.gif</snapshot1>
			<snapshot2>HxpAbtw.gif</snapshot2>
			<snapshot3>JkWk2lA.gif</snapshot3>
			<snapshot4>JSiqBbR.gif</snapshot4>
			<snapshot5>eqb44gF.png</snapshot5>
			<snapshot6>aLteYPD.png</snapshot6>
			<snapshot7>MsMZSCU.png</snapshot7>
			<snapshot8>0NeecN7.png</snapshot8>
			<snapshot9>s5GgJX2.png</snapshot9>
			<snapshot10>23HxqPl.png</snapshot10>
			<clearlogo1>FGUBrIK.png</clearlogo1>
		</game>
		<game name="Stargate (Prototype)">
			<description>Stargate (Prototype)</description>
			<rom crc="1d1cee27" name="MAME_0.185_Software_List_ROMs_non-merged/MAME_0.185_Software_List_ROMs_non-merged.zip/MAME%200.185%20Software%20List%20ROMs%20%28non-merged%29%2Fa5200%2Fstargate.zip" sha1="09d192a3598cdadfb61eceb430b3d5892e40962f" size="11449" />
			<title_clean>Stargate</title_clean>
			<plot>An unreleased prototype port of the popular Williams game Stargate.[CR]The sequel to Defender and much like the arcade game you fly around blasting aliens and trying to survive long enough to save humanoids. You also have a Hyperspace button that can teleport you to a random area which can be good or bad. Also new in Stargate was an Inviso button that would cloak your fighter for a limited time.</plot>
			<releasedate>5/1/1984</releasedate>
			<year>1984</year>
			<genre>Shooter</genre>
			<studio>Atari</studio>
			<nplayers>1-2 Alt</nplayers>
			<videoid>wXMrd2BjkJQ</videoid>
			<thegamesdb_id>34491</thegamesdb_id>
			<boxart1>jHWrhgy.jpg</boxart1>
			<snapshot1>RoRfs47.jpg</snapshot1>
			<snapshot2>tpoaVwB.jpg</snapshot2>
		</game>
		<game name="Super Breakout">
			<description>Super Breakout</description>
			<rom crc="a0642110" name="MAME_0.185_Software_List_ROMs_non-merged/MAME_0.185_Software_List_ROMs_non-merged.zip/MAME%200.185%20Software%20List%20ROMs%20%28non-merged%29%2Fa5200%2Fsbrkout.zip" sha1="f5f9c7f97bf09e5647e808d892b656f3ee1e19e0" size="3223" />
			<title_clean>Super Breakout</title_clean>
			<plot>Super Breakout features similar gameplay to the original, but with several new game variations. Your goal is to earn as many points as possible by destroying the bricks at the top of the playfield. To do this, you need to use the paddle at the bottom of the screen to keep a bouncing ball within the playfield. There are four different game variations included. The first is 'Breakout', and plays the same as the original game. [CR]This leaves three new gameplay concepts. In 'Progressive' the brick walls will slowly drop towards the bottom of the screen and the ball moves progressively faster and faster. When there's room, a new layer of bricks will appear at the top. [CR]The other two games add a second paddle. In 'Double Breakout' you have two balls to keep in play and score with. In 'Cavity' there is a single ball in play when you start, but two additional balls trapped within the bricks. These are freed when their surrounding bricks are destroyed.</plot>
			<releasedate>7/7/1982</releasedate>
			<year>1982</year>
			<genre>Action</genre>
			<studio>Atari</studio>
			<nplayers>1-2 Alt</nplayers>
			<perspective>3rd-Person</perspective>
			<rating>2.8</rating>
			<thegamesdb_id>5221</thegamesdb_id>
			<mobygames_url>http://www.mobygames.com/game/atari-5200/super-breakout</mobygames_url>
			<giantbomb_url>http://www.giantbomb.com/super-breakout/3030-1055/</giantbomb_url>
			<boxart1>mB4eUD8.jpg</boxart1>
			<boxart2>AWVnZbV.jpg</boxart2>
			<boxart3>idxVNqH.jpg</boxart3>
			<boxart4>herGWq8.jpg</boxart4>
			<snapshot1>YlV6gDB.gif</snapshot1>
			<snapshot2>LjZKrbV.gif</snapshot2>
			<snapshot3>oyAyVcY.gif</snapshot3>
			<snapshot4>jlBkIEw.gif</snapshot4>
			<snapshot5>sEo3al7.gif</snapshot5>
			<snapshot6>QZenNtM.png</snapshot6>
			<snapshot7>PiOinZU.jpg</snapshot7>
			<snapshot8>F4IDWRz.jpg</snapshot8>
			<clearlogo1>7rsWr4L.png</clearlogo1>
		</game>
		<game name="Super Cobra">
			<description>Super Cobra</description>
			<rom crc="97debcd2" name="MAME_0.185_Software_List_ROMs_non-merged/MAME_0.185_Software_List_ROMs_non-merged.zip/MAME%200.185%20Software%20List%20ROMs%20%28non-merged%29%2Fa5200%2Fscobra.zip" sha1="8205093f5fb1fdf0ccb71d667ea0a3849fb0a0f2" size="6320" />
			<title_clean>Super Cobra</title_clean>
			<plot>Super Cobra is a side scrolling shooter based on the arcade game. You're a chopper pilot on a surveillance mission in enemy territory; your goal is to make it through the various obstacle courses alive and score as many points as possible. Tall buildings, mountains, narrow tunnels, and various enemies (such as tanks, rockets, mines, and more) can all get in the way and destroy your chopper if you aren't careful. To help defend yourself, the chopper is armed with a machine gun and bombs which can be used to destroy the enemy tanks and rockets. To make the task more difficult, your chopper has a limited amount of fuel. Throughout the landscapes are fuel tanks; if one of these is shot or bombed, you will be awarded extra fuel. As the levels progress, the enemies become more aggressive, fuel becomes more scarce, and the landscape becomes trickier to navigate.</plot>
			<releasedate>7/7/1983</releasedate>
			<year>1983</year>
			<genre>Action</genre>
			<studio>Parker Brothers</studio>
			<nplayers>1</nplayers>
			<perspective>3rd-Person</perspective>
			<rating>2.5</rating>
			<thegamesdb_id>5222</thegamesdb_id>
			<mobygames_url>http://www.mobygames.com/game/atari-5200/super-cobra</mobygames_url>
			<giantbomb_url>http://www.giantbomb.com/super-cobra/3030-10519/</giantbomb_url>
			<boxart1>OnuuLQC.jpg</boxart1>
			<boxart2>wZjjbvA.jpg</boxart2>
			<boxart3>LfU8FBd.jpg</boxart3>
			<snapshot1>uy0LlAh.gif</snapshot1>
			<snapshot2>H4daMIP.gif</snapshot2>
			<snapshot3>GUlE7bi.gif</snapshot3>
			<snapshot4>upRRJCf.gif</snapshot4>
			<snapshot5>ybt2XBk.gif</snapshot5>
			<snapshot6>70MFEAt.jpg</snapshot6>
			<snapshot7>O43TavE.jpg</snapshot7>
			<snapshot8>BsLnzZ1.jpg</snapshot8>
			<snapshot9>cVtWgQq.jpg</snapshot9>
			<snapshot10>jClbxtG.jpg</snapshot10>
			<banner1>Wx3KJRZ.jpg</banner1>
			<clearlogo1>DTS0Bi9.png</clearlogo1>
		</game>
		<game name="Tempest (Prototype)">
			<description>Tempest (Prototype)</description>
			<rom crc="1187342f" name="MAME_0.185_Software_List_ROMs_non-merged/MAME_0.185_Software_List_ROMs_non-merged.zip/MAME%200.185%20Software%20List%20ROMs%20%28non-merged%29%2Fa5200%2Ftempest.zip" sha1="85fcea0a4d4d1f22437801c96229ba96e0f6b711" size="7244" />
			<title_clean>Tempest</title_clean>
			<plot>Tempest is a shooter using wire-frame graphics. Each Wireway is taken on in turn, and has a network of lines guiding the movement paths of both yourself and the aliens. You remain on the outside and keep shooting as the aliens move towards you. Any that reach the outside are fatal to touch, thus limiting your range of movement greatly if 2 or more achieve this. Some aliens move sideways - in dealing with these, plan ahead allowing for the time your shots to take to travel.</plot>
			<studio>Atari</studio>
			<thegamesdb_id>5224</thegamesdb_id>
			<boxart1>zPStCmS.jpg</boxart1>
			<boxart2>uMriMTl.jpg</boxart2>
			<banner1>3tNpXEM.jpg</banner1>
			<clearlogo1>CITGNNl.png</clearlogo1>
		</game>
		<game name="Track and Field (Prototype)">
			<description>Track and Field (Prototype)</description>
			<rom crc="0ba22ece" name="MAME_0.185_Software_List_ROMs_non-merged/MAME_0.185_Software_List_ROMs_non-merged.zip/MAME%200.185%20Software%20List%20ROMs%20%28non-merged%29%2Fa5200%2Ftrackfld.zip" sha1="9dfbb5d8b77504c66ce3ac4382daf79820393dd8" size="11651" />
			<title_clean>Track and Field</title_clean>
			<plot>An unreleased prototype game for the Atari 5200 based on the popular arcade game. While it went unreleased it was ported and released for the Atari 8-Bit computers. Players take part in 6 events.[CR]100 Meter Dash &#8211; Running by quickly alternating button presses.[CR]Long jump &#8211; Running by alternating button press and correct timing for jump. Hold jump button to set angle (42 degrees is optimal).[CR]Javelin throw &#8211; Running by alternating button presses and then using action button correct timing for angle (43 degrees is optimal).[CR]110 Meter Hurdles &#8211; Running by alternating button presses and using action button to time hurdles[CR]Hammer throw &#8211; Spinning initiated by pressing a run button once and then correctly timed press of action button to choose angle (45 is optimal).[CR]High jump &#8211; Running (speed set by computer) and then action button must be held down to determine angle of jump. Once in the air, the run button can be rapidly pressed for additional height.[CR][B]Gameplay:[/B] screenshot of the long jump event.[CR]In each event, there is a qualifying time or level that the player must achieve to advance to the next event; failing to qualify (in one heat for running events or three tries in the other events) will reduce the player's number of lives by one, but if none are present in his/her disposal, the game will end.</plot>
			<releasedate>10/5/1984</releasedate>
			<year>1984</year>
			<genre>Sports</genre>
			<studio>Atari</studio>
			<nplayers>1-2 Alt</nplayers>
			<videoid>4BfPGbV5a-0 Apr</videoid>
			<thegamesdb_id>34492</thegamesdb_id>
			<boxart1>q355V8B.jpg</boxart1>
			<snapshot1>2CpZkg8.jpg</snapshot1>
			<snapshot2>Y8LB2oH.jpg</snapshot2>
			<clearlogo1>LIbiPjn.png</clearlogo1>
		</game>
		<game name="Vanguard">
			<description>Vanguard</description>
			<rom crc="caaea0a4" name="MAME_0.185_Software_List_ROMs_non-merged/MAME_0.185_Software_List_ROMs_non-merged.zip/MAME%200.185%20Software%20List%20ROMs%20%28non-merged%29%2Fa5200%2Fvanguard.zip" sha1="6c633de50e6cc0c0c40061cd24e6f78f552a438f" size="13764" />
			<title_clean>Vanguard</title_clean>
			<plot>Vanguard is an arcade style shooter for one or two players. Your goal is to pilot your spaceship to the City of Mystery which is located at the end of a heavily guarded tunnel, and once there destroy the creature Gond. The tunnel is broken up into several different zones, called the mountain zone, rainbow zone, stick zone, stripe zone, bleak zone, and City of Mystery. Each zone features different types of enemy spaceships to deal with, and can scroll either horizontally or vertically. In the mountain zone or stripe zone, you may also come across an energy pod marked with an 'E'. If you fly through this, your ship temporarily becomes invincible to the deadly cave walls and numerous enemies which are trying to stop you. When not invincible, your space ship is equipped with lasers to help destroy enemies. You can fire in four different directions, however your speed is decreased when firing. You also need to keep an eye on your fuel gauge; your fuel will deplete at a rapid rate, and your ship will crash if it runs out. Fuel is gained each time you destroy an enemy, so make sure you destroy as many as you can! When you finally make it through all the various zones of the tunnel and defeat Gond, the game will repeat at a more difficult skill level.</plot>
			<releasedate>7/7/1983</releasedate>
			<year>1983</year>
			<genre>Action</genre>
			<studio>Atari</studio>
			<nplayers>1</nplayers>
			<perspective>3rd-Person</perspective>
			<rating>4.3</rating>
			<ESRB>E - Everyone</ESRB>
			<thegamesdb_id>5226</thegamesdb_id>
			<mobygames_url>http://www.mobygames.com/game/atari-5200/vanguard</mobygames_url>
			<giantbomb_url>http://www.giantbomb.com/vanguard/3030-11640/</giantbomb_url>
			<boxart1>GVjPWbN.jpg</boxart1>
			<boxart2>ijE1oI2.jpg</boxart2>
			<boxart3>FhnwVtY.jpg</boxart3>
			<snapshot1>YWHpBqI.gif</snapshot1>
			<snapshot2>ZE9RNxQ.gif</snapshot2>
			<snapshot3>U3spj1Y.gif</snapshot3>
			<snapshot4>8u8Msq0.gif</snapshot4>
			<snapshot5>68PiGyi.gif</snapshot5>
			<snapshot6>fmWbMCH.gif</snapshot6>
			<snapshot7>vDgUCFE.gif</snapshot7>
			<snapshot8>9Qd44YS.gif</snapshot8>
			<snapshot9>ANbAWMQ.png</snapshot9>
			<snapshot10>0mENzbi.png</snapshot10>
			<banner1>epX3NaG.jpg</banner1>
			<clearlogo1>iUnKRmO.png</clearlogo1>
		</game>
		<game name="Wizard of Wor">
			<description>Wizard of Wor</description>
			<rom crc="d6f7ddfd" name="MAME_0.185_Software_List_ROMs_non-merged/MAME_0.185_Software_List_ROMs_non-merged.zip/MAME%200.185%20Software%20List%20ROMs%20%28non-merged%29%2Fa5200%2Fwow.zip" sha1="49debdf3c133fde9905d6d9137da5d8dff8d6283" size="12148" />
			<title_clean>Wizard of Wor</title_clean>
			<plot>[CR][B]Gameplay:[/B][CR][B]Gameplay:[/B] consists of a never-ending series of maze-like dungeons, randomly drawn from a large pool of pre-set designs. Each dungeon has doors on either side that warp around to the other side (similar to Pac-Man) Players control "Worriors", and must clear each dungeon of monsters.This game has single-player or simultaneous two-player co-op gameplay. Player One takes the yellow Worrior (right-hand side), and Player Two takes the blue Worrior (left-hand side). In the arcade version's single-player mode, the blue Worrior is controlled by the CPU. Wizard of Wor ScreenThe enemies consist of:Burwor (Blue)Garwor (Yellow)Thorwor (Red)WorlukWizard of WorIf a player or monster uses one of the doors, it closes, temporarily sealing the tunnel. On the Atari 2600 version, the tunnel simply opens and closes periodically.Like Asteroids, the game's enemies move to an audible tempo that increases over time; the longer players take to clear a dungeon, the faster the enemies will move.There are 3 types of Worling - Burwor, Garwor, and Thorwor - in ascending order of speed and viciousness. All Worlings can shoot at the players. Garwor and Thorwor can turn invisible, only becoming visible again when they enter the same corridor as a player. All monsters, including invisible ones, are displayed as blips on the radar display at the bottom of the screen. Players must use this radar to keep track of invisible Worlings.Once a dungeon is cleared of all monsters, from the second dungeon on, there is a random chance that the winged Worluk - the Wizard's familiar - may appear. Worluk appears at a random position in the maze, and makes for an exit tunnel. If the players manage to bullseye Worluk before it escapes, the next level is a "Double Score Dungeon" granting a 2x score-multiplier for that level.If the players manage to kill Worluk, there is a random chance that the angry Wizard of Wor will then appear. The Wizard teleports around the maze randomly, casting deadly lighting bolts, until either the Wizard or a player is killed.On the Bally Astrocade, this game was released as "The Incredible Wizard." The port there makes some graphical cuts and eliminates the CPU-controlled player, but the sound is astoundingly similar to the arcade release.[CR]</plot>
			<releasedate>7/7/1983</releasedate>
			<year>1983</year>
			<genre>Action</genre>
			<studio>CBS Electronics</studio>
			<nplayers>1</nplayers>
			<perspective>3rd-Person</perspective>
			<thegamesdb_id>5227</thegamesdb_id>
			<mobygames_url>http://www.mobygames.com/game/atari-5200/wizard-of-wor</mobygames_url>
			<giantbomb_url>http://www.giantbomb.com/wizard-of-wor/3030-18684/</giantbomb_url>
			<boxart1>RsIJDLC.jpg</boxart1>
			<boxart2>fuqtnbe.jpg</boxart2>
			<boxart3>jU8Wpst.jpg</boxart3>
			<snapshot1>WXnKwR6.gif</snapshot1>
			<snapshot2>AKH23iN.gif</snapshot2>
			<snapshot3>r4hFBx9.gif</snapshot3>
			<snapshot4>MrDG7Qc.gif</snapshot4>
			<snapshot5>qAyo7A5.gif</snapshot5>
			<snapshot6>P6T89aa.jpg</snapshot6>
			<snapshot7>a9D3M9M.png</snapshot7>
			<fanart1>HS7v1Vu.jpg</fanart1>
			<clearlogo1>lSOytsl.png</clearlogo1>
		</game>
		<game name="Xari Arena (Prototype)">
			<description>Xari Arena (Prototype)</description>
			<rom crc="b8faaec3" name="MAME_0.185_Software_List_ROMs_non-merged/MAME_0.185_Software_List_ROMs_non-merged.zip/MAME%200.185%20Software%20List%20ROMs%20%28non-merged%29%2Fa5200%2Fxari.zip" sha1="8b5512d3d2a952c99b9377919f0e06481161d81e" size="11087" />
			<title_clean>Xari Arena</title_clean>
			<plot>An unreleased prototype game for the Atari 5200.[CR]Your goal is to destroy all the Xari's that come out of the well in the center of the screen before they can destroy all your blocks. You can use the joystick or the trackball controller.[CR]Each player resembles a hollow paddle (like a capsule), which you can move around your side of the screen.  Your paddle can catch and hold up to three fireballs (the little star looking things that the Xari's shoot), and each stored fireball allows you to destroy one Xari by running into it.  If you hit a Xari without any fireballs stored in your paddle, it is temporarily stunned and you cannot catch or deflect any shots for a few seconds.  If you already have three fireballs stored up, your paddle will start reflecting the fireballs back at the Xari's (a great tactic for those hard to reach guys that won't come near you) and at your partner (which is not so good).  You can choose to reflect shots even if you don't have three fireballs stored up by pressing the bottom controller button.[CR]If things start to get out of control you can activate your fire extinguisher (using the top controller button) to temporarily protect your blocks.  The fire extinguisher coats your blocks with foam and will destroy any shots that touch it.  the foam moves quickly down your blocks and only lasts for a few seconds so you have to use it wisely (like when fireballs get behind your blocks).  You get one new fire extinguisher each level, which can be stored for later use.</plot>
			<releasedate>20/9/1983</releasedate>
			<year>1983</year>
			<genre>Action</genre>
			<studio>Atari</studio>
			<nplayers>1-2 Alt</nplayers>
			<videoid>88d4-1dOMW0</videoid>
			<thegamesdb_id>34494</thegamesdb_id>
			<boxart1>JcIi3zm.jpg</boxart1>
			<snapshot1>7cAbc8K.jpg</snapshot1>
			<snapshot2>AGQ8AP7.jpg</snapshot2>
		</game>
		<game name="Xevious (Prototype)">
			<description>Xevious (Prototype)</description>
			<rom crc="382634dc" name="MAME_0.185_Software_List_ROMs_non-merged/MAME_0.185_Software_List_ROMs_non-merged.zip/MAME%200.185%20Software%20List%20ROMs%20%28non-merged%29%2Fa5200%2Fxevious.zip" sha1="c3cf33216dfa484309b923f21829d040486bc481" size="15075" />
			<title_clean>Xevious</title_clean>
			<plot>An unreleased prototype based on the popular Namco shooting game.[CR]It's a nightmare, but it's true.  Scientific research has determined that we are the actual aliens on Earth and the evil Xevions are the original inhabitants.  Now the Xevions want Earth back. minus the humans! Earth's last hope is an experimental fighter plane known as the Solvalou.  The mission is dangerous, success isn't guaranteed, and odds are this is a one-way trip.  But at this point it's do or die![CR]As Earth's last hope, you must successfully defeat the Xevion assault fleet before they reclaim earth.  However this won't be an easy task, the Xevions have had over a millennia to develop the biggest, nastiest, and most destructive ships Earth has ever seen.  Thankfully the Solvalou is armed with the latest in weapons technology which will cut through the Xevion hordes like a hot knife through butter.  The Solvalou has two main weapons, a laser blaster for taking out air targets, and a photon bomber for destroying ground targets.  Over the course of the game you'll run into numerous enemy types which can only be destroyed using the appropriate weapon, so mastering the dual shot (air and ground) technique is vital.</plot>
			<releasedate>4/1/1984</releasedate>
			<year>1984</year>
			<genre>Shooter</genre>
			<studio>Atari</studio>
			<nplayers>1-2 Alt</nplayers>
			<videoid>u9Iy6C28c88</videoid>
			<thegamesdb_id>34495</thegamesdb_id>
			<boxart1>6zPujp1.jpg</boxart1>
			<snapshot1>uy1sCWt.jpg</snapshot1>
			<snapshot2>csmsfmc.jpg</snapshot2>
		</game>
		<game name="Zaxxon">
			<description>Zaxxon</description>
			<rom crc="741746d1" name="MAME_0.185_Software_List_ROMs_non-merged/MAME_0.185_Software_List_ROMs_non-merged.zip/MAME%200.185%20Software%20List%20ROMs%20%28non-merged%29%2Fa5200%2Fzaxxon.zip" sha1="4a4c4a25c8ed1b0ae79ca22684d7d311a564a7b5" size="9051" />
			<title_clean>Zaxxon</title_clean>
			<plot>The Zaxxon defence system must be destroyed in this isometric-viewed shoot 'em up which was originally hugely successful in the arcades. The game has 3 stages, first taking you through Asteroid City, which is heavily protected by aircraft, guns and missiles. Many barriers are alarmed, leaving you with limited space to progress through, and fire must constantly be dodged.[CR]Stage two is a space shoot out against hordes of enemy aircraft - those you failed to destroy in the first part of the task. Complete this and you reach the final battle with Zaxxon, with the game looping with increased difficulty if you can survive the first time. There are 3 distinct skill levels, while controls involve using forward to dive and back to climb, in the manner of flight simulation.</plot>
			<releasedate>7/7/1984</releasedate>
			<year>1984</year>
			<genre>Action</genre>
			<studio>Sega</studio>
			<nplayers>1-2 Sim</nplayers>
			<perspective>3rd-Person</perspective>
			<rating>3.0</rating>
			<thegamesdb_id>5229</thegamesdb_id>
			<mobygames_url>http://www.mobygames.com/game/atari-5200/zaxxon</mobygames_url>
			<giantbomb_url>http://www.giantbomb.com/zaxxon/3030-9547/</giantbomb_url>
			<boxart1>7yJbSSv.jpg</boxart1>
			<boxart2>D4lETgl.jpg</boxart2>
			<snapshot1>re16IC0.jpg</snapshot1>
			<snapshot2>Dq1jjkO.gif</snapshot2>
			<snapshot3>Ax6dvn0.gif</snapshot3>
			<snapshot4>lGkJEDG.gif</snapshot4>
			<snapshot5>lCRVWB8.gif</snapshot5>
			<snapshot6>PcS4oNm.gif</snapshot6>
			<snapshot7>FIx7OPL.png</snapshot7>
			<snapshot8>mVanOIA.png</snapshot8>
			<snapshot9>iSDJVnC.png</snapshot9>
			<snapshot10>cvZh21t.png</snapshot10>
			<banner1>KOLpHmL.jpg</banner1>
			<clearlogo1>t2vzxyo.png</clearlogo1>
		</game>
		<game name="Zenji">
			<description>Zenji</description>
			<rom crc="da228530" name="MAME_0.185_Software_List_ROMs_non-merged/MAME_0.185_Software_List_ROMs_non-merged.zip/MAME%200.185%20Software%20List%20ROMs%20%28non-merged%29%2Fa5200%2Fzenji.zip" sha1="55da563b4394508c23d866fb1e543262fb45536d" size="6631" />
			<title_clean>Zenji</title_clean>
			<plot>Zenji is an action/strategy game where you control a rolling face throughout a maze. Each section of the maze can be rotated by the face. The goal is to turn the entire maze green by connecting each section of the maze to the source at the center of the screen. After all sections of the maze have been connected, you can move on to the next, more challenging level. In addition to having a time limit to complete your task, you need to avoid the flames and sparks which wander about the maze. From time to time a number will appear in a maze section and count down from 9 to 0. If you touch the number before it disappears, bonus points are earned. As the levels progress, the mazes become larger, trickier and more flames will appear.</plot>
			<releasedate>7/4/1984</releasedate>
			<year>1984</year>
			<genre>Action, Strategy</genre>
			<studio>Activision</studio>
			<nplayers>1</nplayers>
			<perspective>3rd-Person</perspective>
			<rating>4.5</rating>
			<videoid>mJfy_vl0yj0</videoid>
			<thegamesdb_id>5230</thegamesdb_id>
			<mobygames_url>http://www.mobygames.com/game/atari-5200/zenji</mobygames_url>
			<giantbomb_url>http://www.giantbomb.com/zenji/3030-7619/</giantbomb_url>
			<boxart1>fp24kmz.jpg</boxart1>
			<boxart2>4VRKMfn.jpg</boxart2>
			<boxart3>IVuCs2z.jpg</boxart3>
			<snapshot1>qxxqCyf.gif</snapshot1>
			<snapshot2>FzA1GjQ.gif</snapshot2>
			<snapshot3>gTySb9k.gif</snapshot3>
			<snapshot4>VowMimF.gif</snapshot4>
			<snapshot5>e8mDAxi.gif</snapshot5>
			<snapshot6>dtwPQnu.png</snapshot6>
			<snapshot7>ZUJf9RQ.png</snapshot7>
			<snapshot8>5Pexb6h.png</snapshot8>
			<snapshot9>Bk4o1C4.png</snapshot9>
			<snapshot10>hUgpmjK.png</snapshot10>
			<banner1>JnzFnGd.jpg</banner1>
			<clearlogo1>mUmOMVN.png</clearlogo1>
		</game>
		<game name="Zone Ranger">
			<description>Zone Ranger</description>
			<rom crc="2959d827" name="MAME_0.185_Software_List_ROMs_non-merged/MAME_0.185_Software_List_ROMs_non-merged.zip/MAME%200.185%20Software%20List%20ROMs%20%28non-merged%29%2Fa5200%2Fzonerngr.zip" sha1="18315bec1e62102290feeb77fb290e1266cf5bfc" size="11792" />
			<title_clean>Zone Ranger</title_clean>
			<plot>Zone Ranger is an arcade action game somewhat similar to Asteroids. You are the pilot of a spaceship in a deadly region of space. Large killer rocks, rogue satellites, boomerangs, and more all fill this region of space. Using your ships lasers you need to destroy as many of these as you can to earn points. Each level also contains some warp holes; enter one of these and you will be transported to a new location, which could be useful if you get in trouble. You will also occasionally come across some sonic sparklers; touch one of these, and you will temporarily become invincible. Another oddity you may come across is a super portal, which will transport you to the inner sanctum where bonus dots can be found. Lastly, on level one only a warp to the seventh dimension can be found. Lots of points can be earned there, but it's quite difficult so if you take this warp you probably won't last long!</plot>
			<releasedate>7/7/1984</releasedate>
			<year>1984</year>
			<genre>Action</genre>
			<studio>Activision</studio>
			<nplayers>1-2 Sim</nplayers>
			<perspective>3rd-Person</perspective>
			<thegamesdb_id>5231</thegamesdb_id>
			<mobygames_url>http://www.mobygames.com/game/atari-5200/zone-ranger</mobygames_url>
			<giantbomb_url>http://www.giantbomb.com/zone-ranger/3030-8149/</giantbomb_url>
			<boxart1>AQnZA1U.jpg</boxart1>
			<boxart2>jKgd0Dd.jpg</boxart2>
			<boxart3>FLmfiOA.jpg</boxart3>
			<snapshot1>uoLsHOt.gif</snapshot1>
			<snapshot2>Y64hcO9.gif</snapshot2>
			<snapshot3>7TWP18Z.gif</snapshot3>
			<snapshot4>Zsk6prG.gif</snapshot4>
			<snapshot5>nTaKyBK.gif</snapshot5>
			<snapshot6>XSTVnHI.jpg</snapshot6>
			<snapshot7>JjM1gcv.png</snapshot7>
			<snapshot8>KR1YzhR.png</snapshot8>
			<snapshot9>wVBOJY8.png</snapshot9>
			<snapshot10>QqKrRT6.png</snapshot10>
		</game>
</datafile>