<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<datafile>
	<header>
		<emu_name>CaveStory</emu_name>
		<emu_description>Standalone Game</emu_description>
		<emu_category>Port</emu_category>
		<emu_version>04012018</emu_version>
		<emu_date>9/14/2016</emu_date>
		<emu_author>Lefty420</emu_author>
		<emu_visibility>visible</emu_visibility>
		<emu_homepage>https://archive.org</emu_homepage>
		<emu_baseurl>https://archive.org/download/</emu_baseurl>
		<emu_launcher>retroplayer</emu_launcher>
		<emu_default_addon>game.libretro.nx</emu_default_addon>
		<emu_ext_launch_cmd>none</emu_ext_launch_cmd>
		<emu_downloadpath>default</emu_downloadpath>
		<emu_postdlaction>unzip_to_folder_and_launch_file</emu_postdlaction>
		<emu_comment>Cave Story (Dokutsu Monogatari) is a metroidvania platform-adventure video game released in 2004 for the Windows PC. It was developed over five years by Daisuke "Pixel" Amaya in his free time. Cave Story features 2D platform mechanics and is reminiscent of the classic games Amaya played in his youth, such as Metroid (1986) and Castlevania (1986). After its initial self-published release, Cave Story slowly gained popularity on the Internet. It received wide critical acclaim for its compelling characters, setting, story and gameplay.</emu_comment>
		<emu_thumb>RvNuT6A.jpg</emu_thumb>
		<emu_banner>17Bcl4P.jpg</emu_banner>
		<emu_fanart>5fwtj6a.png</emu_fanart>
		<emu_logo>TK7Mxew.png</emu_logo>
		<emu_trailer>VQpHejqlzzY</emu_trailer>
	</header>
	<game name="CaveStory">
		<description>CaveStory</description>
		<rom name="tom_bftp_D/cs.zip" size="1646720" />
		<title_clean>CaveStory</title_clean>
		<plot>Cave Story, or Doukutsu Monogatari, is a Japanese freeware PC side-scrolling platformer game developed by Studio Pixel.  It has been translated into English by Aeon Genesis Translations and has an official translation for commercial releases such as Cave Story Plus.[CR]Cave Story is really one of those games that can be considered a masterpiece of game design. There are so many wonderful and classic gaming elements, that I cannot even begin to describe just one quality well enough to say, It is for this one reason alone that Cave Story is a great game.[CR]There is just so much effort, originality and ingenuity behind this game and it really shows more and more as you play through it.</plot>
		<releasedate>20/12/2004</releasedate>
		<year>2004</year>
		<genre>Retro</genre>
		<nplayers>1</nplayers>
		<thegamesdb_id>8333</thegamesdb_id>
		<videoid>VQpHejqlzzY</videoid>
		<giantbomb_url>https://www.giantbomb.com/cave-story/3030-20124/</giantbomb_url>
		<boxart1>0Bwc4E7.png</boxart1>
		<banner1>QJK8Key.jpg</banner1>
		<emu_command>Doukutsu.exe</emu_command>
	</game>
</datafile>