<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<datafile>
	<header>
		<emu_name>Internet Archive Best Of - GameCube</emu_name>
		<emu_description>Nintendo GameCube</emu_description>
		<emu_category>Best of, Nintendo, 2000s, Console</emu_category>
		<emu_version>05022020</emu_version>
		<emu_date>02/26/2020</emu_date>
		<emu_author>Zach Morris</emu_author>
		<emu_visibility>visible</emu_visibility>
		<emu_homepage>https://redump.org</emu_homepage>
		<emu_baseurl>https://archive.org/download/</emu_baseurl>
		<emu_launcher>external</emu_launcher>
		<emu_default_addon>none</emu_default_addon>
		<emu_ext_launch_cmd>none</emu_ext_launch_cmd>
		<emu_downloadpath>default</emu_downloadpath>
		<emu_postdlaction>none</emu_postdlaction>
		<emu_comment>It doesn't matter that the GameCube is over 20 years old, looking back at this list of the best GameCube games fills us with nostalgia-twinkling joy. Nintendo's enigmatic fourth home console represents the beginning of Nintendo's tinkering with the quirky, but also delivered some of the purest gaming experiences of all time. While it was nowhere near as ubiquitous as Sony's PS2 or as powerful as Microsoft's Xbox, Nintendo's bizarre little box – complete with a fashionable handle and miniature discs – held its own with a unique and eclectic catalog of first and third-party titles.[CR]GameCube may not have had the most games, but it was never lacking in quality, playing host to some of the best entries in the Zelda, Metroid, and Resident Evil franchises while also bringing an array of incredible, wholly original content. Here are the 50 best GameCube games ever made.</emu_comment>
		<emu_thumb>WY6Tgv6.jpg</emu_thumb>
		<emu_banner>djVWQUj.jpg</emu_banner>
		<emu_fanart>Gq8PRDR.jpg</emu_fanart>
		<emu_logo>8dVYePN.png</emu_logo>
		<emu_trailer>nHo0anLsVP4</emu_trailer>
	</header>
  <game name="Super Smash Bros. Melee (USA) (En,Ja)">
    <description>1. Super Smash Bros Melee</description>
    <rom name="GCRedumpNKitPart2/Super%20Smash%20Bros.%20Melee%20%28USA%29%20%28En%2CJa%29.nkit.gcz" size="1213515412"/>
    <rating>4.60</rating>
    <ESRB>T - Teen</ESRB>
    <studio>Nintendo</studio>
    <releasedate>03/12/2001</releasedate>
    <year>2001</year>
    <plot>Super Smash Bros. Melee differs from traditional fighting games in that inflicting the most damage does not guarantee victory. Instead, opposing players must force their opponents beyond the boundaries of the stage. Most attacks inflict damage and can, if enough damage is dealt, knock back the enemy. Each character's health is measured by a meter that represents the damage received as a percentage. The higher the percentage value, the farther the player gets knocked back, and the easier they are to knock off the stage. Unlike other games of the same genre, in which moves are entered by button-input combinations, most moves in Super Smash Bros. Melee can be accessed via one-button presses and a joystick direction.</plot>
    <genre>Fighter</genre>
    <groups>Super Smash Brothers series,Franchise crossovers,Game feature: Free camera photo mode,Game feature: BGM / music player,Nintendo Player's Choice releases,1G1R,1G1R USA,1G1R English,1G1R Japanese</groups>
    <nplayers>1-4 Co-Op</nplayers>
    <boxart1>LyfCfMQ.jpg</boxart1>
    <boxart2>rsveevW.jpg</boxart2>
    <boxart3>bqXY4Bn.jpg</boxart3>
    <boxart4>qvcMsEz.jpg</boxart4>
    <boxart5>765sgdG.png</boxart5>
    <boxart6>A8jO05n.jpg</boxart6>
    <boxart7>8togKqO.jpg</boxart7>
    <boxart8>drZeobm.jpg</boxart8>
    <snapshot1>M2TEweO.jpg</snapshot1>
    <snapshot2>o3fKYPQ.jpg</snapshot2>
    <snapshot3>Fh2SFHI.jpg</snapshot3>
    <snapshot4>4s2YJUC.jpg</snapshot4>
    <banner1>9NUk663.jpg</banner1>
    <fanart1>d2iIaOx.jpg</fanart1>
    <fanart2>WvADy51.jpg</fanart2>
    <clearlogo1>CUuDnAq.png</clearlogo1>
    <videoid>ORQ4sWskyaM</videoid>
  </game>
  <game name="Resident Evil 4 (USA)">
    <description>2. Resident Evil 4</description>
    <rom name="GCRedumpNKitPart2/Resident%20Evil%204%20%28USA%29%20%28Disc%201%29.nkit.gcz" size="1184754207"/>
    <rom name="GCRedumpNKitPart2/Resident%20Evil%204%20%28USA%29%20%28Disc%202%29.nkit.gcz" size="1075075990"/>
    <rom name="GCRedumpNKitPart2/Resident%20Evil%204%20%28USA%29%20%28Preview%20Disc%29.nkit.gcz" size="532915970"/>
    <rating>4.84</rating>
    <ESRB>M - Mature</ESRB>
    <studio>Capcom</studio>
    <releasedate>11/01/2005</releasedate>
    <year>2005</year>
    <plot>U.S. agent Leon Kennedy has been tasked to look into the abduction of the President's daughter and his investigation has led him to a mysterious location in Europe. As Leon encounters unimaginable horrors, he must find out what is behind the terror.</plot>
    <genre>Shooter</genre>
    <groups>Biohazard / Resident Evil series,Middleware: CRI,Theme: Zombies,Gameplay feature: Quick Time Events / QTEs,Covermount: Fullgames,1G1R,1G1R USA</groups>
    <nplayers>1</nplayers>
    <boxart1>lbA6UVc.jpg</boxart1>
    <boxart2>MX7ZC5M.jpg</boxart2>
    <boxart3>Gn5B6tv.png</boxart3>
    <boxart4>9Uv12w3.jpg</boxart4>
    <boxart5>HsQIiJb.png</boxart5>
    <snapshot1>KNbJlvs.jpg</snapshot1>
    <snapshot2>9IlGpyE.jpg</snapshot2>
    <snapshot3>FGVGuZT.jpg</snapshot3>
    <snapshot4>mvw44Lk.jpg</snapshot4>
    <banner1>B6M44pH.png</banner1>
    <fanart1>qm5ZUEW.jpg</fanart1>
    <fanart2>FrT0zga.jpg</fanart2>
    <clearlogo1>5wyMxGt.png</clearlogo1>
    <videoid>-fGYWQs2WgM</videoid>
  </game>
  <game name="Legend of Zelda, The - The Wind Waker (USA)">
    <description>3. The Legend of Zelda: The Wind Waker</description>
    <rom name="GCRedumpNKitPart1/Legend%20of%20Zelda%2C%20The%20-%20The%20Wind%20Waker%20%28USA%29.nkit.gcz" size="892007107"/>
    <rating>4.68</rating>
    <ESRB>E - Everyone</ESRB>
    <studio>Nintendo</studio>
    <releasedate>24/03/2003</releasedate>
    <year>2003</year>
    <plot>The game is set on a group of islands in a vast sea--a first for the series. The player controls Link, the protagonist of the Zelda series. He struggles against his nemesis, Ganondorf, for control of a sacred relic known as the Triforce. Link spends a large portion of the game sailing, traveling between islands, and traversing through dungeons and temples to gain the power necessary to defeat Ganondorf. He also spends time trying to find his little sister.[CR]The Wind Waker follows in the footsteps of Ocarina of Time and its sequel Majora's Mask, retaining the basic gameplay and control system from the two Nintendo 64 titles. A heavy emphasis is placed on using and controlling wind with a baton called the Wind Waker, which aids sailing and floating in air. Controversial during development for its use of cel shading graphics and younger Link character, The Wind Waker received acclaim on release and is one of the Nintendo GameCube's most popular games.</plot>
    <genre>RPG</genre>
    <groups>Legend of Zelda series,Gameplay feature: Photography,Visual technique / style: Cel shaded,Games made into comics,Gameplay feature: BASE jumping,Protagonist: Elf,Gameplay feature: Day / Night cycle,Gameplay feature: New Game+,Nintendo Selects releases,Nintendo Player's Choice releases,1G1R,1G1R USA</groups>
    <nplayers>1</nplayers>
    <boxart1>CrfUSAa.jpg</boxart1>
    <boxart2>8ukv57H.jpg</boxart2>
    <boxart3>yP60zmh.jpg</boxart3>
    <boxart4>7Swq8L1.jpg</boxart4>
    <boxart5>YStW0Md.png</boxart5>
    <boxart6>5yaR93S.jpg</boxart6>
    <boxart7>P982YCI.png</boxart7>
    <boxart8>8vBxA8H.jpg</boxart8>
    <snapshot1>AHHlUJJ.png</snapshot1>
    <snapshot2>oE9vJQy.jpg</snapshot2>
    <snapshot3>0J3X1AU.jpg</snapshot3>
    <snapshot4>e0OIXuE.jpg</snapshot4>
    <banner1>GM46T1G.png</banner1>
    <fanart1>SOp4J1g.jpg</fanart1>
    <fanart2>BkNrmJo.jpg</fanart2>
    <clearlogo1>47GWeKI.png</clearlogo1>
    <videoid>ibJbjnGKvt0</videoid>
  </game>
  <game name="Metroid Prime (USA)">
    <description>4. Metroid Prime</description>
    <rom name="GCRedumpNKitPart1/Metroid%20Prime%20%28USA%29.nkit.gcz" size="1193930495"/>
    <rating>4.59</rating>
    <ESRB>T - Teen</ESRB>
    <studio>Nintendo</studio>
    <releasedate>17/11/2002</releasedate>
    <year>2002</year>
    <plot>Ten years ago, beneath the surface of Planet Zebes, the mercenaries known as "Space Pirates" were defeated by interstellar bounty hunter Samus Aran. Descending to the very core of the pirate stronghold, Samus exterminated the energy based parasites called "Metroids" and defeated Mother Brain, the leader of the pirate hoarde.[CR]But the Space Pirates were far from finished. Several pirate research vessels were orbiting Zebes when Samus fought on the surface below.[CR]After the fall of Mother Brain, the ships escaped, with the hope of finding enough resources to rebuild their forces and take their revenge.[CR]After discovering a possible pirate colony on planet Talon IV, Samus has once again prepared for war, hoping to end the Pirate threat forever.</plot>
    <genre>Shooter</genre>
    <groups>Metroid series,Metroid Prime series,Games with hidden / unlockable full games,New Play Control! series,Nintendo Player's Choice releases,1G1R,1G1R USA</groups>
    <nplayers>1</nplayers>
    <boxart1>Vonovqa.jpg</boxart1>
    <boxart2>B5J08w2.png</boxart2>
    <boxart3>hkzmLsN.jpg</boxart3>
    <boxart4>oTcxTTV.jpg</boxart4>
    <boxart5>zDOjLBG.png</boxart5>
    <boxart6>nR3OI7F.png</boxart6>
    <snapshot1>dEZWqU2.jpg</snapshot1>
    <snapshot2>LRqnIdb.jpg</snapshot2>
    <snapshot3>gUsSbNf.jpg</snapshot3>
    <snapshot4>FEFmVMS.jpg</snapshot4>
    <banner1>9H3cPQz.png</banner1>
    <fanart1>J4pedup.jpg</fanart1>
    <fanart2>JGlk5lF.jpg</fanart2>
    <clearlogo1>WyVRyAL.png</clearlogo1>
    <videoid>9HNvZuAwAEc</videoid>
  </game>
  <game name="Soulcalibur II (USA)">
    <description>5. Soul Calibur II</description>
    <rom name="GCRedumpNKitPart2/Soulcalibur%20II%20%28USA%29.nkit.gcz" size="805684155"/>
    <rating>4.53</rating>
    <ESRB>T - Teen</ESRB>
    <studio>Namco</studio>
    <releasedate>27/08/2003</releasedate>
    <year>2003</year>
    <plot>Transcending history and the world, a tale of souls and swords eternally retold. [CR]Four years have passed since the spirit sword, Soulcalibur defeated the evil Soul Edge. At the end of that fateful battle, the shards of the shattered Soul Edge were scattered across the world and Soulclibur was lost to the void. Now, the evil that still resides in the scattered shards of Soul Edge threatens again to engulf the world in darkness.[CR]Guest starring exclusively for the Nintendo Gamecube: Link from the Legend of Zelda.</plot>
    <genre>Fighter</genre>
    <groups>Soul Blade / Edge / Calibur series,PlayStation 2 Greatest Hits releases,Middleware: CRI,Nintendo Player's Choice releases,1G1R,1G1R USA</groups>
    <nplayers>2</nplayers>
    <boxart1>RXqd3Jw.png</boxart1>
    <boxart2>BJCnRw1.png</boxart2>
    <boxart3>0wdx6hM.png</boxart3>
    <boxart4>Le1QqZP.png</boxart4>
    <boxart5>wKVt05S.jpg</boxart5>
    <boxart6>v9TukCX.png</boxart6>
    <boxart7>NWLRzzh.jpg</boxart7>
    <snapshot1>zQmR40V.jpg</snapshot1>
    <snapshot2>8nUmg9u.png</snapshot2>
    <snapshot3>5smHZNn.jpg</snapshot3>
    <snapshot4>EpSxCHY.png</snapshot4>
    <banner1>Zg9IGb6.png</banner1>
    <fanart1>EuG6BSx.jpg</fanart1>
    <fanart2>yml3fhE.jpg</fanart2>
    <clearlogo1>8VYWLiL.png</clearlogo1>
    <clearlogo2>1Mss9b6.png</clearlogo2>
    <videoid>_e58pJ6t_-I</videoid>
  </game>
  <game name="Beyond Good &amp; Evil (USA) (En,Es)">
    <description>6. Beyond Good &amp; Evil</description>
    <rom name="GCRedumpNKitPart1/Beyond%20Good%20%26%20Evil%20%28USA%29%20%28En%2CEs%29.nkit.gcz" size="1187708710"/>
    <rating>4.50</rating>
    <ESRB>T - Teen</ESRB>
    <studio>Ubisoft</studio>
    <releasedate>11/11/2003</releasedate>
    <year>2003</year>
    <plot>Beyond Good and Evil takes place in the year 2435 on the mining planet of Hillys, located in Sector Four, a remote section of the galaxy. The architecture of the city around which the game takes place was designed with a rustic European style. The world itself combines modern elements, such as e-mail and credit cards, with those of science fiction and fantasy, such as spaceships and anthropomorphic animals coexisting with humans. The once-peaceful planet is under siege by aliens called the DomZ that abduct beings and either drain their life force for power or implant them with spores to convert them into slaves. A military dictatorship called the Alpha Sections takes power, promising to defend the populace. However, the Alpha Sections seem unable to stop the DomZ despite their public assurances. An underground resistance movement, the IRIS Network, fights the Alpha Sections, believing them to be in league with the DomZ.</plot>
    <genre>Adventure</genre>
    <groups>Game Engine: JADE,Gameplay feature: Photography,Protagonist: Journalist / Reporter,1G1R,1G1R USA,1G1R English</groups>
    <nplayers>1 Co-Op</nplayers>
    <boxart1>lYF8YBX.jpg</boxart1>
    <boxart2>Llm5PvM.jpg</boxart2>
    <boxart3>J3dbtr6.png</boxart3>
    <boxart4>HQQeTmU.png</boxart4>
    <snapshot1>tpEpIJj.jpg</snapshot1>
    <snapshot2>8wmfNTc.jpg</snapshot2>
    <snapshot3>hIKJZSX.jpg</snapshot3>
    <snapshot4>FrpmtGp.jpg</snapshot4>
    <banner1>HWPEP13.jpg</banner1>
    <fanart1>EvfEgAo.jpg</fanart1>
    <fanart2>ozRi6Q3.jpg</fanart2>
    <clearlogo1>TLiuKtj.png</clearlogo1>
    <videoid>Wg4CDpo0aw0</videoid>
  </game>
  <game name="Eternal Darkness - Sanity's Requiem (USA)">
    <description>7. Eternal Darkness: Sanity's Requiem</description>
    <rom name="GCRedumpNKitPart1/Eternal%20Darkness%20-%20Sanity%27s%20Requiem%20%28USA%29.nkit.gcz" size="1357608021"/>
    <rating>4.41</rating>
    <ESRB>M - Mature</ESRB>
    <studio>Nintendo</studio>
    <releasedate>24/06/2002</releasedate>
    <year>2002</year>
    <plot>Eternal Darkness: Sanity's Requiem is a psychological horror action adventure, released in 2002 by Nintendo for the Gamecube. It tells the stories of twelve characters that span across the world and two millennia who have to deal with ancient forces of evil which have been trying to manifest themselves in our world. Chapters take place in Ancient Rome, Persia, the Middle East, and modern-day Rhode Island. Throughout the game, the protagonists will have access to several weapons appropriate for their era, from bastard sword and gladius to flintlock pistol and shotgun.[CR]The game features an involved Magic system, which allows different spells to be created through the combination of runes. These spells can attack enemies, dispel illusions, and heal both the body and items.[CR]Eternal Darkness: Sanity's Requiem also has a unique feature called Sanity. If an enemy sees a character, their Sanity meter drops. When Sanity gets low, hallucinations begin to plague the character. Walls bleed, voices whisper from nowhere, the camera gets disoriented. Sanity can be restored by dealing a finishing move on a dying enemy, or with spells or some items.</plot>
    <genre>Horror</genre>
    <groups>Inspiration: Author - H. P. Lovecraft,Gameplay feature: Multiple endings,1G1R,1G1R USA</groups>
    <nplayers>1</nplayers>
    <boxart1>nLuL2uA.jpg</boxart1>
    <boxart2>XHk8DtE.jpg</boxart2>
    <boxart3>yAc55xs.png</boxart3>
    <boxart4>yx95UjZ.jpg</boxart4>
    <boxart5>c7EUvPv.jpg</boxart5>
    <boxart6>S2ZY7H6.jpg</boxart6>
    <boxart7>la1NVh2.jpg</boxart7>
    <boxart8>FghqQVy.jpg</boxart8>
    <snapshot1>VH7p6sb.jpg</snapshot1>
    <snapshot2>wj7CgTj.jpg</snapshot2>
    <snapshot3>ELoyTG3.jpg</snapshot3>
    <snapshot4>SwZh6fD.jpg</snapshot4>
    <fanart1>5CD1lPP.jpg</fanart1>
    <fanart2>ezUXl8s.jpg</fanart2>
    <clearlogo1>MZLpfI8.png</clearlogo1>
    <videoid>w5__J4JCyMg</videoid>
  </game>
  <game name="Animal Crossing (USA)">
    <description>8. Animal Crossing</description>
    <rom name="GCRedumpNKitPart1/Animal%20Crossing%20%28USA%29.nkit.gcz" size="17215303"/>
    <rating>4.28</rating>
    <ESRB>E - Everyone</ESRB>
    <studio>Nintendo</studio>
    <releasedate>15/09/2002</releasedate>
    <year>2002</year>
    <plot>Animal Crossing allows you to interact with a virtual village of animals that are doing something different every minute of every day. With Animal Crossing's 24-hour clock, the game's unique events can be in synch with real time--as day turns to night in the real world, the sun will also begin to set in the game. The dynamic setup requires you to come back every day and carry out your daily routines, build relationships with villagers, celebrate special days, collect furnishings for your homes, and just live life in the unique world of Animal Crossing.</plot>
    <genre>Sandbox</genre>
    <groups>Games made into movies,Animal Crossing series,Games with hidden / unlockable full games,Gameplay feature: Fishing,Genre: Simulation - Human life,Gameplay feature: Day / Night cycle,Gameplay feature: House ownership,Animals: Raccoons,Nintendo Player's Choice releases,Gameplay feature: Interior decorating,1G1R,1G1R USA</groups>
    <nplayers>1</nplayers>
    <boxart1>0Jf5GHZ.jpg</boxart1>
    <boxart2>aCz7wCI.jpg</boxart2>
    <boxart3>RgUs1K3.jpg</boxart3>
    <boxart4>1AJ97EW.jpg</boxart4>
    <boxart5>tLp07ug.png</boxart5>
    <boxart6>x8dEyoy.jpg</boxart6>
    <snapshot1>P8TkRay.png</snapshot1>
    <snapshot2>su2Wy5y.png</snapshot2>
    <snapshot3>mSEoGlM.jpg</snapshot3>
    <snapshot4>4csNA4L.jpg</snapshot4>
    <banner1>YDcCjjK.jpg</banner1>
    <fanart1>aWbIAiG.jpg</fanart1>
    <fanart2>Exnukno.jpg</fanart2>
    <clearlogo1>CSszHBf.jpg</clearlogo1>
  </game>
  <game name="Metroid Prime 2 - Echoes (USA)">
    <description>9. Metroid Prime 2: Echoes</description>
    <rom name="GCRedumpNKitPart1/Metroid%20Prime%202%20-%20Echoes%20%28USA%29.nkit.gcz" size="1347646297"/>
    <rating>4.58</rating>
    <ESRB>T - Teen</ESRB>
    <studio>Nintendo</studio>
    <releasedate>15/11/2004</releasedate>
    <year>2004</year>
    <plot>The sequel to Metroid Prime puts you in the role of bounty hunter Samus Aran once again. Your mission is to locate federation troopers who are missing on Aether--a planet torn into light and dark domains. To help you travel through the depths of light and dark, you'll have all-new beam weapons, a screw attack, and power-ups. Eliminate your enemies, solve puzzles, and open doors in an effort to restore peace to Aether. Metroid Prime 2: Echoes also features competitive multiplayer modes supporting up to four players.</plot>
    <genre>Shooter</genre>
    <groups>Metroid series,Metroid Prime series,New Play Control! series</groups>
    <nplayers>1</nplayers>
    <boxart1>ZKzt5Np.jpg</boxart1>
    <boxart2>LskKbEe.jpg</boxart2>
    <boxart3>weXxplo.png</boxart3>
    <boxart4>nF2Efgc.jpg</boxart4>
    <boxart5>LNdH9F5.jpg</boxart5>
    <boxart6>nUit27G.png</boxart6>
    <boxart7>portiwG.jpg</boxart7>
    <boxart8>ZpjKlVZ.png</boxart8>
    <snapshot1>6W48Von.png</snapshot1>
    <snapshot2>OVJRuGn.jpg</snapshot2>
    <snapshot3>UFI8s4W.png</snapshot3>
    <snapshot4>angPPJE.png</snapshot4>
    <fanart1>2g7UU6N.jpg</fanart1>
    <fanart2>xyt4983.jpg</fanart2>
    <clearlogo1>LDh17sZ.png</clearlogo1>
    <videoid>Gbl91ADbM9c</videoid>
  </game>
  <game name="Pikmin 2 (USA)">
    <description>10. Pikmin 2</description>
    <rom name="GCRedumpNKitPart2/Pikmin%202%20%28USA%29.nkit.gcz" size="956145183"/>
    <rating>4.40</rating>
    <ESRB>E - Everyone</ESRB>
    <studio>Nintendo</studio>
    <releasedate>30/08/2004</releasedate>
    <year>2004</year>
    <plot>Captain Olimar has returned to the planet where the Pikmin live, and he's all business this time. The company he works for is going bankrupt, so to save it, Olimar must salvage the treasure buried all over the planet. Of course, he'll need the help of the Pikmin to do that--he can't do anything by himself. Control one of two main characters--Olimar or his assistant--as you command your Pikmin to defeat enemies, propagate more Pikmin, collect precious doodads, and solve puzzles. With unlimited time, new colors of Pikmin, and two-player cooperative play, Pikmin 2 improves on the original in many ways.</plot>
    <genre>Strategy</genre>
    <groups>Pikmin series,New Play Control! series,Nintendo Selects releases,1G1R,1G1R USA</groups>
    <nplayers>2</nplayers>
    <boxart1>QxQTPVM.jpg</boxart1>
    <boxart2>qTyVb9W.jpg</boxart2>
    <boxart3>wnvMh86.png</boxart3>
    <boxart4>M22JQ8G.jpg</boxart4>
    <boxart5>vPLQTX9.png</boxart5>
    <boxart6>GsXlNRL.jpg</boxart6>
    <snapshot1>C7jPEH1.jpg</snapshot1>
    <snapshot2>FIHJLo5.jpg</snapshot2>
    <snapshot3>bvxL3GN.png</snapshot3>
    <snapshot4>SdMC5Y4.png</snapshot4>
    <banner1>BuGqjU6.jpg</banner1>
    <fanart1>8DtFYrX.jpg</fanart1>
    <fanart2>5deTRao.jpg</fanart2>
    <clearlogo1>uSXyPlI.jpg</clearlogo1>
    <videoid>cteEOv7pmHI</videoid>
  </game>
  <game name="Viewtiful Joe (USA)">
    <description>11. Viewtiful Joe</description>
    <rom name="GCRedumpNKitPart2/Viewtiful%20Joe%20%28USA%29.nkit.gcz" size="974295020"/>
    <rating>4.47</rating>
    <ESRB>T - Teen</ESRB>
    <studio>Capcom</studio>
    <releasedate>07/10/2003</releasedate>
    <year>2003</year>
    <plot>Joe is no ordinary man and Viewtiful Joe is no ordinary game. Capcom's new superhero action game mixes funky cartoon-style visuals with classic side-scrolling gameplay and introduces the world's quirkiest million dollar action hero. More than just any ordinary dude, Joe must transform into the ultimate superhero. It's up to you to activate the correct view mode like "slow" or "zoom in" in order to clobber your enemies with beautiful style. You can also speed up or slow down your visual effects for even more "viewtiful" moves. Viewtiful Joe mixes an innovative viewpoint with an amazing stunt-filled action movie universe.</plot>
    <genre>Fighter</genre>
    <groups>Viewtiful Joe series,Visual technique / style: Cel shaded,Games made into TV series,Nintendo Player's Choice releases,1G1R,1G1R USA</groups>
    <nplayers>1</nplayers>
    <boxart1>9sJfsSk.jpg</boxart1>
    <boxart2>3Avmg30.jpg</boxart2>
    <boxart3>3kRVX6n.jpg</boxart3>
    <boxart4>kkMGKJh.jpg</boxart4>
    <boxart5>nJjk9fi.png</boxart5>
    <boxart6>8JdMo2W.jpg</boxart6>
    <boxart7>RjbHfUM.jpg</boxart7>
    <boxart8>BqACErD.jpg</boxart8>
    <snapshot1>IbfcrhD.png</snapshot1>
    <snapshot2>ZR0mznO.png</snapshot2>
    <snapshot3>VeVZEAT.png</snapshot3>
    <snapshot4>QABviOv.png</snapshot4>
    <fanart1>14Wcjps.jpg</fanart1>
    <fanart2>dO3d4Wf.jpg</fanart2>
    <clearlogo1>potZs9a.png</clearlogo1>
    <clearlogo2>5AWTJmZ.png</clearlogo2>
    <videoid>QPjyOkt0JUk</videoid>
  </game>
  <game name="Super Mario Sunshine (USA)">
    <description>12. Super Mario Sunshine</description>
    <rom name="GCRedumpNKitPart2/Super%20Mario%20Sunshine%20%28USA%29.nkit.gcz" size="1132371027"/>
    <rating>4.40</rating>
    <ESRB>E - Everyone</ESRB>
    <studio>Nintendo</studio>
    <releasedate>26/08/2002</releasedate>
    <year>2002</year>
    <plot>When Mario arrives on tropical Isle Delfino, the once-pristine island is polluted and plastered with graffiti. Even worse, he's being blamed for the mess! Now instead of enjoying a relaxing vacation, Mario has to clean up the place and track down the real culprit.</plot>
    <genre>Platform</genre>
    <groups>Mario games,Gameplay feature: Jetpack,Super Mario series,Nintendo Player's Choice releases,1G1R,1G1R USA</groups>
    <nplayers>1</nplayers>
    <boxart1>0UcJthJ.jpg</boxart1>
    <boxart2>Cr1ohzx.jpg</boxart2>
    <boxart3>kstrcng.jpg</boxart3>
    <boxart4>ZZ16Ohm.jpg</boxart4>
    <boxart5>aUNTOLh.jpg</boxart5>
    <boxart6>fB1GQT2.jpg</boxart6>
    <boxart7>aQwmhE2.png</boxart7>
    <boxart8>bh9bwYL.jpg</boxart8>
    <snapshot1>OdF4WIu.png</snapshot1>
    <snapshot2>kdxmzmr.png</snapshot2>
    <snapshot3>yfYGufQ.jpg</snapshot3>
    <snapshot4>lxRVcw4.jpg</snapshot4>
    <snapshot5>YKaaZve.jpg</snapshot5>
    <banner1>3pTfew2.jpg</banner1>
    <fanart1>5L5bVzy.jpg</fanart1>
    <fanart2>vmcBoJp.jpg</fanart2>
    <clearlogo1>6fRnoTT.jpg</clearlogo1>
    <videoid>C5mcz3RfwMA</videoid>
  </game>
  <game name="Prince of Persia - The Sands of Time (USA) (En,Fr,Es)">
    <description>13. Prince of Persia: Sands of Time</description>
    <rom name="GCRedumpNKitPart2/Prince%20of%20Persia%20-%20The%20Sands%20of%20Time%20%28USA%29%20%28En%2CFr%2CEs%29.nkit.gcz" size="1315534522"/>
    <rating>4.75</rating>
    <ESRB>T - Teen</ESRB>
    <studio>Ubisoft</studio>
    <releasedate>12/11/2003</releasedate>
    <year>2003</year>
    <plot>Prince of Persia: The Sands of Time is a 3D platformer which focuses on acrobatics and agility. Throughout much of the game, the player must attempt to traverse the palace by running across walls, ascending or descending chasms by jumping back and forth between walls, avoiding traps, climbing structures and jumping from platform to platform, making other types of well-timed leaps, solving puzzles, and using discovered objects to progress.</plot>
    <genre>Adventure</genre>
    <groups>Prince of Persia series,Setting: Middle East,PlayStation 2 Greatest Hits releases,Games made into movies,Game Engine: JADE,Theme: Time Travel,Games with hidden / unlockable full games,Covermount: Fullgames,PlayStation 2 Platinum Range releases,Gameplay feature: Time manipulation,Covermount: Level (Romania),1G1R,1G1R USA,1G1R English</groups>
    <nplayers>1</nplayers>
    <boxart1>S5cMbVR.jpg</boxart1>
    <boxart2>pNY4iLy.jpg</boxart2>
    <boxart3>D22O3Hd.png</boxart3>
    <boxart4>bLh5fY0.png</boxart4>
    <snapshot1>0sCfDDm.png</snapshot1>
    <snapshot2>bX3Yexf.png</snapshot2>
    <snapshot3>ZreZVi7.png</snapshot3>
    <snapshot4>N90LNMO.png</snapshot4>
    <fanart1>KWSB7Wi.jpg</fanart1>
    <fanart2>G5oY65d.jpg</fanart2>
    <clearlogo1>LEzwGVg.png</clearlogo1>
  </game>
  <game name="SSX 3 (USA)">
    <description>14. SSX 3</description>
    <rom name="GCRedumpNKitPart2/SSX%203%20%28USA%29.nkit.gcz" size="1081662948"/>
    <rating>3.9</rating>
    <ESRB>E - Everyone</ESRB>
    <studio>EA</studio>
    <releasedate>20/10/2003</releasedate>
    <year>2003</year>
    <plot>Players can discover the open mountain in the newest version of the smash-hit SSX snowboarding franchise.[CR]SSX 3 allows gamers to go anywhere gravity will take them. Players will discover a colossal mountain where they can immerse themselves in a free-roaming snow paradise. The ultimate all-mountain experience, SSX 3 features all-new events and courses, awe-inspiring tricks and a cast of cool, customisable characters. Discover the open terrain, explore its hidden crevices, and conquer its peaks.[CR]Produced under the EA SPORTS BIG brand, the SSX 3 development team at EA Canada is adding technologies that bring to life rich natural graphics such as snow that sparkles and blows in the wind and realistic character shadowing. A new gameplay experience allows users to seamlessly ride from one awesome area to the next- entering competitions, taking on Big Challenges and discovering hidden collectibles. SSX 3 has blown out the trick component with unlimited combos and new, over-the-top tricks.[CR]In addition to the new boarding venues, Big Challenges rewards players for completing any of the more than 100 unique challenges as they explore the mountain's vast world. Grind billboards, board press logs, even hand plant the fence line.[CR]The musical soundtrack features a broad range of music from artists including the X-Ecutioners, Felix Da Housecat, Queens of the Stone Age, N.E.R.D., and many more.</plot>
    <genre>Sports</genre>
    <groups>SSX series,EA Sports BIG games,PlayStation 2 Greatest Hits releases,PlayStation 2 Platinum Range releases,1G1R,1G1R USA</groups>
    <nplayers>2</nplayers>
    <boxart1>SVA3o5h.jpg</boxart1>
    <boxart2>9w5Fwdm.jpg</boxart2>
    <boxart3>iL4wtHt.png</boxart3>
    <boxart4>gG7Vjou.jpg</boxart4>
    <snapshot1>KRPz7LF.png</snapshot1>
    <snapshot2>lIDTffo.png</snapshot2>
    <snapshot3>VynDLV1.png</snapshot3>
    <snapshot4>e8h5d8Q.png</snapshot4>
    <banner1>xwYIELL.jpg</banner1>
    <fanart1>pC1DN6j.jpg</fanart1>
    <fanart2>zuhHnmd.jpg</fanart2>
    <clearlogo1>ndqs7K5.png</clearlogo1>
    <clearlogo2>k00Txve.png</clearlogo2>
    <videoid>TWFQqYZMvSc</videoid>
  </game>
  <game name="Paper Mario - The Thousand-Year Door (USA)">
    <description>15. Paper Mario: The Thousand-Year Door</description>
    <rom name="GCRedumpNKitPart2/Paper%20Mario%20-%20The%20Thousand-Year%20Door%20%28USA%29.nkit.gcz" size="349005659"/>
    <rating>4.69</rating>
    <ESRB>E - Everyone</ESRB>
    <studio>Nintendo</studio>
    <releasedate>11/10/2004</releasedate>
    <year>2004</year>
    <plot>What sleeps behind the door? Time passes, pages turn... and a new chapter unfolds in an unfamiliar land! Get ready for a two-dimensional role-playing adventure for the ages as Mario returns to paper form to discover a mystery that sleeps behind an ancient, legendary portal called The Thousand-Year Door. The quest is long, the dangers many, and this time, Mario will have to make full use of his papery qualities just to survive!</plot>
    <genre>RPG</genre>
    <groups>Mario games,Mario RPG series,Paper Mario series,1G1R,1G1R USA</groups>
    <nplayers>1</nplayers>
    <boxart1>JTScGoi.jpg</boxart1>
    <boxart2>8ckSe1r.jpg</boxart2>
    <boxart3>PllYhc4.png</boxart3>
    <boxart4>Mh4uFQW.png</boxart4>
    <boxart5>17gAeX5.jpg</boxart5>
    <boxart6>FrCx1Fg.png</boxart6>
    <boxart7>pvQnu2P.jpg</boxart7>
    <snapshot1>NuOCQD1.png</snapshot1>
    <snapshot2>FMNLWsz.png</snapshot2>
    <snapshot3>JawidRc.jpg</snapshot3>
    <snapshot4>IXY8AdE.jpg</snapshot4>
    <fanart1>xuZ1uDw.jpg</fanart1>
    <fanart2>0p9VeUS.jpg</fanart2>
    <clearlogo1>ks7AlNU.jpg</clearlogo1>
    <videoid>xKwpAeCyW0I</videoid>
  </game>
  <game name="Resident Evil (USA)">
    <description>16. Resident Evil</description>
    <rom name="GCRedumpNKitPart2/Resident%20Evil%20%28USA%29%20%28Disc%201%29.nkit.gcz" size="955611291"/>
    <rom name="GCRedumpNKitPart2/Resident%20Evil%20%28USA%29%20%28Disc%202%29.nkit.gcz" size="1113478724"/>
    <rating>5.00</rating>
    <ESRB>M - Mature</ESRB>
    <studio>CAPCOM</studio>
    <releasedate>20/01/2015</releasedate>
    <year>2015</year>
    <plot>Special forces S.T.A.R.S. Bravo team's helicopter malfunctioned and crashed during their mission, disappearing into the Arklay Mountains. This and what happens to them is told in the story of Resident Evil Zero. Now, S.T.A.R.S. Alpha team is sent on a mission to investigate a series of murders around Raccoon Forest. Spotting the Bravo team's helicopter, or what's left of it, they land nearby and investigate the surrounding area. Unaware of what they might expect, one member is attacked and devoured by zombified dobermans. The rest of the team, with a little bit of luck, find shelter in a nearby mansion, not knowing it was probably better to stay out.[CR]You play the entire game with one of the two selectable characters, Chris Redfield, or Jill Valentine. The starting point is the lobby of the mansion the three surviving S.T.A.R.S. members just stepped in. After a short while, the team decides to split and search for any possible survivors or anything useful that may help them break out of this dreadful place. To their amazement, they encountered an enemy they never were trained to confront, zombies. There is only one mission to be considered now: survival.[CR]The GameCube and the later Wii versions are largely a remake of the original Resident Evil for the PlayStation, with some additions. While the floorplan of the returning locations is almost entirely unchanged, several new areas have been added in, extending your stay in the mansion. A new enemy, Lisa, has been added to the game, making your trips outside of the mansion much more dangerous. Finally killing a zombie is now no longer good enough to put them to rest. They must be destroyed totally with fire or else they will rise again; faster, deadlier, and madder than before.[CR]The 2015 PS3, PS4, Xbox 360, Xbox One and Windows version called Resident Evil (also known as Biohazard: HD Remaster) is a remastered version of GameCube remake of the original Resident Evil with enhanced graphics and sounds, widescreen support and an alternative control scheme next to the default one. Additionally, when starting a new game, the player can choose between original character models, or Chris and Jill models from Resident Evil 5 which came after the original GameCube release.</plot>
    <genre>Horror</genre>
    <groups>Biohazard / Resident Evil series,Games made into movies,Games made into books,HUDless games,Theme: Zombies,Games made into comics,Video games turned into board / card games,Live action cut-scenes,PlayStation Platinum Range releases,1G1R,1G1R USA</groups>
    <nplayers>1</nplayers>
    <boxart1>yut01n2.png</boxart1>
    <boxart2>0xF2iGr.jpg</boxart2>
    <snapshot1>exJHGUe.png</snapshot1>
    <snapshot2>3RzgEq4.png</snapshot2>
    <snapshot3>2iQFDDb.jpg</snapshot3>
    <snapshot4>tYG8uTY.jpg</snapshot4>
    <fanart1>rapsnwd.jpg</fanart1>
    <fanart2>6OyMWoh.jpg</fanart2>
    <clearlogo1>AwqGTt7.png</clearlogo1>
  </game>
  <game name="Star Wars - Rogue Squadron II - Rogue Leader (USA)">
    <description>17. Star Wars Rogue Leader: Rogue Squadron II</description>
    <rom name="GCRedumpNKitPart2/Star%20Wars%20-%20Rogue%20Squadron%20II%20-%20Rogue%20Leader%20%28USA%29.nkit.gcz" size="1356446715"/>
    <rating>4.49</rating>
    <ESRB>T - Teen</ESRB>
    <studio>LucasArts</studio>
    <releasedate>18/11/2001</releasedate>
    <year>2001</year>
    <plot>Think you've got what it takes to lead the elite Rogue Squadron? Now's your chance to jump into the cockpit of an X-wing and find out. Join Luke Skywalker and the Star Wars galaxy's most daring pilots as they return to face off against the Empire. As in the original hit game for N64, you'll relive favorite Star Wars battles including the perilous Death Star trench run, a daring space attack on a Star Destroyer, and the legendary battle on the ice planet Hoth. Aerial conflict takes place in a variety of craft such as the legendary X-wing, A-wing, and B-wing. Rogue Leader immerses players in an intense action arcade experience.</plot>
    <genre>Shooter</genre>
    <groups>Star Wars licensees,Star Wars: Rogue Squadron series,Nintendo Player's Choice releases,1G1R,1G1R USA</groups>
    <nplayers>1</nplayers>
    <boxart1>KrGipte.jpg</boxart1>
    <boxart2>QLD9qRR.png</boxart2>
    <boxart3>BAIUdFj.jpg</boxart3>
    <boxart4>WXv7EFe.png</boxart4>
    <boxart5>YNjxI8z.jpg</boxart5>
    <boxart6>3PEPlDW.png</boxart6>
    <boxart7>rBqC4SX.png</boxart7>
    <snapshot1>Hmf7T3R.jpg</snapshot1>
    <snapshot2>3cHPDO8.jpg</snapshot2>
    <snapshot3>NeaEauW.jpg</snapshot3>
    <snapshot4>vMraFOH.jpg</snapshot4>
    <fanart1>RkaqSXC.jpg</fanart1>
    <fanart2>rS7lx4p.jpg</fanart2>
    <clearlogo1>igGs3p0.png</clearlogo1>
    <videoid>lQiAEeFwXac</videoid>
  </game>
  <game name="Mario Kart - Double Dash!! (USA)">
    <description>18. Mario Kart: Double Dash</description>
    <rom name="GCRedumpNKitPart1/Mario%20Kart%20-%20Double%20Dash%21%21%20%28USA%29.nkit.gcz" size="405570763"/>
    <rating>4.63</rating>
    <ESRB>E - Everyone</ESRB>
    <studio>Nintendo</studio>
    <releasedate>17/11/2003</releasedate>
    <year>2003</year>
    <plot>The Mushroom Kingdom just got a whole lot more hectic as Mario and friends double up for furious kart racing. This time around, each kart holds two racers that can switch places at any time, so choose from a huge cast of favorites and pair them up any way you see fit. The character in front handles the driving duties, while the character in the rear doles out damage with six normal items and eight special items that only specific characters can use. Get ready for some intense multiplayer mayhem with your favorite characters, including Mario, Luigi, Donkey Kong, Peach, Bowser, and Koopa.</plot>
    <genre>Racing</genre>
    <groups>Mario games,Mario Kart series,Genre: Kart racing</groups>
    <nplayers>10+ Co-Op</nplayers>
    <boxart1>7PEaf47.jpg</boxart1>
    <boxart2>VOTykFh.jpg</boxart2>
    <boxart3>b11A11K.png</boxart3>
    <boxart4>RXfEAj4.jpg</boxart4>
    <boxart5>n3OAXTU.png</boxart5>
    <boxart6>uHuTp4V.png</boxart6>
    <snapshot1>rpR0ZlL.jpg</snapshot1>
    <snapshot2>u9h3EuH.jpg</snapshot2>
    <snapshot3>ieLi6Nr.png</snapshot3>
    <snapshot4>CNekuju.png</snapshot4>
    <banner1>5YNcjU3.jpg</banner1>
    <fanart1>ZT6hYes.jpg</fanart1>
    <fanart2>d3dvHBe.jpg</fanart2>
    <clearlogo1>7ytJqwY.png</clearlogo1>
    <videoid>5BCMrPn6H3Y</videoid>
  </game>
  <game name="Ikaruga (USA)">
    <description>19. Ikaruga</description>
    <rom name="GCRedumpNKitPart1/Ikaruga%20%28USA%29.nkit.gcz" size="145720259"/>
    <rating>4.07</rating>
    <ESRB>E - Everyone</ESRB>
    <studio>Infogrames</studio>
    <releasedate>05/09/2002</releasedate>
    <year>2001</year>
    <plot>Several years ago in the small island nation of Horai, the leader of the nation, Tenro Horai, discovered the Ubusunagami Okinokai--the Power of the Gods. This energy emanated from an object she dug up from deep underground and granted her unimaginable powers. Soon after, Tenro and her followers, who called themselves "The Divine Ones", began conquering nations one after another. "The Chosen People" carried out these conquests in "the name of peace".[CR]Meanwhile, a freedom federation called Tenkaku emerged to challenge Horai. Using fighter planes called Hitekkai, they fought with the hope of freeing the world from the grips of the Horai - but all their efforts were in vain. They were no match for the Horai and were eventually almost completely wiped out. Miraculously, however, one young man survived. His name was Shinra (Sen Luo ?).[CR]Shot down near a remote village called Ikaruga, inhabited by elderly people who had been exiled by the Horai's conquests, Shinra was dragged from the wreckage and nursed back to health. Shinra regained his health and pledged to defeat the Horai, and the villagers entrusted him with a fighter plane that they had built themselves, called the Ikaruga.[CR]The Ikaruga was no ordinary plane, designed by former engineering genius Amanai (Tian Nei ?) with the help of Kazamori (Feng Shou ?) and the village leaders. Hidden in a secret underground bunker and launched via the transportation device called the "Sword of Acala", it is the first fighter built that integrates both energy polarities, and is capable of successfully switching between the two.</plot>
    <genre>Shooter</genre>
    <groups>Genre: Scrolling shoot 'em up,Steam Greenlight games,Genre: Bullet hell / Danmaku,1G1R,1G1R USA</groups>
    <nplayers>1-2</nplayers>
    <boxart1>FOxS425.jpg</boxart1>
    <boxart2>wHLAJVP.jpg</boxart2>
    <snapshot1>RHElILK.png</snapshot1>
    <snapshot2>evHzuWs.png</snapshot2>
    <snapshot3>5iJLuqr.png</snapshot3>
    <snapshot4>ltVzcjz.png</snapshot4>
    <fanart1>PF3DbBZ.jpg</fanart1>
    <fanart2>QA0y0ip.jpg</fanart2>
  </game>
  <game name="Tales of Symphonia (USA)">
    <description>20. Tales of Symphonia</description>
    <rom name="GCRedumpNKitPart2/Tales%20of%20Symphonia%20%28USA%29%20%28Disc%201%29.nkit.gcz" size="1076735452"/>
    <rom name="GCRedumpNKitPart2/Tales%20of%20Symphonia%20%28USA%29%20%28Disc%202%29.nkit.gcz" size="1095105496"/>
    <rating>4.30</rating>
    <ESRB>T - Teen</ESRB>
    <studio>Namco</studio>
    <releasedate>13/07/2004</releasedate>
    <year>2004</year>
    <plot>Two worlds exist, unaware of each other. Mana, or life force, is shared by both worlds and while one world thrives, the other suffers.[CR]Lloyd Irving lives on Sylvarant, a dying world where nothing is as it seems - a fact he hasn't yet realized. With a strong set of justice, incredible bravery, and a particular loyalty to his friends, he joins them in a very important quest: a journey to save their world.[CR]Lloyd's close friend, Colette Brunel, is the Chosen One, destined to save the dying world as a descendant of the Mana bloodline. At the age of 16, the weight of the world hangs on her shoulders.[CR]Genis Sage, the village intellectual, is a talented magician with a personality to die - or kill - for. Most likely, you'll grow to love him.[CR]Together, they set on this dangerous journey together - to unlock the seals of the world and bring the balance back to their dying town on Sylvarant.</plot>
    <genre>RPG</genre>
    <groups>Tales series,Middleware: CRI,Visual technique / style: Cel shaded,Gameplay feature: Quick Time Events / QTEs,Nintendo Player's Choice releases,1G1R,1G1R USA</groups>
    <nplayers>1-4 Co-Op</nplayers>
    <boxart1>gnmAlgp.jpg</boxart1>
    <boxart2>BpKMVDW.png</boxart2>
    <boxart3>xFbgdcB.jpg</boxart3>
    <boxart4>ONT6Mdl.png</boxart4>
    <snapshot1>LhqoVT4.jpg</snapshot1>
    <snapshot2>ACcArzf.jpg</snapshot2>
    <snapshot3>0LLkSIa.jpg</snapshot3>
    <snapshot4>BxobQlY.jpg</snapshot4>
    <banner1>QBFg6Fr.jpg</banner1>
    <fanart1>PUQBeub.jpg</fanart1>
    <fanart2>f6h6rqH.jpg</fanart2>
    <clearlogo1>N07rvbY.jpg</clearlogo1>
    <videoid>bGEjk62db3c</videoid>
  </game>
  <game name="Tiger Woods PGA Tour 2003 (USA)">
    <description>21. Tiger Woods PGA Tour 2003</description>
    <rom name="GCRedumpNKitPart2/Tiger%20Woods%20PGA%20Tour%202003%20%28USA%29.nkit.gcz" size="1117286261"/>
    <rating>3.7</rating>
    <ESRB>E - Everyone</ESRB>
    <studio>Electronic Arts</studio>
    <releasedate>01/11/2002</releasedate>
    <year>2002</year>
    <plot>Tiger Woods PGA Tour 2003 is the fourth edition in the best-selling golf series.[CR]TG contains over ten PGA tour pros, twelve original golfers, nine PGA Tour golf courses and three fantasy courses, which are completely original.[CR]There are ten different game modes to play, from a stroke game to the actual PGA Tour. You can also go against three other friends in multiplayer.[CR]In the SkillZone area, there are six different mini-games you can attempt, which is purely for fun. Do them yourself or go up against a friend.[CR]The game features a worldwide leaderboard, which tracks stats from you and everybody else who plays the game. Using XBox Live, you can upload your stats and compare them with other players. This feature will last until January 1, 2004.</plot>
    <genre>Sports</genre>
    <groups>Electronic Arts PGA Tour Golf series,Tiger Woods PGA series,EA Sports games,PGA licensees,Licensed title: Athletes,1G1R,1G1R USA</groups>
    <nplayers>1-2 Co-Op</nplayers>
    <boxart1>EdJiARe.png</boxart1>
    <boxart2>LZCKzFK.png</boxart2>
    <boxart3>tovnVR7.png</boxart3>
    <snapshot1>xYuI1yC.jpg</snapshot1>
    <snapshot2>jkST4Q4.jpg</snapshot2>
    <snapshot3>fgpww28.jpg</snapshot3>
    <snapshot4>GyARTbU.jpg</snapshot4>
    <clearlogo1>5g5FyBv.png</clearlogo1>
  </game>
  <game name="Super Monkey Ball (USA)">
    <description>22. Super Monkey Ball</description>
    <rom name="GCRedumpNKitPart2/Super%20Monkey%20Ball%20%28USA%29.nkit.gcz" size="311786508"/>
    <rating>4.40</rating>
    <ESRB>E - Everyone</ESRB>
    <studio>Sega</studio>
    <releasedate>18/11/2001</releasedate>
    <year>2001</year>
    <plot>Super Monkey Ball does exactly what it says on the box: it features a monkey, in a ball, and it is absolutely super. This rather odd game is similar to the classic Marble Madness, except that instead of controlling a marble through a maze-like course you control the course and must tilt and rotate it to get the cheeky little simian to the exit.</plot>
    <genre>Puzzle</genre>
    <groups>Super Monkey Ball series,Animals: Primates (monkeys or apes) ,Genre: Rolling ball,Nintendo Player's Choice releases,Launch title: GameCube (Japan),1G1R,1G1R USA</groups>
    <nplayers>1-4</nplayers>
    <boxart1>29jvMtt.jpg</boxart1>
    <boxart2>yEN05qx.jpg</boxart2>
    <boxart3>mh1esMV.jpg</boxart3>
    <boxart4>5PhHWIw.png</boxart4>
    <boxart5>qqdMn86.png</boxart5>
    <snapshot1>pjjGzuJ.png</snapshot1>
    <snapshot2>N60siR4.jpg</snapshot2>
    <snapshot3>TSkcymt.jpg</snapshot3>
    <snapshot4>gjJcb5G.jpg</snapshot4>
    <banner1>vyTrXNq.jpg</banner1>
    <fanart1>uHFNElM.jpg</fanart1>
    <fanart2>XKjhEhX.jpg</fanart2>
    <clearlogo1>xUVotf0.png</clearlogo1>
    <videoid>5XFUORPA-Q0</videoid>
  </game>
  <game name="Fire Emblem - Path of Radiance (USA)">
    <description>23. Fire Emblem: Path of Radiance</description>
    <rom name="GCRedumpNKitPart1/Fire%20Emblem%20-%20Path%20of%20Radiance%20%28USA%29.nkit.gcz" size="1165229813"/>
    <rating>4.52</rating>
    <ESRB>T - Teen</ESRB>
    <studio>Nintendo</studio>
    <releasedate>17/10/2005</releasedate>
    <year>2005</year>
    <plot>Fire Emblem: Path of Radiance brings back to consoles the strategic combat series Fire Emblem from the Game Boy Advance. In this installment, you can control units such as knights, mages, and winged creatures, and use their unique fighting styles to win battles and gain experience. Fire Emblem: Path of Radiance also includes a detailed story that connects the battles and characters together.</plot>
    <genre>Strategy</genre>
    <groups>Fire Emblem series,Visual technique / style: Cel shaded,Gameplay feature: Armour / weapon deterioration,1G1R,1G1R USA</groups>
    <nplayers>1</nplayers>
    <boxart1>F5yBB5t.jpg</boxart1>
    <boxart2>VTzrAnq.png</boxart2>
    <boxart3>hPvhtOR.png</boxart3>
    <boxart4>oK5BXn7.jpg</boxart4>
    <boxart5>8zbmKEh.png</boxart5>
    <boxart6>NJS6q73.jpg</boxart6>
    <snapshot1>o8CorAQ.png</snapshot1>
    <snapshot2>l313bDz.jpg</snapshot2>
    <snapshot3>2Tr9dkn.jpg</snapshot3>
    <snapshot4>sJ06ybw.jpg</snapshot4>
    <fanart1>aVsqj7u.jpg</fanart1>
    <fanart2>33Zlv5D.jpg</fanart2>
    <clearlogo1>Gruke6w.jpg</clearlogo1>
    <clearlogo2>4K1qhwk.png</clearlogo2>
    <videoid>pSyqra_fm_Q</videoid>
  </game>
  <game name="Skies of Arcadia Legends (USA)">
    <description>24. Skies of Arcadia: Legends</description>
    <rom name="GCRedumpNKitPart2/Skies%20of%20Arcadia%20Legends%20%28USA%29.nkit.gcz" size="1318465575"/>
    <rating>4.62</rating>
    <ESRB>T - Teen</ESRB>
    <studio>Sega</studio>
    <releasedate>29/01/2003</releasedate>
    <year>2003</year>
    <plot>Grasp the wheel of your air-ship and prepare to embark on a legendary adventure. You are Vyse, a young member of the Blue Rogue pirates. Together with your childhood friend Aika and Fina, a mysterious girl, you are locked in an epic struggle with a powerful enemy nation for the fate of the world. You must gather your own crew of air pirates and journey through uncharted skies to vanquish the empire from every corner of the map. Along the way, you'll wage battles against savage monsters and evil pirates as you make a name for yourself on land and in the sky.</plot>
    <genre>RPG</genre>
    <groups>Enhanced remakes,Skies of Arcadia series,1G1R,1G1R USA</groups>
    <nplayers>1</nplayers>
    <boxart1>XYGmrRp.jpg</boxart1>
    <boxart2>Y9kH3bk.png</boxart2>
    <boxart3>WpeRuFn.jpg</boxart3>
    <boxart4>HGHfOak.png</boxart4>
    <boxart5>EFVE39r.jpg</boxart5>
    <boxart6>RMTKd27.png</boxart6>
    <boxart7>Ood9vrf.png</boxart7>
    <snapshot1>85cKiil.jpg</snapshot1>
    <snapshot2>rAzQSmH.jpg</snapshot2>
    <snapshot3>koDgVeY.jpg</snapshot3>
    <snapshot4>yIFOlyX.jpg</snapshot4>
    <fanart1>3hts0Vh.jpg</fanart1>
    <fanart2>RdgmCHc.jpg</fanart2>
    <clearlogo1>d1mbAfB.png</clearlogo1>
    <videoid>FbftmaTnJp0</videoid>
  </game>
  <game name="F-Zero GX (USA)">
    <description>25. F-Zero GX</description>
    <rom name="GCRedumpNKitPart1/F-Zero%20GX%20%28USA%29.nkit.gcz" size="1311839585"/>
    <rating>4.49</rating>
    <ESRB>T - Teen</ESRB>
    <studio>Nintendo</studio>
    <releasedate>26/08/2003</releasedate>
    <year>2003</year>
    <plot>F-Zero GX is the fifth released installment in the F-Zero series and the successor to F-Zero X. The game continues the series' difficult, high-speed racing style, retaining the basic gameplay and control system from the Nintendo 64 game.[CR]A heavy emphasis is placed on track memorization and reflexes, which aids in completing the game. GX introduces a "story mode" element, where the player assumes the role of Captain Falcon through nine chapters while completing various missions.</plot>
    <genre>Racing</genre>
    <groups>F-Zero series,Middleware: CRI,Gameplay feature: Recordable replays,Nintendo Player's Choice releases,1G1R,1G1R USA</groups>
    <nplayers>1-4</nplayers>
    <boxart1>WTrzSkh.jpg</boxart1>
    <boxart2>JIIaZZK.jpg</boxart2>
    <boxart3>L0526MR.png</boxart3>
    <boxart4>CtRTGUr.jpg</boxart4>
    <boxart5>EKhSe0b.png</boxart5>
    <boxart6>4y8oIcS.jpg</boxart6>
    <snapshot1>eZxfFV9.jpg</snapshot1>
    <snapshot2>38usI9h.jpg</snapshot2>
    <snapshot3>3G9tPdG.jpg</snapshot3>
    <snapshot4>hWKnAjG.jpg</snapshot4>
    <banner1>R5l1Xbs.jpg</banner1>
    <fanart1>yYcmWTo.jpg</fanart1>
    <fanart2>olxfho9.jpg</fanart2>
    <clearlogo1>4mg9GTw.png</clearlogo1>
    <videoid>GQ1FLPBw1FE</videoid>
  </game>
  <game name="Baten Kaitos - Eternal Wings and the Lost Ocean (USA)">
    <description>26. Baten Kaitos</description>
    <rom name="GCRedumpNKitPart1/Baten%20Kaitos%20-%20Eternal%20Wings%20and%20the%20Lost%20Ocean%20%28USA%29%20%28Disc%201%29.nkit.gcz" size="1372480202"/>
    <rom name="GCRedumpNKitPart1/Baten%20Kaitos%20-%20Eternal%20Wings%20and%20the%20Lost%20Ocean%20%28USA%29%20%28Disc%202%29.nkit.gcz" size="1261782648"/>
    <rating>3.89</rating>
    <ESRB>T - Teen</ESRB>
    <studio>Namco</studio>
    <releasedate>16/11/2004</releasedate>
    <year>2004</year>
    <plot>The existence of Earth, a planet of continents surrounded by deep oceans, has long become a mere legend. People live now on islands which are floating high in the skies. They also have wings - "Wings of the Hearts" - growing on their backs. Kalas is a young man who was born only with one wing - he replaces the second with an artificial wing manufactured by great masters. He is on a quest to find the murderers of his grandfather and his brother. He meets a girl named Xelha, who is out to stop an evil conspiracy that threatens the country, and they join forces against the newly appeared evil.[CR]In this game, you don't only control Kalas and his party, but also play the role of Kalas' Guardian Spirit. From time to time Kalas will pose questions to you and ask for advise. Your answers will determine Kalas' general disposition and also his behavior in battles.</plot>
    <genre>RPG</genre>
    <groups>Baten Kaitos series,Theme: Amnesia,1G1R,1G1R USA</groups>
    <nplayers>1</nplayers>
    <boxart1>DgQ5LNE.jpg</boxart1>
    <boxart2>Y8ssemL.jpg</boxart2>
    <boxart3>HBYPq9t.png</boxart3>
    <boxart4>ijinGgA.jpg</boxart4>
    <boxart5>ZO5xEs0.jpg</boxart5>
    <boxart6>n2GhD4g.png</boxart6>
    <boxart7>ufqcvWP.jpg</boxart7>
    <boxart8>MgBZCxB.jpg</boxart8>
    <snapshot1>TUA6cGc.jpg</snapshot1>
    <snapshot2>QISXIGy.jpg</snapshot2>
    <snapshot3>s3pkIIP.jpg</snapshot3>
    <snapshot4>vEaabi5.png</snapshot4>
    <fanart1>cL5Ccc0.jpg</fanart1>
    <fanart2>X9eH9nT.jpg</fanart2>
    <clearlogo1>bBisePK.png</clearlogo1>
    <videoid>Z5ki0jBrfVs</videoid>
  </game>
  <game name="Metal Gear Solid - The Twin Snakes (USA)">
    <description>27. Metal Gear Solid: The Twin Snakes</description>
    <rom name="GCRedumpNKitPart1/Metal%20Gear%20Solid%20-%20The%20Twin%20Snakes%20%28USA%29%20%28Disc%201%29.nkit.gcz" size="1230186138"/>
    <rom name="GCRedumpNKitPart1/Metal%20Gear%20Solid%20-%20The%20Twin%20Snakes%20%28USA%29%20%28Disc%202%29.nkit.gcz" size="1312789670"/>
    <rating>4.55</rating>
    <ESRB>M - Mature</ESRB>
    <studio>Konami</studio>
    <releasedate>09/03/2004</releasedate>
    <year>2004</year>
    <plot>The Twin Snakes is a remake of the 1998 tactical espionage action game Metal Gear Solid.[CR]The remake has the same story and dialogues as the original (although voice-overs were re-recorded for this release). The locations in the game also remained the same, but the graphics were updated to look equal in quality to contemporary games. Gameplay was also enhanced, featuring the additions that first appeared in Metal Gear Solid 2. Snake can now roll, hang from ledges, hide in lockers, drag guards' bodies away, as well as aim and shoot from first-person view. New weapons from Metal Gear Solid 2 (such as tranquilizer gun) are also present. [CR]Another noticeable change is in the game's cutscenes. Directed by the Japanese action movie director Ryuhei Kitamura, the cutscenes have been re-worked, featuring dramatic techniques used in action movies, such as slow motion and other effects.</plot>
    <genre>Stealth</genre>
    <groups>Metal Gear series,Enhanced remakes,Protagonist: Mullet haircut,Gameplay feature: Torture,Nintendo Player's Choice releases,1G1R,1G1R USA</groups>
    <nplayers>1</nplayers>
    <boxart1>Zck7ApR.jpg</boxart1>
    <boxart2>YhAWl2O.jpg</boxart2>
    <boxart3>d4PCR8d.jpg</boxart3>
    <boxart4>j9XVPwt.jpg</boxart4>
    <boxart5>D733CMM.png</boxart5>
    <boxart6>gxJwJGZ.jpg</boxart6>
    <boxart7>HFKNpAK.jpg</boxart7>
    <boxart8>wYotTeo.jpg</boxart8>
    <snapshot1>1acE10V.jpg</snapshot1>
    <snapshot2>gunqaVN.jpg</snapshot2>
    <snapshot3>e5dkojV.jpg</snapshot3>
    <snapshot4>UUstrLD.jpg</snapshot4>
    <fanart1>wF4adEo.jpg</fanart1>
    <fanart2>JEXZxb8.jpg</fanart2>
    <clearlogo1>UDdaf8q.png</clearlogo1>
    <clearlogo2>LEuP2wk.png</clearlogo2>
    <videoid>Pz30j3mf9cM</videoid>
  </game>
  <game name="Legend of Zelda, The - Four Swords Adventures (USA)">
    <description>28. The Legend of Zelda: Four Sword Adventures</description>
    <rom name="GCRedumpNKitPart1/Legend%20of%20Zelda%2C%20The%20-%20Four%20Swords%20Adventures%20%28USA%29.nkit.gcz" size="254743878"/>
    <rating>4.40</rating>
    <ESRB>E - Everyone</ESRB>
    <studio>Nintendo</studio>
    <releasedate>07/06/2004</releasedate>
    <year>2004</year>
    <plot>The game begins with the land of Hyrule in a state of fear because of strange happenings that have occurred recently. On a stormy night, Princess Zelda and the shrine maidens fear that the reason for these events is that Vaati's seal is weakening. She summons Link and brings him to the castle so he can protect her and the other maidens while they open the portal to the Four Sword Sanctuary. When they do, however, a shadowy figure appears from the portal. This figure was Shadow Link, who then kidnapped the shrine maidens and sealed them in crystals. Link follows him to the sanctuary where he retrieves the Four Sword to destroy this doppelganger. The Four Sword is a magical sword that splits the wielder into three clones of himself. Vaati is once again released and wreaks havoc on the once peaceful kingdom.</plot>
    <genre>Adventure</genre>
    <groups>Legend of Zelda series,Protagonist: Elf,1G1R,1G1R USA</groups>
    <nplayers>1-4 Co-Op</nplayers>
    <boxart1>irJ127j.jpg</boxart1>
    <boxart2>SBXvhSX.png</boxart2>
    <boxart3>nMqfG8u.png</boxart3>
    <boxart4>HxLxYus.jpg</boxart4>
    <boxart5>gL0OTlu.png</boxart5>
    <boxart6>94jMaoK.jpg</boxart6>
    <snapshot1>mSQc06B.jpg</snapshot1>
    <snapshot2>zad5fI2.png</snapshot2>
    <snapshot3>0asSa52.png</snapshot3>
    <snapshot4>YIeaKoN.png</snapshot4>
    <fanart1>VyTbGnY.jpg</fanart1>
    <fanart2>xxJznJ4.jpg</fanart2>
    <clearlogo1>q9OdHOV.png</clearlogo1>
    <videoid>3YHJUDgHtng</videoid>
  </game>
  <game name="Pikmin (USA)">
    <description>29. Pikmin</description>
    <rom name="GCRedumpNKitPart2/Pikmin%20%28USA%29.nkit.gcz" size="561346116"/>
    <rating>4.43</rating>
    <ESRB>E - Everyone</ESRB>
    <studio>Nintendo</studio>
    <releasedate>02/12/2001</releasedate>
    <year>2001</year>
    <plot>Pikmin may be small and plantlike, but they can be a space traveler's best friend. Stranded on an unknown planet, Captain Olimar must enlist the help of these native Pikmin to rebuild his spaceship before the life-support system runs out. In the meantime, you'll have to fend off attackers and solve various puzzles.[CR]To produce additional multicolored Pikmin you must defeat enemies and carry them back to the Pikmin nests called onions. But beware - watching giant predators gobble your Pikmin might make you angrier than you'd expect.</plot>
    <genre>Strategy</genre>
    <groups>Pikmin series,New Play Control! series,Nintendo Player's Choice releases,1G1R,1G1R USA</groups>
    <nplayers>1</nplayers>
    <boxart1>toXKHnE.jpg</boxart1>
    <boxart2>F5YeH67.png</boxart2>
    <boxart3>JhgURYe.png</boxart3>
    <boxart4>edEDnco.jpg</boxart4>
    <boxart5>T4Gzqx3.png</boxart5>
    <boxart6>99MyEre.jpg</boxart6>
    <snapshot1>lp5UxaQ.jpg</snapshot1>
    <snapshot2>7dRrnux.jpg</snapshot2>
    <snapshot3>QOzBwsB.jpg</snapshot3>
    <snapshot4>kkLWthw.jpg</snapshot4>
    <fanart1>oHjExOC.jpg</fanart1>
    <fanart2>kzAh4UY.jpg</fanart2>
    <clearlogo1>zzraPiJ.png</clearlogo1>
    <clearlogo2>sdGWiLU.jpg</clearlogo2>
    <videoid>-W93M0hJw4Q</videoid>
  </game>
  <game name="Battalion Wars (USA)">
    <description>30. Battalion Wars</description>
    <rom name="GCRedumpNKitPart1/Battalion%20Wars%20%28USA%29.nkit.gcz" size="753721299"/>
    <rating>4.13</rating>
    <ESRB>T - Teen</ESRB>
    <studio>Nintendo</studio>
    <releasedate>19/09/2005</releasedate>
    <year>2005</year>
    <plot>A global conflict has reached a stalemate in the console version of the Game Boy Advance series Advance Wars. The evil Kaiser Vlad, seeking to take advantage of the standoff, has assembled an army of shock troops, forcing The Western Frontier and the Tundran Territories to ally and fight back. Battalion Wars is a real-time strategy game that lets you control teams of soldiers and vehicles and lead them through more than 20 missions, using a variety of weapons and tactics.</plot>
    <genre>Strategy</genre>
    <groups>Famicom Wars series,1G1R,1G1R USA</groups>
    <nplayers>1</nplayers>
    <boxart1>mtV3JrZ.png</boxart1>
    <boxart2>d3Rj4WN.jpg</boxart2>
    <boxart3>1PR7Pf7.jpg</boxart3>
    <boxart4>QLM1uHD.jpg</boxart4>
    <boxart5>7G11qUb.png</boxart5>
    <boxart6>xL1vv7a.jpg</boxart6>
    <snapshot1>xEHTBpC.png</snapshot1>
    <snapshot2>nUR8IqM.jpg</snapshot2>
    <fanart1>H4MZhFq.jpg</fanart1>
    <fanart2>TK7SDlr.jpg</fanart2>
    <clearlogo1>XAybRAO.jpg</clearlogo1>
    <videoid>MHV1zsuf9ys</videoid>
  </game>
  <game name="Super Monkey Ball 2 (USA)">
    <description>31. Super Monkey Ball 2</description>
    <rom name="GCRedumpNKitPart2/Super%20Monkey%20Ball%202%20%28USA%29.nkit.gcz" size="686852398"/>
    <rating>4.35</rating>
    <ESRB>E - Everyone</ESRB>
    <studio>Sega Corporation</studio>
    <releasedate>24/08/2002</releasedate>
    <year>2002</year>
    <plot>AiAi, MeeMee, Baby, and GonGon are on a roll again. Super Monkey Ball 2 brings the party to a whole new level with six brand new party games, a new Story mode, and 150 new main game stages.[CR]In the new Story mode, you'll fight as AiAi to stop the evil plans of the deranged scientist, Dr. Bad-Boon and his mysterious sidekick. But Story mode is just the beginning - you'll want to grab some friends and get groovin' with the 12 new party games. With its new modes, enhanced graphics, and exciting multiplayer features, Super Monkey Ball 2 is keeps your party guests going bananas for hours.</plot>
    <genre>Strategy</genre>
    <groups>Super Monkey Ball series,Animals: Primates (monkeys or apes) ,Genre: Rolling ball,Nintendo Player's Choice releases,1G1R,1G1R USA</groups>
    <nplayers>1-4</nplayers>
    <boxart1>d9eZb1G.jpg</boxart1>
    <boxart2>feX74ng.jpg</boxart2>
    <boxart3>9Vs18BW.jpg</boxart3>
    <boxart4>d323pYE.png</boxart4>
    <boxart5>plTZyzU.png</boxart5>
    <snapshot1>gdEF6Ps.png</snapshot1>
    <snapshot2>SXCJ3PJ.jpg</snapshot2>
    <snapshot3>RfmIzBC.jpg</snapshot3>
    <snapshot4>JiwXjnQ.jpg</snapshot4>
    <fanart1>YroT7eK.jpg</fanart1>
    <fanart2>yAsD6W3.jpg</fanart2>
    <clearlogo1>t1XGEBn.jpg</clearlogo1>
  </game>
  <game name="Burnout 2 - Point of Impact (USA)">
    <description>32. Burnout 2: Point of Impact</description>
    <rom name="GCRedumpNKitPart1/Burnout%202%20-%20Point%20of%20Impact%20%28USA%29.nkit.gcz" size="931884930"/>
    <rating>3.88</rating>
    <ESRB>E - Everyone</ESRB>
    <studio>Acclaim</studio>
    <releasedate>09/04/2003</releasedate>
    <year>2003</year>
    <plot>Burnout is a street racing game focused around speed and crashing. Unlike many games which focus on closed course driving, you get to drive through cities with real traffic and city infrastructure. Designers have built an entire city and surrounding areas, and implement the race courses throughput the countie's streets. As a result, many times certain parts of race-courses interlace with other parts of other races. As well, instead of encouraging strategic driving and safe driving, Burnout strongly encourages offensive driving. Driving on the wrong side of the road, barely missing passing traffic, drifting, and jumps all add to your boost "burnout" meter. Speed boosts and jumps aid your attempt to dive past buses, trucks and anything else that gets in the way. The more offensive and dangerous your driving is, the more boost you get!</plot>
    <genre>Racing</genre>
    <groups>Burnout series,Graphics Engine: RenderWare,PlayStation 2 Platinum Range releases,1G1R,1G1R USA</groups>
    <nplayers>2</nplayers>
    <boxart1>XkqnJ3F.jpg</boxart1>
    <boxart2>u3HECtw.jpg</boxart2>
    <boxart3>tHsF6c7.jpg</boxart3>
    <boxart4>Vgednwc.png</boxart4>
    <boxart5>1WhPFqE.png</boxart5>
    <snapshot1>nqJGOlk.jpg</snapshot1>
    <snapshot2>udnIhhD.jpg</snapshot2>
    <snapshot3>cLNmkqO.jpg</snapshot3>
    <snapshot4>RhHpY8i.jpg</snapshot4>
    <fanart1>dFe9PL5.jpg</fanart1>
    <fanart2>NfxYydw.jpg</fanart2>
    <clearlogo1>Xm3jm2E.png</clearlogo1>
  </game>
  <game name="Def Jam - Fight for NY (USA)">
    <description>33. Def Jam: Fight for NY</description>
    <rom name="GCRedumpNKitPart1/Def%20Jam%20-%20Fight%20for%20NY%20%28USA%29.nkit.gcz" size="1082413695"/>
    <rating>4.50</rating>
    <ESRB>M - Mature</ESRB>
    <studio>Electronic Arts</studio>
    <releasedate>20/09/2004</releasedate>
    <year>2004</year>
    <plot>The ultimate hip-hop fueled fighting game, Def Jam Fight For NY challenges players to step into the shoes of a ruthless street fighter battling for control of New York's hip-hop underground. The game features an all-new fighting engine including weapons, interactive environments, and five unique fighting styles that can be combined to form dozens of customized hybrid styles for the ultimate edge on the streets. Def Jam Fight For NY features more than 40 of the most well-known artists and personalities in hip-hop today, including Busta Rhymes, Carmen Electra, Lil' Kim, Ludacris, Method Man, Redman, Sean Paul, Slick Rick, Snoop Dogg, and many more. Experience 22 interactive venues with destructible environmental objects and rowdy spectators who like to get involved.</plot>
    <genre>Fighter</genre>
    <groups>Def Jam series,Protagonist: Black,Theme: Famous musicians,Protagonist: Gangster,Setting: City - New York,1G1R,1G1R USA</groups>
    <nplayers>1-4</nplayers>
    <boxart1>l5JI7Xf.png</boxart1>
    <boxart2>yplOY48.jpg</boxart2>
    <boxart3>mUpPNBp.png</boxart3>
    <fanart1>DtLQwzV.jpg</fanart1>
    <clearlogo1>lyBZW6y.png</clearlogo1>
  </game>
  <game name="Viewtiful Joe 2 (USA)">
    <description>34. Viewtiful Joe 2</description>
    <rom name="GCRedumpNKitPart2/Viewtiful%20Joe%202%20%28USA%29.nkit.gcz" size="688003162"/>
    <rating>4.40</rating>
    <ESRB>T - Teen</ESRB>
    <studio>Capcom</studio>
    <releasedate>18/11/2004</releasedate>
    <year>2004</year>
    <plot>Joe and Silvia are back in this sequel to Viewtiful Joe. This time you have more style, new special moves, and more than 40 new enemies to defeat. Now Joe's trusty aircraft transforms into various shapes to support his activities throughout the game's many stages. In addition to Joe, you can play as Silva, Joe's girlfriend. Call upon the powers of Joe and Silvia, and get ready to both solve new puzzles and save the day.</plot>
    <genre>Fighter</genre>
    <groups>Viewtiful Joe series,Middleware: CRI,Visual technique / style: Cel shaded,1G1R,1G1R USA</groups>
    <nplayers>1</nplayers>
    <boxart1>wV3510I.jpg</boxart1>
    <boxart2>uHx51Cb.jpg</boxart2>
    <boxart3>NSh5b2c.jpg</boxart3>
    <boxart4>UPHG3np.png</boxart4>
    <boxart5>ZrTMMsI.png</boxart5>
    <snapshot1>cJ5SsEd.jpg</snapshot1>
    <snapshot2>aTEfk1Z.jpg</snapshot2>
    <fanart1>Agipfm1.jpg</fanart1>
    <fanart2>o0rj87u.jpg</fanart2>
    <clearlogo1>1mkLSwC.png</clearlogo1>
    <clearlogo2>X70Y90t.jpg</clearlogo2>
    <videoid>CYv8zBuzB2g</videoid>
  </game>
  <game name="SSX On Tour (USA)">
    <description>35. SSX On Tour</description>
    <rom name="GCRedumpNKitPart2/SSX%20On%20Tour%20%28USA%29.nkit.gcz" size="1042118226"/>
    <rating>4.2</rating>
    <ESRB>E - Everyone</ESRB>
    <studio>EA</studio>
    <releasedate>11/10/2005</releasedate>
    <year>2005</year>
    <plot>Gamers return to the slopes in this third full edition of EA's exaggerated-action snowboarding series, SSX. As the game goes "On Tour," players create their own custom characters, which they'll develop from amateur bunny-hillers to seasoned "Black Diamond" pros. For the first time, the game allows skiers on the mountains as well, and players can decide if they'd rather ski or board when they create their characters. Building upon a distinguishing feature of the series, SSX On Tour features long, seamlessly streaming courses, some of which may take as long as half-an-hour (of real-time) to complete. The slopes are populated with fellow boarders and skiers in this edition, providing some extra personality. Featuring more than 40 songs, the diverse rock soundtrack includes selections by Def Leppard, The Hives, Iron Maiden, Bloc Party, Jurassic 5, and several others.</plot>
    <genre>Sports</genre>
    <groups>SSX series,EA Sports BIG games,1G1R,1G1R USA</groups>
    <nplayers>2</nplayers>
    <boxart1>qY7HCgf.jpg</boxart1>
    <boxart2>N9ZlViQ.jpg</boxart2>
    <boxart3>OpKPcoL.png</boxart3>
    <boxart4>fjGIim9.png</boxart4>
    <snapshot1>SuZ23kJ.png</snapshot1>
    <snapshot2>zl1qdlP.png</snapshot2>
    <snapshot3>6nL9WMK.png</snapshot3>
    <snapshot4>pthUeeE.png</snapshot4>
    <fanart1>5VGe5cM.jpg</fanart1>
    <clearlogo1>PqjGGss.png</clearlogo1>
  </game>
  <game name="Killer7 (USA) (Rev 1)">
    <description>36. Killer7</description>
    <rom name="GCRedumpNKitPart1/Killer7%20%28USA%29%20%28Disc%201%29%20%28Rev%201%29.nkit.gcz" size="973225294"/>
    <rom name="GCRedumpNKitPart1/Killer7%20%28USA%29%20%28Disc%202%29%20%28Rev%201%29.nkit.gcz" size="631093426"/>
    <rating>3.89</rating>
    <ESRB>M - Mature</ESRB>
    <studio>Capcom</studio>
    <releasedate>07/07/2005</releasedate>
    <year>2005</year>
    <plot>Step into the mind of an assassin![CR]Killer7 is a hard hitting surreal action adventure game starring Harman Smith - a mysterious assassin who can harness the unique power of his seven personalities. Working together these personalities are the Killer7.[CR]Their mission: stop the evil Kun Lan and his minions known as the Heaven Smile from taking over the world.</plot>
    <genre>Shooter</genre>
    <groups>Graphics Engine: RenderWare,Visual technique / style: Cel shaded,Gameplay feature: Character development - Skill distribution,Gameplay feature: New Game+</groups>
    <nplayers>1</nplayers>
    <boxart1>pnfZ9Cv.jpg</boxart1>
    <boxart2>9fGjCGQ.png</boxart2>
    <boxart3>F9yPvAG.jpg</boxart3>
    <boxart4>Y6PPV9O.png</boxart4>
    <boxart5>QtHHfYw.png</boxart5>
    <boxart6>8jTBPOf.png</boxart6>
    <snapshot1>n6yd1Xo.jpg</snapshot1>
    <snapshot2>vJ2wpWA.jpg</snapshot2>
    <snapshot3>6fzxluy.jpg</snapshot3>
    <snapshot4>EuFCQk6.jpg</snapshot4>
    <fanart1>x1NHNRH.jpg</fanart1>
    <fanart2>V0oB5AL.jpg</fanart2>
    <clearlogo1>ZcOf9tm.png</clearlogo1>
    <videoid>ytK7DZ25wKc</videoid>
  </game>
  <game name="Star Fox Adventures (USA)">
    <description>37. Star Fox Adventures</description>
    <rom name="GCRedumpNKitPart2/Star%20Fox%20Adventures%20%28USA%29.nkit.gcz" size="554922258"/>
    <rating>4.14</rating>
    <ESRB>T - Teen</ESRB>
    <studio>Nintendo</studio>
    <releasedate>23/09/2002</releasedate>
    <year>2002</year>
    <plot>Out of the cockpit and into epic adventure![CR]At the far edge of the Lylat system, an army of diabolic dinosaurs has shattered the tranquil world of Dinosaur Planet. The future looks bleak... until Fox McCloud enters the fray. For the first time in his legendary career, fox leaves his Arwing to battle enemies hand to hand with an enchanted staff of untold powers.[CR]In the biggest challenge in Team Star Fox's history, he'll wield weapons and magic against massive bosses, fly Arwing missions, and explore vast prehistoric lands. He'll need all the help he can get from old teammates Slippy and Peppy - and new allies like Prince Tricky and the mysterious Krystal. The balance of power shifts ever more to the evil General Scales, and the Fox hunt is on...</plot>
    <genre>Adventure</genre>
    <groups>Star Fox series,Animals: Dinosaurs,Animals: Frogs,Animals: Foxes,Nintendo Player's Choice releases,1G1R,1G1R USA</groups>
    <nplayers>1</nplayers>
    <boxart1>HKJuiWD.jpg</boxart1>
    <boxart2>o4NCliv.png</boxart2>
    <boxart3>DVgg3Ha.png</boxart3>
    <boxart4>CXnrm4q.jpg</boxart4>
    <boxart5>ep6lqMJ.png</boxart5>
    <boxart6>M7VY1bw.jpg</boxart6>
    <snapshot1>FmPL2DU.jpg</snapshot1>
    <snapshot2>mh45wDy.jpg</snapshot2>
    <snapshot3>RnAMbct.jpg</snapshot3>
    <snapshot4>FUQ1ph7.jpg</snapshot4>
    <fanart1>4ShmLS1.jpg</fanart1>
    <fanart2>IQrggqi.jpg</fanart2>
    <clearlogo1>2o97rJb.png</clearlogo1>
    <videoid>KWyxVbOa5PA</videoid>
  </game>
  <game name="Gun (USA)">
    <description>38. Gun</description>
    <rom name="GCRedumpNKitPart1/Gun%20%28USA%29.nkit.gcz" size="1029537733"/>
    <rating>3.40</rating>
    <ESRB>M - Mature</ESRB>
    <studio>Activision</studio>
    <releasedate>08/11/2005</releasedate>
    <year>2005</year>
    <plot>Gunslinger Colton White has lost everything. Everything, that is, except for his gun. White saddles up with only his six-chambered sidekick and sets out for gritty revenge in this story of vigilante justice set in the old West. Travel through an expansive frontier world where the terrain is beautiful but the men you'll encounter can get downright ugly. Spill blood with savage realism using six shooters, cannons, shotguns, explosives, axes, and more. Practice shooting and riding on side missions. Battle on horseback, hijack locomotives, bring down buffalo, and try your luck at the poker table. Multiple styles of play let you decide which side of the law you're on.</plot>
    <genre>Adventure</genre>
    <groups>Setting: Western / Old West,Genre: Open world / Free-roaming / Sandbox action and driving,Gun series,Gameplay feature: Horse riding,Launch title: Xbox 360 (North America),1G1R,1G1R USA</groups>
    <nplayers>1</nplayers>
    <boxart1>tD2NZHf.jpg</boxart1>
    <boxart2>nQIpgaF.jpg</boxart2>
    <boxart3>4B60ETa.jpg</boxart3>
    <snapshot1>fre6bHC.jpg</snapshot1>
    <snapshot2>PL30pv9.jpg</snapshot2>
    <snapshot3>dF8HEp3.jpg</snapshot3>
    <snapshot4>06bSgWD.jpg</snapshot4>
    <fanart1>YY4zbZY.jpg</fanart1>
    <clearlogo1>WX1VZHS.png</clearlogo1>
    <clearlogo2>BRprI9d.jpg</clearlogo2>
  </game>
  <game name="Star Wars - Rogue Squadron III - Rebel Strike (USA)">
    <description>39. Star Wars Rogue Squadron III: Rebel Strike</description>
    <rom name="GCRedumpNKitPart2/Star%20Wars%20-%20Rogue%20Squadron%20III%20-%20Rebel%20Strike%20%28USA%29.nkit.gcz" size="1333531648"/>
    <rating>3.98</rating>
    <ESRB>T - Teen</ESRB>
    <studio>LucasArts</studio>
    <releasedate>20/10/2003</releasedate>
    <year>2003</year>
    <plot>X-wings, B-wings, speeder bikes, AT-STs, tauntauns--you'll have to master them all to save Luke, Wedge, Han, Chewie, and Leia from Darth Vader and his Imperial forces. All new multiplayer modes include the entire Rogue Leader game in co-op, plus endurance, capture-the-base, and dogfight modes. Cinematic realism takes you to new heights as you climb out of your cockpit to battle the Empire on foot in this thrilling third chapter of the Rogue Squadron series.</plot>
    <genre>Shooter</genre>
    <groups>Star Wars licensees,Star Wars: Rogue Squadron series,Games with hidden / unlockable full games</groups>
    <nplayers>2</nplayers>
    <boxart1>aFh4aXO.jpg</boxart1>
    <boxart2>u7LHI45.png</boxart2>
    <boxart3>RHKpnJ3.png</boxart3>
    <boxart4>cKxqZnn.jpg</boxart4>
    <boxart5>doef69F.png</boxart5>
    <boxart6>k5NJv99.png</boxart6>
    <snapshot1>sAgkuBa.jpg</snapshot1>
    <snapshot2>LFOsdih.jpg</snapshot2>
    <snapshot3>VG8vVDQ.jpg</snapshot3>
    <snapshot4>EHTvk7y.jpg</snapshot4>
    <fanart1>9JvCxUM.jpg</fanart1>
    <fanart2>4vu7z8a.jpg</fanart2>
    <clearlogo1>znVwtI1.png</clearlogo1>
    <clearlogo2>p5ue0fl.png</clearlogo2>
    <videoid>vL1hZ3xjXA4</videoid>
  </game>
  <game name="Wave Race - Blue Storm (USA)">
    <description>40. Wave Race: Blue Storm</description>
    <rom name="GCRedumpNKitPart2/Wave%20Race%20-%20Blue%20Storm%20%28USA%29.nkit.gcz" size="1138530468"/>
    <rating>4.25</rating>
    <ESRB>E - Everyone</ESRB>
    <studio>Nintendo</studio>
    <releasedate>14/09/2001</releasedate>
    <year>2001</year>
    <plot>Wave Race: Blue Storm is a wave runner racing game released as a launch title for the Nintendo GameCube on September 14, 2001. A sequel to the 1996 Nintendo 64 game Wave Race 64, Wave Race: Blue Storm was developed by Nintendo-owned development studio, NST and published by Nintendo.</plot>
    <genre>Sports</genre>
    <groups>Wave Race series,Launch title: GameCube (Japan),Drivable Vehicle: Jet Ski,1G1R,1G1R USA</groups>
    <nplayers>1-4</nplayers>
    <boxart1>4WlXAhx.jpg</boxart1>
    <boxart2>fGNPsPl.png</boxart2>
    <boxart3>9QT3zYa.jpg</boxart3>
    <boxart4>RKEmnwD.png</boxart4>
    <boxart5>irTovOF.jpg</boxart5>
    <snapshot1>sxV1zEe.jpg</snapshot1>
    <snapshot2>lQ5FNQj.jpg</snapshot2>
    <fanart1>IZcKBmU.png</fanart1>
    <fanart2>VJhgTDH.jpg</fanart2>
    <clearlogo1>IxVbpAg.png</clearlogo1>
  </game>
  <game name="Aggressive Inline (USA)">
    <description>41. Agressive Inline</description>
    <rom name="GCRedumpNKitPart1/Aggressive%20Inline%20%28USA%29.nkit.gcz" size="723951291"/>
    <rating>1.00</rating>
    <ESRB>E - Everyone</ESRB>
    <studio>Acclaim Entertainment</studio>
    <releasedate>30/07/2002</releasedate>
    <year>2002</year>
    <plot>Combine the many tricks and styles of the extreme sport, inline skating, with a Tony Hawk style system, complete with objectives and huge arenas, and you have Aggressive Inline.[CR]Progress through the career mode, where you must complete objectives (such as grind a certain object(s) to jump over large gaps and gain points) to open up further arenas, which there are 7 in all, and once your bored with them, you can make your own in the park editor. The game doesn't use a hard time limit but the so-called "juice meter": it fills up when performing stunts and if it gets empty, the level ends. During the game you level up your character in seven stats, e.g. speed and grinds. The game uses a "learning by doing" approach to this, meaning that the stat improves if you perform the associated actions often enough. There are also five hidden keys in each level which open up new areas within the level.</plot>
    <genre>Sports</genre>
    <groups>1G1R</groups>
    <nplayers>1-2</nplayers>
    <boxart1>aq5Pcld.jpg</boxart1>
    <boxart2>Z0LBFv0.jpg</boxart2>
    <boxart3>1wbWe6F.jpg</boxart3>
    <boxart4>3XUFVqH.png</boxart4>
    <boxart5>k8kSQRD.png</boxart5>
    <snapshot1>5DhW783.png</snapshot1>
    <snapshot2>0Huo9Qq.jpg</snapshot2>
    <snapshot3>IUpIqQN.jpg</snapshot3>
    <snapshot4>2pmU36M.jpg</snapshot4>
    <banner1>7GcrRvm.jpg</banner1>
    <fanart1>3x1ofFD.jpg</fanart1>
    <fanart2>ZVSCtvM.jpg</fanart2>
    <clearlogo1>wISOgF4.png</clearlogo1>
  </game>
  <game name="Luigi's Mansion (USA)">
    <description>42. Luigi's Mansion</description>
    <rom name="GCRedumpNKitPart1/Luigi%27s%20Mansion%20%28USA%29.nkit.gcz" size="161332946"/>
    <rating>4.25</rating>
    <ESRB>E - Everyone</ESRB>
    <studio>Nintendo</studio>
    <releasedate>12/10/2018</releasedate>
    <year>2018</year>
    <plot>Spooky-good ghost-hunting fun starring Luigi[CR]G-g-ghosts! Time to suck those suckers up because Luigi is back in the first portable version of this spooky classic. After winning a mansion in a contest he didn't enter, he must beat its many bosses and puzzles. Follow a map on the touchscreen, shine a flashlight, blow fire, shoot water, stun ghosts, and trap them...before Mario is trapped forever! All this ghost-catching tomfoolery pays off! As you suck 'em up with your Poltergust 3000, you could also rake in millions in hidden, in-game riches for our hard-luck hero. Make sure to search every area using the Game Boy Horror's map on your touchscreen and activate its Boo Radar to track down every Boo in the mansion or spot ghosts' weak points. After beating and capturing boss ghosts, you can select their portraits from the gallery to best your own score in tense rematches--a new feature in the Nintendo 3DS version!</plot>
    <genre>Adventure</genre>
    <groups>Mario games,Theme: Haunted house,Luigi's Mansion series,Nintendo Player's Choice releases,Launch title: GameCube (Japan),1G1R,1G1R USA</groups>
    <nplayers>1-2 Co-Op</nplayers>
    <boxart1>Fg8R6nX.png</boxart1>
    <boxart2>EK0b7Kn.jpg</boxart2>
    <snapshot1>y6OMrMG.jpg</snapshot1>
    <snapshot2>avbNy0d.jpg</snapshot2>
    <snapshot3>njZ5wC5.jpg</snapshot3>
    <snapshot4>mnz0jsg.jpg</snapshot4>
    <fanart1>LCNVSy0.jpg</fanart1>
    <fanart2>qEixlPH.jpg</fanart2>
    <clearlogo1>IqZhdO9.png</clearlogo1>
  </game>
  <game name="Resident Evil Zero (USA)">
    <description>43. Resident Evil 0</description>
    <rom name="GCRedumpNKitPart2/Resident%20Evil%20Zero%20%28USA%29%20%28Disc%201%29.nkit.gcz" size="1278420341"/>
    <rom name="GCRedumpNKitPart2/Resident%20Evil%20Zero%20%28USA%29%20%28Disc%202%29.nkit.gcz" size="1246797018"/>
    <rating>4.50</rating>
    <ESRB>M - Mature</ESRB>
    <studio>Capcom</studio>
    <releasedate>12/11/2002</releasedate>
    <year>2002</year>
    <plot>The game's storyline serves as a prequel to Resident Evil, covering Rebecca Chambers' ordeal a day prior. [CR]On July 23, 1998, special police STARS Bravo team is sent in to investigate a series of grisly murders in the Arklay Mountains region outside of Raccoon City. On the way to the scene, Bravo's helicopter malfunctions and is forced to crash land in the forest. The team soon discover an overturned military police transport truck, along with the mutilated corpses of two officers. The team split up and Bravo team's field medic, Rebecca Chambers, finds a train stopped in the middle of the forest.[CR]Rebecca soon discovers that the train, the Ecliptic Express, is infested with zombies.</plot>
    <genre>Horror</genre>
    <groups>1G1R</groups>
    <nplayers>1</nplayers>
    <boxart1>eHmQfAc.jpg</boxart1>
    <boxart2>WnAx2ZC.jpg</boxart2>
    <boxart3>0xHcMBk.png</boxart3>
    <boxart4>A74V64R.png</boxart4>
    <boxart5>vxH0Qp6.png</boxart5>
    <boxart6>sbRcXAL.png</boxart6>
    <fanart1>9lFmdbp.jpg</fanart1>
    <fanart2>GpUMGrg.jpg</fanart2>
    <clearlogo1>1OnhT9Z.png</clearlogo1>
  </game>
  <game name="Donkey Kong Jungle Beat (USA)">
    <description>44. Donkey Kong: Jungle Beat</description>
    <rom name="GCRedumpNKitPart1/Donkey%20Kong%20Jungle%20Beat%20%28USA%29.nkit.gcz" size="659885043"/>
    <rating>4.06</rating>
    <ESRB>E10+ - Everyone 10+</ESRB>
    <studio>Nintendo</studio>
    <releasedate>14/03/2005</releasedate>
    <year>2005</year>
    <plot>Donkey Kong Jungle Beat is a Nintendo GameCube video game featuring the ape Donkey Kong and played with the DK Bongos. It was released in Japan on December 16, 2004, in Europe on February 4, 2005, in North America on March 14, 2005, and in Australia on March 17, 2005. In 2008 and 2009, the game was re-released in the New Play Control! series of revamped Nintendo GameCube titles. The Wii version of Donkey Kong Jungle Beat is somewhat changed from the original GameCube version, including new levels, modifications of old levels, and traditional controls that have the player use the analog stick to move and the A button to jump, unlike the GameCube version which required the player to beat the bongos to do both. This is the first game to be rated E10 by the ESRB.</plot>
    <genre>Adventure</genre>
    <groups>Donkey Kong games,Animals: Primates (monkeys or apes) ,Gameplay feature: Quick Time Events / QTEs,1G1R,1G1R USA</groups>
    <nplayers>1</nplayers>
    <boxart1>dgDkMA3.jpg</boxart1>
    <boxart2>po1u4tj.jpg</boxart2>
    <boxart3>BiFkBum.jpg</boxart3>
    <boxart4>ZUVSwuS.png</boxart4>
    <boxart5>rbcnxh8.jpg</boxart5>
    <snapshot1>ADIpWt9.jpg</snapshot1>
    <snapshot2>9oNnofU.jpg</snapshot2>
    <snapshot3>A0bNDRB.jpg</snapshot3>
    <snapshot4>1DfoKhq.jpg</snapshot4>
    <banner1>5WQkZGh.jpg</banner1>
    <fanart1>Aqtxub5.jpg</fanart1>
    <fanart2>vB5ruz6.jpg</fanart2>
    <clearlogo1>xHHIt2o.png</clearlogo1>
    <videoid>3ioW9XC2fu4</videoid>
  </game>
  <game name="Billy Hatcher and the Giant Egg (USA)">
    <description>45. Billy Hatcher and the Giant Egg</description>
    <rom name="GCRedumpNKitPart1/Billy%20Hatcher%20and%20the%20Giant%20Egg%20%28USA%29.nkit.gcz" size="804908019"/>
    <rating>3.77</rating>
    <ESRB>E - Everyone</ESRB>
    <studio>Sega</studio>
    <releasedate>23/09/2003</releasedate>
    <year>2003</year>
    <plot>A boy and his friends playing in the forest get transported to a magical land. Separated from his friends billy finds...a chicken suit? This suit lets him hatch eggs in his quest to bring back morning, save the giant egg, and defeat the evil crows who want to destroy it. On the way he can hatch eggs that he finds when he does he is rewarded with mystical creatures and ''hats''. These help him defeat the crows and save the giant egg.</plot>
    <genre>Platform</genre>
    <groups>Middleware: CRI,1G1R,1G1R USA</groups>
    <nplayers>1-4</nplayers>
    <boxart1>ZYEqVkQ.jpg</boxart1>
    <boxart2>YFOmjo2.png</boxart2>
    <boxart3>hwMgJrp.jpg</boxart3>
    <boxart4>vB5WiEP.png</boxart4>
    <boxart5>UU6wqVY.png</boxart5>
    <snapshot1>ifKfo7t.jpg</snapshot1>
    <snapshot2>RtJEMEu.jpg</snapshot2>
    <snapshot3>4NrmIjk.jpg</snapshot3>
    <snapshot4>qVktfCZ.jpg</snapshot4>
    <fanart1>vixwG5U.jpg</fanart1>
    <fanart2>KKdt7Ff.jpg</fanart2>
    <clearlogo1>XP25sNT.jpg</clearlogo1>
    <videoid>ca9rEn7Ccsk</videoid>
  </game>
  <game name="WarioWare, Inc. - Mega Party Game$! (USA)">
    <description>46. WarioWare: Mega Party Game$</description>
    <rom name="GCRedumpNKitPart2/WarioWare%2C%20Inc.%20-%20Mega%20Party%20Game%24%21%20%28USA%29.nkit.gcz" size="804179442"/>
    <rating>3.97</rating>
    <ESRB>E - Everyone</ESRB>
    <studio>Nintendo</studio>
    <releasedate>06/04/2004</releasedate>
    <year>2004</year>
    <plot>Following the almost universally acclaimed short-attention-span action of the Game Boy Advance's WarioWare, Inc.: Mega Microgame$! comes this party-game adaptation for GameCube. Many of the mini-games featured in the handheld original have been converted for four-player competition on the console. Gamers strive to be the quickest teeth-brushers, the most precise nose pickers, the best free-throwers, the most accurate apple shooters, the most skillful paper-airplane pilots, and the victors in countless other quick contests that take no more than a few seconds to complete.[CR]As in the GBA original, a wide variety of activities combine with a simple, unifying theme, for an experience designed to appeal instantly to anyone who played video games in the days before 3D graphics and complicated storylines. Half the fun is in not knowing which five-second challenge will pop up next, or what the player will be required to do in it. Even when players aren't in control of the active character, some of the mini-games allow them to participate in a more passive fashion, adding to the group-oriented strategy.</plot>
    <genre>Action</genre>
    <groups>Wario games,WarioWare series,Genre: Party / Mini-game,1G1R,1G1R USA</groups>
    <nplayers>1-4</nplayers>
    <boxart1>ujwvENR.jpg</boxart1>
    <boxart2>1JzLlkV.png</boxart2>
    <boxart3>paZGzSo.png</boxart3>
    <boxart4>DH6ayP0.jpg</boxart4>
    <boxart5>wapXEyQ.png</boxart5>
    <boxart6>B78CeaS.jpg</boxart6>
    <snapshot1>9blsruI.png</snapshot1>
    <fanart1>U9WEoV9.jpg</fanart1>
    <clearlogo1>SmbyVP9.png</clearlogo1>
  </game>
  <game name="Second Sight (USA)">
    <description>47. Second Sight</description>
    <rom name="GCRedumpNKitPart2/Second%20Sight%20%28USA%29.nkit.gcz" size="1046220321"/>
    <rating>4.00</rating>
    <ESRB>T - Teen</ESRB>
    <studio>Codemasters</studio>
    <releasedate>21/09/2004</releasedate>
    <year>2004</year>
    <plot>Second Sight emphasizes stealth and minor puzzle-solving over brute force. Vattic uses psionic abilities to supplement his conventional weapons. Being spotted triggers an alarm mode, increasing the number of guards and they search for Vattic. The majority of the psychic powers are meant to be used defensively, avoiding detection or healing wounds.[CR]The Psychic Powers are:[CR]Telekinesis[CR]Healing[CR]Psi Blast[CR]Charm[CR]Projection</plot>
    <genre>Adventure</genre>
    <groups>Theme: Psychic powers / Psionics,Theme: Amnesia,1G1R,1G1R USA</groups>
    <nplayers>1</nplayers>
    <boxart1>kmueDeb.jpg</boxart1>
    <boxart2>XYkAjVX.jpg</boxart2>
    <boxart3>Ar2Kdx4.png</boxart3>
    <boxart4>JDrfga6.jpg</boxart4>
    <snapshot1>MHQJWAc.png</snapshot1>
    <snapshot2>hMD9MyP.png</snapshot2>
    <snapshot3>7kbYMKq.jpg</snapshot3>
    <snapshot4>OIs0XEd.jpg</snapshot4>
    <banner1>L88BvTU.jpg</banner1>
    <clearlogo1>fcGBM06.png</clearlogo1>
  </game>
  <game name="Def Jam - Vendetta (USA)">
    <description>48. Def Jam Vendetta</description>
    <rom name="GCRedumpNKitPart1/Def%20Jam%20-%20Vendetta%20%28USA%29.nkit.gcz" size="1136442452"/>
    <rating>3.93</rating>
    <ESRB>T - Teen</ESRB>
    <studio>Electronic Arts</studio>
    <releasedate>31/03/2003</releasedate>
    <year>2003</year>
    <plot>The unlikely combination of Def Jam recording artists and underground wrestling is the subject of this Electronic Arts release, which features the 3D likenesses of such musicians as Ludacris, Redman, DMX, Scarface, Ghostface Killa, Method Man, and more as playable characters. Developed by AKI Corporation, whose previous experience in the genre includes titles WWF No Mercy and WCW/NWO Revenge, Def Jam Vendetta offers an estimated 1,500 animations for each of the 45 included characters. A total of ten different venues are available, and one of the featured modes offers a storyline complete with soap opera-style drama to go along with the suplexes and body slams. Up to four players can compete in Single, Tag-Team, Handicap, or Battle Royale matches.[CR]EA combines the game-making prowess of Aki and the boisterous characters from hip-hop's Def Jam Records. The result is Def Jam Vendetta, a curious concoction that just might have the goods to attract hardcore and mainstream gamers alike. The game features 12 Def Jam artists including Redman, Method Man, Ludacris, DMX, N.O.R.E., and Scarface. As you make your way through the game, you'll be able to unlock all 45 characters plus aditional venues, girls, and concept art.</plot>
    <genre>Sports</genre>
    <groups>EA Sports BIG games,PlayStation 2 Greatest Hits releases,Def Jam series,Protagonist: Black,Theme: Famous musicians,Snoop Dogg licensees,1G1R,1G1R USA</groups>
    <nplayers>1-4</nplayers>
    <boxart1>IsLwOdA.png</boxart1>
    <boxart2>3LJ7n2C.jpg</boxart2>
    <boxart3>5MLJzk2.png</boxart3>
    <boxart4>wIm1nIq.jpg</boxart4>
    <fanart1>LCdN7dG.jpg</fanart1>
    <fanart2>odWjn0D.jpg</fanart2>
    <clearlogo1>aWHMRVT.png</clearlogo1>
  </game>
  <game name="Mario Golf - Toadstool Tour (USA)">
    <description>49. Mario Golf: Toadstool Tour</description>
    <rom name="GCRedumpNKitPart1/Mario%20Golf%20-%20Toadstool%20Tour%20%28USA%29.nkit.gcz" size="1134389392"/>
    <rating>4.07</rating>
    <ESRB>E - Everyone</ESRB>
    <studio>Nintendo</studio>
    <releasedate>29/07/2003</releasedate>
    <year>2003</year>
    <plot>Hit the links in the Mushroom Kingdom![CR]Mario, Peach, Yoshi, Donkey Kong and others have tee times reserved in the Mushroom Kingdom! Challenge them to tournaments, or take them on in character matches to collect rings or nab coins! Play on resort-style courses or look out for Chain Chomps, Warp Pipes and Thwomps on the Mushroom Kingdom courses!</plot>
    <genre>Sports</genre>
    <groups>Mario games,Mario sports games,Nintendo Player's Choice releases,Mario Golf series,1G1R,1G1R USA</groups>
    <nplayers>1-4</nplayers>
    <boxart1>wL7drrj.jpg</boxart1>
    <boxart2>4KqsKeZ.jpg</boxart2>
    <boxart3>b9bV4lB.jpg</boxart3>
    <boxart4>kMhjDMl.png</boxart4>
    <boxart5>zU8WT0A.jpg</boxart5>
    <snapshot1>EgdmxJh.png</snapshot1>
    <snapshot2>sV6Sj1c.png</snapshot2>
    <snapshot3>MDnDV7X.png</snapshot3>
    <snapshot4>2wqcyFP.png</snapshot4>
    <banner1>v4x9tAX.png</banner1>
    <fanart1>o0tXOO8.jpg</fanart1>
    <fanart2>zNYHXyk.jpg</fanart2>
    <clearlogo1>mBhjUnb.png</clearlogo1>
    <videoid>ne25xKFItMk</videoid>
  </game>
  <game name="Cubivore - Survival of the Fittest (USA)">
    <description>50. Cubivore: Survival of the Fittest</description>
    <rom name="GCRedumpNKitPart1/Cubivore%20-%20Survival%20of%20the%20Fittest%20%28USA%29.nkit.gcz" size="41701661"/>
    <rating>3.85</rating>
    <ESRB>E - Everyone</ESRB>
    <studio>Atlus</studio>
    <releasedate>05/11/2002</releasedate>
    <year>2002</year>
    <plot>Eat or be eaten! Assume the role of an animal in it's early stages of evolutionary development. As your animal instincts take over, you will boldly traverse hostile environments, savagely stalking your prey to assert your place in the animal chain of power. Will you have what it takes to become the new king of beasts?[CR]* Abstract cubic style comes to life, as a huge array of surreal creatures interact with their natural environments![CR]* Dolby Surround Sound immerses you in a world of wild grunts, menacing growls, and terrifying screeches![CR]* Ferociously addictive gameplay! Only a combination of strategy, instinct, and luck can keep your beast alive![CR]* Cultivate your beast's strengths by carefully selecting both your prey and mates to evolve in the most effective way!</plot>
    <genre>Virtual Life,Simulation,Simulation,Simulation</genre>
    <groups>1G1R</groups>
    <nplayers>1</nplayers>
    <boxart1>n9F3U85.jpg</boxart1>
    <boxart2>cZ9wOeO.jpg</boxart2>
    <boxart3>gtWMoOB.jpg</boxart3>
    <boxart4>eKHATAY.jpg</boxart4>
    <boxart5>NqIjUtV.png</boxart5>
    <boxart6>6Y0jXw6.jpg</boxart6>
    <boxart7>aXz5Lku.jpg</boxart7>
    <snapshot1>7aqHigC.jpg</snapshot1>
    <snapshot2>iMjBV0n.jpg</snapshot2>
    <snapshot3>ikx7EAZ.jpg</snapshot3>
    <clearlogo1>V0InJSt.png</clearlogo1>
  </game>
</datafile>