<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<datafile>
	<header>
		<emu_name>Internet Archive Best Of - Game Boy Classic</emu_name>
		<emu_description>Game Boy</emu_description>
		<emu_category>Nintendo, Handheld, 1990s, 8 Bit, Best of</emu_category>
		<emu_version>03192019</emu_version>
		<emu_date>03/03/2015</emu_date>
		<emu_author>Zach Morris</emu_author>
		<emu_visibility>visible</emu_visibility>
		<emu_homepage>http://www.no-intro.org</emu_homepage>
		<emu_baseurl>http://archive.org/download/</emu_baseurl>
		<emu_launcher>retroplayer</emu_launcher>
		<emu_default_addon>none</emu_default_addon>
		<emu_ext_launch_cmd>none</emu_ext_launch_cmd>
		<emu_downloadpath>default</emu_downloadpath>
		<emu_postdlaction>unzip_rom</emu_postdlaction>
		<emu_comment>It wasn't the first handheld videogame system, but the Game Boy is the one that changed everything.[CR]Suddenly, everyone you knew had a Game Boy and was peering intently at that tiny screen the color of overcooked spinach. More than 800 games were released for the system, which is way too many to keep in your desk drawer, so it's important to know what the best Game Boy games really are.  These are the best Game Boy games of all time.</emu_comment>
		<emu_thumb>Z0adoeA.jpg</emu_thumb>
		<emu_banner>WUHJnAi.jpg</emu_banner>
		<emu_fanart>5A0FQNn.png</emu_fanart>
		<emu_logo>wcXeou9.png</emu_logo>
		<emu_trailer>itoY1vl5ZMk</emu_trailer>
	</header>
	<game name="Game &amp; Watch Gallery (USA) (SGB Enhanced)">
		<description>50.  Game &amp; Watch Gallery (USA) (SGB Enhanced)</description>
		<rom crc="99B2FE79" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Nintendo%20-%20Game%20Boy.zip/Nintendo%20-%20Game%20Boy%2FGame%20%26%20Watch%20Gallery%20%28USA%29%20%28SGB%20Enhanced%29.zip" sha1="F8C5AD6D6BF1A5A90DFFEBADA1DBD69A93720C83" size="177832" />
		<title_clean>Game &amp; Watch Gallery</title_clean>
		<plot>The Game &amp; Watch Gallery is Nintendo's first portable compilation featuring their popular line of original 1980's handheld games, featuring the popular "Mr. Game &amp; Watch" himself, as well as Mario and friends.[CR]The compilation consists of four popular titles from the Game &amp; Watch Series, each with a "Classic" and "Modern" version of each game:[CR]1. Octopus: Collects as much treasure as your bag can hold, while avoiding the octopus tentacles that continually swing around you.  In the "Modern" version, Mario becomes the diver, and as he collects more treasure, his bag becomes heavier, making it harder to return to the surface.  Mario can also delay the octopus tentacles by throwing treasure at them.[CR]Fire: Position your net to catch the falling people jumping from the burning building.  The "Modern" version has Mario and Luigi rescuing Toad, Yoshi and Donkey Kong Jr. from Princess Peach's Castle.  Each falling character has different weights and falling patterns.[CR]Manhole: The player must cover the holes to keep the continually walking people from falling through the manholes and into the sewers.  In the "Modern" version, Yoshi must use his tongue to keep Mario, Toad and Donkey Kong Jr. from falling thought the hole, each character having different speeds and patterns.[CR]Oil Panic: The player must collect the dripping blobs of oil before they slip past and ruin everything.  The "Modern" version has Bowser dropping oil blobs at Mario, who has to catch the oil and dump it over to Yoshi before the Koopa King gets the best of Mario.[CR]Each mode (Classic and Modern) has two difficulties: Easy and Hard.  The higher score a player gets in each version, new unlockable bonuses will become available via the "Gallery Corner".  These bonuses include release dates, pictures and animations which tell in greater detail the history behind Gunpei Yokoi's portable creations.[CR][B]Cheat:[/B] Reset Data[CR]Enter the code at the title screen.[CR][B]Cheat:[/B] Gallery Corner Games[CR]After you get the 400 or 800 points in a game, you will unlock an animation and description of another classic G&amp;amp;W title in the Gallery Corner.[CR][B]Cheat:[/B] Gallery Corner Games[CR]Get 1000 points in any Modern game to unlock the special star mode. It is harder than Hard mode, and can be accessed by pressing Up in the version selection screen.</plot>
		<releasedate>14/5/1997</releasedate>
		<year>1997</year>
		<studio>Nintendo of America Inc.</studio>
		<nplayers>1</nplayers>
		<rating>3.8</rating>
		<ESRB>E - Everyone</ESRB>
		<videoid>lxuDhPfk7bA</videoid>
		<thegamesdb_id>3186</thegamesdb_id>
		<gamefaqs_url>http://www.gamefaqs.com/gameboy/919109-game-and-watch-gallery</gamefaqs_url>
		<mobygames_url>http://www.mobygames.com/game/gameboy/game-watch-gallery</mobygames_url>
		<consolegrid_url>http://consolegrid.com/games/8621</consolegrid_url>
		<boxart1>CX99GnO.jpg</boxart1>
		<boxart2>t6ijo8V.jpg</boxart2>
		<boxart3>DyRDWWa.jpg</boxart3>
		<boxart4>nKo1z87.jpg</boxart4>
		<snapshot1>HESTT3W.jpg</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>jtlUvtI.jpg</snapshot2>
		<snapshot3>EQr9TvW.jpg</snapshot3>
		<snapshot4>Kpr2eCk.jpg</snapshot4>
		<snapshot5>GezJsij.jpg</snapshot5>
		<snapshot6>SOteo0H.jpg</snapshot6>
		<snapshot7>0t9btdJ.png</snapshot7>
		<snapshot8>ZIqC8RU.png</snapshot8>
		<snapshot9>nsYNNPQ.png</snapshot9>
		<snapshot10>1UD8s0J.png</snapshot10>
		<banner1>u2z48r5.png</banner1>
	</game>
	<game name="Batman - The Video Game (World)">
		<description>49.  Batman - The Video Game (World)</description>
		<rom crc="6C41D3CD" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Nintendo%20-%20Game%20Boy.zip/Nintendo%20-%20Game%20Boy%2FBatman%20-%20The%20Video%20Game%20%28World%29.zip" sha1="EF7D6684A0F737C01A1F2CC2C6609E0F3AC1310E" size="63593" />
		<title_clean>Batman - The Video Game</title_clean>
		<plot>We all cringe when we watch the Tim Burton Batman movies now, but at the time they defined superhero blockbusters, and left me hopelessly addicted to Batman: The Video Game. I don’t think I played a single Game Boy game more than this one, despite its basic graphics and short and stout depiction of the caped crusader. This one definitely scratches a deep nostalgia itch for me.</plot>
		<releasedate>14/6/1990</releasedate>
		<year>1990</year>
		<genre>Action</genre>
		<studio>SunSoft</studio>
		<nplayers>1</nplayers>
		<perspective>3rd-Person</perspective>
		<rating>3.5</rating>
		<ESRB>E - Everyone</ESRB>
		<videoid>XVz8ZICmjCw</videoid>
		<thegamesdb_id>11199</thegamesdb_id>
		<gamefaqs_url>http://www.gamefaqs.com/gameboy/196709-batman-the-video-game</gamefaqs_url>
		<mobygames_url>http://www.mobygames.com/game/gameboy/batman-the-video-game</mobygames_url>
		<giantbomb_url>http://www.giantbomb.com/batman-the-video-game/3030-21264/</giantbomb_url>
		<consolegrid_url>http://consolegrid.com/games/11238</consolegrid_url>
		<boxart1>3bhzyGT.png</boxart1>
		<boxart2>oe5a9NS.png</boxart2>
		<boxart3>TijT7Xj.jpg</boxart3>
		<boxart4>jtaEWlC.jpg</boxart4>
		<boxart5>yz95myU.jpg</boxart5>
		<snapshot1>F51e33B.gif</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>wB5svW9.gif</snapshot2>
		<snapshot3>w3aks2X.gif</snapshot3>
		<snapshot4>6EwBbhZ.gif</snapshot4>
		<snapshot5>b2UayZ7.gif</snapshot5>
		<snapshot6>qdAPQsQ.png</snapshot6>
		<snapshot7>9NJcnVh.png</snapshot7>
		<snapshot8>IdcGUnG.png</snapshot8>
		<snapshot9>salQojH.png</snapshot9>
		<snapshot10>6ynwXxP.png</snapshot10>
		<banner1>HlJ8CCn.png</banner1>
	</game>
		<game name="Tiny Toon Adventures - Babs' Big Break (USA, Europe)">
		<description>48.  Tiny Toon Adventures - Babs' Big Break (USA, Europe)</description>
		<rom crc="9B5E6219" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Nintendo%20-%20Game%20Boy.zip/Nintendo%20-%20Game%20Boy%2FTiny%20Toon%20Adventures%20-%20Babs%27%20Big%20Break%20%28USA%2C%20Europe%29.zip" sha1="7BAA81C93EA86A5DDB9B26545A446FE9B8979590" size="103302" />
		<title_clean>Tiny Toon Adventures - Babs' Big Break</title_clean>
		<plot>Babs dreams of making it BIG in the BIG city as a BIG star. She slips away on an adventurous downtown journey to the Acme Theater. Montana Max wants to turn the theater into a spectacular safe to show off his money, so he's out to bring the curtain down on Babs. Yikes! It's all up to Buster Bunny, Plucky Duck and Hamton to catch our favorite rising star before Monty catches her first! Join the zaniest star search to hit the Game Boy screen and see Babs in her most thrilling role yet![CR][B]Cheat:[/B] Practice Bonus Levels[CR]Press the following keys at the main menu:[CR][B]Cheat:[/B] Passwords[CR]The password feature is only available in the Japanese version.</plot>
		<releasedate>14/12/1992</releasedate>
		<year>1992</year>
		<genre>Action</genre>
		<studio>Konami</studio>
		<nplayers>1</nplayers>
		<perspective>3rd-Person</perspective>
		<rating>3.6</rating>
		<ESRB>E - Everyone</ESRB>
		<videoid>AG2ya3NfZKg</videoid>
		<thegamesdb_id>17694</thegamesdb_id>
		<gamefaqs_url>http://www.gamefaqs.com/gameboy/585963-tiny-toon-adventures-babs-big-break</gamefaqs_url>
		<mobygames_url>http://www.mobygames.com/game/gameboy/tiny-toon-adventures-babs-big-break</mobygames_url>
		<giantbomb_url>http://www.giantbomb.com/tiny-toon-adventures-babs-big-break/3030-5782/</giantbomb_url>
		<boxart1>k9SOpVi.jpg</boxart1>
		<boxart2>TFDyFpP.jpg</boxart2>
		<boxart3>Zuq6cSo.jpg</boxart3>
		<boxart4>VLiKyOP.jpg</boxart4>
		<boxart5>GlMwkWG.jpg</boxart5>
		<boxart6>JVYvaAd.jpg</boxart6>
		<snapshot1>y27Y2NX.gif</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>ckAqRe0.gif</snapshot2>
		<snapshot3>4onNfbK.gif</snapshot3>
		<snapshot4>q6gxKX0.gif</snapshot4>
		<snapshot5>uBgYAKk.gif</snapshot5>
		<snapshot6>oFDkPZg.gif</snapshot6>
		<snapshot7>KZ67Agi.gif</snapshot7>
		<snapshot8>o9u0ju6.jpg</snapshot8>
		<snapshot9>FNQIg31.jpg</snapshot9>
	</game>
	<game name="SolarStriker (World)">
		<description>47.  SolarStriker (World)</description>
		<rom crc="11817103" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Nintendo%20-%20Game%20Boy.zip/Nintendo%20-%20Game%20Boy%2FSolarStriker%20%28World%29.zip" sha1="A8D6ACB026B0D0A8A2BCAEA094951E915A3DEB80" size="36657" />
		<title_clean>SolarStriker</title_clean>
		<plot>[CR]Developed and released by Nintendo in 1990, Solar Striker is the first  Shoot 'Em Up released for the      Game Boy.  The game has 6 levels ranging from space environments, atmospheric reentry, alien cities, wastelands, and finally the outer and inner core of the enemy's base.  Certain capsules will contain   power-ups which will upgrade your firepower.  The first power-up collected will allow you to fire 2 shots at once, collect 2 more power-ups and you may shoot 3 shots at once, collect 2 power-ups again and you will fire 2 diamond-shaped projectiles which are the most powerful weapon in the game.  The game features dozens of enemy types with different attacks and movement patterns, as well as screen-filling boss monsters and mini bosses.  An remastered version of the first and second levels' background music was featured on several episodes of the Captain N cartoon show.[CR][B]Cheat:[/B] Beat level 1 boss w\o shooting[CR]When you start to hear the Boss music on level one, go to the right hand corner, eventually, the boss will just get bored and leave the screen.  The game will then say you " beat" the boss.  This takes about 2-4 minutes, about 20 rotations of the boss cycle.[CR][B]Cheat:[/B] Beat level 1 boss w\o shooting[CR]After you beat the game and the credits are done, press Start to go back to the title screen. Then press Select to start the game. The game will have a lot more enemies with harder shooting patterns.</plot>
		<releasedate>26/1/1990</releasedate>
		<year>1990</year>
		<genre>Action</genre>
		<studio>Nintendo Co.</studio>
		<nplayers>1</nplayers>
		<perspective>Top-Down</perspective>
		<rating>3.0</rating>
		<videoid>-4Hp87IF9CU</videoid>
		<thegamesdb_id>17780</thegamesdb_id>
		<gamefaqs_url>http://www.gamefaqs.com/gameboy/563293-solar-striker</gamefaqs_url>
		<mobygames_url>http://www.mobygames.com/game/gameboy/solar-striker</mobygames_url>
		<giantbomb_url>http://www.giantbomb.com/solar-striker/3030-10870/</giantbomb_url>
		<boxart1>kM7vLvm.jpg</boxart1>
		<boxart2>yXYZJP6.jpg</boxart2>
		<boxart3>lpjdb6r.jpg</boxart3>
		<boxart4>JuTppAW.jpg</boxart4>
		<snapshot1>sq1IMZV.gif</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>tm5EBha.gif</snapshot2>
		<snapshot3>fwX0vAY.gif</snapshot3>
		<snapshot4>5GQIz54.gif</snapshot4>
		<snapshot5>lUNH0L2.gif</snapshot5>
		<snapshot6>IHb1EaD.gif</snapshot6>
		<snapshot7>CItEgn2.gif</snapshot7>
		<snapshot8>9HffU1V.jpg</snapshot8>
		<snapshot9>Gy0MPnN.jpg</snapshot9>
		<snapshot10>6Sq0O4i.jpg</snapshot10>
	</game>
	<game name="F-1 Race (World) (Rev A)">
		<description>46.  F-1 Race (World) (Rev A)</description>
		<rom crc="AB83BD70" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Nintendo%20-%20Game%20Boy.zip/Nintendo%20-%20Game%20Boy%2FF-1%20Race%20%28World%29%20%28Rev%20A%29.zip" sha1="0256082F482AF57E0472F5713A432A22BFA4D2FC" size="63442" />
		<title_clean>F-1 Race</title_clean>
		<plot>The graphics are laughably basic when compared to modern racers like Forza or Gran Turismo, but that didn’t matter to ‘90s kids because F-1 Race allowed up to four players to race against each other using a bulk adapter we happily carried everywhere we went. If the Game Boy Classic Edition includes wireless multiplayer, this game will be the reason why.</plot>
		<releasedate>14/2/1991</releasedate>
		<year>1990</year>
		<genre>Driving, Racing</genre>
		<studio>Nintendo of America Inc.</studio>
		<nplayers>1-4 Alt</nplayers>
		<perspective>3rd-Person</perspective>
		<rating>3.3</rating>
		<videoid>puPPNaw0PKo</videoid>
		<thegamesdb_id>3180</thegamesdb_id>
		<gamefaqs_url>http://www.gamefaqs.com/gameboy/563271-f-1-race</gamefaqs_url>
		<mobygames_url>http://www.mobygames.com/game/gameboy/f-1-race</mobygames_url>
		<giantbomb_url>http://www.giantbomb.com/f-1-race/3030-16283/</giantbomb_url>
		<boxart1>yHXE97n.jpg</boxart1>
		<boxart2>EQbOaU5.jpg</boxart2>
		<boxart3>m2AXyPE.jpg</boxart3>
		<boxart4>PwrN3fW.jpg</boxart4>
		<boxart5>8aSALt1.jpg</boxart5>
		<boxart6>QzFqYxG.jpg</boxart6>
		<snapshot1>dSDD6HP.gif</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>nMqMxqG.gif</snapshot2>
		<snapshot3>YIXlvjr.gif</snapshot3>
		<snapshot4>BImzfuW.gif</snapshot4>
		<snapshot5>WCafDfi.gif</snapshot5>
		<snapshot6>C1uiUCx.gif</snapshot6>
		<snapshot7>32ZUJ9t.png</snapshot7>
		<snapshot8>P47Pk77.jpg</snapshot8>
		<snapshot9>Wwj8wRB.jpg</snapshot9>
		<snapshot10>ItWinDv.jpg</snapshot10>
		<banner1>aayNDYX.jpg</banner1>
	</game>
	<game name="Tetris 2 (USA, Europe) (SGB Enhanced)">
		<description>45.  Tetris 2 (USA, Europe) (SGB Enhanced)</description>
		<rom crc="EA19A9D9" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Nintendo%20-%20Game%20Boy.zip/Nintendo%20-%20Game%20Boy%2FTetris%202%20%28USA%2C%20Europe%29%20%28SGB%20Enhanced%29.zip" sha1="1F88BE9DEA864EAA74C3B5CE3488E61139818E8D" size="62761" />
		<title_clean>Tetris 2</title_clean>
		<plot>[CR][B]Overview:[/B][CR]Tetris 2 is a multi-platform puzzle game sequel from TOSE and published by Nintendo in most territories. It replaces the standard "fill a line with bricks" goal with the new "connect three like colored blocks" goal, with the primary goal of removing all the marked bricks from the field. In this regard it plays very similarly to Dr. Mario. Most modes of Tetris 2 focus on destroying colored crystals with other like colored blocks to clear the board and advance to the next level. It also introduces new tetrominos that are comprised of non-connected pieces, which adds to their versatility.[CR]Tetris 2 was released on the NES, Game Boy and Super Nintendo. It is not to be confused with the earlier Tetris 2 + Bombliss, also developed by TOSE.[CR][B]Game Modes:[/B][CR]Single Player[CR]Single player modes in Tetris 2 consist of "Normal" and "Puzzle".[CR]Normal Mode[CR]In Normal mode, the screen is filled with a number of colored gems (how many depends on the level). The player's goal is to either destroy all of the colored gems one by one, or, to destroy one of the flashing colored gems. When a flashing colored gem is destroyed, all gems of that color are destroyed. When all colored gems are destroyed, the level is advanced, and more gems are added to the total.[CR]At the start of the game players can choose their speed, one of four songs, and their starting level, up to 30.[CR]Puzzle Mode[CR]In Puzzle mode, the player is given a specific block layout, and specific pieces to begin with. The goal is to find a way to destroy all colored gems with the given pieces. When all colored gems are destroyed, the player advances to the next level, with a new block layout, and new pieces to be used. Every five levels, and cartoon will be unlocked featuring the family seen throughout various parts of the game.[CR]At the start of the game, players can choose whether they way to manually drop the next pieces or if they want the pieces to drop automatically, one of four songs, and their starting level, again, up to 30.[CR]In total there are 100 levels, and a password save feature is included in the game.Multiplayer[CR]Tetris 2's multiplayer has the option to play against a human opponent, or a computer controlled opponent. Regardless of which is chosen, the multiplayer game is the same.[CR]Players begin by choosing their individual speed, level, and one of four songs (when playing the CPU, the speed and level selections will always be the same). In multiplayer, a players level will determine how many colored gems they will have in their playing field; a higher level means more gems.[CR]Unlike in Normal mode, destroying a flashing gem in multiplayer will steal some water from the opponents fish tank, effectively lowering their ceiling, and restoring some height to the player's own if it has been lowered.[CR]A player wins a round by either being the first to destroy all of their colored gems, or by having their opponent go outside their water level (above their ceiling). For winning, a player will receive a fish that swims around in their tank. Multiplayer matches last until a player has won three rounds.[CR][B]Cheat:[/B] Easier Game[CR]For an easier game press and hold [B] up [/B] and [B] start [/B] while on the title screen.[CR][B]Cheat:[/B] Secret borders[CR]If you're playing Tetris 2 on the Super Game Boy, pause the game and press the A button to change default border to a new hidden one. Keep pressing the A button to select from 5 different hidden borders.*This only works on the re-release version of Tetris 2 with SGB support[CR][B]Cheat:[/B] More Choice Pieces[CR]Every time you move a piece over, the game counts it. The more you move it, the game thinks you have more trouble with that certain piece, and will dish out more of them. You can exploit this every time you get a Tetris (Long "I" shape) piece, just move it from side to side as it falls. You will get it more often every time that you do so.</plot>
		<releasedate>14/12/1993</releasedate>
		<year>1993</year>
		<studio>Nintendo of America Inc.</studio>
		<nplayers>1-2 Alt</nplayers>
		<rating>3.6</rating>
		<videoid>F0D66kgyEMI</videoid>
		<thegamesdb_id>18603</thegamesdb_id>
		<gamefaqs_url>http://www.gamefaqs.com/gameboy/585961-tetris-2</gamefaqs_url>
		<mobygames_url>http://www.mobygames.com/game/gameboy/tetris-2</mobygames_url>
		<giantbomb_url>http://www.giantbomb.com/tetris-2/3030-12562/</giantbomb_url>
		<consolegrid_url>http://consolegrid.com/games/13074</consolegrid_url>
		<boxart1>l2yGk8J.jpg</boxart1>
		<boxart2>b0HZJ5P.jpg</boxart2>
		<boxart3>BOqH9Eh.jpg</boxart3>
		<snapshot1>kgJ0dlG.png</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>nUP32k6.png</snapshot2>
		<snapshot3>LMspjDH.png</snapshot3>
		<snapshot4>24oPuJ4.png</snapshot4>
		<snapshot5>WPGGVkP.png</snapshot5>
		<snapshot6>FHHWWNG.png</snapshot6>
		<snapshot7>EGvOwj0.png</snapshot7>
		<snapshot8>dWRvbMj.png</snapshot8>
		<snapshot9>HX0EZgs.png</snapshot9>
		<snapshot10>tZQVMx4.jpg</snapshot10>
		<banner1>0eFDLxX.png</banner1>
	</game>
	<game name="QIX (World)">
		<description>44.  QIX (World)</description>
		<rom crc="9185E89E" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Nintendo%20-%20Game%20Boy.zip/Nintendo%20-%20Game%20Boy%2FQIX%20%28World%29.zip" sha1="FB9935CA821562966EAFA8F60EC2F489AD33940A" size="38042" />
		<title_clean>QIX</title_clean>
		<plot>[CR][B]Overview:[/B][CR]In QIX, the objective is to fence in a large majority of the play field and defeat the QIX. Players must close in the large enemy, the QIX, in a closed space without it touching the player or the lines drawn by the player. Every time the player creates a closed space, they are awarded points and the space becomes solid so the QIX can no longer pass through it. Other enemies besides the QIX exist in the form of Sparx. The Sparx moves on the lines that the player draws and can defeat the player in the same way as the QIX.[CR]QIX was originally released in arcades in 1981 but Taito ported the game to a large variety of consoles such as the Atari 5200, Atari 400/800, Apple II, Commodore 64, DOS, Amiga (with new graphics), Apple IIGS, NES, and Atari Lynx. Nintendo also developed a Game Boy version that featured Mario, Luigi and Princess Peach.[CR][B]Cheat:[/B] Disable Sound[CR]Enter the following code to disable sound:</plot>
		<releasedate>14/5/1990</releasedate>
		<year>1990</year>
		<genre>Action</genre>
		<studio>Nintendo of America Inc.</studio>
		<nplayers>1-2 Sim</nplayers>
		<perspective>Top-Down</perspective>
		<rating>2.6</rating>
		<videoid>2CWBgYIL1wU</videoid>
		<thegamesdb_id>21707</thegamesdb_id>
		<gamefaqs_url>http://www.gamefaqs.com/gameboy/585867-qix</gamefaqs_url>
		<mobygames_url>http://www.mobygames.com/game/gameboy/qix</mobygames_url>
		<giantbomb_url>http://www.giantbomb.com/qix/3030-6136/</giantbomb_url>
		<consolegrid_url>http://consolegrid.com/games/10526</consolegrid_url>
		<boxart1>AVraHsC.jpg</boxart1>
		<boxart2>g7l5La3.jpg</boxart2>
		<boxart3>y5gTWqd.jpg</boxart3>
		<boxart4>osjaT2Q.jpg</boxart4>
		<boxart5>GPAeSkx.jpg</boxart5>
		<boxart6>tvS4VFW.jpg</boxart6>
		<snapshot1>bpM1jPY.gif</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>0O7YFfp.gif</snapshot2>
		<snapshot3>WuWG9Kd.jpg</snapshot3>
		<snapshot4>7j7b8ow.jpg</snapshot4>
		<snapshot5>b0M3Doe.jpg</snapshot5>
		<snapshot6>iaxVn9g.jpg</snapshot6>
		<snapshot7>416pOL1.jpg</snapshot7>
		<snapshot8>oSlzaRg.jpg</snapshot8>
		<snapshot9>eB5Rl9q.jpg</snapshot9>
		<snapshot10>MjF8drK.jpg</snapshot10>
	</game>
	<game name="Golf (World)">
		<description>43.  Golf (World)</description>
		<rom crc="6ED10383" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Nintendo%20-%20Game%20Boy.zip/Nintendo%20-%20Game%20Boy%2FGolf%20%28World%29.zip" sha1="2ACEE1A14BA611E73B0B7D6BCE170107213FCC0C" size="68781" />
		<title_clean>Golf</title_clean>
		<plot>If the moon and stars properly align, there’s a slim chance you can play Nintendo’s original NES Golf game on the Switch. But Nintendo could make it a lot easier for everyone by simply including this Golf port on a Game Boy Classic Edition. It uses a three-click swing system which is still in use by many golf games today, and it managed to one-up the NES version with extra courses and music</plot>
		<releasedate>14/2/1990</releasedate>
		<year>1989</year>
		<genre>Sports</genre>
		<studio>Nintendo of America Inc.</studio>
		<nplayers>1-2 Alt</nplayers>
		<perspective>3rd-Person</perspective>
		<rating>3.4</rating>
		<ESRB>E - Everyone</ESRB>
		<videoid>Wkm_5VVjkTQ</videoid>
		<thegamesdb_id>21510</thegamesdb_id>
		<gamefaqs_url>http://www.gamefaqs.com/gameboy/585733-golf</gamefaqs_url>
		<mobygames_url>http://www.mobygames.com/game/gameboy/golf</mobygames_url>
		<giantbomb_url>http://www.giantbomb.com/golf/3030-22096/</giantbomb_url>
		<boxart1>gRrk3n8.jpg</boxart1>
		<boxart2>kx268EM.jpg</boxart2>
		<boxart3>M9lqXK7.jpg</boxart3>
		<boxart4>qfBjwWj.jpg</boxart4>
		<boxart5>AWhbdCr.jpg</boxart5>
		<snapshot1>QiteD2B.jpg</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>G1VkosX.jpg</snapshot2>
		<snapshot3>aFW6s2L.jpg</snapshot3>
		<snapshot4>mm6wo1Q.jpg</snapshot4>
		<snapshot5>4AoPziv.jpg</snapshot5>
		<snapshot6>PxlE9fJ.jpg</snapshot6>
		<snapshot7>WLfBhV8.jpg</snapshot7>
		<snapshot8>EZV5j0Z.jpg</snapshot8>
		<snapshot9>fPFr7nI.jpg</snapshot9>
		<snapshot10>7N7fIam.jpg</snapshot10>
	</game>
	<game name="Harvest Moon GB (USA) (SGB Enhanced)">
		<description>42.  Harvest Moon GB (USA) (SGB Enhanced)</description>
		<rom crc="1EAE0E10" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Nintendo%20-%20Game%20Boy.zip/Nintendo%20-%20Game%20Boy%2FHarvest%20Moon%20GB%20%28USA%29%20%28SGB%20Enhanced%29.zip" sha1="5B85D2ACCD3877E80D73A7AD19D9F55C288F43CC" size="275281" />
		<title_clean>Harvest Moon GB</title_clean>
		<plot>Predating Farmville by decades, taking over your deceased grandfather’s plot of land and maintaining a thriving farm doesn’t exactly sound like a fun escape from reality. But Harvest Moon GB introduced the idea of micro-management as an addictive gameplay element for handheld consoles, requiring players to deal with crops, livestock, and amass the necessary tools to turn a profit come harvest time.</plot>
		<releasedate>14/8/1998</releasedate>
		<year>1998</year>
		<genre>RPG, Simulation</genre>
		<studio>Natsume</studio>
		<nplayers>1</nplayers>
		<perspective>Top-Down</perspective>
		<rating>3.6</rating>
		<ESRB>E - Everyone</ESRB>
		<videoid>ztKUZNqhRAI</videoid>
		<thegamesdb_id>18808</thegamesdb_id>
		<gamefaqs_url>http://www.gamefaqs.com/gameboy/574647-harvest-moon-gb</gamefaqs_url>
		<mobygames_url>http://www.mobygames.com/game/gameboy/harvest-moon-gb</mobygames_url>
		<giantbomb_url>http://www.giantbomb.com/harvest-moon-gb/3030-3640/</giantbomb_url>
		<consolegrid_url>http://consolegrid.com/games/5193</consolegrid_url>
		<boxart1>9ui2LkN.jpg</boxart1>
		<boxart2>lQLMudX.jpg</boxart2>
		<boxart3>cqhHIW3.jpg</boxart3>
		<snapshot1>2dqVxAa.png</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>o70yfps.png</snapshot2>
		<snapshot3>9OIeMdh.png</snapshot3>
		<snapshot4>EWkVOwV.png</snapshot4>
		<snapshot5>W0FcBhc.png</snapshot5>
		<snapshot6>dhSLHfO.png</snapshot6>
		<snapshot7>egOGhyd.png</snapshot7>
		<snapshot8>P4SHwI0.png</snapshot8>
		<snapshot9>jTpL2hJ.png</snapshot9>
		<snapshot10>Sgec9gz.png</snapshot10>
		<banner1>0otEpyu.png</banner1>
	</game>
		<game name="Bill &amp; Ted's Excellent Game Boy Adventure (USA, Europe)">
		<description>41.  Bill &amp; Ted's Excellent Game Boy Adventure (USA, Europe)</description>
		<rom crc="5E8F656A" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Nintendo%20-%20Game%20Boy.zip/Nintendo%20-%20Game%20Boy%2FBill%20%26%20Ted%27s%20Excellent%20Game%20Boy%20Adventure%20%28USA%2C%20Europe%29.zip" sha1="E19A7E5A5BD8FDE0F31773C22DBEBC9B4CF3824E" size="62350" />
		<title_clean>Bill &amp; Ted's Excellent Game Boy Adventure</title_clean>
		<plot>Based on the movie.[CR]You control Bill &amp; Ted- Rufus, a time travelling "dude" from the future, gives you use of a time-travelling telephone booth.  Use the phone booth to go back in time to many different eras, collect items, and get historical "dudes" to follow you.  Some "dudes" won't come unless you can bribe them with the right object.  You must get them to follow you back to modern times so you can pass a history report and keep your band, the "Wyld Stallyns" together.[CR]At the end of the game, you are graded based on time elapsed, and "dudes" accumulated.[CR][B]Cheat:[/B] Various Cheats[CR]Enter one or more of the following at the Title Screen, you will hear a confirmation sound effect.</plot>
		<releasedate>14/12/1991</releasedate>
		<year>1991</year>
		<genre>Action</genre>
		<studio>LJN</studio>
		<nplayers>1</nplayers>
		<perspective>Platform</perspective>
		<videoid>RRasOwGxOe4</videoid>
		<thegamesdb_id>18305</thegamesdb_id>
		<gamefaqs_url>http://www.gamefaqs.com/gameboy/585630-bill-and-teds-excellent-game-boy-adventure</gamefaqs_url>
		<mobygames_url>http://www.mobygames.com/game/gameboy/bill-teds-excellent-game-boy-adventure</mobygames_url>
		<giantbomb_url>http://www.giantbomb.com/bill-teds-excellent-game-boy-adventure/3030-15213/</giantbomb_url>
		<boxart1>lO2293M.png</boxart1>
		<boxart2>yYBcyPy.jpg</boxart2>
		<boxart3>3ASfopB.jpg</boxart3>
		<snapshot1>wIhDgEu.png</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>tcTmvCF.png</snapshot2>
		<snapshot3>YaF4iDY.png</snapshot3>
		<snapshot4>SuBSxHl.png</snapshot4>
		<snapshot5>XLBjtc6.png</snapshot5>
		<snapshot6>JFvXyZt.jpg</snapshot6>
		<snapshot7>j71wW9S.jpg</snapshot7>
		<snapshot8>lqoxYQ2.jpg</snapshot8>
		<snapshot9>fivRWm0.jpg</snapshot9>
		<snapshot10>EsIaePN.jpg</snapshot10>
	</game>
	<game name="Alleyway (World)">
		<description>40.  Alleyway (World)</description>
		<rom crc="5CC01586" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Nintendo%20-%20Game%20Boy.zip/Nintendo%20-%20Game%20Boy%2FAlleyway%20%28World%29.zip" sha1="0CF2B8D0428F389F5361F67A0CD1ACE05A1C75CC" size="12001" />
		<title_clean>Alleyway</title_clean>
		<plot>[CR][B]Overview:[/B][CR]Alleyway is a puzzle action game and one of the four original games to be released as Game Boy launch titles in the US, Europe and Japan. The developer of the game is not known with 100% certainty as the game is credited to both Nintendo R&amp;D1 and Intelligent Systems Co., Ltd.; the latter claiming credit for the game on their corporate website without delving into any further details. The fact that Intelligent Systems is often cited as having spun off from R&amp;D1 adds additional confusion and so it is hard to identify who exactly developed the game without further information being revealed.[CR]Alleyway is referred to as a Block Kuzushi game in its Japanese box art, which isn't so much a franchise of its own than a title applied to any Japanese game that contains Breakout's "ball and paddle" gameplay.[CR][B]Gameplay:[/B][CR]For players experienced with such games as Breakout and Arkanoid, they will be very familiar with the concept of Alleyway: the player controls a small paddle with the aim of hitting a constellation of bricks with a ball. Each brick disappears once hit with the ball and the goal is to ensure the whole screen is devoid of bricks. Once this is achieved the player then moves onto the next level which becomes that little bit harder to clear. After clearing all of the games 32 stages (24 basic and 8 bonus) the game ends.[CR]Should the ball drops below the paddle the player will lose a life, and once all the lives are gone the player must restart from the beginning. Occasionally, the game will switch to a bonus level in which the ball would not be deflected upon hitting a brick but rather keep charging through, and clearing all the bricks within in the time limit awards a large score boost. Earning enough score eventually increases the player's stock of extra lives, so clearing these bonus stages is often vital.[CR]The game featured Mario who could be seen entering the paddle upon starting a new game, and every time the player lost a life he would appear to jump ship before facing almost certain doom. There were a few other Nintendo subtleties thrown in such as the cameo of certain famous faces each time a bonus stage rolled around.[CR][B]Cheat:[/B] Faster Bat[CR]Hold A while playing.[CR][B]Cheat:[/B] Faster Bat[CR]Hold B while Playing.</plot>
		<releasedate>14/8/1989</releasedate>
		<year>1989</year>
		<studio>Nintendo Co.</studio>
		<nplayers>1</nplayers>
		<rating>3.5</rating>
		<videoid>CLnlPG-kOeM</videoid>
		<thegamesdb_id>3152</thegamesdb_id>
		<gamefaqs_url>http://www.gamefaqs.com/gameboy/585606-alleyway</gamefaqs_url>
		<mobygames_url>http://www.mobygames.com/game/gameboy/alleyway</mobygames_url>
		<giantbomb_url>http://www.giantbomb.com/alleyway/3030-4381/</giantbomb_url>
		<boxart1>pQ97r4m.jpg</boxart1>
		<boxart2>UEJoMdD.jpg</boxart2>
		<boxart3>RRkF3z2.jpg</boxart3>
		<boxart4>8FVxUcf.jpg</boxart4>
		<boxart5>uptZm8f.jpg</boxart5>
		<boxart6>fFfAJ8R.jpg</boxart6>
		<boxart7>kcFCgdC.jpg</boxart7>
		<snapshot1>gLpf5HM.png</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>KOQgZSO.png</snapshot2>
		<snapshot3>SdH6Hnx.png</snapshot3>
		<snapshot4>1K2r4I0.png</snapshot4>
		<snapshot5>If8WXPH.png</snapshot5>
		<snapshot6>Mqe06yM.png</snapshot6>
		<snapshot7>xq5Y29N.png</snapshot7>
		<snapshot8>IGmOpqq.png</snapshot8>
		<snapshot9>rwZHAlV.png</snapshot9>
		<snapshot10>x5qmPcb.jpg</snapshot10>
		<banner1>0aVXBxT.jpg</banner1>
		<clearlogo1>fUGWN70.png</clearlogo1>
	</game>
	<game name="Donkey Kong Land (USA, Europe) (SGB Enhanced)">
		<description>39.  Donkey Kong Land (USA, Europe) (SGB Enhanced)</description>
		<rom crc="49DC0D37" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Nintendo%20-%20Game%20Boy.zip/Nintendo%20-%20Game%20Boy%2FDonkey%20Kong%20Land%20%28USA%2C%20Europe%29%20%28SGB%20Enhanced%29.zip" sha1="4E6D8F085CA197479D59912C1D58E4F3B40C28AC" size="374061" />
		<title_clean>Donkey Kong Land</title_clean>
		<plot>On the SNES, Donkey Kong Country was a graphical delight thanks to the use of 3D-rendered sprites. And despite having one of the most basic screens of any handheld gaming system, somehow the game translated to the Game Boy with the delightful Donkey Kong Land. If you had found yourself stuck in a meeting and needing to rage through the jungle as a giant ape, this was your fix.</plot>
		<releasedate>14/6/1995</releasedate>
		<year>1995</year>
		<genre>Action</genre>
		<studio>Nintendo of America Inc.</studio>
		<nplayers>1</nplayers>
		<perspective>3rd-Person</perspective>
		<rating>3.8</rating>
		<ESRB>E - Everyone</ESRB>
		<videoid>VZsPvw4Z6bs</videoid>
		<thegamesdb_id>2644</thegamesdb_id>
		<gamefaqs_url>http://www.gamefaqs.com/gameboy/197138-donkey-kong-land-2</gamefaqs_url>
		<mobygames_url>http://www.mobygames.com/game/gameboy/donkey-kong-land</mobygames_url>
		<giantbomb_url>http://www.giantbomb.com/donkey-kong-land/3030-8200/</giantbomb_url>
		<consolegrid_url>http://consolegrid.com/games/8016</consolegrid_url>
		<boxart1>xv407kS.jpg</boxart1>
		<boxart2>4wp87lm.jpg</boxart2>
		<boxart3>cjEkXnV.jpg</boxart3>
		<boxart4>zHC10x4.jpg</boxart4>
		<boxart5>y0hs7ik.jpg</boxart5>
		<boxart6>xXEaBIe.jpg</boxart6>
		<boxart7>N9dhBfQ.jpg</boxart7>
		<boxart8>f8SHhbr.jpg</boxart8>
		<boxart9>eLSHkaX.jpg</boxart9>
		<boxart10>nDVhRDX.jpg</boxart10>
		<snapshot1>ldlVYgW.jpg</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>a9whZbt.jpg</snapshot2>
		<snapshot3>GxvcUIy.gif</snapshot3>
		<snapshot4>QwF5G42.gif</snapshot4>
		<snapshot5>31DULKS.gif</snapshot5>
		<snapshot6>6e2l9Sl.gif</snapshot6>
		<snapshot7>i4oQTEG.gif</snapshot7>
		<snapshot8>nrGpeue.gif</snapshot8>
		<snapshot9>I836Pd0.gif</snapshot9>
		<snapshot10>wZ3K5SU.png</snapshot10>
		<fanart1>PI4oMW1.jpg</fanart1>
		<fanart2>dNmdVRu.jpg</fanart2>
		<fanart3>h2G0yQc.jpg</fanart3>
		<fanart4>jNgM6F4.jpg</fanart4>
		<banner1>gy0mR1t.png</banner1>
	</game>
	<game name="Donkey Kong Land 2 (USA, Europe) (SGB Enhanced)">
		<description>38.  Donkey Kong Land 2 (USA, Europe) (SGB Enhanced)</description>
		<rom crc="2827E5D4" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Nintendo%20-%20Game%20Boy.zip/Nintendo%20-%20Game%20Boy%2FDonkey%20Kong%20Land%202%20%28USA%2C%20Europe%29%20%28SGB%20Enhanced%29.zip" sha1="89CC4F01653A6105EE5C00E10FC65AA1437FD320" size="394990" />
		<title_clean>Donkey Kong Land 2</title_clean>
		<plot>[CR][B]Overview:[/B][CR]Donkey Kong Land 2 is the second game in the series starring  Diddy Kong and  Dixie Kong for the Nintendo Game Boy. Compared to the first  DKL title, DKL2 shares more in common to  Donkey Kong Country 2; it keeps the same storyline, worlds and level names, although the design and structure of the levels themselves has been changed so the game is not just a watered down port. The team-up mechanic which was introduced in DKC2 is missing here due to the Game Boy's limitations, but the Kongs' signature moves like Diddy's cartwheel and Dixie's helicopter spin have still been included, as have their animal buddies which still retain their charge-up "super moves" introduced in Donkey Kong Country 2.Compared to the original, Donkey Kong Land 2 has smoother control and better proportioned sprites, but the level of detail with the visuals has been cut down, particularly with the sprites which seem to tear every now and then while playing.[CR][B]Stages:[/B][CR]Gangplank Galleon Pirate PanicMainbrace MayhemGangplank GalleyLockjaw's LockerTopsail TroubleKrow's Nest (Boss)Krem CauldronHot Head HopKannon's KlaimLava LagoonRedhot RideSquawks's ShaftBarrel BayouGlimmer's GalleonKrockhead KlamberRattle BattleSlime ClimbKleaver's Kiln (Boss)Krazy KremlandHornet HoleTarget TerrorBramble BlastRickety RaceBramble ScrambleMudhole MarshRambi RumbleKing Zing Sting (Boss)Gloomy GulchGhostly GroveKrazy KoasterGusty GladeParrot Chute PanicWeb WoodsKreepy Krow (Boss)K.Rool's KeepArctic AbyssWindy WellDungeon DangerClapper's CavernChain Link ChamberToxic TowerStronghold ShowdownThe Flying Krock Screech's SprintK. Rool Duel (Boss)The Lost World (Klubba's Kiosk)Jungle JinxBlack Ice BattleFiery FurnaceKlobber KarnageAnimal AnticsKrocodile Kore (Boss)[CR]Differences to Donkey Kong Country 2[CR]Overworld map has been flipped, as have most of the individual world maps. Crocodile Cauldron and  Krem Quay have been joined together to create Krem Cauldron; some of their levels have been transferred to Krazy Kremland. As a result the boss of Krem Quay in DKC2,  Kudgel, does not make an appearance in this game.Lost World is accessed as an entire world from the overworld map, instead of having individual levels accessed from each of the worlds via Klubba's Kiosk.Removal of Swanky and  Cranky,  Wrinkly no longer gives out hints.No team-up mechanic present.Characters always transform into Animal buddies and cannot ride them.Dixie's ponytail whirl now allows the player to hit B in the air at any time before hitting the peak of their jump.While stages may have the same name as their SNES console counterparts, the level layout (and sometimes mechanics) are completely different.End of a level is marked by a stand-alone target with no prizes for good timing.Stages with water in them do not have dynamic water which raises and falls anymore.Not all music has been ported over, as such many of the different level archtypes share the same music.Music has been remixed by  Grant Kirkhope (composer for Banjo-Kazooie and Viva Pinata) rather than by original composer  David Wise.No bonus stages are accessed via cannons with cannon balls, or by breaking through secret walls. All are found in bonus barrels.Only 47 Bonus or Krem Coins to collect instead of 75.Cat O' Nine Tails enemy has been removed.Glimmer's Galleon no longer features the angler fish Glimmer; instead players must touch various barrels to light up the stage.It's possible to complete the Rattle Battle stage without using Rattly the snake at all.Slime Climb features toxic slime which hurts the player upon touching it instead of containing a dangerous piranha (Snapjaw in Donkey Kong Country 2).Kleaver's Kiln fight utilises Krockheads that the player must use to cross to the other side of the battlefield instead of hooks.Haunted Hall in  Gloomy Gulch has been replaced by a regular rollercoaster level called Krazy Koaster.Only need to scale one set of rigging ropes in Kreepy Krow fight.In King Zing Sting fight, King Zing never shoots barbs. It doesn't matter where players hit him with  Squawks the Parrot's nuts, and he won't make a barricade of Zingers around himself, only leave a trail of them behind him later in the fight instead.Animal Antics is now entirely a jungle level.K. Rool Duel is now set in a castle level, whereas Krocodile Kore fight is now set in a lava level.[CR]</plot>
		<releasedate>14/9/1996</releasedate>
		<year>1996</year>
		<genre>Action</genre>
		<studio>Nintendo of America Inc.</studio>
		<nplayers>1</nplayers>
		<perspective>Platform</perspective>
		<rating>3.7</rating>
		<ESRB>E - Everyone</ESRB>
		<videoid>-nz5FuDqgXk</videoid>
		<thegamesdb_id>3176</thegamesdb_id>
		<gamefaqs_url>http://www.gamefaqs.com/gameboy/197138-donkey-kong-land-2</gamefaqs_url>
		<mobygames_url>http://www.mobygames.com/game/gameboy/donkey-kong-land-2</mobygames_url>
		<giantbomb_url>http://www.giantbomb.com/donkey-kong-land-2/3030-9722/</giantbomb_url>
		<consolegrid_url>http://consolegrid.com/games/8017</consolegrid_url>
		<boxart1>GdhpuBs.jpg</boxart1>
		<boxart2>A8YOwUJ.png</boxart2>
		<boxart3>bAJAQyi.jpg</boxart3>
		<boxart4>9JYkgJ9.jpg</boxart4>
		<boxart5>8g14eUS.jpg</boxart5>
		<boxart6>OYSCoUm.jpg</boxart6>
		<boxart7>BSmLDci.jpg</boxart7>
		<boxart8>6qqCmI3.jpg</boxart8>
		<boxart9>eLSHkaX.jpg</boxart9>
		<boxart10>nDVhRDX.jpg</boxart10>
		<snapshot1>KdSeuIz.jpg</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>B0b3nCa.jpg</snapshot2>
		<snapshot3>TAHT6G9.jpg</snapshot3>
		<snapshot4>PyXMciW.gif</snapshot4>
		<snapshot5>p7hvldL.png</snapshot5>
		<snapshot6>YuziHzj.gif</snapshot6>
		<snapshot7>W0rp3r1.gif</snapshot7>
		<snapshot8>oDB1o8j.gif</snapshot8>
		<snapshot9>3fzKeJi.gif</snapshot9>
		<snapshot10>ntxQXii.gif</snapshot10>
		<fanart1>XJyUjrn.jpg</fanart1>
		<fanart2>WwVH8kt.jpg</fanart2>
		<fanart3>6vhAc7N.jpg</fanart3>
		<fanart4>VlcIT7F.jpg</fanart4>
		<banner1>05Qmm8h.png</banner1>
	</game>
		<game name="Balloon Kid (USA, Europe)">
		<description>37.  Balloon Kid (USA, Europe)</description>
		<rom crc="D4B655EC" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Nintendo%20-%20Game%20Boy.zip/Nintendo%20-%20Game%20Boy%2FBalloon%20Kid%20%28USA%2C%20Europe%29.zip" sha1="0CB5ADC9BDEF5320F3F156EFED0D47A618E2299F" size="75177" />
		<title_clean>Balloon Kid</title_clean>
		<plot>[CR][B]Overview:[/B][CR]Balloon Kid is a sequel to Balloon Fight (NES) for the original Game Boy. The game unlike it&#8217;s predecessor has a plot and 3 characters. Each one of them has it&#8217;s own personality. You fly on your balloons through different locations like an ocean, mountains, industrial building or a town called Pencilvania which is filled with skyscrapers shaped like pencils.[CR]Balloon Kid was developed by Pax Softonica and published by Nintendo in 1990 on Game Boy.[CR][B]Characters:[/B][CR]Alice &#8211; The main character of the game. You control her as player 1 in all of the modes and you have to save your brother Jim from trouble.[CR]Samm &#8211; Your eternal rival. Player 2 controls him.[CR]Jim &#8211; Your brother. He accidentally flew away on some balloons when he trying to make a balloon rainbow in the sky. Jim leaves a trail of balloons for Alice to follow and collect.[CR][B]Gameplay:[/B][CR]Balloon Kid's gameplay can best be compared to a blend of the underwater stages of Super Mario and modern day helicopter flash games. The player was allowed to move back and forth throughout the level but the screen would automatically move from right to left, forcing the player to keep moving constantly. The player starts each stage with 2 balloons and can starting floating by repeatedly pressing A or B. If the balloons are popped by enemies or hazards, players will fall to their death unless they find a safe platform. Players are also allowed to purposely let go of balloons to accomplish different tasks. If the players find themselves on a platform with no balloons to float with, they can always tap down repeatedly to pump more air into their balloons. In some cases, the player is only given enough time to completely fill one balloon before having to advance.[CR]Most enemies and hazards come directly from Balloon Fight (NES). Birds, fire, spikes, fish (as depicted on box art), and lightning are just some of the things that block your path. There are also 4 boss fights in the game. Defeating enemies and bosses is done by head jumping. This could be accomplished by releasing your balloons and dropping onto an enemy or simply jumping while on a platform.[CR]Part of Samm's plan to keep Alice following the right path to save him is to leave a trail of balloons. These balloons serve as the game's collectibles. Once 100 balloons are collected, an extra life is given. In addition to the balloons, there are a few hearts that give extra lives and powerups that give the same effect as the star found in the Mario games, allowing you to kill almost any enemy and hazard.[CR]</plot>
		<releasedate>14/10/1990</releasedate>
		<year>1990</year>
		<genre>Action</genre>
		<studio>Nintendo of America Inc.</studio>
		<nplayers>1-2 Alt</nplayers>
		<perspective>Platform</perspective>
		<rating>3.5</rating>
		<videoid>4MnscS9_ZOw</videoid>
		<thegamesdb_id>18295</thegamesdb_id>
		<gamefaqs_url>http://www.gamefaqs.com/gameboy/196692-balloon-kid</gamefaqs_url>
		<mobygames_url>http://www.mobygames.com/game/gameboy/balloon-kid</mobygames_url>
		<giantbomb_url>http://www.giantbomb.com/balloon-kid/3030-14092/</giantbomb_url>
		<consolegrid_url>http://consolegrid.com/games/10656</consolegrid_url>
		<boxart1>qehjLtI.jpg</boxart1>
		<boxart2>i3gcEgP.jpg</boxart2>
		<boxart3>QkKttQt.jpg</boxart3>
		<snapshot1>xqoWfAs.gif</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>eggPbRc.gif</snapshot2>
		<snapshot3>y0VlUls.gif</snapshot3>
		<snapshot4>KcUAb8B.gif</snapshot4>
		<snapshot5>9tWT7n7.gif</snapshot5>
		<snapshot6>zKhFYwF.gif</snapshot6>
		<snapshot7>0pMXWiC.png</snapshot7>
		<snapshot8>ETOosHf.jpg</snapshot8>
		<snapshot9>mVHSnjJ.jpg</snapshot9>
		<snapshot10>d1hpVfb.jpg</snapshot10>
		<banner1>NPXT4xC.png</banner1>
		<clearlogo1>X19CqOG.png</clearlogo1>
	</game>
	<game name="Mole Mania (USA, Europe) (SGB Enhanced)">
		<description>36.  Mole Mania (USA, Europe) (SGB Enhanced)</description>
		<rom crc="2C36C74C" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Nintendo%20-%20Game%20Boy.zip/Nintendo%20-%20Game%20Boy%2FMole%20Mania%20%28USA%2C%20Europe%29%20%28SGB%20Enhanced%29.zip" sha1="37085973519D61E17797693B23016493DA56A462" size="247594" />
		<title_clean>Mole Mania</title_clean>
		<plot>[CR][B]Overview:[/B][CR]Released on July 21, 1996 in Japan and subsequently 1997 in North America and Australia, Mole Mania is a puzzle game produced by famed game designer Shigeru Miyamoto. Despite being affiliated with one of the most well-known individuals in interactive entertainment, the game has performed particularly poor in sales, and is considered one of the few commercially failed projects he has personally undertaken.[CR][B]Plot:[/B][CR]Jinbe's note informing Muddy of his capture.[CR]On a lazy day, Muddy Mole, his partner and seven children are relaxing in the woods. Suddenly farmer Jinbe, aggravated over the fact that the Mole family continues to steal his cabbages and create subterranean chaos, sweeps in and kidnaps Muddy's entire family. Therefore leaving Muddy to conquer Jinbe Land and face Jinbe himself in his castle.[CR][B]Gameplay:[/B][CR]An above ground view of a typical puzzling situation.[CR]Playing from a top-down perspective, the goal is to advance from screen to screen, each littered with obstacles and enemies. The objective on every single screen is the same: push, shove or throw the black bomb into the breakable exit in any way possible. Barrels and blocks can additionally be used to allow the explosive to cross gaps or as a means to stop it in its tracks. Though the opening stages looking fairly minimalist and simple in their design, later stages become devious and complex fairly quickly. The ending of each world concludes with a boss battle that has a specific theme along with the stage itself.[CR] The same dilemma now displayed beneath the surface.[CR]The defining characteristic of the title is it's use of underground travel. Every stage has an individual underground territory that Muddy can dig through. Holes can be used to traverse from above ground to below ground. The difficulty thus stems from the decision of where the player digs, as the bomb will re-appear at it's starting point as soon as it enters such a hole. Areas that are inaccessible normally may be traversable underground and vice versa. Later challenges include pipes that redirect the bomb and E.g. spikes that Muddy cannot cross, but the bomb is able to regardless.Enemies frequently impede Muddy's progress in more advanced levels.[CR]Furthermore, a multiplayer mode is available where players battle for supremacy over cabbages. The target being to collect more cabbages than the opponent in the allotted time. Cabbages, like in the main game, can be collected by moving them into cavities before the opposition.[CR]The game further includes support for the Super Game Boy; Enabling more colors and tones to be displayed on screen while simultaneously adding a custom-themed border.[CR][B]Trivia:[/B][CR]The boss featured in World 7 has a striking resemblance to an enemy commonly seen in the Kirby franchise.If the player continually nags the Elder Mole (who grants the player health in special stages throughout the adventure) they will eventually get a Game Over.Cabbages feature an important role and when all 20 are collected in a single world, a special Cabbage challenge is unlocked where the player steals more cabbages from Jinbe.[CR]</plot>
		<releasedate>14/2/1997</releasedate>
		<year>1996</year>
		<genre>Action</genre>
		<studio>Nintendo of America Inc.</studio>
		<nplayers>1-2 Sim</nplayers>
		<perspective>3rd-Person</perspective>
		<rating>4.1</rating>
		<thegamesdb_id>21672</thegamesdb_id>
		<gamefaqs_url>http://www.gamefaqs.com/gameboy/585807-mole-mania</gamefaqs_url>
		<mobygames_url>http://www.mobygames.com/game/gameboy/mole-mania</mobygames_url>
		<giantbomb_url>http://www.giantbomb.com/mole-mania/3030-9422/</giantbomb_url>
		<consolegrid_url>http://consolegrid.com/games/7191</consolegrid_url>
		<boxart1>dwd5HDP.jpg</boxart1>
		<boxart2>SRjc6CE.jpg</boxart2>
		<boxart3>IkFimwP.jpg</boxart3>
		<boxart4>yWSeAJ0.jpg</boxart4>
		<snapshot1>VSqF7J0.png</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>HXpMLCP.png</snapshot2>
		<snapshot3>YSsiKBu.png</snapshot3>
		<snapshot4>FHI0Sza.png</snapshot4>
		<snapshot5>ywRlsNK.png</snapshot5>
		<snapshot6>aHaCWc4.png</snapshot6>
		<snapshot7>VNOPwSE.png</snapshot7>
		<snapshot8>0SB7WBQ.png</snapshot8>
		<snapshot9>6bkThXM.png</snapshot9>
		<snapshot10>jU9LVfd.png</snapshot10>
		<banner1>y87KyzM.png</banner1>
	</game>
	<game name="Kid Dracula (USA, Europe)">
		<description>35.  Kid Dracula (USA, Europe)</description>
		<rom crc="F27294B7" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Nintendo%20-%20Game%20Boy.zip/Nintendo%20-%20Game%20Boy%2FKid%20Dracula%20%28USA%2C%20Europe%29.zip" sha1="F186833A2CCEC808210EB4BA669F08401F950E23" size="175964" />
		<title_clean>Kid Dracula</title_clean>
		<plot>[CR][B]Story:[/B][CR] Galamoth has taken over Kid Dracula's castle and minions! Kid Dracula, son of Dracula, must use his magic and the aide of his servant, Death, to regain his land and underlings.   [CR][B]Gameplay:[/B][CR] Kid Dracula is a action platformer that, for the most part, involves running, jumping and shooting fireballs. Kid Dracula learns various spells along the way that will help in various situations.[CR][B]Cheat:[/B] Level Passwords[CR]Enter the password on the Password Screen.[CR][B]Cheat:[/B] Secret Message[CR]By inputting the "Konami Code", Up Up Down Down Left Right Left Right B A Start, on the title screen and hitting Start when it says "Press Start Key" you'll receive a message saying "Sorry. That won't work"</plot>
		<releasedate>14/3/1993</releasedate>
		<year>1993</year>
		<genre>Action</genre>
		<studio>Konami Corporation</studio>
		<nplayers>1</nplayers>
		<perspective>Platform</perspective>
		<rating>4.2</rating>
		<videoid>JHFPp4qvdgE</videoid>
		<thegamesdb_id>11150</thegamesdb_id>
		<gamefaqs_url>http://www.gamefaqs.com/gameboy/585771-kid-dracula</gamefaqs_url>
		<mobygames_url>http://www.mobygames.com/game/gameboy/kid-dracula</mobygames_url>
		<giantbomb_url>http://www.giantbomb.com/kid-dracula/3030-1913/</giantbomb_url>
		<consolegrid_url>http://consolegrid.com/games/8940</consolegrid_url>
		<boxart1>2cUM2bn.jpg</boxart1>
		<boxart2>GGtCEgG.jpg</boxart2>
		<boxart3>czgi1Xn.jpg</boxart3>
		<boxart4>ipmDjr6.jpg</boxart4>
		<snapshot1>4ypqwOk.gif</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>ibuV49v.gif</snapshot2>
		<snapshot3>j0TJLJ0.gif</snapshot3>
		<snapshot4>wo2DWsE.gif</snapshot4>
		<snapshot5>h2sxjKc.gif</snapshot5>
		<snapshot6>ISCLRaD.gif</snapshot6>
		<snapshot7>yQOVZHn.gif</snapshot7>
		<snapshot8>a57kq4q.png</snapshot8>
		<snapshot9>zRafkAq.png</snapshot9>
		<snapshot10>JWLZwgk.png</snapshot10>
		<banner1>ntHGdow.jpg</banner1>
	</game>
	<game name="Tennis (World)">
		<description>34.  Tennis (World)</description>
		<rom crc="5009215F" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Nintendo%20-%20Game%20Boy.zip/Nintendo%20-%20Game%20Boy%2FTennis%20%28World%29.zip" sha1="EC45A932FB3FC21394FEF5E27E7FE9ECCD0C7F70" size="19722" />
		<title_clean>Tennis</title_clean>
		<plot>Balk at the basic graphics all you want, but Nintendo compensated for the Game Boy’s awful screen with terrific controls and solid frame rates, which made a simple game like Tennis satisfyingly addictive. To this day, Nintendo’s tennis games are my go-to titles on any of the company’s consoles when I need a quick pick-up-and-play distraction, and I’d love to take a swing at this one again.</plot>
		<releasedate>14/8/1989</releasedate>
		<year>1989</year>
		<genre>Sports</genre>
		<studio>Nintendo of America Inc.</studio>
		<nplayers>1-2 Alt</nplayers>
		<perspective>3rd-Person</perspective>
		<rating>3.4</rating>
		<videoid>Iax0P3iIXYA</videoid>
		<thegamesdb_id>19845</thegamesdb_id>
		<gamefaqs_url>http://www.gamefaqs.com/gameboy/585955-tennis</gamefaqs_url>
		<mobygames_url>http://www.mobygames.com/game/gameboy/tennis</mobygames_url>
		<giantbomb_url>http://www.giantbomb.com/tennis/3030-20780/</giantbomb_url>
		<boxart1>pwUpnEz.jpg</boxart1>
		<boxart2>RuJ4YoM.jpg</boxart2>
		<boxart3>Vmzsr7k.jpg</boxart3>
		<boxart4>vx6Xqmi.jpg</boxart4>
		<boxart5>tD7idQ4.jpg</boxart5>
		<snapshot1>RqmBbUP.gif</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>glIEqvS.gif</snapshot2>
		<snapshot3>jpRFt3D.gif</snapshot3>
		<snapshot4>GtbA235.gif</snapshot4>
		<snapshot5>lXl3OeP.gif</snapshot5>
		<snapshot6>pzdxGq5.gif</snapshot6>
		<snapshot7>2p3NIrU.jpg</snapshot7>
		<snapshot8>1O7IYW3.jpg</snapshot8>
		<snapshot9>MnHmSVm.jpg</snapshot9>
		<snapshot10>acIH6pn.jpg</snapshot10>
	</game>
	<game name="Baseball (World)">
		<description>33.  Baseball (World)</description>
		<rom crc="6EEA2526" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Nintendo%20-%20Game%20Boy.zip/Nintendo%20-%20Game%20Boy%2FBaseball%20%28World%29.zip" sha1="BB613ED8D492D49DB35370BEC38D9F2515DC24C9" size="37669" />
		<title_clean>Baseball</title_clean>
		<plot>[CR][B]Overview:[/B][CR]Baseball, from Nintendo's in-house R&amp;D1 studio, is a rudimentary version of the sport of the same name that Nintendo created for the NES and the Game Boy. The game was a launch title for both respective systems in the US, first on the NES in 1985 (the Japanese Famicom version was released in late 1983, a few months after the system's debut) and subsequently on the Game Boy in 1989 (it was also a launch title in Japan).[CR]It is notable for being one of the first Game Boy games to be configured for use with the Game Link Cable, which allowed for multiplayer gameplay between two Game Boy units.[CR]Game Boy[CR]Game Boy Box Art[CR]The Game Boy version of "Baseball" was one of the first games available for Nintendo's handheld. It includes Mario and Luigi as captains. Mario himself is featured on the cover.[CR]Mario and Luigi are captains of the team; Mario is the captain of the Bears; Luigi is the captain of the Eagles. The player can select them as their pitcher if they wanted, but graphically all the pitchers look the same. The rest of the team pitchers have common English names, such as "Paul","Randy","Sam", and "Jimmy."[CR]During this era, Nintendo would often include Mario in games just for appearances' sake to help sell the game, though often it wasn't really possible to control Mario in many of these games. Other examples of this is Mario is the ref in Tennis and the paddle in Alleyway.[CR]Baseball-e[CR]Nintendo re-released the NES version of baseball for their short lived GBA e-reader attachment. The game came in a pack much like a pack of baseball cards. There were a total of 5 cards that had to be scanned by the e-reader in the correct order. On the back of each card provided screenshots of the game as well as tips and instructions.[CR]</plot>
		<releasedate>14/8/1989</releasedate>
		<year>1989</year>
		<genre>Sports</genre>
		<studio>Nintendo of America Inc.</studio>
		<nplayers>1</nplayers>
		<perspective>3rd-Person</perspective>
		<rating>2.0</rating>
		<videoid>mAHBKrjBJ-I</videoid>
		<thegamesdb_id>3153</thegamesdb_id>
		<gamefaqs_url>http://www.gamefaqs.com/gameboy/196698-baseball</gamefaqs_url>
		<mobygames_url>http://www.mobygames.com/game/gameboy/baseball</mobygames_url>
		<giantbomb_url>http://www.giantbomb.com/baseball/3030-8145/</giantbomb_url>
		<boxart1>nPeTJAH.jpg</boxart1>
		<boxart2>jynNWLU.jpg</boxart2>
		<boxart3>j7C9TV5.jpg</boxart3>
		<boxart4>tsKF1CE.jpg</boxart4>
		<snapshot1>07Kn6sN.png</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>QYg1zPK.png</snapshot2>
		<snapshot3>QcRxZWP.png</snapshot3>
		<snapshot4>y6309Pi.png</snapshot4>
		<snapshot5>B9JPP2z.png</snapshot5>
		<snapshot6>mW2EgEB.png</snapshot6>
		<snapshot7>3OZGOfJ.png</snapshot7>
		<snapshot8>QpFZ5X6.png</snapshot8>
		<snapshot9>ofVe6ae.jpg</snapshot9>
		<snapshot10>l5zlva8.png</snapshot10>
		<banner1>Hw5UUYv.jpg</banner1>
	</game>
	<game name="Kirby's Pinball Land (USA, Europe)">
		<description>32.  Kirby's Pinball Land (USA, Europe)</description>
		<rom crc="31CB6526" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Nintendo%20-%20Game%20Boy.zip/Nintendo%20-%20Game%20Boy%2FKirby%27s%20Pinball%20Land%20%28USA%2C%20Europe%29.zip" sha1="06EFDB138FF56CD9522DECE44ADADD3FAE169C76" size="121990" />
		<title_clean>Kirby's Pinball Land</title_clean>
		<plot>Fully embracing the hardware limitations of the Game Boy, Kirby’s Pinball Land had that tiny pink blob battling enemies and attempting to defeat each level-specific boss on a virtual pinball table. As long as you’re willing to cut it a few breaks on some questionable ball physics, this is another Game Boy title with great replay value as you try to top your last high score.</plot>
		<releasedate>14/11/1993</releasedate>
		<year>1993</year>
		<genre>Action</genre>
		<studio>Nintendo of America Inc.</studio>
		<nplayers>1</nplayers>
		<perspective>3rd-Person</perspective>
		<rating>4.1</rating>
		<videoid>zwrw-k74TOU</videoid>
		<thegamesdb_id>3191</thegamesdb_id>
		<gamefaqs_url>http://www.gamefaqs.com/gameboy/585778-kirbys-pinball-land</gamefaqs_url>
		<mobygames_url>http://www.mobygames.com/game/gameboy/kirbys-pinball-land</mobygames_url>
		<giantbomb_url>http://www.giantbomb.com/kirbys-pinball-land/3030-14646/</giantbomb_url>
		<consolegrid_url>http://consolegrid.com/games/8613</consolegrid_url>
		<boxart1>DcSIz9q.png</boxart1>
		<boxart2>safAsPA.jpg</boxart2>
		<boxart3>Sxp6NCy.jpg</boxart3>
		<boxart4>3QmzcNQ.jpg</boxart4>
		<boxart5>1fCSTl8.jpg</boxart5>
		<snapshot1>yYOMn3N.png</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>iPHChrG.png</snapshot2>
		<snapshot3>H6b3mpv.png</snapshot3>
		<snapshot4>KQwY6bE.png</snapshot4>
		<snapshot5>PfhnLVC.png</snapshot5>
		<snapshot6>39qkHSp.png</snapshot6>
		<snapshot7>fNcUip5.png</snapshot7>
		<snapshot8>pazMGSm.png</snapshot8>
		<snapshot9>ik5Kl1j.png</snapshot9>
		<snapshot10>w46xzJr.jpg</snapshot10>
		<banner1>9CkRdm4.png</banner1>
	</game>
	<game name="Operation C (USA)">
		<description>31.  Operation C (USA)</description>
		<rom crc="2EBBC1AE" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Nintendo%20-%20Game%20Boy.zip/Nintendo%20-%20Game%20Boy%2FOperation%20C%20%28USA%29.zip" sha1="1DC3E1C62E62F77AC633408B544AC1D02B3761EB" size="86157" />
		<title_clean>Operation C</title_clean>
		<plot>Platformers like Super Mario Land test your reflexes and agility, but Operation C, the first portable version of Contra, was all about running and gunning everything you saw on screen. Equally satisfying were the upgrades that would randomly pop up, turning your blaster into a weapon that would make tank drivers nervous—at least until you died and had to start from scratch again.</plot>
		<releasedate>14/2/1991</releasedate>
		<year>1991</year>
		<genre>Action</genre>
		<studio>Ultra Software Corporation</studio>
		<nplayers>1</nplayers>
		<perspective>3rd-Person</perspective>
		<rating>4.4</rating>
		<videoid>vEl3a1rxGxI</videoid>
		<thegamesdb_id>17779</thegamesdb_id>
		<gamefaqs_url>http://www.gamefaqs.com/gameboy/563289-operation-c</gamefaqs_url>
		<mobygames_url>http://www.mobygames.com/game/gameboy/operation-c</mobygames_url>
		<giantbomb_url>http://www.giantbomb.com/operation-c/3030-2853/</giantbomb_url>
		<consolegrid_url>http://consolegrid.com/games/13505</consolegrid_url>
		<boxart1>xqi0Mnq.jpg</boxart1>
		<boxart2>IiM7V4e.jpg</boxart2>
		<boxart3>brRg5jA.jpg</boxart3>
		<boxart4>Zn70GZi.jpg</boxart4>
		<boxart5>jrq439T.jpg</boxart5>
		<boxart6>3LbeouY.jpg</boxart6>
		<snapshot1>fwZV9jO.gif</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>DT8Ybq8.gif</snapshot2>
		<snapshot3>qmJygGa.gif</snapshot3>
		<snapshot4>4oy4ZK7.gif</snapshot4>
		<snapshot5>D4T86Z2.png</snapshot5>
		<snapshot6>oRNC36y.png</snapshot6>
		<snapshot7>6ncVaqH.png</snapshot7>
		<snapshot8>nKS1ZwC.png</snapshot8>
		<snapshot9>woLXmpr.png</snapshot9>
		<snapshot10>Txj7ssi.png</snapshot10>
		<banner1>k1AdphU.png</banner1>
	</game>
	<game name="Dr. Mario (World) (Rev A)">
		<description>30.  Dr. Mario (World) (Rev A)</description>
		<rom crc="F0225DD0" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Nintendo%20-%20Game%20Boy.zip/Nintendo%20-%20Game%20Boy%2FDr.%20Mario%20%28World%29%20%28Rev%20A%29.zip" sha1="D31D67D0682515C7C85DEAA1752B02231150E5BF" size="20684" />
		<title_clean>Dr. Mario</title_clean>
		<plot>Most games see releases across multiple consoles, and in the late ‘80s and early ‘90s, it was a given that the Game Boy port would pale in comparison to the original NES or SNES versions. But Dr. Mario held his own on the handheld, providing a unique twist on our beloved Tetris that was still an addictive puzzler even with a limited color palette. For quick subway rides, this would be the perfect time-killer.</plot>
		<releasedate>31/12/1990</releasedate>
		<year>1990</year>
		<studio>Nintendo of America Inc.</studio>
		<nplayers>1-2 Sim</nplayers>
		<rating>3.8</rating>
		<videoid>TyesS0S38g0</videoid>
		<thegamesdb_id>3178</thegamesdb_id>
		<gamefaqs_url>http://www.gamefaqs.com/gameboy/563270-dr-mario</gamefaqs_url>
		<mobygames_url>http://www.mobygames.com/game/gameboy/dr-mario</mobygames_url>
		<giantbomb_url>http://www.giantbomb.com/dr-mario/3030-17641/</giantbomb_url>
		<consolegrid_url>http://consolegrid.com/games/10559</consolegrid_url>
		<boxart1>Y7YCfJ9.png</boxart1>
		<boxart2>pE87zu7.jpg</boxart2>
		<boxart3>9rNVYT6.jpg</boxart3>
		<boxart4>2sZ9QGz.jpg</boxart4>
		<boxart5>j7L5neD.jpg</boxart5>
		<boxart6>zzMXAjr.jpg</boxart6>
		<boxart7>gQnwDQW.jpg</boxart7>
		<boxart8>TwY8LGT.jpg</boxart8>
		<snapshot1>ELgzVP2.png</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>ZYmIoyH.png</snapshot2>
		<snapshot3>P2JjTuq.png</snapshot3>
		<snapshot4>NY9OG9t.png</snapshot4>
		<snapshot5>xPhZLFp.png</snapshot5>
		<snapshot6>mMQV2np.png</snapshot6>
		<snapshot7>KBUZolE.jpg</snapshot7>
		<snapshot8>2Wiw9Hs.png</snapshot8>
		<snapshot9>kZ3If1g.png</snapshot9>
		<snapshot10>RQlkdnL.png</snapshot10>
		<fanart1>VvjPjTQ.jpg</fanart1>
		<banner1>qnjozoN.png</banner1>
		<clearlogo1>J3hAKYT.png</clearlogo1>
	</game>
	<game name="Gargoyle's Quest (USA, Europe)">
		<description>29.  Gargoyle's Quest (USA, Europe)</description>
		<rom crc="0030E61F" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Nintendo%20-%20Game%20Boy.zip/Nintendo%20-%20Game%20Boy%2FGargoyle%27s%20Quest%20%28USA%2C%20Europe%29.zip" sha1="1DA5834CD7CEA711195CD8581614C5022DA768B7" size="87789" />
		<title_clean>Gargoyle's Quest</title_clean>
		<plot>Without the internet around in the early ‘90s, Gargoyle’s Quest didn’t get the credit and hype it deserved. Part of the Ghosts ‘n Goblins series it has you playing one of the monsters instead of the brave knight. It might seem like another Super Mario Land wannabe, but it introduced new and novel platforming power-ups like the ability to float, climb walls, and super-jumps.</plot>
		<releasedate>14/7/1990</releasedate>
		<year>1990</year>
		<genre>Action</genre>
		<studio>Capcom</studio>
		<nplayers>1</nplayers>
		<perspective>Side-Scrolling</perspective>
		<rating>3.9</rating>
		<videoid>cxU3EnDZnJo</videoid>
		<thegamesdb_id>13069</thegamesdb_id>
		<gamefaqs_url>http://www.gamefaqs.com/gameboy/585723-gargoyles-quest</gamefaqs_url>
		<mobygames_url>http://www.mobygames.com/game/gameboy/gargoyles-quest</mobygames_url>
		<giantbomb_url>http://www.giantbomb.com/gargoyles-quest/3030-13688/</giantbomb_url>
		<consolegrid_url>http://consolegrid.com/games/9413</consolegrid_url>
		<boxart1>yg4nadZ.png</boxart1>
		<boxart2>c1NoWFI.jpg</boxart2>
		<boxart3>Lp3nWpD.jpg</boxart3>
		<boxart4>bxcEuTN.jpg</boxart4>
		<snapshot1>iJInB0z.png</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>PeZoYfF.png</snapshot2>
		<snapshot3>rcUlNjj.png</snapshot3>
		<snapshot4>WTeH1Bh.png</snapshot4>
		<snapshot5>CdSFDi2.png</snapshot5>
		<snapshot6>WsM8jKE.png</snapshot6>
		<snapshot7>9Aaweof.png</snapshot7>
		<snapshot8>xQShJHf.png</snapshot8>
		<snapshot9>H99Ker4.png</snapshot9>
		<snapshot10>9hIEsnd.png</snapshot10>
		<banner1>7c8To95.jpg</banner1>
	</game>
	<game name="Super Mario Land 2 - 6 Golden Coins (USA, Europe) (Rev B)">
		<description>28.  Super Mario Land 2 - 6 Golden Coins (USA, Europe) (Rev B)</description>
		<rom crc="635A9112" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Nintendo%20-%20Game%20Boy.zip/Nintendo%20-%20Game%20Boy%2FSuper%20Mario%20Land%202%20-%206%20Golden%20Coins%20%28USA%2C%20Europe%29%20%28Rev%20B%29.zip" sha1="D11D94FA3C36B9F72E925070B66BB4F16D31001E" size="294261" />
		<title_clean>Super Mario Land 2 - 6 Golden Coins</title_clean>
		<plot>Released early in the Game Boy’s lifespan when developers were still getting familiar with the hardware, Super Mario Land wasn’t exactly a graphical powerhouse. But its sequel, Super Mario Land 2: 6 Golden Coins, is, with large cartoonish sprites, countless things happening on screen at once, and the introduction of Wario. The more side-scrolling Mario adventures that can be included, the better.</plot>
		<releasedate>14/11/1992</releasedate>
		<year>1992</year>
		<genre>Action</genre>
		<studio>Nintendo of America Inc.</studio>
		<nplayers>1-2 Alt</nplayers>
		<perspective>3rd-Person</perspective>
		<rating>4.0</rating>
		<ESRB>E - Everyone</ESRB>
		<videoid>EA0jfJ2v6hI</videoid>
		<thegamesdb_id>1727</thegamesdb_id>
		<gamefaqs_url>http://www.gamefaqs.com/gameboy/585934-super-mario-land-2-6-golden-coins</gamefaqs_url>
		<mobygames_url>http://www.mobygames.com/game/gameboy/super-mario-land-2-6-golden-coins</mobygames_url>
		<giantbomb_url>http://www.giantbomb.com/super-mario-land-2-6-golden-coins/3030-14425/</giantbomb_url>
		<consolegrid_url>http://consolegrid.com/games/6987</consolegrid_url>
		<boxart1>UEfjA8s.jpg</boxart1>
		<boxart2>gbrSKUp.png</boxart2>
		<boxart3>kFSRyZE.jpg</boxart3>
		<boxart4>Zf9um8F.jpg</boxart4>
		<boxart5>EqARANg.jpg</boxart5>
		<boxart6>OMrHd8z.jpg</boxart6>
		<boxart7>9UKYxW1.jpg</boxart7>
		<snapshot1>I4OlgWT.jpg</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>zhNRoW0.jpg</snapshot2>
		<snapshot3>f9E8Nw2.jpg</snapshot3>
		<snapshot4>JjPMYuB.jpg</snapshot4>
		<snapshot5>rmHJO1G.gif</snapshot5>
		<snapshot6>ZzY7KUr.png</snapshot6>
		<snapshot7>dgiCGw9.gif</snapshot7>
		<snapshot8>DX4rvgZ.gif</snapshot8>
		<snapshot9>pmTirgL.gif</snapshot9>
		<snapshot10>0SGXmBr.gif</snapshot10>
		<fanart1>o07ibnV.jpg</fanart1>
		<fanart2>Gi1LmPb.jpg</fanart2>
		<fanart3>3AXjg2I.jpg</fanart3>
		<banner1>ztJYyal.png</banner1>
	</game>
	<game name="Kirby's Dream Land 2 (USA, Europe) (SGB Enhanced)">
		<description>27.  Kirby's Dream Land 2 (USA, Europe) (SGB Enhanced)</description>
		<rom crc="8DC07C35" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Nintendo%20-%20Game%20Boy.zip/Nintendo%20-%20Game%20Boy%2FKirby%27s%20Dream%20Land%202%20%28USA%2C%20Europe%29%20%28SGB%20Enhanced%29.zip" sha1="8A2898FFA17E25F43793F40C88421D840D372D3C" size="331784" />
		<title_clean>Kirby's Dream Land 2</title_clean>
		<plot>[CR][B]Overview:[/B][CR] Dream Land 2 introduces three new rideable friends, such as Rick the Hamster above.Kirby's Dream Land 2 (known in Japan as Kirby of the Stars 2) is a side-scrolling platformer developed by HAL and published by Nintendo for the Game Boy on March 21, 1995 (in Japan), May 1, 1995 (in North America), and July 31, 1995 (in Europe).The third main installment in the Kirby series (starring the pink puffball of the same name), Kirby's Dream Land 2 builds upon Kirby's Adventure by adding three animal friends that Kirby can ride to aid him on his adventure: Rick the Hamster, Coo the Owl, and Kine the Ocean Sunfish. For Kirby, each ally gives him bonus maneuverability on certain environments (ground for Rick, air for Coo, and water for Kine), allows him to inhale at places where he couldn't (in the air for Coo, in the water for Kine), and alters his abilities (for example, using Spark while riding Rick changes it to the Beam attack from Kirby's Adventure).Set in Dream Land, the story involves a mysterious and evil force called Dark Matter, who has possessed King Dedede and has destroyed the Rainbow Bridges (connecting the seven Rainbow Islands) with the intent of conquering Dream Land. It's up to Kirby and his three animal friends to restore peace to the Rainbow Islands.Kirby's Dream Land 2 also features Super Game Boy support, using the power of the SNES to add enhanced color palettes (adding separate color schemes for the background, status bar, etc.), a unique game border (showing Kirby and his three animal friends), and some special sound effects. The enhanced color palette support is also used when played with the Game Boy Color. Initially, an enhanced color re-release of the game was planned for the Game Boy Color (akin to The Legend of Zelda: Link's Awakening DX), but was cancelled.The game was later digitally re-released for the Nintendo 3DS (via Virtual Console) on February 15, 2012 (in Japan), May 17, 2012 (in Europe), and August 1, 2013 (in North America) and was included in the Kirby's Dream Collection compilation for the Wii.[CR][B]Gameplay:[/B][CR]The gameplay of Kirby's Dream Land 2 expands on that of the original Kirby's Dream Land, as well as Kirby's Adventure. For the most part, the game is a traditional side-scrolling platformer. The goal in each level is to reach the final door, by traversing throughout a (sometimes mazelike) level, defeating enemies, gathering items, and dodging obstacles. Kirby must collect the seven Rainbow Drops to save Dram Land.Kirby has six health points. Each hit takes away one of these points, which can be replenished by picking up a variety of items, such as the well-known Maxim Tomato. Kirby's other abilities include an indefinite jump (by inhaling air and flying upward), exhalation as an attack (even when Kirby doesn't posses an enemy's ability), as well as swimming and regular jumping.The key new feature of Kirby's Dream Land 2 is the addition of several animal friends to assist Kirby. There are three allies in Dream Land 2: Rick the Hamster, Kine the Ocean Sunfish, and Coo the Owl. Each specializes in a different mode of travel, which are (respectively) ground, sea, and air. Kirby is still able to use enemy's abilities while riding these creatures, but they may sometimes be modified. It also gives Kirby higher power in terms of speed, attack, and health points.[CR][B]Levels:[/B][CR]There is a total of seven separate worlds Kirby must travel through.Level 1 - Grass LandLevel 2 - Big ForestLevel 3 - Ripple FieldLevel 4 - IcebergLevel 5 - Red CanyonLevel 6 - Cloudy ParkLevel 7 - Dark CastleRainbow DropsTo achieve the true ending and face a final confrontation with the Dark Matter, Kirby must locate seven Rainbow Drops (each located on their own Rainbow Island), which then forms into a Rainbow Sword. Each Rainbow Drop is hidden in a way that requires clever use of his copy abilities.[CR][B]Abilities:[/B][CR] One of Kirby's many abilities.This is a list of the available copy abilities in Kirby's Dream Land 2.Cutter - Kirby throws a sharp blade like a boomerang.Burning - Kirby turns into a fireball.Ice - Kirby breathes a freezing breath.Parasol - Kirby swings a parasol like a sword.Spark - Kirby stands still and shoots sparks around himself.Needle - Kirby sprouts needles like a porcupine.Stone - Kirby transforms into an invincible boulder. If used in the air, Kirby will fall on his enemies.[CR][B]Cheat:[/B] Option Mode[CR]Once you complete the game 100%, go back to load up your file. It will come up with two choices-Start and option. In option Mode you have access to a sound test, a boss battle game or a bonus game.[CR][B]Cheat:[/B] Gain an extra life every enemy you destroy[CR]Once you have 9999990 points every time you destroy an enemy or earn any more points in any way you will get 1 extra life.</plot>
		<releasedate>14/5/1995</releasedate>
		<year>1995</year>
		<genre>Action</genre>
		<studio>Nintendo of America Inc.</studio>
		<nplayers>1</nplayers>
		<perspective>3rd-Person</perspective>
		<rating>4.1</rating>
		<ESRB>E - Everyone</ESRB>
		<videoid>EI4QuYRtAbs</videoid>
		<thegamesdb_id>3190</thegamesdb_id>
		<gamefaqs_url>http://www.gamefaqs.com/gameboy/563276-kirbys-dream-land-2</gamefaqs_url>
		<mobygames_url>http://www.mobygames.com/game/gameboy/kirbys-dream-land-2</mobygames_url>
		<giantbomb_url>http://www.giantbomb.com/kirbys-dream-land-2/3030-4474/</giantbomb_url>
		<consolegrid_url>http://consolegrid.com/games/11833</consolegrid_url>
		<boxart1>7Qfvt0T.png</boxart1>
		<boxart2>rY8Q8Pe.jpg</boxart2>
		<boxart3>KHppUNr.jpg</boxart3>
		<boxart4>iredkqK.jpg</boxart4>
		<boxart5>5X25Wdd.jpg</boxart5>
		<snapshot1>A9Fr3LX.gif</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>8fR563B.gif</snapshot2>
		<snapshot3>d7TX77c.gif</snapshot3>
		<snapshot4>nDmPckL.gif</snapshot4>
		<snapshot5>NibpfuT.gif</snapshot5>
		<snapshot6>D61Tleo.png</snapshot6>
		<snapshot7>zpPrS6q.png</snapshot7>
		<snapshot8>xf6q6Vn.png</snapshot8>
		<snapshot9>VckgkIB.png</snapshot9>
		<snapshot10>dxPyMa6.png</snapshot10>
		<fanart1>6SUi9hD.jpg</fanart1>
		<fanart2>z3YgTrO.jpg</fanart2>
		<banner1>kfQCz7b.png</banner1>
	</game>
	<game name="Kirby's Dream Land (USA, Europe)">
		<description>26.  Kirby's Dream Land (USA, Europe)</description>
		<rom crc="40F25740" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Nintendo%20-%20Game%20Boy.zip/Nintendo%20-%20Game%20Boy%2FKirby%27s%20Dream%20Land%20%28USA%2C%20Europe%29.zip" sha1="90979BAA1D0E24B41B5C304C5DDAF77450692D5A" size="136759" />
		<title_clean>Kirby's Dream Land</title_clean>
		<plot>It’s become clear that Nintendo’s Classic Edition consoles are cattle calls for all of the company’s most memorable characters. So you can’t really have a Game Boy Classic Edition without including Kirby. The game falls on the easier side of the gaming spectrum, but that’s not necessarily a bad thing if you’re just looking to unwind. You’ll just have to get used to seeing Kirby in green.</plot>
		<releasedate>14/8/1992</releasedate>
		<year>1992</year>
		<genre>Action</genre>
		<studio>Nintendo of America Inc.</studio>
		<nplayers>1</nplayers>
		<perspective>3rd-Person</perspective>
		<rating>3.9</rating>
		<ESRB>E - Everyone</ESRB>
		<videoid>a3nI2J_OW8s</videoid>
		<thegamesdb_id>8706</thegamesdb_id>
		<gamefaqs_url>http://www.gamefaqs.com/gameboy/563275-kirbys-dream-land</gamefaqs_url>
		<mobygames_url>http://www.mobygames.com/game/gameboy/kirbys-dream-land</mobygames_url>
		<giantbomb_url>http://www.giantbomb.com/kirbys-dream-land/3030-19788/</giantbomb_url>
		<consolegrid_url>http://consolegrid.com/games/8030</consolegrid_url>
		<boxart1>gub0X2I.jpg</boxart1>
		<boxart2>YUggiEN.jpg</boxart2>
		<boxart3>ApjwyV9.jpg</boxart3>
		<boxart4>SnkkGUI.jpg</boxart4>
		<boxart5>9hRsgXW.jpg</boxart5>
		<boxart6>4mpO7N8.jpg</boxart6>
		<boxart7>T9FOOY0.jpg</boxart7>
		<snapshot1>PhMKhF0.jpg</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>LGYZbos.gif</snapshot2>
		<snapshot3>BJNNJNj.gif</snapshot3>
		<snapshot4>CotE7k6.gif</snapshot4>
		<snapshot5>Ny9kP07.gif</snapshot5>
		<snapshot6>BeqTg9Z.gif</snapshot6>
		<snapshot7>agsBDRm.gif</snapshot7>
		<snapshot8>uMlHppH.gif</snapshot8>
		<snapshot9>JlFQRJd.gif</snapshot9>
		<snapshot10>WwuUCkI.png</snapshot10>
		<banner1>m4ZsWXu.png</banner1>
	</game>
	<game name="Wario Land - Super Mario Land 3 (World)">
		<description>25.  Wario Land - Super Mario Land 3 (World)</description>
		<rom crc="40BE3889" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Nintendo%20-%20Game%20Boy.zip/Nintendo%20-%20Game%20Boy%2FWario%20Land%20-%20Super%20Mario%20Land%203%20%28World%29.zip" sha1="AE65800302438E37A99E623A71D1C954D73C843E" size="284332" />
		<title_clean>Wario Land - Super Mario Land 3</title_clean>
		<plot>Now better known for WarioWare Inc., the fantastic collection of mini games on the GBA, Wario also starred in a handful of side-scrolling platformers, and even managed to best his nemesis’ Mario’s outing on the Game Boy. The graphics in Wario Land: Super Mario Land 3 eclipse those in Super Mario Land, and the game includes far better weapons and outfits for Wario to accessorize with.</plot>
		<releasedate>14/2/1994</releasedate>
		<year>1994</year>
		<genre>Action</genre>
		<studio>Nintendo of America Inc.</studio>
		<nplayers>1-2 Alt</nplayers>
		<perspective>3rd-Person</perspective>
		<rating>3.9</rating>
		<ESRB>E - Everyone</ESRB>
		<videoid>ZJuxdR0KH-s</videoid>
		<thegamesdb_id>1728</thegamesdb_id>
		<gamefaqs_url>http://www.gamefaqs.com/gameboy/563296-super-mario-land-3-wario-land</gamefaqs_url>
		<mobygames_url>http://www.mobygames.com/game/gameboy/wario-land-super-mario-land-3</mobygames_url>
		<giantbomb_url>http://www.giantbomb.com/wario-land-super-mario-land-3/3030-19225/</giantbomb_url>
		<consolegrid_url>http://consolegrid.com/games/7673</consolegrid_url>
		<boxart1>B3bA02i.png</boxart1>
		<boxart2>Q5yWIQi.jpg</boxart2>
		<boxart3>KhfOM79.png</boxart3>
		<boxart4>Ry40u5I.jpg</boxart4>
		<boxart5>nYORM8s.jpg</boxart5>
		<boxart6>ZfzrzEZ.jpg</boxart6>
		<boxart7>qU7101A.jpg</boxart7>
		<boxart8>suxKXap.jpg</boxart8>
		<boxart9>T6qIxGf.jpg</boxart9>
		<boxart10>BHpefQo.jpg</boxart10>
		<snapshot1>aMMMBZ3.gif</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>rFgQNva.gif</snapshot2>
		<snapshot3>7z3cyUZ.gif</snapshot3>
		<snapshot4>UKP89m5.gif</snapshot4>
		<snapshot5>x7H6Mqi.gif</snapshot5>
		<snapshot6>UhUMuF1.png</snapshot6>
		<snapshot7>DjySB8R.png</snapshot7>
		<snapshot8>wJLrPR8.png</snapshot8>
		<snapshot9>ycviyKD.png</snapshot9>
		<snapshot10>ahmKlDg.png</snapshot10>
		<fanart1>8Ybb5O5.jpg</fanart1>
		<fanart2>Tk8ChYC.jpg</fanart2>
		<banner1>QFyaLhx.png</banner1>
	</game>
	<game name="Wario Land II (USA, Europe) (SGB Enhanced)">
		<description>24.  Wario Land II (USA, Europe) (SGB Enhanced)</description>
		<rom crc="9C54358D" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Nintendo%20-%20Game%20Boy.zip/Nintendo%20-%20Game%20Boy%2FWario%20Land%20II%20%28USA%2C%20Europe%29%20%28SGB%20Enhanced%29.zip" sha1="C65820B2E52D00E6CE60E0A432FAB002FEC4386F" size="400646" />
		<title_clean>Wario Land II</title_clean>
		<plot>[CR][B]Plot:[/B][CR]Title screen for Wario Land II on the GBC.[CR]One morning while Wario is sleeping in his castle, Captain Syrup and her Black Sugar Gang sneak into his home. The invaders manage to steal all of Wario's treasure he had collected in the first Wario Land game and flood his home by leaving a large water faucet in his basement running. During the raid, the Pirate Gooms accidentally set off Wario's giant alarm clock, but make their escape before he begins stirring. Eventually Wario wakes up and figures out what Syrup and her Gooms have done, setting out to find them. He pursues the Brown Sugar Gang across the varied areas outside of his castle in the hopes of having his treasure returned and gaining his revenge against the intruders.[CR][B]Gameplay:[/B][CR]Dungeons! Giant snakes! Giant snakes in dungeons![CR]Wario Land 2 is noticeably different from the first Wario Land game. The most notable difference is that Wario is now invulnerable, and is instead susceptible to different effects from enemy effects. For instance if an enemy stomps on Wario's head, he might be flattened, enabling him to cross gaps he might otherwise have fallen through. Of course some enemies are just nuisances and won't help Wario in any way, but regardless an enemy will never cause Wario to die. This change emphasizes puzzle solving and platforming rather than traditional survival.[CR]The game has several branching level paths that change how the game's storyline plays out, many of which have their own variation of the game's ending. Once the player has completed one of the endings, they can select any stage they have completed and see which treasures they have and have not collected. In order to see the game's "true" ending, the player has to collect every treasure available in the game and complete the entire picture panel that appears after a level is completed.[CR][B]Stages:[/B][CR]Each world, or chapter, consists of five stages and one boss (usually). With only 25 of 50 stages being available with the standard playthrough, searching for hidden level exits adds to the replayability of the game.Chapter 1: One Noisy Morning[CR]The first chapter takes place in Wario's castle and dungeon, kicking out his invaders and doing some damage control. Basic gameplay mechanics are introduced. The very first level also features the most fiendishly hidden secret level exit in the game.Chapter 2: SS Tea Cup[CR]Chapter 2 features the outskirts of Wario's Castle and a return to Captain Syrup's flagship, the SS Tea Cup. This chapter includes an escort mission, of sorts, involving Wario's prize hen, and water/nautical themed levels. The boss of the chapter is Bobo, also familiar from Wario Land 1.Chapter 3: Maze Woods[CR]A heavily forested area, several of the Maze Woods levels are arguably the most punitive, requiring above average reaction skills from the player. The Puffy Wario form is introduced, as is flying by owl.Chapter 4: In Town[CR]An urban themed environment, complete with breaking-and-entering shenanigans! Culminates in a basketball showdown with a giant rabbit, of all things.Chapter 5: Syrup Castle[CR]As the (ordinarily) final chapter, the completely rebuilt Syrup Castle is another castle environment filled with traps and hidden areas. Tricky platforming a puzzles abound, but you can finally confront Captain Syrup and her floating bomb deployment platform in an elaborate multi-stage fight! Well, okay, two stages. Requiring 2 hits each. Still, with her defeat Wario can demolish Syrup's tower a second time, and reclaim his stolen loot.Secret Chapter 1: Invade Wario CastleWario sleeps like a log.[CR]As mentioned, the entrance to the very first secret chapter is fiendishly hidden, and nearly impossible to intentionally reach. Hidden in the first level of the game, you must simply... do nothing. As Wario starts off asleep, simply refraining from touching any buttons will leave him in his slumber, ending the level soon after. In this alternate route, Wario was never awakened by his alarm clock, and Syrup's gang simply toss Wario out and move in! This exit is not reachable the first time you play the game, and can only be accessed after you beat it once, possibly adding to the confusion. The chapter is heavy on the castle theme, as ends with a showdown with Syrup and an armor-plated, radio controlled, robotic giant spear man.Secret Chapter 2: Go To The Cellar[CR]In this alternate route, following the first chapter, Wario takes a short-cut to Maze Woods through the dungeons and caves beneath his castle, meaning the levels are subterranean in theme. Most of these levels are filled with underground monsters and ghosts, although one does take place on a train very similar to the one Wario travels on during the "In Town" chapter. The area's final boss is a repeat of a fight which took place in the original Wario Land, which pits Wario against a giant bull who wants to knock him off of a platform.Secret Chapter 3: Ruins At the Bottom of the Sea[CR]If Wario stumbles upon the giant cork blocking a leak in the SS Tea Cup, he may destroy it, sinking the ship with all hands. Luckily, they are able to emerge in a series of ancient underwater ruins filled with ancient traps and ancient treasure, and so on. The chapter diverges at the fourth level, allowing Wario to continue down the standard path again or go on to the fifth level, containing a game-end boss. This time, Syrup has been captured by a nefarious self-inflatable newt, whose behind Wario kicks, along with Syrup, for good measure.Secret Chapter 4: Mysterious FactoryThis factory does not observe any occupational safety regulations.[CR]Accessible from the factory level in Town, Wario follows Syrup into her hideout in a seemingly purposeless and highly dangerous industrial complex. Get ready for some intense conveyor belt action!Secret Chapter 5: Uncanny Mansion[CR]Also an alternate route from Town, Wario tracks Syrup down in a spooky haunted mansion, filled with a number of devilish puzzles and challenges. The end boss is a slimy ghost with Syrup in his clutches. After defeating him, Wario spots his stolen treasure, but falls down a hidden trap door! Seemingly endless, Wario keeps falling until, (phew!) he wakes up in his bed. It was all a dream! And in a twist on the usual credits sequence, which shows Wario running home with his treasure, we are shown a hot air balloon with Syrup's insignia flying to Wario's castle. Looks like the dream came true.The Really Final Chapter: Steal the Syrup Treasure![CR]Collecting every single treasure and map piece unlocks the true final level: Syrup's treasure vault! A bizarre and surreal environment, this time challenge level tests every skill you've learned and introduces a couple new ones in this challenging and worthy final stage. As it turns out, the final boss is... the giant spear man. Last line of defense or the puppet master? We may never know.[CR][B]Power-ups:[/B][CR]All wound up.[CR]While Wario may be invincible this time around, Wario Land 2 introduces many transformations that change Wario's abilities. Often the player must use these temporary forms to solve platforming challenges, or avoid gaining them to pass a room.Fat Wario[CR]After being force-fed cake by rogue chefs, Wario swells to an impressive size. His speed and jumping is severely restricted, but he now breaks blocks by simply jumping onto them, and crushes enemies underfoot.Flat Wario[CR]Being flattened by a stone idol turns Wario comically flat. He becomes defenseless but can lazily drift through the air like a sheet of paper, allowing him to cross chasms and fit into small gaps, as well as crossing holes in the floor he would otherwise fall through.Puffy Wario[CR]Wario is highly allergic to bee stings! Being stung makes Wario's face puff up and apparently fill with helium, causing him to float to the ceiling.Spring Wario[CR]Being hit by a hammer turns Wario into a human spring, turning him defenseless but allowing him to jump much higher.Zombie Wario[CR]Touching a ghost or being infected by a fellow zombie turns Wario undead. He loses the ability to jump, but can now fall through thin floors.[CR][B]Cheat:[/B] Boss Battles[CR]Beat the game with 100% status with all treasure and map pieces. The levels  with a boss will have a skull nearby them on the map, marked with an arrow. Choose one of these levels. Then at the name of the level screen, hold Down and press the A button. You will now go directly to the boss.[CR][B]Cheat:[/B] 100% Completion Unlockables[CR]To get the 100% completion, get every treasure and beat every level, this includes all side-levels and then two new areas are unlocked. One is a bonus game which has nothing to do with Wario, and the other is a very tough level that times how fast you can beat it.[CR][B]Cheat:[/B] Play the hidden chapter.[CR]Start a new game without waking Wario up, let the pirates knock him out of the castle. The game will begin at a hidden chapter.</plot>
		<releasedate>14/3/1998</releasedate>
		<year>1998</year>
		<genre>Action</genre>
		<studio>Nintendo of America Inc.</studio>
		<nplayers>1</nplayers>
		<perspective>Platform</perspective>
		<rating>3.7</rating>
		<ESRB>E - Everyone</ESRB>
		<videoid>P6DS1LkTEiE</videoid>
		<thegamesdb_id>11547</thegamesdb_id>
		<gamefaqs_url>http://www.gamefaqs.com/gameboy/562638-wario-land-ii</gamefaqs_url>
		<mobygames_url>http://www.mobygames.com/game/gameboy/wario-land-ii</mobygames_url>
		<giantbomb_url>http://www.giantbomb.com/wario-land-ii/3030-13721/</giantbomb_url>
		<consolegrid_url>http://consolegrid.com/games/5519</consolegrid_url>
		<boxart1>QpS8YqP.jpg</boxart1>
		<boxart2>s16PvE4.jpg</boxart2>
		<boxart3>DNS7ERF.jpg</boxart3>
		<boxart4>sLJonnR.jpg</boxart4>
		<boxart5>h3lEGjg.jpg</boxart5>
		<boxart6>flJCjJa.jpg</boxart6>
		<boxart7>FwX1Uvk.jpg</boxart7>
		<snapshot1>M4so262.png</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>3SqUJ2i.png</snapshot2>
		<snapshot3>KCcMClG.png</snapshot3>
		<snapshot4>FtxwpK5.png</snapshot4>
		<snapshot5>mPbUp7p.png</snapshot5>
		<snapshot6>taXT0xA.png</snapshot6>
		<snapshot7>tH4wb2X.png</snapshot7>
		<snapshot8>E7PAlZC.png</snapshot8>
		<snapshot9>uMTaGar.png</snapshot9>
		<snapshot10>WGTChb6.png</snapshot10>
		<fanart1>TsSLVRb.jpg</fanart1>
		<banner1>oeKQRFU.png</banner1>
	</game>
	<game name="Final Fantasy Adventure (USA)">
		<description>23.  Final Fantasy Adventure (USA)</description>
		<rom crc="18C78B3A" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Nintendo%20-%20Game%20Boy.zip/Nintendo%20-%20Game%20Boy%2FFinal%20Fantasy%20Adventure%20%28USA%29.zip" sha1="8B93C55EE2660C60CF86DD70058F96ACE98782C8" size="159533" />
		<title_clean>Final Fantasy Adventure</title_clean>
		<plot>Is it really a true Final Fantasy adventure? Who cares. The Game Boy version of the long-running series might technically be the first game in the Mana series, but it still managed to recreate the wonderful isometric game play of Zelda with role-playing battles that required strategy and experience, not just hacking and slashing with the latest weapon you’ve found.</plot>
		<releasedate>14/11/1991</releasedate>
		<year>1991</year>
		<genre>RPG</genre>
		<studio>Square Soft</studio>
		<nplayers>1</nplayers>
		<perspective>Top-Down</perspective>
		<rating>3.8</rating>
		<videoid>di5Vhk3AEUc</videoid>
		<thegamesdb_id>3182</thegamesdb_id>
		<gamefaqs_url>http://www.gamefaqs.com/gameboy/563272-final-fantasy-adventure</gamefaqs_url>
		<mobygames_url>http://www.mobygames.com/game/gameboy/final-fantasy-adventure</mobygames_url>
		<giantbomb_url>http://www.giantbomb.com/final-fantasy-adventure/3030-9971/</giantbomb_url>
		<consolegrid_url>http://consolegrid.com/games/6829</consolegrid_url>
		<boxart1>Uvj5E4J.png</boxart1>
		<boxart2>h4I4mIg.jpg</boxart2>
		<boxart3>28jVJTD.jpg</boxart3>
		<boxart4>o50aotq.jpg</boxart4>
		<boxart5>K9wlfdK.jpg</boxart5>
		<boxart6>SBdWDRn.jpg</boxart6>
		<boxart7>ZHoydAM.jpg</boxart7>
		<boxart8>UbAiWEF.jpg</boxart8>
		<snapshot1>g79NZZa.jpg</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>9t90N3f.jpg</snapshot2>
		<snapshot3>7YTgWAJ.gif</snapshot3>
		<snapshot4>pMMT5wz.png</snapshot4>
		<snapshot5>RUhH6aI.png</snapshot5>
		<snapshot6>6w4qA9d.gif</snapshot6>
		<snapshot7>hO1tHuL.gif</snapshot7>
		<snapshot8>Z2PklZf.gif</snapshot8>
		<snapshot9>aeKkCC6.gif</snapshot9>
		<snapshot10>rdMVJeJ.gif</snapshot10>
		<banner1>OPhxTVq.png</banner1>
	</game>
	<game name="Final Fantasy Legend, The (USA)">
		<description>22.  Final Fantasy Legend (USA)</description>
		<rom crc="8046148F" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Nintendo%20-%20Game%20Boy.zip/Nintendo%20-%20Game%20Boy%2FFinal%20Fantasy%20Legend%2C%20The%20%28USA%29.zip" sha1="901DFC83C72E172D35A376835807FC788444A9BB" size="95803" />
		<title_clean>Final Fantasy Legend, The</title_clean>
		<plot>[CR][B]Overview:[/B][CR]You command a party of four warriors who journey through a variety of different worlds, connected by a central tower, in order to discover the tower's secrets--which, reportedly, lead to paradise. Each of the worlds is terrorized by a Fiend--a monster of great power--and the party is compelled to seek out and defeat these fiends, saving each world's denizens in the process. The final floor of the tower reveals a startling truth about the nature of the Fiends, the tower, and your party's involvement in all of the events that unfold throughout the game.[CR]Part of the SaGa series, SaGa--or Final Fantasy Legend, as it was known in North America--started some trends that repeated throughout the franchise. Instead of equipping a single weapon for attacking purposes, as was the case in the core Final Fantasy franchise, SaGa had each character equipping a "bag" of weapons and items, as described below in the Gameplay section. The series' method of character growth through taking actions and eating monster meat, as opposed to gaining experience levels, also originated here. (The "do X more and become better at Y" methodology did find its way into Final Fantasy II.) However, the multi-character, "non-linear" method of progression didn't really begin until the Super Famicom entries in the series, which were the Romancing SaGa games.</plot>
		<releasedate>30/9/1990</releasedate>
		<year>1989</year>
		<genre>RPG</genre>
		<studio>Square Soft</studio>
		<nplayers>1</nplayers>
		<perspective>Top-Down</perspective>
		<rating>3.2</rating>
		<ESRB>T - Teen</ESRB>
		<videoid>tbkQ-LMDPT4</videoid>
		<thegamesdb_id>3183</thegamesdb_id>
		<gamefaqs_url>http://www.gamefaqs.com/gameboy/563273-the-final-fantasy-legend</gamefaqs_url>
		<mobygames_url>http://www.mobygames.com/game/gameboy/final-fantasy-legend</mobygames_url>
		<giantbomb_url>http://www.giantbomb.com/the-final-fantasy-legend/3030-18601/</giantbomb_url>
		<consolegrid_url>http://consolegrid.com/games/8023</consolegrid_url>
		<boxart1>pdMKY0Y.png</boxart1>
		<boxart2>tiNVBhf.jpg</boxart2>
		<boxart3>wKYHHBU.jpg</boxart3>
		<boxart4>Vo3V7dS.jpg</boxart4>
		<boxart5>dHdPzfO.jpg</boxart5>
		<snapshot1>MyXQxrS.gif</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>SMC9N2L.gif</snapshot2>
		<snapshot3>3niVjQG.gif</snapshot3>
		<snapshot4>78jhGOR.gif</snapshot4>
		<snapshot5>waboF7r.gif</snapshot5>
		<snapshot6>RbVRtAI.gif</snapshot6>
		<snapshot7>1BJhoWt.jpg</snapshot7>
		<snapshot8>YhTdANQ.jpg</snapshot8>
		<snapshot9>kWpt2xt.jpg</snapshot9>
		<snapshot10>MRx7NWj.jpg</snapshot10>
		<banner1>IhjrS76.jpg</banner1>
	</game>
	<game name="Mega Man - Dr. Wily's Revenge (USA)">
		<description>21.  Mega Man - Dr. Wily's Revenge (USA)</description>
		<rom crc="47E70E08" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Nintendo%20-%20Game%20Boy.zip/Nintendo%20-%20Game%20Boy%2FMega%20Man%20-%20Dr.%20Wily%27s%20Revenge%20%28USA%29.zip" sha1="277EDB3C844E812BA4B3EB9A96C9C30414541858" size="114016" />
		<title_clean>Mega Man - Dr. Wily's Revenge</title_clean>
		<plot>Mega Man’s first Game Boy outing is probably remembered by kids as being their first real introduction to ulcers, because to this day I don’t think I’ve ever played a more challenging platformer. I can already feel my hands getting sweaty at the thought of tackling Wily’s robot henchmen again, but 20+ years of additional gaming experience should make it a breeze this time... right?</plot>
		<releasedate>14/12/1991</releasedate>
		<year>1991</year>
		<genre>Action</genre>
		<studio>Capcom</studio>
		<nplayers>1</nplayers>
		<perspective>3rd-Person</perspective>
		<rating>3.9</rating>
		<ESRB>E - Everyone</ESRB>
		<videoid>yXiASzQjtcM</videoid>
		<thegamesdb_id>13078</thegamesdb_id>
		<gamefaqs_url>http://www.gamefaqs.com/gameboy/563283-mega-man-dr-wilys-revenge</gamefaqs_url>
		<mobygames_url>http://www.mobygames.com/game/gameboy/mega-man-dr-wilys-revenge</mobygames_url>
		<giantbomb_url>http://www.giantbomb.com/mega-man-dr-wilys-revenge/3030-17134/</giantbomb_url>
		<consolegrid_url>http://consolegrid.com/games/10728</consolegrid_url>
		<boxart1>IsDQwfF.jpg</boxart1>
		<boxart2>3IpGEzl.jpg</boxart2>
		<boxart3>GkQgdsr.jpg</boxart3>
		<boxart4>uCei5ND.jpg</boxart4>
		<boxart5>mj86lAF.jpg</boxart5>
		<boxart6>VYLUVw6.jpg</boxart6>
		<snapshot1>J7crkj9.png</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>kJkSfmC.png</snapshot2>
		<snapshot3>rssbz06.png</snapshot3>
		<snapshot4>NgyfIs7.png</snapshot4>
		<snapshot5>7dOrPCP.png</snapshot5>
		<snapshot6>AV1jEdP.png</snapshot6>
		<snapshot7>wzCH3fb.png</snapshot7>
		<snapshot8>THm74dJ.png</snapshot8>
		<snapshot9>KH7Ec2w.jpg</snapshot9>
		<snapshot10>GnoFm8h.jpg</snapshot10>
		<banner1>G8o55VL.jpg</banner1>
	</game>
	<game name="Mega Man V (USA) (SGB Enhanced)">
		<description>20.  Mega Man V (USA) (SGB Enhanced)</description>
		<rom crc="72E6D21D" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Nintendo%20-%20Game%20Boy.zip/Nintendo%20-%20Game%20Boy%2FMega%20Man%20V%20%28USA%29%20%28SGB%20Enhanced%29.zip" sha1="9A7DA0E4D3F49E4A0B94E85CD64E28A687D81260" size="301539" />
		<title_clean>Mega Man V</title_clean>
		<plot>Equipped with a new Mega Arm and saddled with a robo-assistant named Tango, Mega Man was sent on an entirely original adventure. Thanks to artist Keiji Inafune's Stardroids vision, the series entered fresh territory while keeping a solid foot in its time-honored Mega Man gameplay. All said, Mega Man V was different; and by that point in the robo-warrior's career, different was good.</plot>
		<releasedate>14/9/1994</releasedate>
		<year>1994</year>
		<genre>Action</genre>
		<studio>Capcom</studio>
		<nplayers>1</nplayers>
		<perspective>Side-Scrolling</perspective>
		<rating>4.8</rating>
		<ESRB>E - Everyone</ESRB>
		<videoid>oy__jgK_k9k</videoid>
		<thegamesdb_id>13077</thegamesdb_id>
		<gamefaqs_url>http://www.gamefaqs.com/gameboy/563282-mega-man-v</gamefaqs_url>
		<mobygames_url>http://www.mobygames.com/game/gameboy/mega-man-v</mobygames_url>
		<giantbomb_url>http://www.giantbomb.com/mega-man-v/3030-15447/</giantbomb_url>
		<consolegrid_url>http://consolegrid.com/games/8025</consolegrid_url>
		<boxart1>FIUVzKf.png</boxart1>
		<boxart2>GaZbTVO.jpg</boxart2>
		<boxart3>GZgjER7.jpg</boxart3>
		<boxart4>PH8l4Up.jpg</boxart4>
		<snapshot1>eIXngZr.png</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>tetLJH5.png</snapshot2>
		<snapshot3>9pU3yds.png</snapshot3>
		<snapshot4>rhdqt2j.png</snapshot4>
		<snapshot5>d9K339a.png</snapshot5>
		<snapshot6>ax7CXNw.png</snapshot6>
		<snapshot7>40ltkkq.png</snapshot7>
		<snapshot8>9vMSh83.png</snapshot8>
		<snapshot9>inmA1oG.png</snapshot9>
		<snapshot10>iVjNHT5.jpg</snapshot10>
		<banner1>9SC9Eu4.png</banner1>
	</game>
	<game name="Blades of Steel (USA)">
		<description>19.  Blades of Steel (USA)</description>
		<rom crc="E81C9FB9" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Nintendo%20-%20Game%20Boy.zip/Nintendo%20-%20Game%20Boy%2FBlades%20of%20Steel%20%28USA%29.zip" sha1="82761DBF5ABE276F8E0C82F575356AED87155141" size="79596" />
		<title_clean>Blades of Steel</title_clean>
		<plot>I can pretend like I asked for Blades of Steel for Christmas because I loved hockey as a kid. But the reality is that before EA became the juggernaut of sports games, Konami’s Blades of Steel included fighting, so it was an easy to way to sneak a video game with hand-to-hand combat past your parents, before we all became desensitized to violence.</plot>
		<releasedate>14/8/1991</releasedate>
		<year>1991</year>
		<studio>Ultra Software Corporation</studio>
		<nplayers>1</nplayers>
		<rating>3.3</rating>
		<videoid>xQ9HVfBDWqc</videoid>
		<thegamesdb_id>18308</thegamesdb_id>
		<gamefaqs_url>http://www.gamefaqs.com/gameboy/585634-blades-of-steel</gamefaqs_url>
		<mobygames_url>http://www.mobygames.com/game/gameboy/blades-of-steel</mobygames_url>
		<giantbomb_url>http://www.giantbomb.com/blades-of-steel/3030-6109/</giantbomb_url>
		<boxart1>vAQeZvW.jpg</boxart1>
		<boxart2>3JHD2MN.jpg</boxart2>
		<boxart3>4PLuOKY.jpg</boxart3>
		<snapshot1>lSIrtF0.png</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>U3z9dBL.png</snapshot2>
		<snapshot3>mQJ9hIh.png</snapshot3>
		<snapshot4>A37BcOO.png</snapshot4>
		<snapshot5>1bN8sYe.png</snapshot5>
		<snapshot6>NAiWtuC.png</snapshot6>
		<snapshot7>CdQZx8h.png</snapshot7>
		<snapshot8>NcUEPiD.png</snapshot8>
		<snapshot9>0dmXf1x.png</snapshot9>
		<snapshot10>LpTlowG.jpg</snapshot10>
	</game>
	<game name="R-Type (USA, Europe)">
		<description>18.  R-Type (USA, Europe)</description>
		<rom crc="E0F23FC0" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Nintendo%20-%20Game%20Boy.zip/Nintendo%20-%20Game%20Boy%2FR-Type%20%28USA%2C%20Europe%29.zip" sha1="28531A4EB668477DF98CAF0E87CEDC0E5FDFE53B" size="61404" />
		<title_clean>R-Type</title_clean>
		<plot>[CR][B]Overview:[/B][CR]R-Type is a classic side scrolling shoot-em up game produced by Irem Corp. The game was first released to Japanese arcades in July 1987. The player controls a spacecraft and is tasked with defending humanity against the alien life forms known as Bydo. R-Type is infamously known for its extreme difficulty.[CR]R-Type was originally released in the Arcades and became a major early hit for Irem. It was eventually ported to many home computers and consoles of the era, with the unusual exception of the NES (a bootleg Chinese cart exists, however). The PC Engine of R-Type was split across two releases, but the US TG-16 version manages to fit the whole game onto one HuCard. This TG16 version is also the one that was added to the Wii's Virtual Console in 2006.[CR]R-Type also saw multiple sequels and spin-offs, as well as inspiring many future horizontal-scrolling shoot 'em ups.[CR][B]Gameplay:[/B][CR]Set in the 22nd century, the game takes place in the Bydo Empire. The player must make their way through the 8 merciless levels and defend mankind from the evil attackers. Bydo Dobkeratops - Boss of the first level[CR]The Bydo are biologically engineered weapons created by mankind to be used against their enemies in their quest for universal domination. This plan backfired however and the Bydo began to attack their creators. [CR] The Ship [CR]The player pilots a ship called the R-9a "Arrowhead". The ship is named for its distinctive shape and is the 9th model of the R series of star fighter. The Force[CR]The R-9a "Arrowhead" can be equipped with an indestructible living weapon called "The Force". The force, a spherical pod that can be attached to the ship, is made of Bydo flesh and can absorb energy in order to increase in power. To obtain the force, the player must obtain a weapon power up. The force will appear behind the players ship and they can obtain the force by flying into it. [CR]The force acts as the ship's weapon system and will fire in the whatever direction it is facing. The force also acts as a shield and can be used to block incoming enemy attacks. [CR]The force has three levels of power. Collecting weapon power ups increases the power level of the force. The forces visual appearance changes as it increases in power.Red - A powerful counter-air laser beam that fires horizontally.Blue - Three thin laser beams. One forward firing and two that fire at a 45 degree angle from the front of the ship These beams rebound off walls.Yellow - Two flame beams that fire above and below the ship. These flames can travel along the ground or walls to destroy enemies.[CR]The force can be controlled by the user by using the force button. By pressing the force button, the user can attach the force to the front or the rear of the ship. They can also propel the force forward to execute an attack called the "force ram". Wave Cannon[CR]The R9-a is equipped with a beam weapon called the wave cannon. Holding the fire button will charge up the wave cannon and increase its power. Wave Cannon[CR]    [CR][B]Cheat:[/B] Sketching Program[CR]On the High Scores Screen, press:[CR]Left, Down, A and B together.[CR]A program called ''De Souza Editor'' will appear.[CR][B]Cheat:[/B] Secret Menu[CR]On the main menu press Down + Select to make a secret menu with new options apear.</plot>
		<releasedate>14/5/1991</releasedate>
		<year>1991</year>
		<genre>Action</genre>
		<studio>Irem Corp.</studio>
		<nplayers>1</nplayers>
		<perspective>Side-Scrolling</perspective>
		<rating>3.4</rating>
		<videoid>mNx9g_xQhTM</videoid>
		<thegamesdb_id>21709</thegamesdb_id>
		<gamefaqs_url>http://www.gamefaqs.com/gameboy/585869-r-type</gamefaqs_url>
		<mobygames_url>http://www.mobygames.com/game/gameboy/r-type</mobygames_url>
		<giantbomb_url>http://www.giantbomb.com/r-type/3030-13745/</giantbomb_url>
		<consolegrid_url>http://consolegrid.com/games/7324</consolegrid_url>
		<boxart1>Gg2x4fF.jpg</boxart1>
		<boxart2>eSRqYM3.jpg</boxart2>
		<snapshot1>VhfMdLE.gif</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>yF6HCvF.gif</snapshot2>
		<snapshot3>i3ERXHT.gif</snapshot3>
		<snapshot4>EpbnJBT.gif</snapshot4>
		<snapshot5>2j2H3yS.gif</snapshot5>
		<snapshot6>80AEKKD.gif</snapshot6>
		<snapshot7>Bc7Ehlk.png</snapshot7>
		<snapshot8>D5goljw.png</snapshot8>
		<snapshot9>5L3caJP.png</snapshot9>
		<snapshot10>y6gV4Xq.jpg</snapshot10>
		<banner1>05Wk9M9.png</banner1>
	</game>
	<game name="Mario's Picross (USA, Europe) (SGB Enhanced)">
		<description>17.  Mario's Picross (USA, Europe) (SGB Enhanced)</description>
		<rom crc="F2D652AD" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Nintendo%20-%20Game%20Boy.zip/Nintendo%20-%20Game%20Boy%2FMario%27s%20Picross%20%28USA%2C%20Europe%29%20%28SGB%20Enhanced%29.zip" sha1="9712F37171B8A0CDC99A60170EA7B2AED161195E" size="76263" />
		<title_clean>Mario's Picross</title_clean>
		<plot>Playing Tetris is fun, but its never-ending onslaught of falling tetrominoes is far from relaxing. When I really need some stress relief, I always turn to a puzzler called Picross, which the Game Boy introduced to many of us. It’s less about reflexes, and more about genuine puzzle solving that keeps you motivated to complete each brain teaser (and the next) to reveal a mystery image.</plot>
		<releasedate>14/3/1995</releasedate>
		<year>1995</year>
		<studio>Nintendo of America Inc.</studio>
		<nplayers>1</nplayers>
		<rating>3.8</rating>
		<videoid>BT5cSu9QhPc</videoid>
		<thegamesdb_id>18863</thegamesdb_id>
		<gamefaqs_url>http://www.gamefaqs.com/gameboy/563278-marios-picross</gamefaqs_url>
		<mobygames_url>http://www.mobygames.com/game/gameboy/marios-picross</mobygames_url>
		<giantbomb_url>http://www.giantbomb.com/marios-picross/3030-6316/</giantbomb_url>
		<consolegrid_url>http://consolegrid.com/games/10557</consolegrid_url>
		<boxart1>V3KDH5P.jpg</boxart1>
		<boxart2>Da7eW6T.jpg</boxart2>
		<boxart3>BS53SYp.jpg</boxart3>
		<boxart4>4qfEJJX.jpg</boxart4>
		<boxart5>naoOiS1.jpg</boxart5>
		<snapshot1>y2yGhpW.png</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>zD7TkAn.png</snapshot2>
		<snapshot3>309ayoQ.png</snapshot3>
		<snapshot4>tGpiCDS.png</snapshot4>
		<snapshot5>CY7gg9h.png</snapshot5>
		<snapshot6>suGSYfc.png</snapshot6>
		<snapshot7>hg2QJ4L.png</snapshot7>
		<snapshot8>JncUy7P.png</snapshot8>
		<snapshot9>KpdoImZ.png</snapshot9>
		<snapshot10>nWmhToS.png</snapshot10>
		<banner1>y0yBCfP.jpg</banner1>
	</game>
	<game name="Teenage Mutant Ninja Turtles - Fall of the Foot Clan (USA)">
		<description>16.  Teenage Mutant Ninja Turtles - Fall of the Foot Clan (USA)</description>
		<rom crc="5A6984C3" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Nintendo%20-%20Game%20Boy.zip/Nintendo%20-%20Game%20Boy%2FTeenage%20Mutant%20Ninja%20Turtles%20-%20Fall%20of%20the%20Foot%20Clan%20%28USA%29.zip" sha1="6E8A43BC0C18129D74FF3322658A2CE8C24D201E" size="84134" />
		<title_clean>Teenage Mutant Ninja Turtles - Fall of the Foot Clan</title_clean>
		<plot>I can still remember the game stuttering and struggling to spit out frames while Michelangelo battled the foot clan in a sewer. But it didn’t matter, because Teenage Mutant Ninja Turtles: Fall of the Foot Clan hit the Game Boy at the height of TMNT’s popularity, and delivered a solid take on the arcade version of the game that didn’t require a constant supply of quarters—just AA batteries.</plot>
		<releasedate>3/8/1990</releasedate>
		<year>1990</year>
		<genre>Action</genre>
		<studio>Ultra Software Corporation</studio>
		<nplayers>1</nplayers>
		<perspective>Platform</perspective>
		<rating>3.5</rating>
		<ESRB>E10+ - Everyone 10+</ESRB>
		<videoid>L7iWHlu8vG0</videoid>
		<thegamesdb_id>6024</thegamesdb_id>
		<gamefaqs_url>http://www.gamefaqs.com/gameboy/585954-teenage-mutant-ninja-turtles-fall-of-the-foot-clan</gamefaqs_url>
		<mobygames_url>http://www.mobygames.com/game/gameboy/teenage-mutant-ninja-turtles-fall-of-the-foot-clan</mobygames_url>
		<giantbomb_url>http://www.giantbomb.com/teenage-mutant-ninja-turtles-fall-of-the-foot-clan/3030-15797/</giantbomb_url>
		<consolegrid_url>http://consolegrid.com/games/7289</consolegrid_url>
		<boxart1>Vt7g5wC.png</boxart1>
		<boxart2>n7fMvIV.jpg</boxart2>
		<boxart3>ccB0jk1.jpg</boxart3>
		<boxart4>8GesOJI.jpg</boxart4>
		<boxart5>3dEtc9q.jpg</boxart5>
		<snapshot1>VbFygdP.gif</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>b0jahcT.gif</snapshot2>
		<snapshot3>rQ932Pn.gif</snapshot3>
		<snapshot4>7NZLlI0.gif</snapshot4>
		<snapshot5>cSRxnDJ.gif</snapshot5>
		<snapshot6>D7CtJ45.gif</snapshot6>
		<snapshot7>Ei215O9.gif</snapshot7>
		<snapshot8>guW53z7.gif</snapshot8>
		<snapshot9>4OQbCC9.gif</snapshot9>
		<snapshot10>n6CQCaa.jpg</snapshot10>
		<fanart1>YKaOaOM.jpg</fanart1>
		<fanart2>ME3RE9D.jpg</fanart2>
		<fanart3>Vu5QZg4.jpg</fanart3>
		<banner1>2Tc7kSh.png</banner1>
	</game>
	<game name="Metroid II - Return of Samus (World)">
		<description>15.  Metroid II - Return of Samus (World)</description>
		<rom crc="DEE05370" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Nintendo%20-%20Game%20Boy.zip/Nintendo%20-%20Game%20Boy%2FMetroid%20II%20-%20Return%20of%20Samus%20%28World%29.zip" sha1="74A2FAD86B9A4C013149B1E214BC4600EFB1066D" size="110484" />
		<title_clean>Metroid II - Return of Samus</title_clean>
		<plot>It’s probably against the laws of the gaming universe to not include a Metroid game on a Nintendo Classic Edition console. Metroid II - Return of Samus falls in between the two retro titles already re-released by Nintendo, and managed to squeeze some impressive graphics onto the Game Boy’s dull green and gray display—which somehow added to Metroid II’s moody cave-exploring gameplay.</plot>
		<releasedate>14/11/1991</releasedate>
		<year>1991</year>
		<genre>Action</genre>
		<studio>Nintendo of America Inc.</studio>
		<nplayers>1</nplayers>
		<perspective>3rd-Person</perspective>
		<rating>3.8</rating>
		<ESRB>E - Everyone</ESRB>
		<videoid>AF1C0xZxBOw</videoid>
		<thegamesdb_id>6771</thegamesdb_id>
		<gamefaqs_url>http://www.gamefaqs.com/gameboy/585799-metroid-ii-return-of-samus</gamefaqs_url>
		<mobygames_url>http://www.mobygames.com/game/gameboy/metroid-ii-return-of-samus</mobygames_url>
		<giantbomb_url>http://www.giantbomb.com/metroid-ii-return-of-samus/3030-5708/</giantbomb_url>
		<consolegrid_url>http://consolegrid.com/games/6936</consolegrid_url>
		<boxart1>X86SRwF.jpg</boxart1>
		<boxart2>FPp0zW7.jpg</boxart2>
		<boxart3>XU3ConA.jpg</boxart3>
		<boxart4>bxXQmDq.jpg</boxart4>
		<boxart5>UxLQ9BX.jpg</boxart5>
		<boxart6>mpatsmR.jpg</boxart6>
		<boxart7>I7QrMsn.jpg</boxart7>
		<boxart8>Vokyrmm.jpg</boxart8>
		<snapshot1>9Aa3ar3.gif</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>exXRpEU.gif</snapshot2>
		<snapshot3>HdIlc6p.gif</snapshot3>
		<snapshot4>woBrXqG.gif</snapshot4>
		<snapshot5>AxOrykD.gif</snapshot5>
		<snapshot6>pKvEghm.gif</snapshot6>
		<snapshot7>Q6Vw4Zq.png</snapshot7>
		<snapshot8>La6vmJj.png</snapshot8>
		<snapshot9>XYoc8mz.png</snapshot9>
		<snapshot10>scnyC70.png</snapshot10>
		<fanart1>ZHGtRYn.jpg</fanart1>
		<fanart2>ikmztwc.jpg</fanart2>
		<fanart3>87iUddS.jpg</fanart3>
		<fanart4>5zmyNMx.jpg</fanart4>
		<banner1>yMlVaXv.png</banner1>
		<clearlogo1>QnLZLGg.png</clearlogo1>
	</game>
	<game name="Castlevania - The Adventure (USA)">
		<description>14.  Castlevania - The Adventure (USA)</description>
		<rom crc="216E6AA1" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Nintendo%20-%20Game%20Boy.zip/Nintendo%20-%20Game%20Boy%2FCastlevania%20-%20The%20Adventure%20%28USA%29.zip" sha1="FD9116EFCD8EB9698F483CC5745F83B3674D7D13" size="41964" />
		<title_clean>Castlevania - The Adventure</title_clean>
		<plot>Although far better executed in Castlevania IV which is included on the SNES Classic Edition, wielding a whip is one of the highlights of the Castlevania series, and helps the first Game Boy title stand out amongst thousands of other platformers available for the console—even if you don’t actually get to play as Simon Belmont, but one of his ancestors who fought Dracula long before he was born.</plot>
		<releasedate>14/12/1989</releasedate>
		<year>1989</year>
		<genre>Action</genre>
		<studio>Konami</studio>
		<nplayers>1</nplayers>
		<perspective>Side-Scrolling</perspective>
		<rating>3.6</rating>
		<videoid>5qEZ-5FIZVc</videoid>
		<thegamesdb_id>3172</thegamesdb_id>
		<gamefaqs_url>http://www.gamefaqs.com/gameboy/585660-castlevania-the-adventure</gamefaqs_url>
		<mobygames_url>http://www.mobygames.com/game/gameboy/castlevania-the-adventure</mobygames_url>
		<giantbomb_url>http://www.giantbomb.com/castlevania-the-adventure/3030-8654/</giantbomb_url>
		<consolegrid_url>http://consolegrid.com/games/6812</consolegrid_url>
		<boxart1>ut080Wp.jpg</boxart1>
		<boxart2>i8IwwP8.jpg</boxart2>
		<boxart3>CcJpfGh.jpg</boxart3>
		<boxart4>7W1WZcH.jpg</boxart4>
		<boxart5>n47Fj8M.jpg</boxart5>
		<snapshot1>RPLnZJg.gif</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>RacQ1AP.gif</snapshot2>
		<snapshot3>klMrV6f.gif</snapshot3>
		<snapshot4>0ovDZhK.gif</snapshot4>
		<snapshot5>Sv7iD6c.gif</snapshot5>
		<snapshot6>hrKf0v7.gif</snapshot6>
		<snapshot7>v9lkIYw.gif</snapshot7>
		<snapshot8>KoYxujs.png</snapshot8>
		<snapshot9>KEWWdBG.png</snapshot9>
		<snapshot10>wbioXm7.png</snapshot10>
		<fanart1>LyZLVIr.jpg</fanart1>
		<banner1>541ZiO4.jpg</banner1>
	</game>
	<game name="Castlevania II - Belmont's Revenge (USA, Europe)">
		<description>13.  Castlevania II - Belmont's Revenge (USA, Europe)</description>
		<rom crc="8875C8FE" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Nintendo%20-%20Game%20Boy.zip/Nintendo%20-%20Game%20Boy%2FCastlevania%20II%20-%20Belmont%27s%20Revenge%20%28USA%2C%20Europe%29.zip" sha1="696B9AD1E9CFB7112977C9A7C05CF64FE8423D8A" size="89192" />
		<title_clean>Castlevania II - Belmont's Revenge</title_clean>
		<plot>Belmont's Revenge was a totally unique, Game Boy-exclusive edition that proudly carried the NES Castlevania traditions onto the portable. Sure, as a typical 2D walk-right-and-whip-baddies game, it wasn't a groundbreaking moment for the franchise. But it was a solid entry that made up for the weaker original and proved Game Boy could, on occasion, bust out a console-level experience with just four colors to back it up.</plot>
		<releasedate>14/8/1991</releasedate>
		<year>1991</year>
		<genre>Action</genre>
		<studio>Konami</studio>
		<nplayers>1</nplayers>
		<perspective>Platform</perspective>
		<rating>3.6</rating>
		<videoid>dSaorGLcjrc</videoid>
		<thegamesdb_id>3167</thegamesdb_id>
		<gamefaqs_url>http://www.gamefaqs.com/gameboy/585659-castlevania-ii-belmonts-revenge</gamefaqs_url>
		<mobygames_url>http://www.mobygames.com/game/gameboy/castlevania-ii-belmonts-revenge</mobygames_url>
		<giantbomb_url>http://www.giantbomb.com/castlevania-ii-belmonts-revenge/3030-16921/</giantbomb_url>
		<consolegrid_url>http://consolegrid.com/games/6813</consolegrid_url>
		<boxart1>vjxbyuc.png</boxart1>
		<boxart2>ZQdittK.jpg</boxart2>
		<boxart3>naKU4HT.jpg</boxart3>
		<boxart4>e6IxPV4.jpg</boxart4>
		<snapshot1>NOlnxPM.gif</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>bGHYoDN.gif</snapshot2>
		<snapshot3>unGDF1w.gif</snapshot3>
		<snapshot4>QHOAJKG.gif</snapshot4>
		<snapshot5>1mS2GBy.gif</snapshot5>
		<snapshot6>dgeQfG0.gif</snapshot6>
		<snapshot7>jWFWcNt.png</snapshot7>
		<snapshot8>JdtgmJ9.png</snapshot8>
		<snapshot9>NTobLWp.png</snapshot9>
		<snapshot10>7N60sOe.png</snapshot10>
		<banner1>DDdJUXT.jpg</banner1>
	</game>
		<game name="Gradius - The Interstellar Assault (USA)">
		<description>12.  Gradius - The Interstellar Assault (USA)</description>
		<rom crc="90F87D57" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Nintendo%20-%20Game%20Boy.zip/Nintendo%20-%20Game%20Boy%2FGradius%20-%20The%20Interstellar%20Assault%20%28USA%29.zip" sha1="7A50FDF0B8AD15556C933DF0657FAE0A2CD8BC92" size="132671" />
		<title_clean>Gradius - The Interstellar Assault</title_clean>
		<plot>[CR][B]Overview:[/B][CR]Gradius: The Interstellar Assault is a shoot 'em up developed and published by Konami for the Game Boy platform.[CR]This game lacks some characteristics of most other Gradius games, such as certain terminology, the lack of Moai imagery, and an unfamiliar soundtrack.[CR][B]Gameplay:[/B][CR]Players take control of the Vic Viper as they fight their way through the Bacterion Army in five levels. [CR]The game retains the signature Gradius power-up system. This system allows players to save power-ups to unlock more powerful powers instead of having the power-up applied instantly when picked up. These power-ups include a speed boost, missiles, double firepower, lasers, options, and a force field.[CR]A weapon select screen is displayed before the player starts. Each option has a bearing on the types of missiles, double firepower, and lasers the player can get. There are three options:Missle - Normal, Two Way, TailDouble Firepower - Normal, Twin Cannon, Twin GunLaser - Normal, Twin, Ripple[CR]</plot>
		<releasedate>14/1/1992</releasedate>
		<year>1991</year>
		<genre>Action</genre>
		<studio>Konami</studio>
		<nplayers>1</nplayers>
		<perspective>Side-Scrolling</perspective>
		<rating>4.1</rating>
		<videoid>3IKUa6qwcSk</videoid>
		<thegamesdb_id>21646</thegamesdb_id>
		<gamefaqs_url>http://www.gamefaqs.com/gameboy/585734-gradius-the-interstellar-assault</gamefaqs_url>
		<mobygames_url>http://www.mobygames.com/game/gameboy/gradius-the-interstellar-assault</mobygames_url>
		<giantbomb_url>http://www.giantbomb.com/gradius-the-interstellar-assault/3030-4072/</giantbomb_url>
		<boxart1>5zuzGPN.jpg</boxart1>
		<boxart2>GxcxS93.jpg</boxart2>
		<boxart3>FLuMOMi.jpg</boxart3>
		<boxart4>KxQHqPd.jpg</boxart4>
		<snapshot1>PoRbx2i.gif</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>F2TKujY.gif</snapshot2>
		<snapshot3>SWbt2zn.gif</snapshot3>
		<snapshot4>oYLKDP7.gif</snapshot4>
		<snapshot5>YKrVszL.gif</snapshot5>
		<snapshot6>jizm9Mu.gif</snapshot6>
		<snapshot7>Am8leYY.gif</snapshot7>
		<snapshot8>79JWLwI.jpg</snapshot8>
		<snapshot9>4P1djTs.jpg</snapshot9>
		<snapshot10>QtoU9s8.jpg</snapshot10>
	</game>
		<game name="Double Dragon (USA, Europe)">
		<description>11.  Double Dragon (USA, Europe)</description>
		<rom crc="40A8BF12" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Nintendo%20-%20Game%20Boy.zip/Nintendo%20-%20Game%20Boy%2FDouble%20Dragon%20%28USA%2C%20Europe%29.zip" sha1="6565A3D89827717D8E5D2E041C743266BA14B412" size="68685" />
		<title_clean>Double Dragon</title_clean>
		<plot>[CR][B]Overview:[/B][CR]Originally released in 1987 in arcades, Double Dragon is an early brawler game credited, in part, for the popularity of the beat-em-up genre during the 1980s and 1990s. The game was first developed by Technos Japan Corporation and published by Taito Corporation, and has since been ported to numerous consoles, computers, handhelds, and even cellular phones. The game also spawned the popular Double Dragon franchise, which has had five games in the main franchise, as well as two Neo-Geo fighting games.[CR]After the initial arcade release, the game has been ported to a variety of systems, including the Nintendo Entertainment System, Sega Master System, ZX Spectrum, Amstrad CPC, Commodore 64 (two different versions), PC, Atari ST, Amiga, Atari 2600, Atari 7800, Game Boy, Sega Genesis, Atari Lynx, Xbox Live Arcade, Zeebo, iPhone and Android. Every release differs in some aspect or another, particularly the Game Gear, NES, Game Boy, and Atari 2600 versions.[CR]The game's popularity led to several sequels (with the latest iteration released in 2003), a cartoon series (which ran for two seasons), a comic book (published by Marvel, ran for six issues), and even a movie (which was released in 1994, inspired by the television cartoon). The cartoon and its resulting movie release were both loosely based on the NES version of the game, whereas Jimmy Lee is initially a villain (having been raised by the antagonist of the franchise, the Shadow Master).[CR]The game's soundtrack was composed by Kazunaka Yamane, and was released in an album on February 21, 1988. The soundtrack, titled Original Sound of Double Dragon, features all nine tracks from the arcade version of the game. These tracks are all arranged versions of the songs found in the game.Gameplay[CR]Double Dragon follows Billy Lee and Jimmy Lee (incorrectly named Hammer and Spike in the promotional materials with the American version of the arcade game), two martial artists whose love interest, Marian, is kidnapped by a gang called the Black Warriors. Playing in cooperative mode triggers a different ending, where Billy and Jimmy must fight each other for the affection of Marian.The Black Warriors kidnapping Marian in the Arcade version[CR]A three button beat-em-up, there are three base moves in Double Dragon; punching, kicking, and jumping. Various combinations of these moves produce other moves, such as head butts, elbow smashes, jumping kicks, backwards kicks, or the signature Double Dragon hair grab (in which the character grabs the enemy by the hair, making them vulnerable to attacks and throws).[CR]In addition to moves, Double Dragon has a variety of weapons that can be carried from fight to fight (this was altered in the NES version, where weapons could only be used if the enemy it was taken from is still alive). There are four weapons; baseball bats, whips (neither of which are incredibly effective), knives (which are arguably the most powerful weapons in the game), and explosives (timed explosives which can be thrown).[CR]Other Versions[CR]NES VersionOnly two enemies can be on-screen simultaneously in NES version[CR]Released in 1988 (and later on the Wii Virtual Console in 2008), the NES version of Double Dragon was among the better received ports of the game. Published by Tradewest, Double Dragon on the NES has many differences from the arcade game on which it is based, beyond the obvious decrease in graphical and sound quality. The plot was altered, due to the exclusion of a two-player cooperative mode. Rather than fighting the leader of the Shadow Warriors, Billy Lee faces off against his brother, Jimmy Lee.[CR]Other than the single player story, there are a few other modes that implement two player gameplay. Mode A allows players to do a tag-team style game, alternating who is playing after each death. Mode B is a one-on-one tournament fighting game, where players can choose to fight either computer controlled opponents or player controlled characters.The two player fighting mode in NES version[CR]The game also implemented an upgrade system, where players earn hearts for dispatching certain amounts of enemies. These hearts upgrade the character's abilities, allowing for more complicated moves such as backwards elbowing and face punching. In addition to moves, there are a variety of weapons available, ranging from baseball bats to whips (as well as ranging in damage dealt, and subsequently usefulness).[CR]There are many other differences found in the NES version, some due to general technical limitations. For example, only two enemies can be onscreen simultaneously due to the NES's abilities. Naturally, the stage design deviates from what was found in the original arcade version, including new areas, expanded sections, and completely new levels.Master System VersionSega Master System home console port of Double Dragon[CR]After the NES version was released, Sega brought the game to their 8-bit platform as well. Due to the Sega Master System's more powerful hardware, the Master System version has better graphics (with more colors), more enemies on-screen, and modes and levels that are very similar to the arcade version.[CR]Unlike the NES version of Double Dragon, the Sega Master System version retains the two-player cooperative mode found in the original arcade version. Although it doesn't include the head-to-head versus mode found in the NES game, Double Dragon on the Sega Master System does have one other feature not found in the NES or arcade versions; an unlimited amount of continues (except for the final level).Mega Drive/Genesis Version[CR]In 1992, Double Dragon was ported to the Sega Mega Drive/Genesis. This game was developed by Ballistic, and is very similar to the arcade release. Double Dragon on the Sega Genesis was criticized for one key aspect; its control. The game, according to fans and critics, makes it incredibly difficult to hit enemies, with small hit boxes and sloppy movement.Handheld VersionsThe Game Gear version only features Billy Lee as a playable character[CR]The game has had three different handheld ports; Game Boy, Sega Game Gear, and Atari Lynx. The first of these three versions was released in 1990. The Game Boy version of Double Dragon is heavily influenced by the NES game, with similar level design, enemies, and overall graphical style.[CR]The Game Boy version varies on one key aspect from the NES Double Dragon; it does not include the heart system found in this game. Every move is accessible from the start. In some areas, portions of stages were removed completely for the Game Boy port, particularly some platforming segments of the final stage. Additionally, every character in the two player fighting mode was removed except for Billy Lee and Jimmy Lee.[CR]On the Game Gear, Double Dragon was significantly different from other versions of the game. Subtitled "The Revenge of Billy Lee" in Europe, this game centers around the murder of Jimmy Lee, and Billy Lee's quest of vengeance against the Dragon Clan. Other than this, the game was largely a different game, with altered stage design, different weapons (i.e. guns), and the lack of any modes beyond a single player story mode.[CR]With large sprites, the Atari Lynx version is another recreation of the original arcade game. Giving only a small view of the stage, the game was criticized due to the fact that enemy and character sprites take up nearly three fourths of the Lynx's screen size. The Atari Lynx version also includes a practice mode, which allows players to fight a varying amount of enemies to learn the controls and moves of the game.[CR]In 2003 the game received an enhanced remake for the Game Boy Advance in the form of Double Dragon Advance, which added several new features including cutscenes, additional levels, and new moves.Smartphone VersionSmartphone version[CR]In 2011 a smartphone version of Double Dragon was released on both iPhone and Android. Rather than a straight port, this version adds several features, some of which originated in the Game Boy Advance remake. In addition to the Lee brothers, players can unlock 24 playable characters for use in any mode.Other Versions[CR]Like the sequels to Double Dragon, Binary Designs worked on computer ports to create a variety of versions of the game. Additionally, a second Commodore 64 port was created by Ocean Software, and differed in many ways from the previous Commodore 64 port. While all of the games naturally differ from the arcade game on which they are based, there are several relevant details relating to the ports.[CR]The ZX Spectrum version was incredibly different when it came to graphical style. Due to an attempt at the detail of the arcade version, this version had character and enemy sprites which were transparent other than the black outlines. This, combined with an attempt at some detailed color, caused the game to run very slowly.Both of the Atari versions of the game were created by Activision[CR]Both of the Commodore 64 ports were very close in style, attempting to emulate the gameplay of the arcade release (the first even included a two player mode, almost unheard of among the computer ports). A major difference for the first version was a complete lack of sound, other than the sound effects created by punching and kicking. The second version lacked a two player mode, although it is considered by Double Dragon fans to be a slightly better port.[CR]Also released for the Atari 2600 and Atari 7800, these two ports were handled by Activision. The 2600 version of the game naturally cut much of the game's content; with redone sound and graphics to fit the platform's capabilities, removed enemy sprites, cut weapons, and a shorter story mode (although there is still a two player cooperative mode, as well as a two player versus mode). The 7800 version was improved graphically and sound-wise, although it removes the versus mode.SoundtrackOpening (Double Dragon)The City Slums (The Black Warriors Arrive)The Industrial Area (The Great Fray)After the BattleSetting Off (A New Battle)The WoodsThe Giant Abobo AppearsThe Hideout (Willy the Nemesis)Ending (Reunion With Marian)[CR][B]Trivia:[/B][CR]Data East's Bad Dudes advertisement.Two Amstrad CPC ports of Double Dragon were created. One for the CPC 6128 hardware, which was very well-received and released almost exclusively in France, and another version created for the CPC 464 which was universally panned.The more well-received version of Double Dragon on the Amstrad CPC actually had more in common with the Atari ST and Amiga versions.An advertising campaign from Data East around the release of Bad Dudes stated that, "Bad Dudes Makes Double Dragon Pale by Comparison."Most versions of Double Dragon are infamous for their glitches and exploits, such as suicidal enemies, weapons that can be carried to future stages, frozen sprites, incorrect graphics, and even walking up walls or in the air.[CR]</plot>
		<releasedate>14/8/1990</releasedate>
		<year>1990</year>
		<genre>Action</genre>
		<studio>Tradewest</studio>
		<nplayers>1-2 Sim</nplayers>
		<perspective>3rd-Person</perspective>
		<rating>3.2</rating>
		<videoid>3O9SwMUhJT4</videoid>
		<thegamesdb_id>3177</thegamesdb_id>
		<gamefaqs_url>http://www.gamefaqs.com/gameboy/197144-double-dragon</gamefaqs_url>
		<mobygames_url>http://www.mobygames.com/game/gameboy/double-dragon</mobygames_url>
		<giantbomb_url>http://www.giantbomb.com/double-dragon/3030-20752/</giantbomb_url>
		<boxart1>6ZSRG5I.png</boxart1>
		<boxart2>Bd2jDXg.jpg</boxart2>
		<boxart3>NV9UAzo.jpg</boxart3>
		<boxart4>q4ErUQb.jpg</boxart4>
		<boxart5>LX1pJ1k.jpg</boxart5>
		<snapshot1>H0ROyLD.gif</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>ItCfc4f.gif</snapshot2>
		<snapshot3>Rg05O3y.gif</snapshot3>
		<snapshot4>LKwSqUT.gif</snapshot4>
		<snapshot5>nkCKrkz.gif</snapshot5>
		<snapshot6>wI45nZo.gif</snapshot6>
		<snapshot7>afs0nBq.gif</snapshot7>
		<snapshot8>x1ZBbRQ.gif</snapshot8>
		<snapshot9>7mdSeAR.gif</snapshot9>
		<snapshot10>zUOMxnL.jpg</snapshot10>
		<fanart1>ZAGb39A.jpg</fanart1>
		<banner1>mRX9waV.jpg</banner1>
		<clearlogo1>Iv8e7SU.png</clearlogo1>
	</game>
	<game name="Battletoads (USA, Europe)">
		<description>10.  Battletoads (USA, Europe)</description>
		<rom crc="B0C3361B" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Nintendo%20-%20Game%20Boy.zip/Nintendo%20-%20Game%20Boy%2FBattletoads%20%28USA%2C%20Europe%29.zip" sha1="BA839BEA8F76BF955E3EDF7083D2CBE780244ADD" size="113545" />
		<title_clean>Battletoads</title_clean>
		<plot>[CR][B]Overview:[/B][CR]As the video game market slowly turned towards the Super Nintendo Entertainment System and Sega Genesis, Rare Ltd released this game which can be considered one of the best looking games on the NES. The game begins aboard the space ship &#8216;The Vulture&#8217; where Battletoads Rash, Zitz, and Pimple (all disgustingly named after skin diseases) are escorting Princess Angelica back to her home planet. Pimple and Princess Angelica go cruisin&#8217; and get intercepted by the game&#8217;s villain, the Dark Queen of Ragnarok. Both are kidnapped and taken back to Ragnarok. The Professor (captain of The Vulture) takes Rash and Zitz to &#8216;rumble&#8217; with the Dark Queen on Ragnarok and &#8216;get the Princess and Pimple back.&#8217; The remainder of the game takes place on planet Ragnarok where Rash and Zitz set off to save their friend Pimple and Princess Angelica.Gameplay[CR]While the first level is a typical 2d beat em up similar to Double Dragon, other levels have a variety of gameplay styles, including rappelling down a pit, riding speed bikes and surfboards, navigating a level on a unicycle-like vehicle that can ride up walls and on the ceiling, etc. The main objective of each level is to defeat as many enemies and overcome as many obstacles as possible and reach the endpoint. General strategy is to memorize these obstacles[CR]and rely on quick reflexes to reach the end. The entire game rounds up to two difficult levels where you climb a tower and, at the end, reach the Dark Queen.[CR]The most memorable aspect of this game is the absurd difficulty. Not only did it employ a decent amount of memorization but reflexes had to be fast, even for veteran gamers. Another memorable moment for this game would be the humorous way enemies were finished off, be it by using a football helmet or sprouting horns and ramming the enemy off screen.[CR]When the game was released on the Game Boy Electronic Gaming Monthly awarded it the scores of 8,8,8,7 saying, "...one of the best Game Boy games I've ever played". The Game Boy version had the same basic theme found in the NES adventure, with the toads using all of the same fighting moves. The levels and bosses however were entirely original.[CR]</plot>
		<releasedate>14/11/1991</releasedate>
		<year>1991</year>
		<genre>Action</genre>
		<studio>Tradewest</studio>
		<nplayers>1</nplayers>
		<perspective>3rd-Person</perspective>
		<rating>3.7</rating>
		<videoid>TGJ8LEatY-I</videoid>
		<thegamesdb_id>13061</thegamesdb_id>
		<gamefaqs_url>http://www.gamefaqs.com/gameboy/585623-battletoads</gamefaqs_url>
		<mobygames_url>http://www.mobygames.com/game/gameboy/battletoads_</mobygames_url>
		<giantbomb_url>http://www.giantbomb.com/battletoads/3030-21228/</giantbomb_url>
		<boxart1>dMkAKYz.jpg</boxart1>
		<boxart2>vSkj2IA.jpg</boxart2>
		<boxart3>91Cbp8x.jpg</boxart3>
		<boxart4>toABPGG.jpg</boxart4>
		<snapshot1>VsEllCd.gif</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>JPCb0t5.png</snapshot2>
		<snapshot3>cp1vtEk.png</snapshot3>
		<snapshot4>uCFyYsG.gif</snapshot4>
		<snapshot5>WIYZbkn.png</snapshot5>
		<snapshot6>30tBHAW.png</snapshot6>
		<snapshot7>ENeye1Q.png</snapshot7>
		<snapshot8>QIVdpxk.png</snapshot8>
		<snapshot9>idt8vQL.gif</snapshot9>
		<snapshot10>CfD148t.png</snapshot10>
	</game>
	<game name="Donkey Kong (World) (Rev A) (SGB Enhanced)">
		<description>9.  Donkey Kong (World) (Rev A) (SGB Enhanced)</description>
		<rom crc="F777A5D8" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Nintendo%20-%20Game%20Boy.zip/Nintendo%20-%20Game%20Boy%2FDonkey%20Kong%20%28World%29%20%28Rev%20A%29%20%28SGB%20Enhanced%29.zip" sha1="397AD2FF25627B83E02C71B54C72BB4DEB39E0C0" size="268469" />
		<title_clean>Donkey Kong</title_clean>
		<plot>[CR][B]Overview:[/B][CR][B]Gameplay:[/B] when in use with the Super Game Boy[CR]Donkey Kong '94 is an update to the original Donkey Kong arcade game. In addition to featuring the first four levels from the original arcade game, this new adventure goes on to feature eight additional worlds that add an entirely new form of gameplay to the the original story of Mario rescuing Pauline from Donkey Kong. Where before Mario simply had to reach the top of the stage, he now found himself forced to chase Donkey Kong for miles and miles across varying locations and past dozens of identical locked doors sitting mysteriously out in the open. Eventually, Donkey Kong Jr. will join into the fray. He will interfere in both boss stages and normal stages, doing his best to make life difficult for Mario.[CR]The game is also notable for its heavy use in promotion for the Super Game Boy, featuring an enhanced color palette as well as a game border resembling the original arcade machine.[CR][B]Gameplay:[/B][CR]Donkey Kong '94 is a hybrid platforming puzzle game. Mario's goal is to drag a key to a locked door. He must accomplish this task by outwitting enemies and finding his way past obstacles while holding onto the key. The key will disappear and return to it's starting point if he lets go of it for too long. Mario is much more acrobatic, being able to jump, do handstands, perform a triple-jump, and perform backwards somersaults. In this version Mario can only be hit once before he dies, although taking a hit from an enemy will only result in Mario being stunned for a moment. Mario does not have the ability to fall infinite distances in this game, if he plummets too far and lands on a solid surface, he will strike his head and die on impact. There are no powerups in this game, Mario's abilities at the start are the same as the abilities he has at the end. However, there are extra lives scattered throughout many stages, and a hat, parasol, and handbag hidden in every stage that has a key. If all of these items are collected, a mini-game will begin after the stage is finished which will allow Mario to gain more extra lives.Boss FightsRoll out the barrel.[CR]Every four stages, Mario must complete a boss stage where Donkey Kong will attempt to slow him down in a manner similar to the way he did in the original arcade game. Reaching Pauline will complete these levels. At the end of every world Mario and Donkey Kong duke it out. Mario must defeat Donkey Kong by hitting him with the barrels that he flings at Mario. After doing this enough times he will win the battle and proceed to the next world. After every boss fight, a cutscene plays which demonstrates one of Mario's abilities or a new gameplay mechanic while showing Mario and Donkey Kong moving into a new area.Worlds:[CR]Each world has a certain mechanic that the player must use, such as levers to create bridges or buttons to create ladders.[CR]World 0: Construction Site[CR]World 1: The Big City[CR]World 2: The Forest[CR]World 3: Sailing Ship[CR]World 4: The Jungle[CR]World 5: The Desert[CR]World 6: Airplane[CR]World 7: Iceberg[CR]World 8: Rocky Valley[CR]World 9: The Tower[CR][B]Cheat:[/B] View Level Records[CR]At the title screen, press SELECT to bring up a list of every single Level complete with fastest time and highest score on all files.</plot>
		<releasedate>14/6/1994</releasedate>
		<year>1994</year>
		<genre>Action</genre>
		<studio>Nintendo of America Inc.</studio>
		<nplayers>1</nplayers>
		<perspective>Platform</perspective>
		<rating>3.9</rating>
		<ESRB>E10+ - Everyone 10+</ESRB>
		<videoid>D8G0mVmvxdo</videoid>
		<thegamesdb_id>3174</thegamesdb_id>
		<gamefaqs_url>http://www.gamefaqs.com/gameboy/197137-donkey-kong</gamefaqs_url>
		<mobygames_url>http://www.mobygames.com/game/gameboy/donkey-kong-</mobygames_url>
		<giantbomb_url>http://www.giantbomb.com/donkey-kong/3030-25744/</giantbomb_url>
		<consolegrid_url>http://consolegrid.com/games/7048</consolegrid_url>
		<boxart1>T6wrNVV.jpg</boxart1>
		<boxart2>eTwiwk1.jpg</boxart2>
		<boxart3>7WKuwHJ.jpg</boxart3>
		<boxart4>a7tPq4d.jpg</boxart4>
		<boxart5>b765jPF.jpg</boxart5>
		<boxart6>FZ7WnZ7.jpg</boxart6>
		<boxart7>acoR27q.jpg</boxart7>
		<boxart8>do7XyMH.jpg</boxart8>
		<snapshot1>F3ey4PP.gif</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>Ygf4OOa.gif</snapshot2>
		<snapshot3>ObeiaOt.gif</snapshot3>
		<snapshot4>MaSTza9.gif</snapshot4>
		<snapshot5>kWgfvbq.gif</snapshot5>
		<snapshot6>dfU6PUt.gif</snapshot6>
		<snapshot7>MB3N6s8.png</snapshot7>
		<snapshot8>7SIh9yC.png</snapshot8>
		<snapshot9>ioKTMNA.png</snapshot9>
		<snapshot10>nmuOMp7.png</snapshot10>
		<fanart1>x0hTLE3.jpg</fanart1>
		<fanart2>KMEO0B4.jpg</fanart2>
		<banner1>oBxAZV3.png</banner1>
		<banner2>MjaFd5L.jpg</banner2>
		<clearlogo1>QBwamXP.png</clearlogo1>
	</game>
	<game name="Yoshi's Cookie (USA, Europe)">
		<description>8.  Yoshi's Cookie (USA, Europe)</description>
		<rom crc="75336712" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Nintendo%20-%20Game%20Boy.zip/Nintendo%20-%20Game%20Boy%2FYoshi%27s%20Cookie%20%28USA%2C%20Europe%29.zip" sha1="233DCC94D86951DDF167AAA82EC9B94B87B29E2D" size="62084" />
		<title_clean>Yoshi's Cookie</title_clean>
		<plot>[CR][B]Overview:[/B][CR]Yoshi's Cookie was originally released in April 28, 1992 for the Nintendo Entertainment System. Initially developed by  Nintendo R&amp;D1 and published by  Nintendo, the game has been released in a variety of forms and versions since its original release. The ports of the game include the  Game Boy version (which changes little from the NES version), a  SNES version (which reskinned the game to reference  Super Mario World more frequently), and inclusion in a Japan-only compilation for the  GameCube titled Nintendo Puzzle Collection.[CR]The game included on Nintendo Puzzle Collection is technically an enhanced port of Yoshi's Cookie. There are added things, however, such as upgraded graphics and sound. Other than that, the game is completely identical to the  Super Nintendo Entertainment System version of the game).[CR][B]Gameplay:[/B][CR]The game is made up of a square grid, broken up into 25 to 49 sections (5 x 5 or 7 x 7) depending on the version. Cookies of various decorations fill in the entire grid. The player manipulates entire rows either horizontally or vertically to try to match cookies that are alike. Once a row is filled with cookies of the same design, their point count increases by one and the row is wiped off of the screen.[CR]The multiplayer portion of this game has two of the cookie grids side by side, with a different player controlling each grid while different power-ups cycle on the screen. Once a player correctly aligns a row of cookies, the power up on the screen at that time is put upon the opposing player. This could range from losing five points to scrambling the cookies on their grid.[CR][B]Cheat:[/B] Extra Levels[CR]Set the Music Type to Off, the Speed to Hi. Highlight Round, and then hold Up and press Select.</plot>
		<releasedate>14/12/1993</releasedate>
		<year>1992</year>
		<studio>Nintendo of America Inc.</studio>
		<nplayers>1-2 Alt</nplayers>
		<rating>3.4</rating>
		<videoid>SWou0TTQ7wY</videoid>
		<thegamesdb_id>18723</thegamesdb_id>
		<gamefaqs_url>http://www.gamefaqs.com/gameboy/563309-yoshis-cookie</gamefaqs_url>
		<mobygames_url>http://www.mobygames.com/game/gameboy/yoshis-cookie</mobygames_url>
		<giantbomb_url>http://www.giantbomb.com/yoshis-cookie/3030-16966/</giantbomb_url>
		<consolegrid_url>http://consolegrid.com/games/12317</consolegrid_url>
		<boxart1>FWn4V4B.jpg</boxart1>
		<boxart2>m4cSoOw.jpg</boxart2>
		<boxart3>ZVEapsH.jpg</boxart3>
		<boxart4>2qgAhGa.jpg</boxart4>
		<boxart5>Kgp3Vtk.jpg</boxart5>
		<snapshot1>yiiDnVG.png</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>M8KGwmJ.png</snapshot2>
		<snapshot3>7xnuqff.png</snapshot3>
		<snapshot4>szdpOf1.png</snapshot4>
		<snapshot5>KD8710k.png</snapshot5>
		<snapshot6>vLLiuc8.png</snapshot6>
		<snapshot7>xYmHIjf.png</snapshot7>
		<snapshot8>W8N6yxd.png</snapshot8>
		<snapshot9>0PPBNtj.png</snapshot9>
		<snapshot10>CAjVK8w.png</snapshot10>
		<banner1>JgqaDOG.png</banner1>
	</game>
	<game name="Yoshi (USA)">
		<description>7.  Yoshi (USA)</description>
		<rom crc="F2F4BCCA" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Nintendo%20-%20Game%20Boy.zip/Nintendo%20-%20Game%20Boy%2FYoshi%20%28USA%29.zip" sha1="1B6E41C2270CE67E6FE15CC4977EF2DEBDD6E6CE" size="32181" />
		<title_clean>Yoshi</title_clean>
		<plot>[CR][B]Overview:[/B][CR]Yoshi was released for the NES and Game Boy systems, and later Released on the 3DS Virtual Console via the Ambassador Program. It played much like Tetris, in that you were assigned to eliminate objects that endlessly fell from the sky. The player is able to choose to play as either Mario or Luigi, who were the on-screen characters who moved the stacks of enemies back and forth two at a time.[CR][B]Gameplay:[/B][CR]Goombas, Piranha Plants, Boo Buddies, and Bloopers all rain from the sky. They can be eliminated by pairing up two identical characters at a time. Enemies can only be removed by lining them up vertically, there are no horizontal eliminations. Extra points can be earned and space can quickly be created by sandwiching enemies between the top and bottom halves of Yoshi eggs. Depending on how many enemies are placed between the eggshells; larger Yoshis can be created, as follows:Small Yoshi - No enemies, 50 points.Tall Yoshi - Between one and four enemies, 100 points.Winged Yoshi - Five or six enemies, 200 points.Star Yoshi - Seven enemies, 500 points.[CR]There are also two different gameplay modes and a multiplayer mode:Mode A - The game's endless mode, start with a clean slate and play until you run out of space in a column and lose.Mode B - The game's round clear mode, eliminate all of the enemies on a screen to earn a bonus and move on to the next round. Each stage starts with a greater number of enemies on it.Multiplayer - Compete to see which player can complete their stage the fastest, or who can at least survive the longest.[CR]Critical Reception[CR]Yoshi was poorly rated by the video game press when it was re-released on the Virtual Console, reviewers felt that it was too unoriginal and similar to other puzzle games.[CR]</plot>
		<releasedate>14/7/1992</releasedate>
		<year>1991</year>
		<genre>Action</genre>
		<studio>Nintendo of America Inc.</studio>
		<nplayers>1</nplayers>
		<perspective>1st-Person</perspective>
		<rating>3.2</rating>
		<ESRB>E - Everyone</ESRB>
		<videoid>iyE-3E6xzJw</videoid>
		<thegamesdb_id>13129</thegamesdb_id>
		<gamefaqs_url>http://www.gamefaqs.com/gameboy/563308-yoshi</gamefaqs_url>
		<mobygames_url>http://www.mobygames.com/game/gameboy/yoshi</mobygames_url>
		<giantbomb_url>http://www.giantbomb.com/yoshi/3030-19197/</giantbomb_url>
		<boxart1>0kYrjZY.jpg</boxart1>
		<boxart2>d0ci4hY.jpg</boxart2>
		<boxart3>EjEJAGS.jpg</boxart3>
		<boxart4>HPKnvc5.jpg</boxart4>
		<boxart5>7FuHUMu.jpg</boxart5>
		<snapshot1>lcOANmd.png</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>7HfjHwN.png</snapshot2>
		<snapshot3>WwaBQok.png</snapshot3>
		<snapshot4>1Xz2d7c.jpg</snapshot4>
		<snapshot5>o6Lahhf.jpg</snapshot5>
		<snapshot6>SIay0dY.jpg</snapshot6>
		<snapshot7>m90xfSA.jpg</snapshot7>
		<snapshot8>1UoOocp.jpg</snapshot8>
		<snapshot9>keik5ka.jpg</snapshot9>
		<snapshot10>vJ6vAnl.jpg</snapshot10>
	</game>
	<game name="Pokemon - Red Version (USA, Europe) (SGB Enhanced)">
		<description>6.  Pokemon - Red Version (USA, Europe) (SGB Enhanced)</description>
		<rom crc="9F7FDD53" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Nintendo%20-%20Game%20Boy.zip/Nintendo%20-%20Game%20Boy%2FPokemon%20-%20Red%20Version%20%28USA%2C%20Europe%29%20%28SGB%20Enhanced%29.zip" sha1="EA9BCAE617FDF159B045185467AE58B2E4A48B9A" size="378637" />
		<title_clean>Pokemon - Red Version</title_clean>
		<plot>Aside from Tetris, there’s no game that defines the Game Boy (and Game Boy Color) like the original Pokemon Red and Blue. They weren’t only incredibly deep and satisfying role-playing titles that launched countless sequels (and helped keep Nintendo afloat during the lean GameCube years) they also managed to hook players who strived to capture as many pocket monsters as they could find.</plot>
		<releasedate>14/12/1998</releasedate>
		<year>1996</year>
		<genre>RPG</genre>
		<studio>Nintendo</studio>
		<nplayers>1</nplayers>
		<perspective>Top-Down</perspective>
		<rating>3.9</rating>
		<ESRB>E - Everyone</ESRB>
		<videoid>QghgrmYhGK4</videoid>
		<thegamesdb_id>2356</thegamesdb_id>
		<gamefaqs_url>http://www.gamefaqs.com/gameboy/367023-pokemon-red-version</gamefaqs_url>
		<mobygames_url>http://www.mobygames.com/game/gameboy/pokmon-red-version</mobygames_url>
		<consolegrid_url>http://consolegrid.com/games/6679</consolegrid_url>
		<boxart1>aFgXWZf.jpg</boxart1>
		<boxart2>rL7RQ9u.jpg</boxart2>
		<boxart3>Qt9w1Zv.jpg</boxart3>
		<boxart4>J184pUG.jpg</boxart4>
		<boxart5>7Wt4GDy.jpg</boxart5>
		<boxart6>DPYeilz.jpg</boxart6>
		<boxart7>NiIdPd8.jpg</boxart7>
		<snapshot1>cmVh6AC.jpg</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>qjoUhUr.png</snapshot2>
		<snapshot3>QLpz92L.png</snapshot3>
		<snapshot4>u8LE4Dt.png</snapshot4>
		<snapshot5>O0G7ULo.png</snapshot5>
		<snapshot6>FSG6N5b.png</snapshot6>
		<snapshot7>eR02LiX.png</snapshot7>
		<snapshot8>siV12Qm.png</snapshot8>
		<snapshot9>7BcRofj.png</snapshot9>
		<snapshot10>4QyLGFL.png</snapshot10>
		<fanart1>ILaLJVL.jpg</fanart1>
		<fanart2>bUCqOtl.jpg</fanart2>
		<fanart3>TCvTM9R.jpg</fanart3>
		<fanart4>SrPRLTd.jpg</fanart4>
		<fanart5>ms3sQl8.jpg</fanart5>
		<fanart6>gKaHng6.jpg</fanart6>
		<fanart7>EdLSUtP.jpg</fanart7>
		<fanart8>GopAtm5.jpg</fanart8>
		<fanart9>1Km49tJ.jpg</fanart9>
		<fanart10>jGxjm7l.jpg</fanart10>
		<banner1>SzH2aIQ.png</banner1>
		<clearlogo1>fBLQxW6.png</clearlogo1>
	</game>
	<game name="Pokemon - Blue Version (USA, Europe) (SGB Enhanced)">
		<description>5.  Pokemon - Blue Version (USA, Europe) (SGB Enhanced)</description>
		<rom crc="D6DA8A1A" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Nintendo%20-%20Game%20Boy.zip/Nintendo%20-%20Game%20Boy%2FPokemon%20-%20Blue%20Version%20%28USA%2C%20Europe%29%20%28SGB%20Enhanced%29.zip" sha1="D7037C83E1AE5B39BDE3C30787637BA1D4C48CE2" size="378365" />
		<title_clean>Pokemon - Blue Version</title_clean>
		<plot>Aside from Tetris, there’s no game that defines the Game Boy (and Game Boy Color) like the original Pokemon Red and Blue. They weren’t only incredibly deep and satisfying role-playing titles that launched countless sequels (and helped keep Nintendo afloat during the lean GameCube years) they also managed to hook players who strived to capture as many pocket monsters as they could find.</plot>
		<releasedate>14/12/1998</releasedate>
		<year>1996</year>
		<genre>RPG</genre>
		<studio>Nintendo</studio>
		<nplayers>1</nplayers>
		<perspective>3rd-Person</perspective>
		<rating>4.0</rating>
		<ESRB>E - Everyone</ESRB>
		<videoid>6lBqaQuKAVQ</videoid>
		<thegamesdb_id>2357</thegamesdb_id>
		<gamefaqs_url>http://www.gamefaqs.com/gameboy/907714-pokemon-blue-version</gamefaqs_url>
		<mobygames_url>http://www.mobygames.com/game/gameboy/pokmon-blue-version</mobygames_url>
		<consolegrid_url>http://consolegrid.com/games/6678</consolegrid_url>
		<boxart1>mqOoVY7.png</boxart1>
		<boxart2>uhMeHQ8.png</boxart2>
		<boxart3>jNvWXEC.jpg</boxart3>
		<boxart4>LZ8MXsA.jpg</boxart4>
		<boxart5>918QWUg.jpg</boxart5>
		<snapshot1>2mO4Sxx.jpg</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>cu6DnON.png</snapshot2>
		<snapshot3>rrPkwZO.png</snapshot3>
		<snapshot4>UHCPuFk.png</snapshot4>
		<snapshot5>HQkGr5l.png</snapshot5>
		<snapshot6>VMVXuZc.png</snapshot6>
		<snapshot7>d4Q7I2b.png</snapshot7>
		<snapshot8>jioiyD6.png</snapshot8>
		<snapshot9>MffgrTv.png</snapshot9>
		<snapshot10>kc8HsEj.png</snapshot10>
		<fanart1>Ndiy7gN.jpg</fanart1>
		<fanart2>1YBd34W.jpg</fanart2>
		<fanart3>BZUuH0q.jpg</fanart3>
		<fanart4>omExfh8.jpg</fanart4>
		<fanart5>gbE2GUp.jpg</fanart5>
		<fanart6>fct7xtE.jpg</fanart6>
		<fanart7>sO5I8AQ.jpg</fanart7>
		<fanart8>B3SJVe3.jpg</fanart8>
		<banner1>csE6YGu.png</banner1>
	</game>
	<game name="DuckTales (USA)">
		<description>4.  DuckTales (USA)</description>
		<rom crc="2BBBB54D" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Nintendo%20-%20Game%20Boy.zip/Nintendo%20-%20Game%20Boy%2FDuckTales%20%28USA%29.zip" sha1="93460364E33E8FB09A0659738044D0297CD4DF69" size="45942" />
		<title_clean>DuckTales</title_clean>
		<plot>There’s a good reason Duck Tales is being revived. The original animated series was a highlight of many childhoods, and it spawned an equally memorable Game Boy title that introduced some wonderful new ideas to side-scrolling adventures, including Uncle Scrooge pogo-sticking over enemies using his cane.</plot>
		<releasedate>1/11/1990</releasedate>
		<year>1990</year>
		<genre>Action</genre>
		<studio>Capcom, Disney Interactive</studio>
		<nplayers>1</nplayers>
		<perspective>3rd-Person</perspective>
		<rating>3.2</rating>
		<videoid>id9RhqA_Tq4</videoid>
		<thegamesdb_id>2890</thegamesdb_id>
		<gamefaqs_url>http://www.gamefaqs.com/gameboy/197170-disneys-ducktales</gamefaqs_url>
		<mobygames_url>http://www.mobygames.com/game/gameboy/disneys-ducktales</mobygames_url>
		<giantbomb_url>http://www.giantbomb.com/ducktales/3030-15799/</giantbomb_url>
		<consolegrid_url>http://consolegrid.com/games/7183</consolegrid_url>
		<boxart1>08OGCyb.jpg</boxart1>
		<boxart2>Jg6noW3.jpg</boxart2>
		<boxart3>tEnTXOP.jpg</boxart3>
		<boxart4>YK2IwNT.jpg</boxart4>
		<boxart5>WgwCttG.jpg</boxart5>
		<boxart6>CcnVC2v.jpg</boxart6>
		<snapshot1>dvPk6jG.png</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>DbZOzUH.png</snapshot2>
		<snapshot3>aR5mpGe.png</snapshot3>
		<snapshot4>YKgWTJl.png</snapshot4>
		<snapshot5>fMjAMHi.png</snapshot5>
		<snapshot6>F2mfZ0p.png</snapshot6>
		<snapshot7>Mt8Zwjb.png</snapshot7>
		<snapshot8>B18xNEL.png</snapshot8>
		<snapshot9>gSlVKQO.png</snapshot9>
		<snapshot10>RwQ1405.png</snapshot10>
		<fanart1>VbGLdnR.jpg</fanart1>
		<banner1>5cijJ0x.jpg</banner1>
	</game>
	<game name="Tetris (World) (Rev A)">
		<description>3.  Tetris (World) (Rev A)</description>
		<rom crc="46DF91AD" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Nintendo%20-%20Game%20Boy.zip/Nintendo%20-%20Game%20Boy%2FTetris%20%28World%29%20%28Rev%20A%29.zip" sha1="74591CC9501AF93873F9A5D3EB12DA12C0723BBC" size="19566" />
		<title_clean>Tetris</title_clean>
		<plot>There's a story in Nintendo's history that goes like this: When deciding what game to pack in with the Game Boy (remember when you'd get a free game with a brand-new system?), a Nintendo executive said, if you want to sell this to boys, pack in Mario. If you want to sell it to everyone, pack in Tetris. The moment Nintendo saw the USSRs enigmatic puzzler, they knew it was the perfect game to sell the system, and worked tirelessly to get it.[CR]A title some have called the perfect game, Tetris and its seven simple shapes are the epitome of the design philosophy "easy to learn, hard to master." All you had to do was place those shapes in a certain order to complete a line and then clear it, like you were building a puzzle from scratch, but every puzzle felt different. It was understandable to any new player, and addicted people to such an extent it invaded their dreams. Even with all the different versions that have come in the two decades since, the original portable release is just as playable today as it was when it made the Game Boy a huge success right from the start.</plot>
		<releasedate>14/12/1989</releasedate>
		<year>1989</year>
		<studio>Nintendo of America Inc.</studio>
		<nplayers>1</nplayers>
		<rating>4.1</rating>
		<ESRB>E - Everyone</ESRB>
		<videoid>KcBD5Zje1h8</videoid>
		<thegamesdb_id>10616</thegamesdb_id>
		<gamefaqs_url>http://www.gamefaqs.com/gameboy/585960-tetris</gamefaqs_url>
		<mobygames_url>http://www.mobygames.com/game/gameboy/tetris________</mobygames_url>
		<giantbomb_url>http://www.giantbomb.com/tetris/3030-1896/</giantbomb_url>
		<consolegrid_url>http://consolegrid.com/games/7083</consolegrid_url>
		<boxart1>FCaS9gx.jpg</boxart1>
		<boxart2>XIhcbL9.jpg</boxart2>
		<boxart3>QnPSfK3.jpg</boxart3>
		<boxart4>QU4gut5.jpg</boxart4>
		<boxart5>DpGk0d5.jpg</boxart5>
		<boxart6>67gacdu.jpg</boxart6>
		<boxart7>7AEqLOr.jpg</boxart7>
		<boxart8>C2sA6SC.jpg</boxart8>
		<boxart9>jsyiZtw.jpg</boxart9>
		<boxart10>vn0Bxkg.jpg</boxart10>
		<snapshot1>Ls9zqNz.gif</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>WtW5wwS.gif</snapshot2>
		<snapshot3>hLwRFak.gif</snapshot3>
		<snapshot4>2OdGUTO.gif</snapshot4>
		<snapshot5>xBRTo4x.gif</snapshot5>
		<snapshot6>rtGIK5J.jpg</snapshot6>
		<snapshot7>dRu06yN.jpg</snapshot7>
		<snapshot8>7ItADsD.jpg</snapshot8>
		<snapshot9>DP8YMno.jpg</snapshot9>
		<snapshot10>LioXWYq.jpg</snapshot10>
		<fanart1>9eyQIDu.jpg</fanart1>
		<fanart2>E5D7rH1.jpg</fanart2>
		<fanart3>0gVs006.jpg</fanart3>
		<banner1>8mOkTPn.png</banner1>
		<clearlogo1>EhvqRky.png</clearlogo1>
	</game>
	<game name="Super Mario Land (World) (Rev A)">
		<description>2.  Super Mario Land (World) (Rev A)</description>
		<rom crc="2C27EC70" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Nintendo%20-%20Game%20Boy.zip/Nintendo%20-%20Game%20Boy%2FSuper%20Mario%20Land%20%28World%29%20%28Rev%20A%29.zip" sha1="418203621B887CAA090215D97E3F509B79AFFD3E" size="37626" />
		<title_clean>Super Mario Land</title_clean>
		<plot>Super Mario Land doesn't gets a pass out of nostalgia alone (though that is a big reason). Dust off Super Mario Land today and you'll still be treated to a lively platformer dripping with Gunpei Yokoi's off-kilter design. The Super Mario Land series evolved with each sequel, but thanks to this pioneer it got off on the right foot.</plot>
		<releasedate>14/8/1989</releasedate>
		<year>1989</year>
		<genre>Action</genre>
		<studio>Nintendo of America Inc.</studio>
		<nplayers>1</nplayers>
		<perspective>3rd-Person</perspective>
		<rating>3.9</rating>
		<ESRB>E - Everyone</ESRB>
		<videoid>XC_cibiH6Zg</videoid>
		<thegamesdb_id>1726</thegamesdb_id>
		<gamefaqs_url>http://www.gamefaqs.com/gameboy/585933-super-mario-land</gamefaqs_url>
		<mobygames_url>http://www.mobygames.com/game/gameboy/super-mario-land</mobygames_url>
		<giantbomb_url>http://www.giantbomb.com/super-mario-land/3030-19834/</giantbomb_url>
		<consolegrid_url>http://consolegrid.com/games/6711</consolegrid_url>
		<boxart1>xEQuMps.png</boxart1>
		<boxart2>vMD0n8I.jpg</boxart2>
		<boxart3>4UbvUb0.png</boxart3>
		<boxart4>dJiRJb3.png</boxart4>
		<boxart5>7Ft9e2r.png</boxart5>
		<boxart6>rsslxHi.jpg</boxart6>
		<boxart7>OHLfiQR.jpg</boxart7>
		<boxart8>5p4ZA9J.jpg</boxart8>
		<boxart9>igrcESp.jpg</boxart9>
		<boxart10>ZGt0t1z.jpg</boxart10>
		<snapshot1>PTHYh8H.jpg</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>AP8Ls21.jpg</snapshot2>
		<snapshot3>FzAEHA1.jpg</snapshot3>
		<snapshot4>tnvBjvt.jpg</snapshot4>
		<snapshot5>GYHZvj1.gif</snapshot5>
		<snapshot6>hD4qd0V.gif</snapshot6>
		<snapshot7>4o52Y2x.gif</snapshot7>
		<snapshot8>YXLDXnd.gif</snapshot8>
		<snapshot9>3IwaJ2u.gif</snapshot9>
		<snapshot10>4doamFK.gif</snapshot10>
		<fanart1>JfqBmX3.jpg</fanart1>
		<fanart2>jxHtGyw.jpg</fanart2>
		<fanart3>ZFSddOb.jpg</fanart3>
		<banner1>EdESH92.png</banner1>
	</game>
	<game name="Legend of Zelda, The - Link's Awakening (USA, Europe) (Rev B)">
		<description>1.  Legend of Zelda - Link's Awakening (USA, Europe) (Rev B)</description>
		<rom crc="34D08E7B" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Nintendo%20-%20Game%20Boy.zip/Nintendo%20-%20Game%20Boy%2FLegend%20of%20Zelda%2C%20The%20-%20Link%27s%20Awakening%20%28USA%2C%20Europe%29%20%28Rev%20B%29.zip" sha1="5AB63DEF958728933571C3B4F6AF54DB14F3F8B2" size="296379" />
		<title_clean>Legend of Zelda, The - Link's Awakening</title_clean>
		<plot>After the SNES game Legend of Zelda: A Link to the Past, the Zelda development team decided it was about time they made an adventure specifically crafted for the Game Boy. But since it was designed to be a side adventure for Link, the team took some liberties with the formula, and ended up with a Zelda whose gameplay was the same, but with a strange, engrossing plot unlike anything LoZ fans had seen before.[CR]After Link shipwrecks on a strange island, he awakens in the land of Koholint where everything feels slightly off compared to Hyrule, and it's filled with people that remind Link of characters he's met before. Throughout the game Link must find and explore eight dungeons to collect the sacred instruments to wake the fabled Wind Fish so he can go home. But what happens to Koholint when it wakes up? Link's Awakening kept the series' winning gameplay and mixed it with a Twin Peaks vibe to create one of the most unforgettable games ever, proving that Zelda could be just as astonishing even at a smaller scale.</plot>
		<releasedate>14/8/1993</releasedate>
		<year>1993</year>
		<genre>Action</genre>
		<studio>Nintendo of America Inc.</studio>
		<nplayers>1</nplayers>
		<perspective>3rd-Person</perspective>
		<rating>4.1</rating>
		<ESRB>E - Everyone</ESRB>
		<videoid>YY4MuqGhVUo</videoid>
		<thegamesdb_id>3193</thegamesdb_id>
		<gamefaqs_url>http://www.gamefaqs.com/gameboy/563277-the-legend-of-zelda-links-awakening</gamefaqs_url>
		<mobygames_url>http://www.mobygames.com/game/gameboy/legend-of-zelda-links-awakening</mobygames_url>
		<giantbomb_url>http://www.giantbomb.com/the-legend-of-zelda-links-awakening/3030-3645/</giantbomb_url>
		<consolegrid_url>http://consolegrid.com/games/10145</consolegrid_url>
		<boxart1>jc78q2M.jpg</boxart1>
		<boxart2>ExNEsZo.png</boxart2>
		<boxart3>49P6qnE.jpg</boxart3>
		<boxart4>ivQ3d0x.jpg</boxart4>
		<boxart5>U4fz2ld.jpg</boxart5>
		<boxart6>RYtSV7M.jpg</boxart6>
		<boxart7>8F2C9Es.jpg</boxart7>
		<boxart8>J4G7atY.jpg</boxart8>
		<boxart9>HFto7IR.jpg</boxart9>
		<snapshot1>vwae3XH.gif</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>vsOfZ0W.gif</snapshot2>
		<snapshot3>zbqLhuq.gif</snapshot3>
		<snapshot4>xMQ202r.gif</snapshot4>
		<snapshot5>U3lmQ84.gif</snapshot5>
		<snapshot6>x2imBSI.gif</snapshot6>
		<snapshot7>YUuMmk2.gif</snapshot7>
		<snapshot8>CohIlRX.gif</snapshot8>
		<snapshot9>q3et74Y.gif</snapshot9>
		<snapshot10>O40fSrW.gif</snapshot10>
		<fanart1>EzVPK3O.jpg</fanart1>
		<fanart2>9hPnoDy.jpg</fanart2>
		<fanart3>dYXnVxf.jpg</fanart3>
		<fanart4>wup0ruT.jpg</fanart4>
		<fanart5>ZEKvCQb.jpg</fanart5>
		<banner1>6o2kJRY.png</banner1>
	</game>
</datafile>