<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<datafile>
    <header>
        <emu_name>Game Boy Advance Hacks</emu_name>
        <emu_description>Game Boy Advance</emu_description>
        <emu_category>Handheld, Nintendo, 32 Bit, 2000s, Hacks</emu_category>
        <emu_version>10152019</emu_version>
        <emu_date>10/15/2019</emu_date>
        <emu_author>Zach Morris</emu_author>
        <emu_visibility>visible</emu_visibility>
        <emu_homepage>http://www.no-intro.org</emu_homepage>
        <emu_baseurl>http://archive.org/download/</emu_baseurl>
        <emu_launcher>retroplayer</emu_launcher>
        <emu_default_addon>none</emu_default_addon>
        <emu_ext_launch_cmd>none</emu_ext_launch_cmd>
        <emu_downloadpath>default</emu_downloadpath>
        <emu_postdlaction>none</emu_postdlaction>
        <emu_comment>Hacks are modified versions of old games. Some games get minor tweaks such as retranslations or simple gameplay improvements, others get complete overhauls that completely transform the original game. This is a list of just some of the Nintendo Gameboy Advance hacks available today.</emu_comment>
        <emu_thumb>MhEDfkW.jpg</emu_thumb>
        <emu_banner>LZzNOlO.jpg</emu_banner>
        <emu_fanart>r1Kk58D.jpg</emu_fanart>
        <emu_logo>4WSSkGz.png</emu_logo>
        <emu_trailer>pF-3S-HTJSg</emu_trailer>
    </header>
  <game name="Advance Wars_2 - War Room C (X)">
    <description>Advance Wars_2 - War Room C (X)</description>
    <title_clean>Advance Wars_2 - War Room C</title_clean>
    <rom name="EmuROMHacks/ROM_Hacks_1.zip/GBA%2FAdvance%20Wars_2%20-%20War%20Room%20C%20%28X%29.gba" size="8220733"/>
    <plot>This patch is for Advance Wars 2 (U). If it is an intro dump, use the[CR]cleaner patch included beforehand. This patch adds the ability to see defence[CR]ratings for all COs when viewing the CO Dossier. It also adds the ability to[CR]see the firepower ratings for COs with 'dynamic' firepower (Like Colin's Power[CR]of Money). If using custom stats, the game will now also round up the number[CR]to display into these bounds: * 30% or less * 20% * 10% Normal +10% +15% +20%[CR]+30% +40% +50% +60% +70% +75% or more Eg, a firepower boost of +12% would show[CR]as +15% - the display is very coarse. Have fun! * Xenesis[CR]Read[CR]Me:[CR]Readme[CR]This patch is for Advance Wars 2 (U). If it is an intro dump,[CR]use the cleaner patch included beforehand.[CR]This patch adds the ability to[CR]see defence ratings for all COs when viewing the CO Dossier. It also adds the[CR]ability to see the firepower ratings for COs with dynamic firepower (Like[CR]Colins Power of Money).[CR]If using custom stats, the game will now also round[CR]up the number to display into these bounds:[CR]-30% or[CR]less[CR]-20%[CR]-10%[CR]Normal[CR]+10%[CR]+15%[CR]+20%[CR]+30%[CR]+40%[CR]+50%[CR]+60%[CR]+70%[CR]+75%[CR]or more[CR]Eg, a firepower boost of +12% would show as +15% - the display is[CR]very coarse.[CR]Have fun![CR]-Xenesis</plot>
    <studio>Xenesis</studio>
    <snapshot1>N1lVWLP.png</snapshot1>
  </game>
  <game name="Breath of Fresh Fire II (X)">
    <description>Breath of Fresh Fire II (X)</description>
    <title_clean>Breath of Fresh Fire II</title_clean>
    <rom name="EmuROMHacks/ROM_Hacks_1.zip/GBA%2FBreath%20of%20Fresh%20Fire%20II%20%28X%29.gba" size="4194304"/>
    <plot>Breath of Fire 2 is another one of the author's favorite RPGs from the 1990s.[CR]The early Breath of Fire games weren't anything particularly new (character-[CR]development-wise), but they were well executed and fun to play, and definite[CR]creativity was demonstrated in different character's abilities. Every[CR]character can do something nifty to help out your team, and the party lineup[CR]can be organized differently in battle via different attack formations, which[CR]have varying affects on the attack/defense/speed of each combatant. The Breath[CR]of Fire series catapulted non-humans into central, heroic roles (Breath of[CR]Fire was the first game that the author remembers that memorably did this).[CR]And lastly, building a new town was an incredible feature, and gave the player[CR]a sense that they were really are making their own destiny and affecting the[CR]game world. This modification serves to fine-tune the Player Characters, to[CR]provide the player with strong reasons to use any of them. Ryu is also able to[CR]use his Dragon powers more liberally (like his ancestor did in Breath of Fire[CR]1), as they do not zero out his AP anymore. Dragon abilities do damage based[CR]on Ryu's level and his Wisdom. There are a few more Shaman combinations, as[CR]well. To peruse a more exhaustive changelog, go to . There's also information[CR]on the [characters](http://jeffludwig.com/bof2/characters.php), [shaman[CR]combos](http://jeffludwig.com/bof2/shaman.php),[CR][weapons](http://jeffludwig.com/bof2/weaponlist.php), and[CR][armor](http://jeffludwig.com/bof2/armorlist.php).[CR]Read[CR]Me:[CR]*************************************************************************[CR]***[CR]The Breath of Fresh Fire modification ***[CR]*** for ***[CR]*** Breath of Fire[CR]2 for Game Boy Advance[CR]***[CR]*************************************************************************[CR]Version:[CR]v1.0, rev.1 Released December 29th, 2011.[CR] Initially released on March[CR]24th, 2011.[CR]Author: ludmeister (aka Jeff Ludwig)[CR]Website:[CR]http://jeffludwig.com[CR]Notice, effective March 1st, 2012[CR]******************************************************************************[CR]For this release and all new releases, I am discontinuing the use of [CR]IPS2EXE to create patches that can be applied without an IPS patching [CR]program. These executable patches set off certain virus and malware [CR]scanners. [CR]Aim[CR]******************************************************************************[CR]The aim of this mod is simply to create a fresh Breath of Fire 2[CR]experience,[CR] and to allow for more liberal use of Dragon powers.[CR]Version[CR]1.0 Revision 1[CR]Changelog[CR]******************************************************************************[CR] * Sten has been given the use of the Warp spell, so players may avoid[CR]some [CR] needless backtracking early in the campaign.[CR] [CR] [CR]Version[CR]1.0[CR]Changelog[CR]******************************************************************************[CR]* Spells are modified, especially their AP costs, names, and damage done.[CR] * Every character casts different spells, and some have different[CR]starting [CR] spells as well.[CR] [CR] * Starting stats, and level up[CR]progressions for all characters, including [CR] Bleu have been meticulously[CR]reworked. Some of the characters will play [CR] much differently than stock[CR]Breath of Fire 2, making your strategies [CR] different.[CR] [CR] * Items have[CR]been renamed (no 2 character demarcation at the end of each [CR] item). This[CR]allowed for 8 characters for each item name (6 for stackable [CR] items).[CR]There are numerous items with different properties, and almost all [CR] non-[CR]equipable items are stackable.[CR] [CR] * Dragon Magic has been significantly[CR]changed. No more zero-ing out of the [CR] Dragonbroods AP when using Dragon[CR]abilities! They have been given an AP [CR] cost, and do damage based off of[CR]hero level (not AP remaining).[CR] [CR] * Fixed a bug in the original code[CR]that prevented the Dragon abilities [CR] (Fire, Ice and Thunder Dragon) from[CR]inflicting damage according to their [CR] elemental classification.[CR] [CR] *[CR]I have meticulously realigned the Shaman combo system. The Holy and Devil [CR]shamans are more powerful on their own. In face, a bug in the original code[CR] (namely, Luck was not affected as it should have been) meant that the[CR]Holy [CR] shaman by itself was worthless. I bypassed this by allowing the Holy[CR]Shaman [CR] to increase other attributes. I have also added new Shaman combos.[CR]I may [CR] post the new Shaman Combo list as time permits. For now, Ill leave[CR]you with [CR] this teaser... Nina + Fire + Water... is very powerful![CR] [CR]* The "Special" message when characters critically hit monsters always [CR]annoyed me. It has been changed to "Smoked!"[CR] [CR] * Of course, to[CR]compensate for the various nifty new powers your characters [CR] have, your[CR]enemies power had to be increased proportionally. To keep things [CR]interesting.[CR]Installation[CR]instructions[CR]******************************************************************************[CR]The[CR]following applies this and all future releases of the Breath of Fresh Fire[CR]mod.[CR] * First of all, you will need to obtain a clean GBA ROM of Breath of[CR]Fire 2. [CR] The ROM title that you are looking for is "0510 - Breath of Fire[CR]II (E).gba". [CR] You are on your own for this step, as it is illegal to[CR]provide ROMs of [CR] copyrighted material. There are sites that do provide[CR]this ROM though, [CR] and you should be able to obtain it.[CR] [CR] * Note:[CR]This patch does not work with the "0403 - Breath of Fire II (U).gba" ROM![CR] * When you get it, make a backup of it if you would want to play the[CR]vanilla [CR] version (or, in case I post an updated version of the mod here...[CR]I am not [CR] going to make version 1.0 to "version whatever" patches for my[CR]mods, for [CR] instance).[CR] [CR] * Download the Breath of Fresh Fire[CR]mod.[CR] [CR] * Use the IPS patching program of your choice to apply the .ips[CR]patch to the[CR] correct ROM. As I use IPS XP[CR](http://home.arcor.de/minako.aino/ipsXP/) to[CR] create my patches, I[CR]recommend using this program to patch your ROM.[CR] [CR] * I hope you enjoy[CR]it!</plot>
    <genre>Text,Gameplay</genre>
    <studio>ludmeister</studio>
    <snapshot1>b0aLO6d.png</snapshot1>
    <snapshot2>sdUtOwN.png</snapshot2>
  </game>
  <game name="Castlevania - Revenge On Findesiecle X">
    <description>Castlevania - Revenge On Findesiecle X</description>
    <title_clean>Castlevania - Revenge On Findesiecle X</title_clean>
    <rom name="EmuROMHacks/ROM_Hacks_1.zip/GBA%2FCastlevania%20-%20Revenge%20On%20Findesiecle%20X.gba" size="8388608"/>
    <plot>A comprehensive hack for the Japanese version of Castlevania HOD. It can only[CR]be used with the Japanese version. Several characters have been added and[CR]original characters have been improved upon. There are two types of Simon[CR](Original and enhanced), two Justes (Original and Devil), Julius from AOS,[CR]Maxim, Megaman, and Mario. Several other features have been added or changed[CR]including sprites, palettes, music, and other things which are detailed in the[CR]read me.[CR]Read Me:[CR]Castlevania Harmony of Dissodance - Revenge On The[CR]Findesiecle[CR]This is a hack which improves on the japanese version of[CR]Castlevania HOD (Byakuya no Concerto) in many ways. It was created by PUNKEMNX[CR]and TONYJIH.[CR]Here are some features:[CR]1.New characters are added[CR]Julius?Simon (story mode also), Enhanced Simon, Devil Juste, Mega Man, Mario.[CR]They are accessed by using the following names at the character selection[CR]screen.[CR]MAXIM - Still works.[CR]JULIUS - Julius Belmont from Castlevania[CR]Aria Of Sorrow. Menu, level up, sub-weapons and items functions are also[CR]available for Julius.[CR]SIMON - Classic Simon Belmont. The same seen in the[CR]boss rush mode.[CR]SIMONX - Enhanced Classic Simon. This one has a higher jump[CR]and can gain abilities.[CR]JUSTEX - Devil Juste. A special version of Juste[CR]with super speed.[CR]A remade sword substitutes his original whip.[CR]ROCKMAN[CR]- Megaman from the Megaman games.[CR]MARIO - Mario from the Super Mario[CR]games.[CR]2.Some sprites sheets of characters like Juste and Julius are[CR]remade[CR]3.Palette Updated[CR]4.Classic music added [CR]Dont wait until night[CR](GBA)[CR]HC Another Tune[CR]Sotn I am the wind[CR]Sotn Nocturne - Furniture[CR]Room[CR]AOS Heart of Fire - Played during intro.[CR]5.Some sound effects[CR]changed[CR]6.Actions optimized (e.x.Maxim). Techniques change and become[CR]easier to use now.[CR]7.More secrets added (special places, infinite[CR]items...)[CR]8.Enemies, items and some other factors are adjusted. The game is[CR]harder overall.[CR]9.All characters can level up and start at level 1. They[CR]can also pick up relics to increase their abilities.[CR]10.Some characters[CR]have unique sub-weapons like Devil Juste with fist, Enhanced Simon with the[CR]Holy Book.[CR]Some questions and answers:[CR]1.Q:Will there be more changes[CR]from now on?[CR]A:No. Well, actually, it was started just as a simple try.[CR]PUNKEMNX and TONYJIH did not even plan to put too much work on it. But, all[CR]your generous feedback encouraged them so much that they decided to improve[CR]it. At last, thats this current version you see. Not perfect, but its still[CR]not bad.[CR]2.Q:What about the next project?[CR]A:As it is mentioned above,[CR]this is just a simple try. New features will be showed in the hacked hod[CR]version with sotns sprites. Making a perfect hod is PUNKEMNX&amp;TONYJIHs;[CR]dream.[CR]Hope you enjoy it</plot>
    <genre>Graphics,Sound,Gameplay</genre>
    <studio>PUNKEMNX &amp; TonyJih</studio>
    <snapshot1>QHmZpXY.png</snapshot1>
    <snapshot2>rVuJ2lj.png</snapshot2>
  </game>
  <game name="Final Fantasy VI Advance (X)">
    <description>Final Fantasy VI Advance (X)</description>
    <title_clean>Final Fantasy VI Advance</title_clean>
    <rom name="EmuROMHacks/ROM_Hacks_1.zip/GBA%2FFinal%20Fantasy%20VI%20Advance%20%28X%29.gba" size="16777216"/>
    <plot>Final Fantasy VI Advance is a port/remake of Final Fantasy VI to the Game Boy Advance, featuring two new optional dungeons (Dragon's Den and Soul Shrine) and a new optional superboss. Oh and the English script was completely retranslated from scratch, causing eternal confusion in strategy guides due to the totally different enemy names.</plot>
    <snapshot1>fN9XCa9.png</snapshot1>
  </game>
  <game name="Final Fantasy_Tactics - Advance (X)">
    <description>Final Fantasy Tactics - Advance (X)</description>
    <title_clean>Final Fantasy Tactics - Advance</title_clean>
    <rom name="EmuROMHacks/ROM_Hacks_1.zip/GBA%2FFinal%20Fantasy_Tactics%20-%20Advance%20%28X%29.gba" size="16777216"/>
    <plot>This simple hack insert 3 streamed songs from Final Fantasy Tactics Advance 2[CR]into Final Fantasy Tactics Advance into the unused space at the end of the[CR]ROM. They are the same songs, but with better quality (slightly remixed). The[CR]songs are : * Companions That Surpassed Their Tribe * Beyond the Wasteland *[CR]Painful Battle[CR]Read Me:[CR]Final Fantasy Tactics Advance - FFTA2 music[CR]insertion hack[CR]By Bregalad - june 11th 2010[CR]This simple hack insert 3[CR]streamed songs from Final Fantasy Tactics Advance 2 into Final Fantasy Tactics[CR]Advance into the unused space at the end of the ROM. They are the same songs,[CR]but with better quality (slightly remixed).[CR]The songs are :[CR]- Companions[CR]That Surpassed Their Tribe[CR]- Beyond the Wasteland[CR]- Painful[CR]Battle[CR]Other than that the game should be completely unaffected - but I[CR]cant give a 100% guarantee there is no bug/errors with the patch.[CR]Note that[CR]this hack only applies to the (U) version of Final Fantasy Tactics Advance.[CR]The (E) version didnt have enough free space for the song to fit at a decent[CR]quality.</plot>
    <genre>Sound</genre>
    <studio>Bregalad</studio>
    <snapshot1>wz48xhA.png</snapshot1>
    <snapshot2>0vRwCc0.png</snapshot2>
  </game>
  <game name="Fire Emblem 6.5 - Shining Armor (X)">
    <description>Fire Emblem 6.5 - Shining Armor (X)</description>
    <title_clean>Fire Emblem 6.5 - Shining Armor</title_clean>
    <rom name="EmuROMHacks/ROM_Hacks_1.zip/GBA%2FFire%20Emblem%206.5%20-%20Shining%20Armor%20%28X%29.gba" size="16788636"/>
    <plot>Shining Armor is a quick sequel to the trial maps in the 6th installment of[CR]the Fire Emblem series. Made up of only 2 chapters, you simple play 2 trial-[CR]map chapters that are 100% custom made. The thing is, the only units you have[CR]are Roy and his Knights. There's little text but a good 1+ hour of gameplay[CR]here. It's the 1st finished FE6 custom event/map hack. In fact, it's probably[CR]the first finished custom event hack between all the games, considering[CR]everything so far has just been demos. But this is not a demo. It's just a[CR]really short hack; if you think it's lame, get over it. Not all hacks are[CR]going to be super long. Most hacks that plan on being big don't finish anyway.[CR]I made it small and w00t, it finished. happy.gif Nonetheless, look and if it[CR]appeals to you, download. There are 2 patches included; one patches over the[CR]2.1 translation patch from RHND. The 2nd one patches over the original FE6 (J)[CR]ROM. Just start a new game and play. I copied the "How to Patch" and "Start[CR]Game" files from another hack so if it mentions another hack just ignore it.[CR]Enjoy![CR]Read Me:[CR]README[CR]-------[CR]Fire Emblem: Shining Armor[CR]created by Fire[CR]Blazer/Keriku[CR]smashfire17@gmail.com[CR]http://www.feshrine.net[CR]AIM:[CR]fireblazerx17[CR]If you need help with patching check the other files.[CR]This[CR]may NOT be re-distrubuted or used in anyway except for playing enjoyment[CR]without given permission from me, the creator.[CR]Thanks to everyone who has[CR]somehow helped the FE hacking community, bla bla bla.[CR]Hope you enjoy it!</plot>
    <genre>Graphics,Levels,Text,Gameplay</genre>
    <studio>Blazer</studio>
    <snapshot1>cSRLG8N.png</snapshot1>
    <snapshot2>1FDQQkf.png</snapshot2>
  </game>
  <game name="Fire Emblem 7 - AoTM (X)">
    <description>Fire Emblem 7 - AoTM (X)</description>
    <title_clean>Fire Emblem 7 - AoTM</title_clean>
    <rom name="EmuROMHacks/ROM_Hacks_1.zip/GBA%2FFire%20Emblem%207%20-%20AoTM%20%28X%29.gba" size="16777216"/>
    <snapshot1>6sD1hKU.jpg</snapshot1>
    <plot>Fire Emblem Attack of the Morphs![CR]You now have access to about 70 characters, which are bosses and npcs not normaly playable[ (duh :E)[CR]-There are a lot of new items. There are no longer stat boosters in the game.[CR]-Most weapons have reduced use, increased MT, reduced WT, increased Crit and Hit[CR]-Most staves have increased use[CR]-Level cap is 30[CR]-Promote your characters all the way to 3rd tiers.[CR]-All 3rd tiers have 7-12 move and +15 Crit, caps are 28-30</plot>
  </game>
  <game name="Fire Emblem 7 - Death or Glory (X)">
    <description>Fire Emblem 7 - Death or Glory (X)</description>
    <title_clean>Fire Emblem 7 - Death or Glory</title_clean>
    <rom name="EmuROMHacks/ROM_Hacks_1.zip/GBA%2FFire%20Emblem%207%20-%20Death%20or%20Glory%20%28X%29.gba" size="20782572"/>
    <plot>A new hack on FE7. A young soldier named Ragnar, who is a simple knight under oath to Azalia (country), is aiming to make a difference. Silvatica, a country that recently had a changed of heart, began its invasion against neighboring countries. In their invasion, they’ve not only captured many people to be used as soldiers or slaves, but also have destroyed entire cities and towns. Upon their attempt of taking over Azalia, they failed and suffered defeat for the first time. Due to rage, Azalia declared war. However, things didn’t go accordingly and now Azalia suffers in the palms of Silvatica as well as the others. But, only one knight has the will to stop them.</plot>
    <snapshot1>oGOTp87.jpg</snapshot1>
  </game>
  <game name="Fire Emblem 7 - Ostian Princess (X)">
    <description>Fire Emblem 7 - Ostian Princess (X)</description>
    <title_clean>Fire Emblem 7 - Ostian Princess</title_clean>
    <rom name="EmuROMHacks/ROM_Hacks_1.zip/GBA%2FFire%20Emblem%207%20-%20Ostian%20Princess%20%28X%29.gba" size="16777216"/>
    <plot>Based from: Fire Emblem - The Blazing Sword (FE7)[CR]WARNING: Extremely noobish hack ahead made with tons of non-existent experience, skipping it and going ahead with your life is recommended.[CR]This is my first Fire Emblem Hack, and it tells a story similar to Lyn’s. It features the daughter of Lilina(from Fire Emblem VI), Lilian.[CR]A young girl who looks a lot like her mother when she was young, like Lyn, she was born on the Lorca tribe but her father was not Hassar, Lilian’s father was Monke, a former member of the Djute clan.[CR]Monke joined the Lorca because that was the most peaceful tribe to live happily with his wife and daughter. There, he became the Lorca tribe’s chief. The rest of the story you will find out</plot>
    <snapshot1>XW9oD9K.png</snapshot1>
  </game>
  <game name="Fire Emblem 7 - Sacred Contention (X)">
    <description>Fire Emblem 7 - Sacred Contention (X)</description>
    <title_clean>Fire Emblem 7 - Sacred Contention</title_clean>
    <rom name="EmuROMHacks/ROM_Hacks_1.zip/GBA%2FFire%20Emblem%207%20-%20Sacred%20Contention%20%28X%29.gba" size="19126032"/>
    <plot>This game takes place on a remote island never introduced in any Fire Emblem game. The characters of Elibe and Magvel have both gathered on this island to wage a war against each other, in order to see which of the people and games are better. The Elibian characters are specifically from Fire Emblem 7: Blazing Sword, and NOT Fire Emblem: Fuuin no Tsurigi (Sealed Sword/Binding Blade).[CR]Thus the main characters of each side rally their former allies and enemies alike to face off against the people of another continent in a Sacred Contention.</plot>
    <snapshot1>DqABY67.jpg</snapshot1>
  </game>
  <game name="Fire Emblem 7 - The Last Promise (X)">
    <description>Fire Emblem 7 - The Last Promise (X)</description>
    <title_clean>Fire Emblem 7 - The Last Promise</title_clean>
    <rom name="EmuROMHacks/ROM_Hacks_1.zip/GBA%2FFire%20Emblem%207%20-%20The%20Last%20Promise%20%28X%29.gba" size="32505856"/>
    <plot>A millennium ago, on the continent of Blaine, humans and dragons fought.[CR]Humans, unable to match the power of the dragons, gathered together and saved[CR]themselves from the brink of extinction by relocating to Solum. On this new[CR]continent, the people were divided-and over time, each territory formed its[CR]own way of life, choosing how its people would live and what ideals they would[CR]carry. However, this all changes when Magnus, an empire with the greatest[CR]military on the continent, begins to invade the other territories. Though[CR]their campaign is time-consuming, they are successful in every way imaginable,[CR]quickly dominating Alicia to the north and Atheya to the east. But across the[CR]continent, there are people ready to fight back to their dying breath. One of[CR]them is Siegfried, a former Knight Commander who has been in hiding ever since[CR]an injury he received from ten years ago. With his pain serving as a reminder[CR]of the vow he made that fated day, he and his son, Shon, take up arms to[CR]gather allies and do whatever it takes to stop Magnus from dominating the[CR]continent. ...Because some promises, are just worth dying for. Go to[[CR]http://www.feshrine.net/thelastpromise/]([CR]http://www.feshrine.net/thelastpromise/) for more information[CR]Read[CR]Me:[CR]README[CR]-------[CR]Very briefly:[CR]- Patching instructions and[CR]version info are in the main folder. Before you try to patch, read the[CR]instructions. There are two ways to patch, but as far as I know, only NUPS[CR]will work with non-Windows users.[CR]- Version info details all the releases[CR]including whats in them but it does NOT include a list of bugs and glitches.[CR]The game is a hack and it isnt perfect; furthermore, before you go reporting[CR]things, please check the "Documentation" folder for the list of already known[CR]issues.[CR]- All special patches are in .ups (NUPS-only) form. You can apply[CR]them on top of any already patched version of The Last Promise. Applying them[CR]alone will likely break the game. Youve been warned.[CR]- Another warning--you[CR]may create your own problems by patching improperly or trying to use certain[CR]programs or cheats on the game. Dont blame me for stuff you try to do to the[CR]hack--play it normally and you should have minimal issues with the game.[CR]-[CR]A lot of people helped with this project, so be sure to take a peek at the[CR]credits.[CR]Enjoy!</plot>
    <genre>Graphics,Sound,Levels,Text,Gameplay</genre>
    <studio>Blazer</studio>
    <snapshot1>zRSKlci.jpg</snapshot1>
  </game>
  <game name="Fire Emblem 7.5 - Elibian Nights (X)">
    <description>Fire Emblem 7.5 - Elibian Nights (X)</description>
    <title_clean>Fire Emblem 7.5 - Elibian Nights</title_clean>
    <rom name="EmuROMHacks/ROM_Hacks_1.zip/GBA%2FFire%20Emblem%207.5%20-%20Elibian%20Nights%20%28X%29.gba" size="24443328"/>
    <plot>Elibian Nights is a fan-made sequel to Fire Emblem: The Blazing Sword (released as just "Fire Emblem" in the United States and Europe). The game follows the stories of Blazing Sword's cast between the end of that game and the beginning of its sequel, Binding Blade.[CR]The game is centered around "tales," which are like your standard Fire Emblem chapter. The main difference, however, is that each tale is completely independent. The cast of the first tale will not carry over into the second, and the stories, while some do link plot points together, each map's respective gameplay is completely independent.[CR]After a tale is completed, the player will be transported to the "Tale Select" screen. At this hub, you can select the next tale you wish to play, choose to replay any of the tales you've completed, and view your Achievements. If you're familiar with the XBOX360, you'll recognize the concept of "Achievements." The game features a total of 15 Achievements to unlock! Also included is a hub for "Bonus Content," unlockable extra cutscenes, and the new "Matchmaker" feature, which allows you to modify the default support pairing choices among FE7's characters.</plot>
    <snapshot1>R4h6kAt.jpg</snapshot1>
  </game>
  <game name="Golden Sun II - The Lost Age_RS (X)">
    <description>Golden Sun II - The Lost Age RS (X)</description>
    <title_clean>Golden Sun II - The Lost Age RS</title_clean>
    <rom name="EmuROMHacks/ROM_Hacks_1.zip/GBA%2FGolden%20Sun%20II%20-%20The%20Lost%20Age_RS%20%28X%29.gba" size="16777216"/>
    <plot>The bass-lines in Golden Sun and Golden Sun 2: The Lost Age soundtrack are[CR]almost inaudible through the GBA/GBA-SP/NDS small portable speakers, because[CR]such speakers aren't able to produce low sounds. To completely fix the[CR]problem, you will need large hi-quality headphones to plug in your GBA/GB-[CR]Micro/NDS. Unfortunately if you have a GBA-SP, a special adapter is needed.[CR]This hack partially fix that problem by replacing the bass guitar sample in[CR]both games by another bass guitar sample with much more harmonics, that will[CR]make more noise through the small crappy speaker so you'll hear the bass-lines[CR]better. This patch applies to the US version Golden Sun 2: The Lost Age. If[CR]you want to apply the hack to a version in another language and/or if you want[CR]to supply your own bass sample to try out, please contact me by email at[CR]jmasur [at] microclub [dot] ch.[CR]Read[CR]Me:[CR]****************************[CR]*** GOLDEN SUN BASS HACK[CR]***[CR]****************************[CR]By Bregalad, 21st June 2009[CR]The[CR]basslines in Golden Sun and Golden Sun 2 : The Lost Age soundtrack are almost[CR]unaudible through the GBA/GBA-SP/NDS small portable speakers, because such[CR]speakers arent able to produce low sounds.[CR]To completely fix the problem,[CR]you will need large hi-quality headphones to plug in your GBA/GB-Micro/NDS.[CR]Unfortunately if you have a GBA-SP, a special adapter is needed, and my[CR]adapter just stopped working after some usage so thats why I made this[CR]hack.[CR]This hack partially fix that problem by replacing the bass guitar[CR]sample in both games by another bass guitar sample with much more harmonics,[CR]that will make more noise through the small crappy speaker so youll hear the[CR]basslines better.[CR]This patch applies to the US version of Golden Sun 2 :[CR]The Lost Age. If you want to apply the hack to a version in another language[CR]and/or if you want to supply your own bass sample to try out, plese contact me[CR]by email at jmasur [at] microclub [dot] ch.</plot>
    <genre>Sound</genre>
    <studio>Bregalad</studio>
    <snapshot1>37CIWCE.png</snapshot1>
    <snapshot2>omYTZ1j.png</snapshot2>
  </game>
  <game name="Metroid - ZM Boss Rush (X)">
    <description>Metroid - ZM Boss Rush (X)</description>
    <title_clean>Metroid - ZM Boss Rush</title_clean>
    <rom name="EmuROMHacks/ROM_Hacks_1.zip/GBA%2FMetroid%20-%20ZM%20Boss%20Rush%20%28X%29.gba" size="8388608"/>
    <plot>Created using Double Helix by interdpth. Pit yourself against all the bosses[CR]in the game, room after room with some healing save rooms in between. All[CR]power ups are given in the beginning for you to pick. Try to aim for a fast[CR]time with the lowest item collection percentage possible! There are some weird[CR]graphic errors now and then as you can see with Kraid in the screenshot. This[CR]results from changing the tileset. It does not hinder the gameplay.</plot>
    <genre>Levels,Text</genre>
    <studio>monkeyboi</studio>
    <snapshot1>jf8eInq.png</snapshot1>
    <snapshot2>Mawrf0T.png</snapshot2>
  </game>
  <game name="Metroid - ZM Disturbance (X)">
    <description>Metroid - ZM Disturbance (X)</description>
    <title_clean>Metroid - ZM Disturbance</title_clean>
    <rom name="EmuROMHacks/ROM_Hacks_1.zip/GBA%2FMetroid%20-%20ZM%20Disturbance%20%28X%29.gba" size="8388608"/>
    <plot>This is my first ASM hack. At the start of the game it messes up some[CR]graphics. To fix it, as soon as you can move Samus, just start then go back to[CR]the game to play. Bomb jumping skills are needed for this hack. Enjoy! Apply[CR]to English MZM ROM.[CR]Read Me:[CR]Metroid Disturbance version[CR]0.2[CR]Instruction[CR]Theres my first ASM hack at the start of the game it[CR]messed up some graphics. To fix as soon as you can move Samus just start then[CR]go back to the game to play. :)[CR]Bomb jumping skills[CR]needed.[CR]Enjoy![CR]Apply to English MZM rom</plot>
    <genre>Graphics,Levels,Text,Gameplay</genre>
    <studio>interdpth</studio>
    <snapshot1>HsZusMu.png</snapshot1>
    <snapshot2>EslkgYh.png</snapshot2>
  </game>
  <game name="Pokemon - Flora Sky (X)">
    <description>Pokemon - Flora Sky (X)</description>
    <title_clean>Pokemon - Flora Sky</title_clean>
    <rom name="EmuROMHacks/ROM_Hacks_1.zip/GBA%2FPokemon%20-%20Flora%20Sky%20%28X%29.gba" size="33554432"/>
    <plot>Pokemon Flora Sky is a hack version of Pokemon Emerald Version. You can also[CR]see and catch all Pokemons from Gen IV and V that you just see in Pokemon[CR]games in Nintendo DS. Please rememer Pokemon Flora Sky is just a GameBoy[CR]Advance Game but you can enjoy more than you think. Below is Pokemon Flora Sky[CR]Story You'll come to a land with many mysteries of the legendary Pokemon.[CR]After the battle between Dialga and Palkia, the portal between Torn World -[CR]the world of Giratina and real world is opened. Giratina appears and brings[CR]many unanticipated dangers. And you must close this portal before its too[CR]late. Meanwhile, Team Magma and Aqua are seeking the legendary Fire and Water[CR]type Pokemon to dominate their world. Together with other friends, our hero[CR]will prevent the heat of the legendary Pokemon by the actions of Team Magma[CR]and Aqua. What will help Groudon and Kyogre calm down? For more stories, let's[CR]play.. We are also happy to introduce you new Features of Pokemon Flora Sky,[CR]having many differences from the original version, Pokemon Emerald. Pokemon[CR]Flora Sky Features: * Gen IV and V Pokemon * New Story * New Event For[CR]Legendary Pokemon * New Character * 386 Pokemon in the hack with new Sprites,[CR]4th and 5th Sprites * New Moves * New Map * New Items * New HM * New Minigame[CR]* Day Night System, Daily Events * Main Legendary (In Story): Shaymin,[CR]Giratina, Dialga. * After beat E4: Groudon, Kyogre, Rayquza, Mew, Arceus. And[CR]more... * 2 Versions: Main and Complement Dex Version. All is the lastest[CR]version.</plot>
    <genre>Graphics,Levels,Text,Gameplay</genre>
    <studio>Sky</studio>
    <snapshot1>gRYcuWO.png</snapshot1>
    <snapshot2>an8nqjJ.png</snapshot2>
  </game>
  <game name="Pokemon - Ultra Violet (X)">
    <description>Pokemon - Ultra Violet (X)</description>
    <title_clean>Pokemon - Ultra Violet</title_clean>
    <rom name="EmuROMHacks/ROM_Hacks_1.zip/GBA%2FPokemon%20-%20Ultra%20Violet%20%28X%29.gba" size="16777216"/>
    <plot>Pokemon Ultra Violet Version is a hack of the GameBoy Advance game Pokemon[CR]Fire Red Version. This new game has been altered in many ways to make the game[CR]more enjoyable, but it still has the same general design and story as the[CR]original Nintendo release. Among many other improvements, it has been made so[CR]that 1 player with 1 gamesave can play through the entire game and actually[CR]catch all of the Pokemon from the first 3 generations. Right off the bat, when[CR]you begin to play you will notice the new title screen. Along with the[CR]TitleScreen you may (or may not) notice that the stock names chosen for you[CR](if you press start with no name typed) have been augmented to reflect the[CR]game title, you will not find FIRE or RED as a name anymore, but ULTRA and[CR]VIOLET... also the rival names have been altered to match a fictitious rival[CR]game (based on blue version). Also, as you are getting your first Pokemon you[CR]may or may not notice an option to Catch your First Pokemon. If you talk to[CR]Professor Oak without choosing any of his 3 Pokemon, he realizes you do not[CR]want his hand me downs, and offers to let you catch your first Pokemon by your[CR]self. He will take you to one of his facilities and let you throw your fill of[CR]Safari Balls at some rare Pokemon until one is finally your Partner. Be sure[CR]to catch a good one, you will never be able to go back to that area again. If[CR]you choose this option, while you are gone, your impatient Rival picks[CR]Charmander as his partner. All pokemon from Fire Red and Leaf Green, that are[CR]catchable, will be residing in the area that they were obtainable in the[CR]regular version of the game. For example; on route 24 in Fire Red you can find[CR]Oddish, but in Leaf Green you will find Bellsprout... in Ultra Violet, you can[CR]find BOTH Oddish and Bellsprout. There are 2 instances where you are given a[CR]choice between 2 Pokemon. In Mt. Moon you choose between Kabuto and Omanyte[CR](by picking a fossil) and in Saffron you pick either Hitmonlee or Hitmonchan[CR]after defeating the Karate Master. In Ultra Violet you are allowed to take[CR]BOTH Fossils and BOTH fighting Pokemon. This makes it so there is not random[CR]location with these rare Pokemon residing. It would be silly to find extinct[CR]Pokemon chilling out on Route 14 wouldn't it. The 3 starter Pokemon are[CR]scattered throughout the land. They are rare and in logical locations. Prof.[CR]Oak was a real traveler back in his youth. Pokemon that you need to trade to[CR]evolve have been modified so they evolve in some other way now. You don't need[CR]to trade to do anything. Even Pokemon above 151 that would require you to[CR]trade with an item now evolve without trading, either by stone or level or[CR]some other logical manner. That includes Eevee and her night/day evolutions.[CR]Fire Red has no clock, so Umbreon and Espeon were impossible to get... now[CR]they are not. (no, a clock has not been added) All these, along with Mew being[CR]added in an undisclosed location, that covers all of the first generation and[CR]nearly all of the second generation Pokemon. For the few remaining Gen 2[CR]Pokemon that you could not originally aquire in Fire Red or Leaf Green, they[CR]have all been added in the Sevii Islands. All the ones (plus some) that[CR]belonged in Altering Cave are there, and all the rest are hidden throughout[CR]the islands in logical locations. Getting Hooh and Lugia and Dyoxis is now[CR]possible without going to a Nintendo event. You get to travel to the last 2[CR]islands and catch them as if you had attended the event, you simply buy the[CR]ticket at the store and take the boat as normal. The final Pokemon that need[CR]to be added are the 3 mystical dogs; Raikou, Entei, and Suicune. In Fire Red[CR]or Leaf Green, one dog is released based on your choice of Pokemon at the[CR]beginning of the game. That dog is then released into the wilderness of Kanto[CR]and you must find him and catch him... What about the other 2? You cannot get[CR]them in Fire Red or Leaf Green without trading. New locations had to be[CR]implemented, with new events that allowed players to catch the other 2 dogs.[CR]the correct 2 dogs. So if you look hard enough in Kanto you might just find[CR]the 2 dogs that are not roaming around chilling by the road or perhaps in a[CR]cave somewhere. Based on which starting Pokemon you chose, you may find any of[CR]the 3 in either location. Charmander has Suicune roaming Kanto, Raikou in[CR]location 1 and Entei in location 2. Bulbasaur has Entei roaming Kanto, Suicune[CR]in location 1 and Raikou in location 2. Squirtle has Raikou roaming Kanto,[CR]Entei in location 1 and Suicune in location 2. There has been some store and[CR]text modifications to match the new layout of Pokemon and new events. For[CR]example, Fire Red and Leaf Green have no sun stones... you cannot evolve[CR]Sunkern without a sun stone. So now sun stones are available in the Pokemart.[CR]* UPDATE (1.20)- There has been a new Island added. To get to the island you[CR]must talk to the girl in the southern most house in Virmillion city. This new[CR]island, 4-Points Isle, houses ALL gen 3 pokemon... there are several new[CR]events and areas to explore. (updating will not hurt version 1.10 gamesaves) *[CR]UPDATE (1.21)- Final update... no more work will be done on this hack... All[CR]game ending glitches have been fixed (many many minor glitches have also been[CR]fixed. EVERY Pokemon has been double checked as obtainable, a few new events[CR]have been added, (a celebi event in berry forest, try killing celebi before[CR]you catch it) Safe to play with all previous gamesaves... Also, a players[CR]guide has been added to the .rar... Use it... Its got the locations of every[CR]pokemon, item, and tm in the game... as well as an in depth walkthrough of[CR]every event... * 1.22 UPDATE- Players that cannot utilize in game saving (cell[CR]phone emulators) can now skip the game reset that occurs after fighting the[CR]e4... and can play the after game content...[CR]Read Me:[CR]Pokemon -[CR]Ultra Violet Version: By LocksmithArmy[CR]I never was a big fan of games you[CR]could not get everything by yourself. I am a 100%er so I always want to get[CR]EVERYTHING. Pokemon games by design make you either trade or buy and play more[CR]than one game to get everything. I did not like this...[CR]So I mixed Pokemon[CR]Fire Red and Leaf Green, that gave me ALL the pokemon from the first 2[CR]generations (I only neede to add a few gen 2 pokemon that were not in fire red[CR]or leaf green) ;)[CR]well that was not good enough becauseyou still could not[CR]complete the pokedex...[CR]so I made a new Island... To get to the island you[CR]must talk to the girl in the southern most house in Virmillion city. This new[CR]island, 4-Points Isle, houses ALL gen 3 pokemon... there are several new[CR]events and areas to explore.[CR]there are other changes other than pokemon[CR]changes... you may find them ;) they are to help you through the game, getting[CR]all the pokemon can be hard, even impossible if you dont have the right[CR]items... for example, how can you evolve your Sunkurn if you dont have any[CR]sunstones.[CR]Included in the .rar file you downloaded is an Official Players[CR]Guide, it contains all the secrets of the game... including all the locations[CR]for all 386 Pokemon and every TM and Item location[CR]aswell.[CR]INSTRUCTIONS:[CR]For to patch this IPS file you only need the[CR]contents of this .rar file and your origional copy of Pokemon - Fire Red[CR]Version (USA).[CR]Unzip this .rar archive (I use WinRAR) to any location on[CR]your computer.[CR]Add your Pokemon Fire Red Version rom to that[CR]folder.[CR]Double click the "Lunar IPS.exe" application[CR]Once it is opened[CR]click "Apply IPS Patch"[CR]Then select the "Pokemon - Ultra Violet[CR]Version(1.21) LSA.ips" file[CR]Next you will be prompted to select your clean[CR]copy of Pokemon Fire Red Version... [CR]After you select your rom the patch[CR]will be applied... you may want to rename your patched rom.[CR]If your[CR]emulator uses a "game_config.txt" file just add the text from the included[CR]"game_config.txt" to your existing file.[CR]Enjoy it![CR]Special thanks[CR]to:[CR]TheZunar123 for ideas and support [CR]karatekid552 for help with[CR]unsolvable problems ;)[CR]FBI agent for jogging my noggin when I wasnt seeing[CR]the big picture[CR]Lizzzz for being the best beta tester ever[CR]And one great[CR]big THANK YOU!!! to all the players who enjoy catching all the pokemon in this[CR]hack &lt;3.</plot>
    <genre>Levels,Text</genre>
    <studio>LocksmithArmy</studio>
    <snapshot1>W44CF19.png</snapshot1>
    <snapshot2>YKA4B1J.png</snapshot2>
  </game>
</datafile>