<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<datafile>
    <header>
        <emu_name>Sega Genesis Hacks</emu_name>
        <emu_description>Sega Genesis</emu_description>
        <emu_category>Sega, 1980s, Console, 16 Bit, Hacks</emu_category>
        <emu_version>10152019</emu_version>
        <emu_date>10/15/2019</emu_date>
        <emu_author>Zach Morris</emu_author>
        <emu_visibility>visible</emu_visibility>
        <emu_homepage>http://www.no-intro.org</emu_homepage>
        <emu_baseurl>http://archive.org/download/</emu_baseurl>
        <emu_launcher>retroplayer</emu_launcher>
        <emu_default_addon>none</emu_default_addon>
        <emu_ext_launch_cmd>none</emu_ext_launch_cmd>
        <emu_downloadpath>default</emu_downloadpath>
        <emu_postdlaction>none</emu_postdlaction>
        <emu_comment>Hacks are modified versions of old games. Some games get minor tweaks such as retranslations or simple gameplay improvements, others get complete overhauls that completely transform the original game. This is a list of just some of the Sega Genesis hacks available today.</emu_comment>
        <emu_thumb>LertPfl.jpg</emu_thumb>
        <emu_banner>uSg51Xq.jpg</emu_banner>
        <emu_fanart>r1Kk58D.jpg</emu_fanart>
        <emu_logo>4WSSkGz.png</emu_logo>
        <emu_trailer>KO-yCGIZZcY</emu_trailer>
    </header>
  <game name="Amy Rose in Sonic the Hedgehog (Rev.1.8)">
    <description>Amy Rose in Sonic the Hedgehog (Rev.1.8)</description>
    <title_clean>Amy Rose in Sonic the Hedgehog</title_clean>
    <rom name="EmuROMHacks/ROM_Hacks_1.zip/Genesis%2FAmy%20Rose%20in%20Sonic%20the%20Hedgehog%20%28Rev.1.8%29.bin" size="1048576"/>
    <plot>This is a hack which makes Amy Rose the primary character in the original[CR]Sonic the Hedgehog for Genesis. It is classic Amy designed after her Sonic CD[CR]appearance. Amy's moves are inspired by those used in her Sonic Advance[CR]appearance. She is slower than Sonic, can't use spin attack but has other[CR]moves. An attack button has been added and other moves can also be performed[CR]by using combinations of buttons and directional pad presses. A complete move[CR]list is found in the readme. This has been tested on a 1.0 version ROM in BIN[CR]format. It has not been tested for compatibility on other formats or other[CR]revisions. The patch is in xdelta format due to shifted data resulting in a[CR]ips patch larger than the ROM itself. Revision 1.9 * Physics are closer to[CR]Advance 1. Halting while ducking is less jerky and the hammer spin is now a[CR]slow descent. * Decided to add upward dash. Hold up and jump to charge like[CR]with super peel out. * Added ability to hammer switches and egg prison buttons[CR]I overlooked from Advance. * Collision issues with hammer downplayed. Attacks[CR]also work when Amy actually lands the hammer. * Loads of palette fixes. Far[CR]less pink this time round. * Rev 01 graphics added (e.g. extra scrolling and[CR]level select order fixed). * A few minor bug fixes added. Revision 2.0 * The[CR]hearts are now separate sprites and flow properly just like in Advance.[CR]Special thanx to Selbi, Snkenjoi, Flamewing and Shockwave677 for coding help.[CR]* A couple more bug fixes and palette tweaks (both the roller glitch and the[CR]bumper colour mentioned above are fixed). Revision 2.1 * Fixes Rev 01[CR]background errors and some glitches stemmed from hammering under certain[CR]circumstances. Special thanx Selbi.[CR]Read Me:[CR]Amy Rose in Sonic the[CR]Hedgehog[CR]version 2.1[CR]Credits: E-122-Psi[CR]Additional programming and[CR]coding by:[CR]MarkeyJester, Aquaslash, Selbi, and many others[CR]Hammer[CR]Attack: Press A and Amy swings her hammer, damaging enemies. In addition, Amy[CR]can use her hammer to smash obstacles such as walls and hit springs.[CR]Hammer[CR]Jump: Press Down + A on the ground and Amy smashes the hammer into the ground,[CR]launching her into the air.[CR]Hammer Whirl: Press Down + A in the air and Amy[CR]swirls down toward the ground. If an enemy is hit Amy will bounce up[CR]again.[CR]Giant Steps: Press Down + B/C while on the ground and Amy will take[CR]a giant step forward as opposed to a spin dash. This can be repeated so long[CR]as there is room. This move is good for getting up steep slopes; she can even[CR]get up slopes the others cant spin dash up!</plot>
    <genre>Graphics,Gameplay</genre>
    <studio>E-122-Psi</studio>
    <snapshot1>9X9tHnD.png</snapshot1>
    <snapshot2>ZDNIRbz.png</snapshot2>
  </game>
  <game name="Amy Rose in Sonic the Hedgehog 2 (Rev.1.5)">
    <description>Amy Rose in Sonic the Hedgehog 2 (Rev.1.5)</description>
    <title_clean>Amy Rose in Sonic the Hedgehog 2</title_clean>
    <rom name="EmuROMHacks/ROM_Hacks_1.zip/Genesis%2FAmy%20Rose%20in%20Sonic%20the%20Hedgehog%202%20%28Rev.1.5%29.bin" size="2097152"/>
    <plot>This is a hack which makes Amy Rose the primary character in Sonic the[CR]Hedgehog 2 for Genesis. It is classic Amy designed after her Sonic CD[CR]appearence. Amy's moves are inspired by those used in her Sonic Advance[CR]appearance. She is slower than Sonic, can't use spin attack but has other[CR]moves. An attack button has been added and other moves can also be performed[CR]by using combinations of buttons and directional pad presses. A complete move[CR]list is found in the readme. This has been tested on a 1.0 version ROM in BIN[CR]format. It has not been tested for compatibility on other formats or other[CR]revisions. The patch is in xdelta format due to shifted data resulting in a[CR]ips patch larger than the ROM itself. Revision 1.6 * Certain physic tweaks as[CR]with the S1 hack to be more authentic to Advance 1. * Amy can now use Giant[CR]Steps (upward dash is now activated with Up and B/C). * Amy can hammer[CR]switches and egg prisons. * Hammer hearts now trailing objects as in S1. *[CR]Select tracks, 03, 03, 03, 0B, 10, 10, 10 and 04 on the level select sound[CR]test to play a secret gameplay mode. * Continue screen freeze bug[CR]fixed.[CR]Read Me:[CR]Amy Rose in Sonic the Hedgehog 2[CR]Credits:[CR]E-122-Psi[CR]Additional programming and coding by:[CR]MarkeyJester,[CR]MainMemory, Selbi, Hayate. [CR]==Controls==[CR]Amys abilities mirror those she[CR]utilized in the Sonic Advance series. She is slower than[CR]Sonic and cant use[CR]spin attacks, however has a number of abilities (mostly using her Piko[CR]Piko[CR]Hammer) to gain manueverability and access areas Sonic had difficulty[CR]reaching:[CR]*Hammer Attack: Press A and Amy swings her hammer, damaging[CR]enemies. In addition, Amy can[CR] use her hammer to smash obstacles such as[CR]walls and hit springs.[CR]*Hammer Jump: Press Down + A on the ground and Amy[CR]smashes the hammer into the ground,[CR] launching her into the air.[CR]*Hammer[CR]Whirl: Press Down + A in the air and Amy swirls down toward the ground. If[CR]an[CR] enemy is hit Amy will bounce up again.[CR]*Upward Dash: Hold Up + B/C[CR]while on the ground and Amy will rev her feet on the spot as[CR] opposed to a[CR]spin dash. Let go of Down to charge full throttle in the facing direction.[CR]Be careful though, Amy is vulnerable to blockading obstacles and[CR]enemies.[CR]*Giant Steps: Press Down + B/C while on the ground and Amy will[CR]take a giant step forward[CR] as opposed to a spin dash. This can be repeated[CR]so long as there is room. This move is[CR] good for getting up steep slopes;[CR]she can even get up slopes the others cant spin dash up![CR]Amy gains a few[CR]stipulations akin to Knuckles in Sonic 2, for example, the ring quota[CR]in[CR]Special Stages are depleted and she retains her ring count after losing[CR]lives or entering[CR]starposts. 2 Player options and the ability to play as[CR]Tails remain from the original game[CR]however.</plot>
    <genre>Graphics,Gameplay</genre>
    <studio>E-122-Psi</studio>
    <snapshot1>v464Kjj.png</snapshot1>
    <snapshot2>PPFBLOl.png</snapshot2>
  </game>
  <game name="An Ordinary Sonic ROM Hack (SHC 2013 Build)">
    <description>An Ordinary Sonic ROM Hack (SHC 2013 Build)</description>
    <title_clean>An Ordinary Sonic ROM Hack</title_clean>
    <rom name="EmuROMHacks/ROM_Hacks_1.zip/Genesis%2FAn%20Ordinary%20Sonic%20ROM%20Hack%20%28SHC%202013%20Build%29.bin" size="1572864"/>
    <plot>Here is a hack for Sonic where you not only play through the levels but every[CR]so often you will warp to an alternate dimension where you cant hurt some[CR]enemies and you are being chased by "creepypasta" sonic... You only means to[CR]temporarily escape the twisted dimension is to smash an item box.</plot>
    <genre>Graphics,Sound,Text,Gameplay</genre>
    <studio>Cinossu</studio>
    <snapshot1>Nx5tKNy.png</snapshot1>
    <snapshot2>bdUThat.png</snapshot2>
  </game>
  <game name="Angry Birds">
    <description>Angry Birds</description>
    <title_clean>Angry Birds</title_clean>
    <rom name="EmuROMHacks/ROM_Hacks_1.zip/Genesis%2FAngry%20Birds.bin" size="2621440"/>
  </game>
  <game name="Angry Birds - Star Wars">
    <description>Angry Birds - Star Wars</description>
    <title_clean>Angry Birds - Star Wars</title_clean>
    <rom name="EmuROMHacks/ROM_Hacks_1.zip/Genesis%2FAngry%20Birds%20-%20Star%20Wars.bin" size="1048576"/>
  </game>
  <game name="Atomic Sonic">
    <description>Atomic Sonic</description>
    <title_clean>Atomic Sonic</title_clean>
    <rom name="EmuROMHacks/ROM_Hacks_1.zip/Genesis%2FAtomic%20Sonic.bin" size="1048576"/>
    <plot>This is a hack for Sonic 3D Blast on the Sega Genesis. It gives Sonic the[CR]ability to transform into Super Sonic, a super powered version of himself. As[CR]in other Sonic titles this is done by acquiring all 7 Chaos Emeralds, getting[CR]50 or more rings then pressing jump during a jump. Rings decrease[CR]automatically while in this form. The transformation cannot be done while[CR]using a shield but the shield can still be collected after using the[CR]transformation is complete. Sonic is mostly invincible while in Super form but[CR]can still be killed by objects that crush him and the electric walls in Gene[CR]Gadget zone. This hack is based on the [Sonic 3D: No[CR]Flickies](http://www.romhacking.net/hacks/1052/) hack which means it has the[CR]same features and flaws of that hack. The patch is in xdelta format due to[CR]shifted data resulting in IPS patches that sometimes contain original game[CR]code. The ROM should be in BIN format.[CR]Read Me:[CR]Super Sonic in Sonic[CR]3D[CR]Credits: Sik[CR]Super Sonic in Sonic 3D is a hack of Sonic 3D: Flickies[CR]Island. This hack allows the player to turn into Super Sonic in the game after[CR]collecting all seven Chaos Emeralds, mimicking its prequels Sonic 2, Sonic 3[CR]and Sonic and Knuckles. The rules are borrowed from the latter two games, so[CR]the player must double jump to transform and also must not have a shield in[CR]that moment, besides the basic requirements (having all emeralds and 50[CR]rings).[CR]All of Super Sonics behaviour is implemented: custom palette, a[CR]transformation pose with a fading palette, invincibility (with stars), speed[CR]shoes and the music changes when transformed. Rings drain while transformed as[CR]well. Super Sonic can still be killed by getting crushed by some falling[CR]platforms, however, so he isnt completely immune to death.[CR]This hack is[CR]based off Sonic 3D: No Flickies, and as such it shares the same gameplay[CR]rules.[CR]==Implemented changes==[CR]Super Sonic in this hack behaves in a[CR]similar way to how it behaves in Sonic 3 and Sonic and Knuckles:[CR]*If you[CR]have 7 emeralds and 50 rings, you can double jump to become Super[CR]Sonic.[CR]*You cant transform as long as you have a shield. You can get a[CR]shield after being transformed though, allowing Super Sonic to get and keep[CR]the Blast Attack, the predecessor to the Homing Attack of the later[CR]games.[CR]*Being Super Sonic drains rings.[CR]*Super Sonic automatically[CR]detransforms when the level finishes.[CR]==Known issues==[CR]*The score tally[CR]doesnt mention that the player can transform into Super Sonic after getting[CR]all seven emeralds.[CR]*Touching the electric walls in Gene Gadget zone while[CR]transformed will cause Super Sonic to stay stuck until the rings drain[CR]completely and he dies.[CR]*The water in Green Grove becomes yellow. Because a[CR]RAM or ROM altering code is needed to be able to transform in that zone, this[CR]isnt considered a serious bug. Some other graphics across the game are also[CR]affected, but arent as noticeable.[CR]*All issues from Sonic 3D: No Flickies[CR]still are present in this hack.</plot>
    <genre>Graphics,Gameplay</genre>
    <studio>Sik</studio>
    <snapshot1>qbuFcwd.png</snapshot1>
    <snapshot2>AP7ue9W.png</snapshot2>
  </game>
  <game name="Big's Fishing Derby (SHC 2015 Build)">
    <description>Big's Fishing Derby (SHC 2015 Build)</description>
    <title_clean>Big's Fishing Derby</title_clean>
    <rom name="EmuROMHacks/ROM_Hacks_1.zip/Genesis%2FBig%27s%20Fishing%20Derby%20%28SHC%202015%20Build%29.bin" size="1048576"/>
    <plot>* Help Big the Cat fish Froggy out of the fifteen different ponds spanning across four Sonic games. * Compete against a friend to fish out Froggy. * Catch fish for items that either hinder the opponent or otherwise assist you. The more rings you have, the better the item. V2 Update After taking last year's contest by storm, here is a vastly improved Big's Fishing Derby. Changes include: * 14 brand new levels, and many old ones improved! * All new single-player game modes: race against the clock 'time attack', battle bosses, limited lives and increasing difficulty on 'arcade mode', or just chill on 'zen mode'. * Many new multiplayer options: play random levels, or play them in sequence, or play a 'best X out of Y' game. * Amazing new music by Ivan IO, Nineko, Spanner, S_T_D and ValleyBell. * Amazing new Big by E-122-Psi. * Rebalanced powerup probabilities, and a brand new shield power-up. Later Updates * A second player can also play Eggman, and he competes with Big in the race to catch Froggy.</plot>
    <genre>Graphics,Sound,Levels,Text,Gameplay</genre>
    <studio>flamewing</studio>
    <snapshot1>XQLzOmg.png</snapshot1>
    <snapshot2>selJlpT.png</snapshot2>
  </game>
  <game name="Castlevania - Bloodlines Enhanced Colors (v.1.0)">
    <description>Castlevania - Bloodlines Enhanced Colors (v.1.0)</description>
    <title_clean>Castlevania - Bloodlines Enhanced Colors</title_clean>
    <rom name="EmuROMHacks/ROM_Hacks_1.zip/Genesis%2FCastlevania%20-%20Bloodlines%20Enhanced%20Colors%20%28v.1.0%29.md" size="1048576"/>
    <plot>This patch aims improve the graphics of this underrated classic from Mega[CR]Drive. Konami made questionable choices regarding the use of colors. Now[CR]everyone can enjoy the Bloodlines in all your glory, enjoy! * The images do[CR]not represent how much this game has changed. Modifications: * All openings[CR]were thoroughly improved. * Characters received new skin colors. * All enemies[CR]have received more appropriate colors and better shading. * The stages[CR]received a new finish and are much better. * The game was 100% modified and[CR]polished.</plot>
    <genre>Graphics</genre>
    <studio>Pyron</studio>
    <snapshot1>u16Mcsh.gif</snapshot1>
    <snapshot2>GWVJatc.png</snapshot2>
  </game>
  <game name="Contra - Hard Corps (X) [!]">
    <description>Contra - Hard Corps (X) [!]</description>
    <title_clean>Contra - Hard Corps</title_clean>
    <rom name="EmuROMHacks/ROM_Hacks_1.zip/Genesis%2FContra%20-%20Hard%20Corps%20%28X%29%20%5B%21%5D.bin" size="2097304"/>
    <plot>It's a hack, not a retranslation, although the script has been cleaned up.[CR]Lots of minor tweaks and things to make this my ideal version of the far[CR]superior USA release. There may even be some undocumented stuff I added... *[CR]Copyright screen edited slightly. * Copyright screen can now be skipped by[CR]pressing the start button. * Minor rewording in options menus. * Maximum[CR]number of lives in options menu increased to 5 (default is still 3). * Got rid[CR]of the annoying "press start to exit" feature in some menus. * Start button[CR]can now be used to confirm some options. * Start button can now be used to[CR]select your character. * Mission briefings can now be skipped by pressing the[CR]start button. * You can now hold buttons B and C to skip through text faster.[CR]* In-game font fixed such that lower-case characters are now usable. * Added[CR]an alternate font (activated with a code). * Added 'e accent aigu' for 'coup[CR]d'etat'. * Script corrected, edited, and optimized. * Soft reset[CR]added.[CR]Read Me:[CR]Patch version 120527 (yymmdd)[CR]Readme version[CR]120527 (yymmdd)[CR] Contra: Hard Corps[CR] Enhancement Hack[CR] by[CR]M.I.J.E.T.[CR]History[CR]-----------------------------------------------------------------------------[CR]080924[CR]Initial release[CR]120527 Special Champion Edition release[CR]Overview[CR]-----------------------------------------------------------------------------[CR]This[CR]is a patch for the Genesis game "Contra: Hard Corps" which makes[CR]numerous[CR]minor enhancements. It started out as a simple hack to permit[CR]the user to[CR]skip the mission briefings, which get annoying when one has[CR]played the game[CR]dozens of times.[CR]Since that hack was implemented by manipulating the text-[CR]printing state[CR]machine, it eventually led to a full script replacement to[CR]enhance and[CR]correct the original. Quite a few other minor[CR]fixes/enhancements were[CR]added as well. See the complete list of changes in[CR]this file for details.[CR]As far as the script corrections go, this patch[CR]should take care of the[CR]agreement-in-number problems and also improves the[CR]phrasing here and there.[CR]Some minor errors were also fixed, such as the[CR]misspelling of "Noiman".[CR] Applying the[CR]Patch[CR]-----------------------------------------------------------------------------[CR]Hopefully[CR]included with this document is a patch file in the IPS format.[CR]You can use[CR]any program that supports that file format to apply this[CR]patch to your ROM[CR]file.[CR]Alternatively, you can use the program from my website to apply the[CR]patch,[CR]but make sure that you have the latest version or it wont work. The[CR]program[CR]will check the ROM file (de-interleaving it if necessary) and will[CR]give[CR]you an error message if something went wrong. A normal IPS program[CR]cannot[CR]do this as it has no idea what it is patching. The program has not[CR]been[CR]extensively tested, so if you have problems (or simply dont trust a[CR]foreign[CR]executable) you always have the option of using a different[CR]program.[CR]Remember to use the USA version of the game; other editions will[CR]not work.[CR] Playing the[CR]Game[CR]-----------------------------------------------------------------------------[CR]Once[CR]youve patched the ROM file, simply load it up in your favorite[CR]Genesis /[CR]Mega Drive emulator, console copier, or flash cartridge.[CR]You can perform a[CR]soft reset by pressing A, B, C, and Start any time after[CR]the game has[CR]finished initializing (once it starts displaying graphics).[CR]Holding down B[CR]and C will allow you to skip through text faster.[CR]You can toggle the in-[CR]game font by holding down A and C for at least one full[CR]second any time[CR]after the game has initialized. This wont take effect until[CR]the next time[CR]the font is loaded, so you wont see an immediate difference if[CR]you enter[CR]this code while text is printing. Enter the code again to switch[CR]back to[CR]the other font. A sound effect will play whenever the swap occurs.[CR]Another[CR]new feature is the ability to select the same character in two-[CR]player[CR]games. This changes the gameplay and destroys an element of realism,[CR]which[CR]Konami probably would not have approved of. Therefore it must be[CR]activated[CR]at the title screen by entering a code: the already overused[CR]Konami Code. *[CR]You will hear a sound effect if you entered it[CR]correctly.[CR]Note that the above assumes you are using the default button[CR]configuration.[CR]Another caveat is that soft reset doesnt work as well in[CR]Gens (at least[CR]not in the versions Ive tried; it may have been fixed in[CR]other releases).[CR]I suspect the problem is that its not emulating bit 6 of[CR]$A1000D correctly.[CR]As a result, it always does a full reset, wasting[CR]several seconds of your[CR]life. Soft reset works properly in Fusion and on a[CR]real Genesis.[CR]* Konami Code: Up, Up, Down, Down, Left, Right, Left, Right,[CR]B, A[CR] Q and[CR]A[CR]-----------------------------------------------------------------------------[CR]Q:[CR]This patch doesnt work! What do I do?[CR]A: Make sure that your ROM file is[CR]not in an interleaved format. Its also[CR] possible that you are using the[CR]wrong version of the game, or that your[CR] copy is corrupt. If you have[CR]problems, try using the program that I wrote[CR] to apply the patch; it checks[CR]for the above issues. It is available on my[CR] website.[CR]Q: It doesnt work[CR]with my copier / flash cartridge! Why not?[CR] This was tested on a real[CR]Genesis so you shouldnt have any problems in[CR] that respect. The most likely[CR]reason is that something went wrong during[CR] the patching process. See the[CR]previous question and try it in an emulator[CR] to see if that works.[CR]Another possibility is that you are using a PAL Mega Drive. This game was[CR]designed for NTSC systems and I didnt make any changes in that respect.[CR] It[CR]should still run (probably at the wrong speed), but you never know...[CR]Q: Is[CR]your patcher program safe?[CR]A: No. Anyone could replace it with a trojan and[CR]rewrite this readme to[CR] make it seem safe. Thats one reason why I dont[CR]include it with the[CR] patch itself. Its up to you to decide which program to[CR]use to apply[CR] the patch, but unless you wrote the program yourself theres[CR]always[CR] some risk involved.[CR]Q: How do I activate the new "Special[CR]Champion Edition" feature?[CR]A: Enter the Konami Code at the title screen.[CR]Either controller will work.[CR] Both players will then be able to select the[CR]same character.[CR]Q: What is the Konami Code?[CR]A: Up, Up, Down, Down, Left,[CR]Right, Left, Right, B, A.[CR]Q: Is this game subtitled "Hardcorps" or "Hard[CR]Corps"?[CR]A: Well, first lets look at some data:[CR] USA credits: HARD /[CR]CORPS[CR] USA ROM header: ZA*HAADOKOA and HARDCORPS[CR] USA music test: THE[CR]HARD CORPS (2x)[CR] USA title screen: HARD / CORPS[CR] USA copyright screen:[CR]HARDCORPS[CR] USA cartridge label (top): Hard Corps[CR] Japanese credits: HARD[CR]/ CORPS (no the)[CR] Japanese ROM header: ZA*HAADOKOA and HARDCORPS[CR]Japanese music test: THE HARD CORPS (2x)[CR] Japanese title screen:[CR]ZA*HAADOKOA[CR] Japanese copyright screen: THE HARDCORPS[CR] The Japanese[CR]authors didnt sort this out properly, but they seemed to[CR] have intended the[CR]two-word version. The copyright screen and ROM header[CR] can be excused since[CR]typical Japanese rarely marks the separation in[CR] compound words/phrases[CR]derived from Western languages.[CR] Despite the copyright screen, the evidence[CR]strongly suggests "Hard Corps"[CR] is the proper way to write it, and so I[CR]recommend using "Hard Corps" for[CR] the American version and "The Hard Corps"[CR]for the Japanese version. This[CR] patch adjusts the copyright screen to[CR]reflect that. The ROM header hasnt[CR] been changed because its not meant to[CR]be seen by the user and I frown[CR] on the practice of editing the title part[CR]of headers; there are too many[CR] worthless hacked versions of ROMs floating[CR]around because of it.[CR]Q: Whats with the subtitle anyway? Is it some kind of[CR]play on words?[CR]A: For those not familiar with the word, corps is pronounced[CR]like core.[CR] Technically, "hard core" is a noun, while hard-core (or[CR]hardcore) is an[CR] adjective. Therefore "Contra: Hardcorps" would have made[CR]more sense for[CR] the American version, at least from a grammatical[CR]standpoint. On the[CR] other hand, "The Hard Corps" works just fine for the[CR]Japanese version.[CR]Q: How do you pronounce "Neumann"?[CR]A: Written[CR]phonetically, its "Noiman" or "Noyman". Same sound as oyster.[CR]Q: Why is the[CR]font a bit hard to read?[CR]A: If youre playing on a real Genesis, you may[CR]find the games default font[CR] difficult to read because it is so thin. See[CR]the relevant section above[CR] for information on how to switch the font[CR]during play.[CR] The default font is a modified version of the font that the[CR]game uses[CR] normally, which is why it is used by default, even though I dont[CR]like it.[CR]Q: Why is this game so hard?[CR]A: Because its "hard core". But in[CR]case you arent, you can now increase[CR] the starting number of lives in the[CR]options menu.[CR] Aside from training/practice sessions, you should stick with[CR]the default[CR] of 3 lives. Unless you are playing along with your retarded[CR]sibling or[CR] girlfriend or something. Real men play this game with 3 lives[CR]or fewer. *[CR] The Japanese version, on the other hand, is decidedly NOT[CR]"hard core",[CR] with unlimited continues and 3 hits per life. The life bars[CR]alone are[CR] roughly equivalent to tripling the number of lives you start[CR]with in the[CR] USA version. This is compounded every time you gain extra[CR]lives from[CR] points (normally this happens for the first time after beating[CR]the giant[CR] robot in the first stage). The fact that you only lose your[CR]weapon every[CR] third time you are hit makes it even EASIER. Whats so "hard[CR]core" about[CR] a game that can be easily beaten with extremely sloppy play?[CR]Wheres the[CR] rush when you can only lose if you give up and quit[CR]playing?[CR] * M.I.J.E.T. does not endorse sexist statements, except when used[CR]for[CR] hyperbole, and affirms that females are fully capable of playing[CR]games[CR] well; its as natural as shopping, crying, and tool-assisted speed[CR]runs.[CR] List of[CR]Changes[CR]-----------------------------------------------------------------------------[CR]Soft[CR]reset added.[CR]Copyright screen edited slightly.[CR]Copyright screen can now[CR]be skipped by pressing the start button.[CR]Minor rewording in options[CR]menus.[CR]Maximum number of lives in options menu increased to 5 (default is[CR]still 3).[CR]Got rid of the annoying "press start to exit" feature in some[CR]menus.[CR]Start button can now be used to confirm some options.[CR]Start[CR]button can now be used to select your character.[CR]Entering a code permits[CR]the same character to be selected by both players.[CR]Mission briefings can[CR]now be skipped by pressing the start button.[CR]You can now hold buttons B and[CR]C to skip through text faster.[CR]The hide-pause-banner feature now requires a[CR]certain debugging mode.[CR]In-game font fixed such that lower-case characters[CR]are now usable.[CR]Added an alternate font (activated with a code).[CR]Added e[CR]accent aigu to font for coup detat.[CR]Script corrected, edited, and[CR]optimized.[CR]Fixed a display bug if your bomb stock exceeds 99.[CR]Contact[CR]-----------------------------------------------------------------------------[CR]mijeto@gmail.com[CR]Warning:[CR]The above address is often not checked for months at a[CR]time.[CR]http://mijet.eludevisibility.org/</plot>
    <genre>Text</genre>
    <studio>M.I.J.E.T.</studio>
    <snapshot1>1PlzU75.png</snapshot1>
    <snapshot2>Xn853L0.png</snapshot2>
  </game>
  <game name="Doctor Robotnik's Creature Capture (X)">
    <description>Doctor Robotnik's Creature Capture (X)</description>
    <title_clean>Doctor Robotnik's Creature Capture</title_clean>
    <rom name="EmuROMHacks/ROM_Hacks_1.zip/Genesis%2FDoctor%20Robotnik%27s%20Creature%20Capture%20%28X%29.bin" size="4194304"/>
    <plot>This is a hack which changes Sonic the Hedgehog for Genesis into a entirely[CR]different game with new gameplay. It stars Dr. Robotnik whom must capture[CR]creatures with a net and put them in creature capsules. The graphics are the[CR]same as previous Sonic games but the rest is mostly changed. Most levels are[CR]open by default. The ROM should be in BIN format. The patch is in XDelta[CR]format as the games data has been shifted. Shifted data is incorporated into[CR]IPS patches thus copyrighted data is incorporated into IPS patches. Using[CR]XDelta fixes this.[CR]Read Me:[CR]Doctor Robotniks Creature[CR]Capture[CR]==Unlockables==[CR]The remaining levels are unlocked when beating[CR]MarkyJesters best time: 3:57:2348.[CR]==Credits==[CR]*SSRG (chat) for their[CR]ideas[CR]*E-122-Psi for the HUD lettering[CR]*Destructiox for the major layout[CR]changes and cleverly setout objects[CR]*Spanner for the original Cyber Track[CR]import[CR]*SonicVaan for the credits screen[CR]*...A few other random people[CR]for testing it out (I dont think I can list them all, sorry)</plot>
    <genre>Graphics,Levels,Text,Gameplay</genre>
    <studio>MarkeyJester</studio>
    <snapshot1>PTImS5d.png</snapshot1>
    <snapshot2>cpR1Pc8.png</snapshot2>
  </game>
  <game name="Doctor Robotnik's Plan B (Rev 1)">
    <description>Doctor Robotnik's Plan B (Rev 1)</description>
    <title_clean>Doctor Robotnik's Plan B</title_clean>
    <rom name="EmuROMHacks/ROM_Hacks_1.zip/Genesis%2FDoctor%20Robotnik%27s%20Plan%20B%20%28Rev%201%29.bin" size="524288"/>
  </game>
  <game name="Dr. Robotnik's Creature Capture (v.1.3)">
    <description>Dr. Robotnik's Creature Capture (v.1.3)</description>
    <title_clean>Dr. Robotnik's Creature Capture</title_clean>
    <rom name="EmuROMHacks/ROM_Hacks_1.zip/Genesis%2FDr.%20Robotnik%27s%20Creature%20Capture%20%28v.1.3%29.bin" size="4194304"/>
    <plot>This is a hack which changes Sonic the Hedgehog for Genesis into a entirely[CR]different game with new gameplay. It stars Dr. Robotnik whom must capture[CR]creatures with a net and put them in creature capsules. The graphics are the[CR]same as previous Sonic games but the rest is mostly changed. Most levels are[CR]open by default. The ROM should be in BIN format. The patch is in XDelta[CR]format as the games data has been shifted. Shifted data is incorporated into[CR]IPS patches thus copyrighted data is incorporated into IPS patches. Using[CR]XDelta fixes this.[CR]Read Me:[CR]Doctor Robotniks Creature[CR]Capture[CR]==Unlockables==[CR]The remaining levels are unlocked when beating[CR]MarkyJesters best time: 3:57:2348.[CR]==Credits==[CR]*SSRG (chat) for their[CR]ideas[CR]*E-122-Psi for the HUD lettering[CR]*Destructiox for the major layout[CR]changes and cleverly setout objects[CR]*Spanner for the original Cyber Track[CR]import[CR]*SonicVaan for the credits screen[CR]*...A few other random people[CR]for testing it out (I dont think I can list them all, sorry)</plot>
    <genre>Graphics,Levels,Text,Gameplay</genre>
    <studio>MarkeyJester</studio>
    <snapshot1>PTImS5d.png</snapshot1>
    <snapshot2>cpR1Pc8.png</snapshot2>
  </game>
  <game name="Jester's Challenge (v.1.0)">
    <description>Jester's Challenge (v.1.0)</description>
    <title_clean>Jester's Challenge</title_clean>
    <rom name="EmuROMHacks/ROM_Hacks_1.zip/Genesis%2FJester%27s%20Challenge%20%28v.1.0%29.bin" size="4194304"/>
    <plot>This is a hack of Sonic the Hedgehog for the Sega Genesis. It nearly[CR]completely changes all graphics, music, and layout. Sonic's sprite remains the[CR]same but the rest is mostly changed. The game consists of a single maze-like[CR]level which can take 20 minutes or more to complete. A special boss awaits at[CR]the end of the maze. Most of the power-up monitors from Sonic 1 are still[CR]present in addition to two new ones. Monitors with red and blue arrows will[CR]change the stage layout when hit. Breaking monitors with a snowflake on them[CR]will freeze the level or thaw it out if it is already frozen. The music is[CR]notable for being several sets of DAC samples which are played together. These[CR]segments will play in random order making for unique tracks each time the game[CR]is played. This also saves space used by making a single song. The song[CR]segments are well composed and make for great atmosphere to the[CR]game.[CR]Read Me:[CR]Jesters Challenge[CR]Credits: MarkeyJester,[CR]SonicVaan, Irixion, Selbi, DalekSam, theocas, SOTI, and Tweaker.[CR]Jesters[CR]Challenge is a hack of Sonic the Hedgehog for the Sega Mega Drive/Genesis[CR]featuring a simple maze-like level hack which extended.[CR]==Gameplay==[CR]As[CR]soon as the ROM is loaded Sonic is dropped into a level called the Param Zone.[CR]Jester can be seen in many locations in the maze and when you press B while[CR]standing next to him an arrow will appear above his head directing you to[CR]where you should go. At particular points he may have short messages to say[CR]like "Youre on track!".[CR]Most of the normal monitors from the original Sonic[CR]1 are present as well as two new monitors. Monitors with red and blue arrows[CR]inside will change the stage layout when hit, and hitting monitors with a[CR]snowflake in them will freeze the entire stage or thaw it out if it is already[CR]frozen. Wind turbines can be seen in the background at the top of the maze and[CR]as Sonic proceeds further downward in the stage things get hotter as the[CR]pallette changes and heat shimmers indicate an inferno in the background. When[CR]everything is frozen the heat shimmers arent there, the turbines stop moving[CR]and Sonics breath can be seen. Motobugs appear in many random places in the[CR]maze.[CR]Once the player reaches the end of the maze, there will be something[CR]big and suprising waiting for him/her, however, the only way for YOU to find[CR]out what "it" is, is to play right through it, good luck![CR]==Music==[CR]The[CR]music is notable for being a series of DAC samples played together. Instead of[CR]having an entire PCM track in the ROM taking up a lot of space, they have been[CR]split into small samples that can be repeated and reused to make the tracks[CR]feel longer while keeping the ROM size down.[CR]Song listings:[CR]*Param Zone[CR]= Remix of DJ Ron - Dangerous (Cannan Land).[CR]*Param Zone ICE = Toshio[CR]Shimizu and Tate Norio (Yasuo Yamate) - Last Resort (The Melting[CR]Pot).[CR]*Invincible = Remix of Ultraworld - Northern Piano (Hardcore Piano[CR]Mix).[CR]*Boss Theme = Tweaker - made exclusively for this hack.[CR]*Credits[CR]Theme = Unknown author - Fantazia 1992.</plot>
    <genre>Graphics,Sound,Levels,Text,Gameplay</genre>
    <studio>MarkeyJester</studio>
    <snapshot1>3GSGVzl.png</snapshot1>
    <snapshot2>Cuq26mu.png</snapshot2>
  </game>
  <game name="Kid Chameleon 2 - Heady Metal's Revenge (v.5.0).smd">
    <description>Kid Chameleon 2 - Heady Metal's Revenge (v.5.0).smd</description>
    <title_clean>Kid Chameleon 2 - Heady Metal's Revenge .smd</title_clean>
    <rom name="EmuROMHacks/ROM_Hacks_1.zip/Genesis%2FKid%20Chameleon%202%20-%20Heady%20Metal%27s%20Revenge%20%28v.5.0%29.smd" size="2097152"/>
    <plot>This is a complete level hack of the original Kid Chameleon game for the[CR]Genesis/Mega Drive. Most of the palettes have been altered as well.</plot>
    <genre>Graphics,Levels</genre>
    <studio>super1rios</studio>
    <snapshot1>9MRv3og.jpg</snapshot1>
    <snapshot2>kKXcUQn.jpg</snapshot2>
  </game>
  <game name="Knuckles in Sonic the Hedgehog 2 Long Version (v1.8.1)">
    <description>Knuckles in Sonic the Hedgehog 2 Long Version (v1.8.1)</description>
    <title_clean>Knuckles in Sonic the Hedgehog 2 Long Version</title_clean>
    <rom name="EmuROMHacks/ROM_Hacks_1.zip/Genesis%2FKnuckles%20in%20Sonic%20the%20Hedgehog%202%20Long%20Version%20%28v1.8.1%29.bin" size="3407872"/>
    <plot>This is a hack which adds levels that were scrapped from Sonic the Hedgehog 2[CR]for Sega Genesis. The levels in the hack are listed below: * Emerald Hill Zone[CR]* Chemical Plant Zone * Aquatic Ruin Zone * Casino Night Zone * Hill Top Zone[CR]* Wood Zone: (scrapped from final release) * Dust Hill Zone: This version[CR]switches between both desert and winter settings. It's probably meant to be a[CR]fusion of Dust Hill Zone and the Winter level. (scrapped from final release) *[CR]Oil Ocean Zone * Genocide City Zone: Original graphics. (scrapped from final[CR]release) * Hidden Palace Zone: (scrapped from final release) * Metropolis Zone[CR]* Sky Chase Zone * Wing Fortress Zone * Death Egg Zone: (original level) The[CR]archive contains two patches, one for Sonic and Tails, and one for Knuckles as[CR]playable characters. The patch is in xdelta format due to shifted data[CR]resulting in IPS patches containing original code. The ROM should be in BIN[CR]format.[CR]Read Me:[CR]Sonic 2 Long Version[CR]Credits - Main Programer:[CR]Sonic Hachelle-Bee, Tile and Level Design: Esrael[CR]Sonic 2 Long Version is a[CR]more complete version of Sonic 2, which makes it somewhat similar to Sonic 2[CR]Delta. This hack features four levels originally scrapped during Sonic 2s[CR]development. Few levels have been changed, four are added. This hack was[CR]written in hex, without the aid of any special hacking programs, because the[CR]creator uses a Mac, and no hacking tools had been released on that platform at[CR]the time of development.[CR]==Levels==[CR]In order according to the level[CR]select menu, Sonic 2 Long Versions levels include:[CR]*Emerald Hill[CR]Zone[CR]*Chemical Plant Zone[CR]*Aquatic Ruin Zone[CR]*Casino Night[CR]Zone[CR]*Hill Top Zone[CR]*Wood Zone: The graphics are similar to what is seen[CR]in the Simon Wai prototype. It uses different background music (2 player[CR]Emerald Hill Zone). The boss is the same as Aquatic Ruin Zones boss, but the[CR]stone columns are replaced with wooden totem poles and an extra pit has been[CR]added.[CR]*Mystic Cave Zone[CR]*Dust Hill Zone: Uses graphics similar to the[CR]mockup screenshot of Dust Hill Zone which was featured in many magazines. This[CR]version switches between both desert and winter settings. Its probably meant[CR]to be a fusion of Dust Hill Zone and the Winter level. The BGM used is from 2[CR]player Mystic Cave Zone. The Emerald Hill Zone boss is reused for this level[CR]with no alterations, other than the animal ribs on the ground which act as[CR]spikes.[CR]*Oil Ocean Zone[CR]*Genocide City Zone: The graphics used are[CR]completely original to a Sonic game. The level has a night time setting with[CR]water on the bottom to replicate an underground city sewer. The BGM is[CR]different than what was on the Nick Arcade prototype (it is in fact the 2[CR]player Casino Night Zone). This level is actually only one act repeated twice,[CR]with a boss at the end of Act 2. The Chemical Plant Zone boss is reused with[CR]no alterations made to him.[CR]*Hidden Palace Zone: The graphics and layout[CR]are the same as those found in the Nick Arcade prototype. The BGM used is the[CR]same that was used in the Final version of Sonic 2. The Mystic Cave Zone boss[CR]is reused with no alterations made.[CR]*Metropolis Zone[CR]*Sky Chase[CR]Zone[CR]*Wing Fortress Zone[CR]*Death Egg Zone: Act 1 and Act 2 use the exact[CR]level layout and graphics from Chemical Plant Zone, but with a space[CR]background. Act 3 is Act 1 of the released version.</plot>
    <genre>Graphics,Levels</genre>
    <studio>Sonic Hachelle-Bee</studio>
    <snapshot1>gTlKK3O.png</snapshot1>
    <snapshot2>xnsfxBK.png</snapshot2>
  </game>
  <game name="Knuckles' Emerald Hunt (SHC2016 Build)">
    <description>Knuckles' Emerald Hunt (SHC2016 Build)</description>
    <title_clean>Knuckles' Emerald Hunt</title_clean>
    <rom name="EmuROMHacks/ROM_Hacks_1.zip/Genesis%2FKnuckles%27%20Emerald%20Hunt%20%28SHC2016%20Build%29.bin" size="2097152"/>
  </game>
  <game name="Metal Sonic Hyperdrive (Rev 4.2)">
    <description>Metal Sonic Hyperdrive (Rev 4.2)</description>
    <title_clean>Metal Sonic Hyperdrive</title_clean>
    <rom name="EmuROMHacks/ROM_Hacks_1.zip/Genesis%2FMetal%20Sonic%20Hyperdrive%20%28Rev%204.2%29.bin" size="1048576"/>
    <plot>Metal Sonic Hyperdrive is a heavy modification of Sonic the Hedgehog (1991) by[CR]Darkon360 for the Sega Genesis. with brand new Zones, Sonic CD style gameplay,[CR]Music, Playable Characters, and Modes. Starting Metal Sonic, taking Sonic's[CR]role as the main protagonist to stop Dr.Robotnik's greatest inventions yet.[CR]Also starting special guests such as Kirby, and Somari. Story: One day, after[CR]the defeat of Dr.Robotnik by the hands of Sonic. Robotnik decided to rebuild[CR]Eggrobo to travel Mobius to search for the Chaos Emeralds. Eggrobo kidnapped[CR]Tails in the Mystic Ruins, by sending him into Metallic Madness, but luckily,[CR]Tails escaped. he decided to sneak into Robotnik's lab and grab the parts of[CR]his robots and pieces. Tails later go to his home in the Mystic Ruins and[CR]created a new robot, based off Metal Sonic's classic model, Codename: METAL.[CR]with the ability to feel and behave almost exactly like Sonic. Tails was able[CR]to track Eggrobo to where hes heading by using his Radar, so Tails sent Metal[CR]Sonic to Robotic Isle, where Eggrobo is heading to. in hopes to find the Chaos[CR]Emeralds and destroy Dr.Eggman's plans once and for all. Obtaining Chaos[CR]Emeralds: To obtain all 6 emeralds, find and destroy emerald monitors to[CR]enable the Giant Ring. (no Special Stages required) Level Select: Hint: Sonic[CR]CD North America Release date. Extras Menu: Press C button on the Title Screen[CR]to access the special extra features, including character selection and[CR]Survival Mode. [Genesis/Megadrive covers and cartstickers ready for print[CR]here.](http://darkon.sonicgamesdimension.net/Boxarts/)</plot>
    <genre>Graphics,Sound,Levels,Text,Gameplay</genre>
    <studio>Lone Devil</studio>
    <snapshot1>Fn6DIz6.png</snapshot1>
    <snapshot2>igfsGK1.png</snapshot2>
  </game>
  <game name="Mortal Kombat II - Ultimate (X)">
    <description>Mortal Kombat II - Ultimate (X)</description>
    <title_clean>Mortal Kombat II - Ultimate</title_clean>
    <rom name="EmuROMHacks/ROM_Hacks_1.zip/Genesis%2FMortal%20Kombat%20II%20-%20Ultimate%20%28X%29.bin" size="3740342"/>
  </game>
  <game name="Mortal Kombat III - Revelations (X)">
    <description>Mortal Kombat III - Revelations (X)</description>
    <title_clean>Mortal Kombat III - Revelations</title_clean>
    <rom name="EmuROMHacks/ROM_Hacks_1.zip/Genesis%2FMortal%20Kombat%20III%20-%20Revelations%20%28X%29.bin" size="10485760"/>
    <plot>This is a hack of Ultimate Mortal Kombat 3 for the Sega Genesis. It adds[CR]nearly all legit characters from Mortal Kombat 1, 2, and Trilogy, and adds[CR]additional characters that were not in the former Ultimate Mortal Kombat[CR]Trilogy Patch now giving you a total of 50 playable characters! It also adds[CR]backgrounds, new moves, combos, finishing moves, and missing audio samples are[CR]restored. It's the ultimate Mortal Kombat hack done again! Compatibility[CR]Either by creating a custom cart or using the MEGA EverDrive Flash cart the[CR]game can be played on a real console. The following is a list of emulators[CR]that work with the hack: Computer Gens version 2.11 (hacked with support of[CR]roms over 4mb). Gens32 Surreal version 1.69. Gens version 2.12 (Hacked with[CR]support of roms over 4mb). Dgen version 1.21 (with errors). Gens Plus! version[CR]0.0.9.61 (Hacked with support of roms over 4mb).. Picodrive version 1.45a.[CR]Other systems Neogenesis version 22 (Xbox). Pico Drive version 1.51 (PSP).[CR]Gens Plus version 16-07-08 (Wii). Genesis Plus GX version 080716 [aka 2008[CR]release] or later (Supports 10MB max so don't work with +Tracks patch) (Wii)[CR]MD Emu version undetermined (iOS). PICODRIVE ENG version 1.35 (Symbian OS 9.1,[CR]9.2 and 9.3 s60v3 smartphones). Pico Drive version 0.47 (Windows Mobile). MD[CR]Emu version 1.4.0 (Android). The main patch is in XDelta format. The ROM[CR]should be in BIN format.</plot>
    <genre>Graphics,Sound,Levels,Text,Gameplay</genre>
    <studio>Smoke</studio>
    <snapshot1>iT5bWZV.png</snapshot1>
    <snapshot2>KofcEMk.png</snapshot2>
  </game>
  <game name="Mortal Kombat III - Ultimate MK3 Trilogy (X)">
    <description>Mortal Kombat III - Ultimate MK3 Trilogy (X)</description>
    <title_clean>Mortal Kombat III - Ultimate MK3 Trilogy</title_clean>
    <rom name="EmuROMHacks/ROM_Hacks_1.zip/Genesis%2FMortal%20Kombat%20III%20-%20Ultimate%20MK3%20Trilogy%20%28X%29.bin" size="10485760"/>
    <plot>This is a hack by KABAL_MK of Ultimate Mortal Kombat 3 for the Sega Genesis.[CR]It adds nearly all playable characters from the Genesis/MegaDrive versions of[CR]Mortal Kombat 1, 2, and 3 -including the absent Sheeva, and also adds new[CR]backgrounds, specials, combos, finishing moves, and missing audio samples. New[CR]in v23 (5125) * Added more arena backgrounds * Improved computer AI * Bug[CR]Fixes * Added more specials, combos, finishing moves. Compatibility The[CR]following is a list of emulators that work with the hack: Computer and[CR]Retroarch (all platforms using these cores): * GenesisPlus-GX * Picodrive[CR]Other systems: * NeoGenesis version 22+ (Xbox). * PicoDrive version 1.51+[CR](PSP). * GenesisPlus-GX version 1.7.4 (Wii) (1.7.5 is incompatible for some[CR]reason) * MD Emu (Android, iOS) Some older, but compatible emulators can be[CR]found [here](http://umk3.hacking- cult.org/eng/download.htm). It also works on[CR]a real console using a Mega Everdrive flash cartridge. The patch(s) are in[CR]XDelta format, and need to be applied to a ROM in "BIN" format. A "+Tracks"[CR]patch is also included which changes some music. It is recommend to use [Delta[CR]Patcher ](http://www.romhacking.net/utilities/704/). NOTE: The "+Tracks" patch[CR]must be applied AFTER the main patch.</plot>
    <genre>Graphics,Sound,Levels,Text,Gameplay</genre>
    <studio>KABAL_MK</studio>
    <snapshot1>xtKHE6A.png</snapshot1>
    <snapshot2>l7bz803.png</snapshot2>
  </game>
  <game name="Oh Mummy Genesis">
    <description>Oh Mummy Genesis</description>
    <title_clean>Oh Mummy Genesis</title_clean>
    <rom name="EmuROMHacks/ROM_Hacks_1.zip/Genesis%2FOh%20Mummy%20Genesis.bin" size="1048576"/>
  </game>
  <game name="Pac-Mania Arcade Graphics Hack (v.1.00)">
    <description>Pac-Mania Arcade Graphics Hack (v.1.00)</description>
    <title_clean>Pac-Mania Arcade Graphics Hack</title_clean>
    <rom name="EmuROMHacks/ROM_Hacks_1.zip/Genesis%2FPac-Mania%20Arcade%20Graphics%20Hack%20%28v.1.00%29.bin" size="262144"/>
    <plot>Another victim of localization was Langrisser, at least graphically. When it[CR]became Warsong, Treco redid a few of the character portraits. Not really a big[CR]deal, and some might even prefer the changes, but this patch will revert the[CR]graphics anyway. This patch is more interesting when combined with D's text[CR]hack, which fixes the names to better match Langrisser. Make sure you apply[CR]this graphics patch last.[CR]Read Me:[CR]Patch version 070103[CR](yymmdd)[CR]Readme version 070103 (yymmdd)[CR] Warsong[CR] Graphics Hack[CR]by M.I.J.E.T.[CR]History[CR]-----------------------------------------------------------------------------[CR]070103[CR]Initial release[CR]Overview[CR]-----------------------------------------------------------------------------[CR]This[CR]is a patch for the Genesis game Warsong. Warsong was localized by Treco[CR]and[CR]some of the graphics were changed in the process. This patch hacks[CR]the[CR]graphics back to the ones used by Langrisser.[CR] Applying the[CR]Patch[CR]-----------------------------------------------------------------------------[CR]Hopefully[CR]included with this document is a patch file in the IPS format.[CR]You can use[CR]any program that supports that file format to apply this[CR]translation patch[CR]to your ROM file.[CR]Alternatively, you can use the program from my website to[CR]apply the patch,[CR]but make sure that you have the latest version or it wont[CR]work. The program[CR]will check the ROM file (de-interleaving it if necessary)[CR]and will give[CR]you an error message if something went wrong. A normal IPS[CR]program cannot[CR]do this as it has no idea what it is patching. The program[CR]has not been[CR]extensively tested, so if you have problems (or simply dont[CR]trust a foreign[CR]executable) you always have the option of using a different[CR]program.[CR]Please note that you are morally obligated to own an original copy[CR]of this[CR]game in order to use the ROM file. However, I am sceptical of those[CR]who say[CR]that it is illegal to do otherwise.[CR] Playing the[CR]Game[CR]-----------------------------------------------------------------------------[CR]Once[CR]youve patched the ROM file, simply load it up in your favorite[CR]Genesis /[CR]Mega Drive emulator, console copier, or flash cartridge.[CR] Q and[CR]A[CR]-----------------------------------------------------------------------------[CR]Q:[CR]This patch doesnt work! What do I do?[CR]A: Make sure that your ROM file is[CR]not in an interleaved format. Its also[CR] possible that there is more than[CR]one version of the game, or that your[CR] copy is corrupt. If you have[CR]problems, try using the program that I wrote[CR] to apply the patch; it checks[CR]for the above issues. It is available on my[CR] website.[CR]Q: It doesnt work[CR]with my copier / flash cartridge! Why not?[CR] This was tested on a real[CR]Genesis so you shouldnt have any problems in[CR] that respect. The most likely[CR]reason is that something went wrong during[CR] the patching process. See the[CR]previous question and try it in an emulator[CR] to see if that works.[CR]Another possibility is that you are using a PAL Mega Drive. This game was[CR]designed for NTSC systems and I didnt make any changes in that respect.[CR] It[CR]should still run (probably at the wrong speed), but you never know...[CR]Q: Is[CR]your patcher program safe?[CR]A: No. Anyone could replace it with a trojan and[CR]rewrite this readme to[CR] make it seem safe. Thats one reason why I dont[CR]include it with the[CR] patch itself. Its up to you to decide which program to[CR]use to apply[CR] the patch, but unless you wrote the program yourself theres[CR]always[CR] some risk involved.[CR]Q: Is this compatible with the Warsong-to-[CR]Langrisser text hack?[CR]A: Yes, as long as this graphics hack is applied[CR]last. The checksum will be[CR] wrong, but the game will not fail.[CR] List of[CR]Changes[CR]-----------------------------------------------------------------------------[CR]Treco[CR]logo reverted to Masaya logo[CR]Title graphics changed from Warsong to[CR]Langrisser (in katakana)[CR]Character portraits reverted[CR]Checksum[CR]disabled[CR] Hacking[CR]Notes[CR]-----------------------------------------------------------------------------[CR]The[CR]biggest problem with this hack, aside from finding the graphics data to[CR]be[CR]replaced, was the extreme lack of free ROM space. There was less than 2k[CR]of[CR]free space total and little more than 1k of it was contiguous.[CR]Further[CR]complicating things was the fact that Warsongs graphics were[CR]smaller so[CR]simply overwriting them was not possible. The data had to be[CR]split up and[CR]loaded into RAM prior to processing. As it stands, there are[CR]only a few[CR]hundred free bytes left scattered throughout the ROM.[CR]Contact[CR]-----------------------------------------------------------------------------[CR]mijeto@gmail.com[CR]I[CR]cannot guarantee a timely reply; this address is sometimes not checked[CR]for[CR]weeks or months at a time, depending on recent activity levels and[CR]Internet[CR]availability.[CR]And on the[CR]web:[CR]http://mijet.eludevisibility.org/[CR]http://www.geocities.com/tougi_ou/[CR](backup site)</plot>
    <genre>Graphics</genre>
    <studio>M.I.J.E.T.</studio>
    <snapshot1>vaggtw1.png</snapshot1>
    <snapshot2>IrE9CoI.png</snapshot2>
  </game>
  <game name="Pana der Hejhog (v.1.0)">
    <description>Pana der Hejhog (v.1.0)</description>
    <title_clean>Pana der Hejhog</title_clean>
    <rom name="EmuROMHacks/ROM_Hacks_1.zip/Genesis%2FPana%20der%20Hejhog%20%28v.1.0%29.bin" size="1048576"/>
  </game>
  <game name="Phantasy Star II Modernization Hack (v.3.0)">
    <description>Phantasy Star II Modernization Hack (v.3.0)</description>
    <title_clean>Phantasy Star II Modernization Hack</title_clean>
    <rom name="EmuROMHacks/ROM_Hacks_1.zip/Genesis%2FPhantasy%20Star%20II%20Modernization%20Hack%20%28v.3.0%29.md" size="786432"/>
    <plot>The purpose of this hack is to mitigate many of the flaws of Phantasy Star II[CR]in order to create an overall play experience more similar to that of Phantasy[CR]Star IV. This means decreasing the amount of level and money grinding,[CR]increasing the number of references to other games in the series, script[CR]improvement, bug fixing, and more. Major changes include: character niches and[CR]specialties are enhanced, technique arsenals are improved and mastered more[CR]speedily, shop and treasure chest contents are streamlined, characters join[CR]with better equipment, useless items are retired in favor of better ones,[CR]enemy names are expanded and made more consistent with the other games, etc.[CR]We are currently on Version 4.0, the sixth release of this hack. 4.0 is a[CR]complete rebuild from the ground up using the Phantasy Star II Disassembly[CR]document by lory1990, available on this site. This version introduces new[CR]enhancements, including an entirely rewritten script! Please see the readme[CR]for details, and thank you to everyone who tries the hack! Please note,[CR]patched ROMs may need to have their checksum corrected before they will play.[CR]The suggested fix for this is to use[CR][FixChecksum.exe](http://romhacking.net/utilities/342/).[CR]Read[CR]Me:[CR]+--------------------------+[CR]| |[CR]| Phantasy Star II |[CR]| |[CR]|[CR]SEGA Genesis / Megadrive |[CR]| |[CR]| Modernization |[CR]| |[CR]| Version 4.0[CR]|[CR]| |[CR]| Release: 09-24-2019 |[CR]| |[CR]| - By - |[CR]| |[CR]|[CR]Fauntleroy |[CR]| |[CR]| fedorajoe@hotmail.com |[CR]|[CR]|[CR]+--------------------------+[CR]* * * * * * * * * * * * * * * * * * * * *[CR]* * * * * * * * * * * * *[CR]+-------------------+[CR]| |[CR]| Table of[CR]Contents |[CR]|[CR]|[CR]+-------------------+[CR]I...........Introduction[CR]II....Setup[CR]Instructions[CR]III..............Credits[CR]* * * * * * * * * * * * * * * * *[CR]* * * * * * * * * * * * * * * * *[CR]+-----------------+[CR]| |[CR]| I.[CR]Introduction |[CR]| |[CR]+-----------------+[CR]Thank you for downloading this[CR]Modernization hack for Phantasy Star[CR]II, a classic RPG for the SEGA[CR]Genesis/Megadrive system. First[CR]released in the United States in 1990,[CR]Phantasy Star II was a big[CR]leap forward in gaming technology for its era.[CR]It also made bold[CR]design decisions, introducing increased difficulty,[CR]darker themes,[CR]subtle social commentary, and science fiction elements not[CR]seen in[CR]its predecessor, nor in many other games up to that time.[CR]With[CR]all of that being said, however, this great game has not aged[CR]as well as[CR]its thematic successor, Phantasy Star IV. IV was[CR]released in the United[CR]States in 1995, and although only five years[CR]had passed since IIs release,[CR]gaming technology had again made[CR]many major advancements, from which IV[CR]benefited in dramatic[CR]fashion. II, when compared to IV, seems very slow in[CR]its pacing,[CR]too unfair and even cheap in its obstacles, and ambiguous in[CR]its[CR]storytelling.[CR]So, this project attempts to remake II to better match[CR]the style of[CR]presentation in IV, while also providing greater thematic[CR]cohesion[CR]with the other entries in the series.[CR]Heres a quick overview of[CR]the major changes to the game that are[CR]introduced by this[CR]hack.[CR]Characters[CR]----------[CR]All party members have had their[CR]individual specialties enhanced.[CR]Where possible, characters from IV were[CR]used as a template to base[CR]these enhancements around.[CR]* Rolf: Like Chaz[CR]in IV. The core of your party. Strong, can use[CR] the best equipment, and has[CR]a great technique selection.[CR] Even if you didnt have to use him, you[CR]would.[CR]* Nei: Like Rika in IV. Rolfs essential backup. Strong double[CR]attack, fast, great healing, and solid support techniques.[CR] Once again:[CR]even if you didnt have to use her, you would.[CR]* Rudo: Like Wren in IV. The[CR]tank of the party. The nearest thing[CR] to unkillable with his high HP, high[CR]defense, and ability[CR] to use the best armors. Has no techniques, but is the[CR]only[CR] party member who can use vulcans, allowing for a multi-hit[CR] energy[CR](gun) attack. Absolutely essential in the vanilla[CR] game, and still a very,[CR]very strong choice for your team.[CR]* Amy: Like Raja in IV. No fighter, and[CR]quite fragile, but has[CR] all the best healing techniques. She also has a few[CR]really[CR] good support skills, along with the highest TP max of all.[CR] She[CR]can equip both knives and shots (small guns), allowing[CR] her to inflict both[CR]types of damage in one round. This is[CR] great against enemies like machines[CR]or the kites.[CR]* Hugh: Like Hahn in IV. Just a tiny bit stronger and less[CR]fragile[CR] than Amy, but a very dynamic party member. Like Amy, he[CR] can[CR]deliver both types of damage by having a knife in one[CR] hand and a shot in[CR]the other. He learns all of the special[CR] techniques to kill and handicap[CR]living enemies, whether[CR] animals, biohazards, or demons. He also has a good[CR]arsenal[CR] of healing and attack techniques.[CR]* Anna: Like Alys in IV. Anna[CR]is the only character who can use[CR] slashers, delivering a multi-hit bladed[CR]attack essential[CR] for crowd control. Shes fast as lightning, and while[CR]her[CR] technique list is short, it contains a number of essential[CR] attack[CR]and support abilities. Another party member you[CR] almost have to use in the[CR]vanilla game, and still a very[CR] awesome partner to have around.[CR]* Kain:[CR]Combine Hahn and Gryz from IV and you get Kain. Kain is[CR] Hughs counterpart,[CR]being the party member who learns all[CR] the techniques to destroy and weaken[CR]mechanical enemies.[CR] Hes good with techniques, but his use of heavy guns[CR]and[CR] the best armors, paired with relatively high defense and[CR] HP, also[CR]make him workable as a multi-purpose tank. In[CR] short, hes more durable than[CR]Hugh but doesnt have the[CR] same variety of skills, and while less effective[CR]than Rudo[CR] at tanking, hes also much more versatile.[CR]* Shir: Shir is[CR]basically Neis replacement. Her attack isnt as[CR] strong, but shes got an[CR]amazing set of support, attack,[CR] and healing techniques. She also has[CR]travel techniques to[CR] help the party escape a jam, especially if Rolf is[CR]out for[CR] the count, and shes freakishly fast. In short, shes less[CR]durable than Anna, and not as strong of a physical fighter[CR] as Nei, but she[CR]outdoes both of them in terms of speed and[CR] versatility. And of course,[CR]being a thief, she randomly[CR] steals from shops. :)[CR]Technique arsenals[CR]for all characters (well, except for Rudo) were[CR]expanded, and made more[CR]unique and diverse. Characters who learn a[CR]basic technique will also learn[CR]any Gi, Na, or Sa levels for it.[CR]Rolf and Nei learn their last techniques[CR]at Level 35. Amy, Hugh,[CR]Anna, Kain, and Shir learn their last techniques at[CR]Level 27. This[CR]way, its pretty easy to keep everyone at a level where you[CR]can[CR]actually use them, and learn all of their skills.[CR]In the vanilla[CR]game, some characters like Hugh are kept feeble[CR]because they cant use[CR]stronger pieces of equipment. In the hack,[CR]characters can generally use all[CR]items of a certain type. So, for[CR]example, Rolf and Hugh can both use all[CR]MAIL armors. Rudo and Kain[CR]can use all GEAR helmets. Amy, Anna, and Shir[CR]can use all CROWNS,[CR]CAPES, and EMELS.[CR]New party members still start at[CR]Level 1, but they come equipped[CR]with the best gear available up to that[CR]point. Everyone also joins[CR]with one technique already learned (except Rudo,[CR]of course).[CR]All party members default to the Fight command rather than[CR]the[CR]Defend command at the start of a battle.[CR]Also, I know that a lot of[CR]you like to hack Nei back into the party[CR]after the Climatrol events. To[CR]help you out, youll find that Nei[CR]can use a lot of the late-game equipment[CR]used by Amy, Anna, and[CR]Shir, including Shirs unique weapons.[CR]Items and[CR]Techniques[CR]------------------[CR]There are TONS of new items, new pieces of[CR]equipment, and yes, new[CR]techniques! Most will be familiar to fans of the[CR]other games in the[CR]series.[CR]Item prices, equipment stats, technique stats[CR]and TP costs, etc.[CR]have been rebalanced.[CR]This is my absolute favorite...[CR]Using the Neisword ANYWHERE will[CR]warp you to Lutzs throne. Either planets[CR]overworld, any town,[CR]any dungeon, absolutely wherever. How cool is that? It[CR]makes it[CR]really easy to stock up on Trimates, Star Mist, and Moon Dew[CR]and[CR]then quickly warp back to Esper Mansion.[CR]All vulcans (multi-hit[CR]guns) will attempt to fire four times. It[CR]wont always happen. Most of the[CR]time, one shot will go to each of[CR]the first four enemies in a group, but[CR]sometimes, two or more shots[CR]will pile up on a single enemy for big[CR]damage.[CR]The technique Eijia was removed, only because Kain ran out of[CR]space[CR]in his technique list, since he has some cool new stuff.[CR]Actually,[CR]all techniques from II and IV appear in this hack except for[CR]Regen[CR]and Eijia![CR]The Shinb technique is no longer glitched. When[CR]successful, the[CR]party instantly escapes from battle. This works in many[CR]situations[CR]where the Run command will fail.[CR]The Shift technique can now[CR]be cast on any ally, rather than being[CR]automatically applied to the[CR]caster.[CR]As described above, Hughs special biohazard-specific[CR]techniques[CR]will work on any enemy that appears to be a living being.[CR]Kains[CR]techniques work on all machines, but they also work on all[CR]demon[CR]enemies that arent living things, like the shadow, fire, and[CR]sword[CR]monsters. The Dark Force boss is unique in that it is[CR]susceptible to both[CR]types of technique.[CR]Presentation[CR]------------[CR]While the story hasnt[CR]been changed, the script was completely[CR]rewritten, top to bottom. Im really[CR]proud of it, honestly! I hope[CR]you enjoy it! And please please please, talk[CR]to my NPCs![CR]Text always goes to the end of the text box before theres a[CR]hard[CR]return.[CR]Menu and battle text was changed to be more consistent with[CR]that[CR]used in IV. In other words, its clear and brief.[CR]Menus were resized[CR]to properly fit their options. This made most[CR]text abbreviations in menus[CR]unnecessary.[CR]Enemy names now use the full 10 characters allowed, rather[CR]than[CR]just the first eight, as in the vanilla game.[CR]Many item and enemy[CR]names were changed to be more consistent with[CR]other games in the[CR]series.[CR]All enemies now give double the meseta and experience points as[CR]in[CR]the vanilla game, so while this game will always require grinding,[CR]it[CR]now goes by FAST.[CR]The party members are placed above their status windows[CR]in battle,[CR]as in IV.[CR]In battle, Rolf now has dark blue hair to match his[CR]in-game art[CR]and map sprite, and Neis ears are no longer purple.[CR]Kain now[CR]speaks like a street-smart cockney, rather than being[CR]borderline[CR]incomprehensible as in the vanilla game.[CR]The Algo Star System map shown[CR]during the Gaila sequence was[CR]updated to show the planet names as they were[CR]in the original[CR]Phantasy Star: Palma, Motavia, Dezoris. These are the names[CR]used[CR]throughout the hack, along with:[CR]* Algo rather than Algol[CR]*[CR]Palman rather than Parmanian[CR]* Dezorian rather than Dezolisian[CR]* Alis[CR]rather than Alisa[CR]* Lutz rather than Noah[CR]* Lassic rather than[CR]Lashiec[CR]* Altiplano rather than Alplatin[CR]* Gaila rather than Gaira[CR]*[CR]Alsulin rather than Alshline[CR]* Laerma rather than Laeruma[CR]* And probably[CR]more that Im forgetting![CR]Okay, this last one is going to be controversial,[CR]but... the towns[CR]of Kueri and Piata switched names. I know, I know, it[CR]sounds really[CR]weird, but hear me out. It always bugged me that, in IV, the[CR]town[CR]of Piata has moved from the southeastern quadrant of Motavia to[CR]the[CR]southwestern quadrant. It makes no sense. Assuming for a moment[CR]that[CR]Zema and Uzo are in "more or less" the same place in IV as[CR]they were in II,[CR]that means IVs Piata is right around where IIs[CR]Kueri would be. So, to[CR]resolve the apparent continuity error, I[CR]swapped the two names. I hope it[CR]doesnt break anyones immersion![CR]Bug Fixes[CR]---------[CR]Hugh is now able[CR]to use Gires both in and out of battle.[CR]Incorrect text is no longer[CR]displayed when trying to rearrange the[CR]party while Rolf is alone.[CR]The[CR]text boxes when examining the entrances to Uzo Island and[CR]Climatrol are no[CR]longer cut off.[CR]In the vanilla game, one townsperson in Paseo would recite[CR]part of[CR]Lutzs speech if spoken to after the Climatrol events. This[CR]strange[CR]behavior is fixed, and in fact, he now gives an important[CR]clue[CR]about accessing the four dams.[CR]The middle entry in the Van/Aerotank[CR]enemy group can now be found[CR]at the Blue and Green Dams.[CR]The music no[CR]longer crashes during Lutzs speech.[CR]A few minor bugs involving stat growth[CR]and items were addressed.[CR]* * * * * * * * * * * * * * * * * * * * * * * * *[CR]* * * * * * * * *[CR]+------------------------+[CR]| |[CR]| II. Setup[CR]Instructions |[CR]| |[CR]+------------------------+[CR]Youll need the[CR]20190924psiipatch.ips file and an unaltered copy of[CR]the Phantasy Star II[CR]Genesis/Megadrive English language ROM. Please[CR]dont ask me for a copy of[CR]the ROM; I wont provide one.[CR]Recommended ROMs:[CR]* Phantasy Star II (UE)[CR](REV 02) [!][CR] * Unmodified ROM CRC32: 904FA047[CR] * Patch Applied CRC32:[CR]179CCF64[CR]The recommended ROM is sometimes labeled as:[CR]* Phantasy Star II[CR](REV 02)[CR]* Phantasy Star II (UE) (REV02) [!][CR]*[CR]Phantasy_Star_II_(UE)_(REV02)_[!][CR]PLEASE NOTE: The REV01 version of the ROM[CR]should work also, but[CR]some minor glitches may result.[CR]I recommend using[CR]the Lunar IPS utility to apply the patch to the[CR]ROM. As of this writing,[CR]you can download Lunar IPS[CR]here:[CR]http://fusoya.eludevisibility.org/lips/[CR]To apply the patch:[CR]1.)[CR]Open Lunar IPS and click the Apply IPS Patch button.[CR]2.) Select the[CR]20190924psiipatch.ips file.[CR]3.) Select the ROM.[CR]4.) Youre all set! Its[CR]that easy![CR]As far as which emulator to use, I personally like Kega[CR]Fusion.[CR]Kega Fusion has its own[CR]website:[CR]http://segaretro.org/Kega_Fusion[CR]* * * * * * * * * * * * * * *[CR]* * * * * * * * * * * * * * * * * * *[CR]+--------------+[CR]| |[CR]| III.[CR]Credits |[CR]| |[CR]+--------------+[CR]Im the creator of this hack. All of[CR]the ideas, for good or bad,[CR]were my own.[CR]However, I never couldve[CR]completed the hack without some special[CR]assistance along the way.[CR]I have[CR]to thank lory1990 for creating the amazing Phantasy Star II[CR]Disassembly[CR]document, which made most changes an absolute breeze.[CR]Hes created similar[CR]utilities for all of the classic Phantasy Star[CR]games, so check them out! He[CR]was also extremely patient and[CR]gracious in answer a million questions I had[CR]about implementing my[CR]goofy ideas.[CR]Thank you lory1990 for making this[CR]project possible!</plot>
    <genre>Graphics,Text,Gameplay</genre>
    <studio>Fauntleroy</studio>
    <snapshot1>nkjXihA.png</snapshot1>
    <snapshot2>IHHd7Sr.png</snapshot2>
  </game>
  <game name="Probotector (X)">
    <description>Probotector (X)</description>
    <title_clean>Probotector</title_clean>
    <rom name="EmuROMHacks/ROM_Hacks_1.zip/Genesis%2FProbotector%20%28X%29.bin" size="2097152"/>
    <plot>Robotnik was getting frantic. Every plan he made seemed to be thwarted[CR]effortlessly by the blue hedgehog, and his ideas were getting stupider and[CR]stupider by the week. Utterly confused and enraged, he looked back on some of[CR]his old files, and realized that his previous ideas were much better than his[CR]current schemes! They'd given Sonic a run for his money, and he had just[CR]barely escaped Robotnik's seemingly fool-proof plan. Perhaps, if he lured[CR]Sonic back to South Island, he could get his old lairs back in working order.[CR]Of course, most of the ruins had been torn apart by the test of time and Dr.[CR]Eggman's "Modifications". Green Hill Zone was protected by the lingering chaos[CR]emerald magic, and spring yard zone had to be left behind. He got lucky,[CR]though. Scrap Brain Zone was in working order, and he worked hard to make it[CR]as cruel and soul crushing as Sonic could ever imagine... Features: * New[CR]music, palettes, artwork, names, and layouts for various zones. * Completely[CR]different level order * A new character, activated by pressing B: Sanic Teh[CR]Hegehog! * A re-imagining of Hidden Palace Zone added the way that Sega[CR]intended (currently, its just a shortcut to Scrapped Ruin Zone). * Alterations[CR]to the boss arenas * Various bonuses for collecting all six chaos emeralds[CR](start with 10 rings, orbinauts spawn with no rings, S monitors give 50 rings,[CR]etc.) * New special stage layouts * A new zone at the SBZ2 twist * And of[CR]course, a badly ported spindash XD[CR]Read Me:[CR]Hack Name: Robotnik[CR]Returns[CR]Author:[CR]Pacguy[CR]----------------------------------------------------------------[CR]This[CR]is a new hack by a new hacker. Unlike most noobs, however, I have an obsession[CR]with constantly play testing it, so it shouldnt have the barrage of flow[CR]breaks, bugs, and dick moves most new hackers plague their hacks with. Any[CR]way, heres some info about Robotnik Returns![CR]Story:[CR]Robotnik was getting[CR]frantic. Every plan he made seemed to be thwarted effortlessly by the blue[CR]hedgehog, and his ideas were getting stupider and stupider by the week.[CR]Utterly confused and enraged, he looked back on some of his old files, and[CR]realized that his previous ideas were much better than his current schemes![CR]Theyd given Sonic a run for his money, and he had just barely escaped[CR]Robotniks seemingly fool-proof plan. Perhaps, if he lured Sonic back to South[CR]Island, he could get his old lairs back in working order. Of course, most of[CR]the ruins had been torn apart by the test of time and Dr. Eggmans[CR]"Modifications". Green Hill Zone was protected by the lingering chaos emerald[CR]magic, and spring yard zone had to be left behind. He got lucky, though. Scrap[CR]Brain Zone was in working order, and he worked hard to make it as cruel and[CR]soul crushing as Sonic could ever imagine...[CR]Features:[CR]New music,[CR]palettes, artwork, names, and layouts for various zones.[CR]Completely[CR]different level order[CR]A new character, activated by pressing B: Sanic Teh[CR]Hegehog![CR]A reimagining of Hidden Palace Zone added the way that Sega[CR]intended (currently, its just a shortcut to Scrapped Ruin[CR]Zone).[CR]Alterations to the boss arenas[CR]Various bonuses for collecting all[CR]six chaos emeralds (start with 10 rings, orbinauts spawn with no rings, S[CR]monitors give 50 rings, etc.)[CR]New special stage layouts[CR]A new zone at[CR]the SBZ2 twist[CR]And of course, a badly ported spindash XD[CR]I have a lot of[CR]future plans for this hack as my skills improve, and Ill take any[CR]suggestion/comments/ideas into consideration.[CR]Credits:[CR]Nineko, for all[CR]custom music besides the themes for Lazy Field and Pollutant Plant Zone, which[CR]are my own ports, as well as helping with code for Sanics level[CR]layouts.[CR]Xeta (Sonic Retro), for an edit of the theme used for Construction[CR]Zone (made by nineko) which uses Sonic 1s default DAC[CR]LooneyDude (SSRG),[CR]who gave me some advice for art changes[CR]Professor Neo (SSRG), who helped[CR]with the special stage layouts[CR]The Sonic Retro wiki How to section, for[CR]lots of coding, and teaching me how to edit raw ASM[CR]The SSRG repository,[CR]where I found Ninekos songs[CR]And the Sonic Retro and SSRG forum members, for[CR]playtesting and general[CR]feedback[CR]----------------------------------------------------------------[CR]Sonic[CR]Hacking Contest 2014[CR]http://shc.sonicresearch.org/entry/34</plot>
    <genre>Graphics,Sound,Levels,Text,Gameplay</genre>
    <studio>Pacguy</studio>
    <snapshot1>0GO8jQQ.png</snapshot1>
    <snapshot2>8R9RLX2.png</snapshot2>
  </game>
  <game name="Robotnik Returns 2 (SHC 2016 Build)">
    <description>Robotnik Returns 2 (SHC 2016 Build)</description>
    <title_clean>Robotnik Returns 2</title_clean>
    <rom name="EmuROMHacks/ROM_Hacks_1.zip/Genesis%2FRobotnik%20Returns%202%20%28SHC%202016%20Build%29.bin" size="4194310"/>
    <plot>Robotnik was getting frantic. Every plan he made seemed to be thwarted[CR]effortlessly by the blue hedgehog, and his ideas were getting stupider and[CR]stupider by the week. Utterly confused and enraged, he looked back on some of[CR]his old files, and realized that his previous ideas were much better than his[CR]current schemes! They'd given Sonic a run for his money, and he had just[CR]barely escaped Robotnik's seemingly fool-proof plan. Perhaps, if he lured[CR]Sonic back to South Island, he could get his old lairs back in working order.[CR]Of course, most of the ruins had been torn apart by the test of time and Dr.[CR]Eggman's "Modifications". Green Hill Zone was protected by the lingering chaos[CR]emerald magic, and spring yard zone had to be left behind. He got lucky,[CR]though. Scrap Brain Zone was in working order, and he worked hard to make it[CR]as cruel and soul crushing as Sonic could ever imagine... Features: * New[CR]music, palettes, artwork, names, and layouts for various zones. * Completely[CR]different level order * A new character, activated by pressing B: Sanic Teh[CR]Hegehog! * A re-imagining of Hidden Palace Zone added the way that Sega[CR]intended (currently, its just a shortcut to Scrapped Ruin Zone). * Alterations[CR]to the boss arenas * Various bonuses for collecting all six chaos emeralds[CR](start with 10 rings, orbinauts spawn with no rings, S monitors give 50 rings,[CR]etc.) * New special stage layouts * A new zone at the SBZ2 twist * And of[CR]course, a badly ported spindash XD[CR]Read Me:[CR]Hack Name: Robotnik[CR]Returns[CR]Author:[CR]Pacguy[CR]----------------------------------------------------------------[CR]This[CR]is a new hack by a new hacker. Unlike most noobs, however, I have an obsession[CR]with constantly play testing it, so it shouldnt have the barrage of flow[CR]breaks, bugs, and dick moves most new hackers plague their hacks with. Any[CR]way, heres some info about Robotnik Returns![CR]Story:[CR]Robotnik was getting[CR]frantic. Every plan he made seemed to be thwarted effortlessly by the blue[CR]hedgehog, and his ideas were getting stupider and stupider by the week.[CR]Utterly confused and enraged, he looked back on some of his old files, and[CR]realized that his previous ideas were much better than his current schemes![CR]Theyd given Sonic a run for his money, and he had just barely escaped[CR]Robotniks seemingly fool-proof plan. Perhaps, if he lured Sonic back to South[CR]Island, he could get his old lairs back in working order. Of course, most of[CR]the ruins had been torn apart by the test of time and Dr. Eggmans[CR]"Modifications". Green Hill Zone was protected by the lingering chaos emerald[CR]magic, and spring yard zone had to be left behind. He got lucky, though. Scrap[CR]Brain Zone was in working order, and he worked hard to make it as cruel and[CR]soul crushing as Sonic could ever imagine...[CR]Features:[CR]New music,[CR]palettes, artwork, names, and layouts for various zones.[CR]Completely[CR]different level order[CR]A new character, activated by pressing B: Sanic Teh[CR]Hegehog![CR]A reimagining of Hidden Palace Zone added the way that Sega[CR]intended (currently, its just a shortcut to Scrapped Ruin[CR]Zone).[CR]Alterations to the boss arenas[CR]Various bonuses for collecting all[CR]six chaos emeralds (start with 10 rings, orbinauts spawn with no rings, S[CR]monitors give 50 rings, etc.)[CR]New special stage layouts[CR]A new zone at[CR]the SBZ2 twist[CR]And of course, a badly ported spindash XD[CR]I have a lot of[CR]future plans for this hack as my skills improve, and Ill take any[CR]suggestion/comments/ideas into consideration.[CR]Credits:[CR]Nineko, for all[CR]custom music besides the themes for Lazy Field and Pollutant Plant Zone, which[CR]are my own ports, as well as helping with code for Sanics level[CR]layouts.[CR]Xeta (Sonic Retro), for an edit of the theme used for Construction[CR]Zone (made by nineko) which uses Sonic 1s default DAC[CR]LooneyDude (SSRG),[CR]who gave me some advice for art changes[CR]Professor Neo (SSRG), who helped[CR]with the special stage layouts[CR]The Sonic Retro wiki How to section, for[CR]lots of coding, and teaching me how to edit raw ASM[CR]The SSRG repository,[CR]where I found Ninekos songs[CR]And the Sonic Retro and SSRG forum members, for[CR]playtesting and general[CR]feedback[CR]----------------------------------------------------------------[CR]Sonic[CR]Hacking Contest 2014[CR]http://shc.sonicresearch.org/entry/34</plot>
    <genre>Graphics,Sound,Levels,Text,Gameplay</genre>
    <studio>Pacguy</studio>
    <snapshot1>0GO8jQQ.png</snapshot1>
    <snapshot2>8R9RLX2.png</snapshot2>
  </game>
  <game name="Robotnik's Revenge (v.1.0)">
    <description>Robotnik's Revenge (v.1.0)</description>
    <title_clean>Robotnik's Revenge</title_clean>
    <rom name="EmuROMHacks/ROM_Hacks_1.zip/Genesis%2FRobotnik%27s%20Revenge%20%28v.1.0%29.bin" size="2097152"/>
    <plot>This is a hack which adds a boss attack which features all the bosses from[CR]Sonic the Hedgehog and Sonic the Hedgehog 2 for Genesis. The hack is based on[CR]Sonic the Hedgehog 2 for Genesis. The hack takes place in Death Egg zone and[CR]the objective is to get a good time and ranking. There are two modes, time[CR]attack and survival mode. Time attack mode grants infinite lives and has rings[CR]placed in-between battles. Survival mode has only three lives and has no rings[CR]whatsoever. The patch is in xdelta format due to shifted data resulting in IPS[CR]patches containing original code. The ROM should be in BIN format.</plot>
    <genre>Graphics,Sound,Levels</genre>
    <studio>ColinC10</studio>
    <snapshot1>Tkz0VFs.png</snapshot1>
    <snapshot2>jtL8y9T.png</snapshot2>
  </game>
  <game name="Rock 'N Roll Racing Hack (v.15.0)">
    <description>Rock 'N Roll Racing Hack (v.15.0)</description>
    <title_clean>Rock 'N Roll Racing Hack</title_clean>
    <rom name="EmuROMHacks/ROM_Hacks_1.zip/Genesis%2FRock%20%27N%20Roll%20Racing%20Hack%20%28v.15.0%29.bin" size="2097152"/>
    <plot>It doesn't change the whole game, but expands most aspects of game. (adding 6[CR]cars in-race, new cars, tracks, characters with new stats, planets, graphics,[CR]music, colors, improvements, bug-fix, AI, translations, some unique things,[CR]new objects and upgrades, new weapon and more...) Documentation should be[CR]included in archive. If some critical bug will appear, please let me know. The[CR]reason why I've made a patch for alpha-version, because it's too many changes,[CR]different internal structure, and usage of data from some other games.</plot>
    <genre>Graphics,Sound,Levels,Text</genre>
    <studio>Ti</studio>
    <snapshot1>usO11TV.jpg</snapshot1>
    <snapshot2>sYKefdd.png</snapshot2>
  </game>
  <game name="Rock n' Roll Racing (X)">
    <description>Rock n' Roll Racing (X)</description>
    <title_clean>Rock n' Roll Racing</title_clean>
    <rom name="EmuROMHacks/ROM_Hacks_1.zip/Genesis%2FRock%20n%27%20Roll%20Racing%20%28X%29.bin" size="2097152"/>
    <plot>It doesn't change the whole game, but expands most aspects of game. (adding 6[CR]cars in-race, new cars, tracks, characters with new stats, planets, graphics,[CR]music, colors, improvements, bug-fix, AI, translations, some unique things,[CR]new objects and upgrades, new weapon and more...) Documentation should be[CR]included in archive. If some critical bug will appear, please let me know. The[CR]reason why I've made a patch for alpha-version, because it's too many changes,[CR]different internal structure, and usage of data from some other games.</plot>
    <genre>Graphics,Sound,Levels,Text</genre>
    <studio>Ti</studio>
    <snapshot1>usO11TV.jpg</snapshot1>
    <snapshot2>sYKefdd.png</snapshot2>
  </game>
  <game name="Shadow Run (X)">
    <description>Shadow Run (X)</description>
    <title_clean>Shadow Run</title_clean>
    <rom name="EmuROMHacks/ROM_Hacks_1.zip/Genesis%2FShadow%20Run%20%28X%29.bin" size="2097152"/>
    <plot>After a more detailed analysis, it has been concluded that Shadowrun from Sega[CR]is based on the rules of the second edition, and not on the first edition as[CR]previously understood. This new Shadowrun 2050 patch, which will now be called[CR]Shadowrun 2058, will retain many of the changes made in the previous versions[CR]plus some revisions and new improvements. A new optional bug fix patch has[CR]been added to the downloadable file. Please, READ THE INSTRUCTIONS AND README[CR]FILE for future clarification. VERSION 1.4 NEW IMPROVEMENTS: * Now the main[CR]purpose of the hack will be get closer to the Shadowrun second edition rules[CR]instead of the first edition * Changes the hack name from Shadowrun 2050 to[CR]Shadowrun 2058 * Cyberdecks attributes have been modified; some of them are[CR]downgraded but they all are more easy and cheaper to upgrade * Armor values[CR]have been revised * Original damage codes have been restored: "ballistic" for[CR]"guns" and "impact" for "weapons" * All the firearms have been modified to[CR]correctly correspond to their respective sprite * Cyberwear prices are changed[CR]again * Some enemies have been boosted, specially the melee fighters *[CR]Contacts offers cheaper items and services * All runs gives more karma and[CR]better payment * All spells have less stamina drainage and some of them have[CR]been renamed or modified in some way * Some items are cheaper now * All[CR]Shadowruners and Joshuas start with better equipment * A lot of new general[CR]description based on the Shadowrun literature Please, see the README file to[CR]see the full list of changes.[CR]Read Me:[CR]Shadowrun[CR]2050[CR]November 2018 by Vikfield[CR]This modification is the revised update[CR]of the previous vikfields mod; retains the changes made in the first[CR]installment, plus some improvements and new features based on the original[CR]rules of the first edition of shadowrun: "Shadowrun 2050".[CR]----------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------[CR]Shadowrun[CR]2058[CR]August 2019 by Vikfield[CR]After a more detailed analysis, it has been[CR]concluded that Shadowrun from Sega is based on the rules of the second[CR]edition, and not on the first edition as previously understood. This new[CR]shadowrun 2050 patch, which will now be called shadowrun 2058, will retain[CR]many of the changes made in the previous versions plus some revicions and new[CR]improvements.[CR]----------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------[CR]Improvements[CR]list[CR]Version 1.0:[CR]- Shamans do not take up space in their inventory to[CR]load totems[CR]- Joshua samurai has its full essence and does not wear any[CR]cyberwear[CR]- When you restart in the hospital after being defeated, your[CR]physical and mental health is 100%[CR]- More random enemy encounters[CR]-[CR]Fixed instakill bug[CR]- Debug mod available all the time[CR]version 1.1:[CR]-[CR]Some weapons and cyberdecks have been renamed[CR]- All cyberdeck cost[CR]less[CR]- All weapons stores have the same prices for accessories, and they[CR]are cheaper[CR]- All cyberwear stores have the same prices, and in turn, have[CR]lower prices[CR]- The armor values have been readjusted[CR]- The firearms have[CR]been revised to harmonize with the game and at the same time with the first[CR]edition of shadowrun[CR]- Some esprites of NPCs have been changed and the[CR]equipment of these[CR]- Stark is now an orc; In addition, its cyberwear has[CR]been slightly modified, so it is possible to install smartlink[CR]- Illene two[CR]fist has been updated with better skills and equipment[CR]version 1.2:[CR]-[CR]some items description corections[CR]version 1.3:[CR]- All Mr. Johnson pay[CR]twice as much as usual per run[CR]- All contracts have negotiation[CR]bonuses[CR]- The karma points earned by run are higher, except for courier and[CR]bodyguad contracts[CR]version 1.4:[CR]- Now the main purpose of the hack will[CR]be get closer to the Shadowrun second edition rules instead of the firs[CR]edition[CR]- Changes the hack name from Shadowrun 2050 to Shadowrun 2058[CR]-[CR]Cyberdecks atributes have been modifie; some of them are downgrade but they[CR]all are more esay and cheaper to upgrade[CR]- Armor values have been[CR]revised[CR]- Original damage codes have been restore: "ballistic" for "guns"[CR]and "impact" for "weapons"[CR]- All the firearms have been modify to correctly[CR]corresponding to their respective sprite[CR]- Cyberwear prices are changed[CR]again[CR]- Some enemies have been boosted, specialy the melee figthers[CR]-[CR]Contacts offers cheaper items and services[CR]- All runs gives more karma and[CR]better payment [CR]- All spells have less stamina drainage and some of them[CR]have been renamed or modified in some way (thank to dyetryc for the[CR]request)[CR]- Some items are cheaper now[CR]- All shadowruners and joshuas[CR]stares with better equipment[CR]- A lot of new general description based on[CR]the shadowrun[CR]literature[CR]--------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------[CR]VERY[CR]IMPORTANT NOTE:[CR]Due to the increase of enemy encounters, it is very likely[CR]that when entering certain buildings, such as the bar of a Mr. Johnson, the[CR]combat mode gets activated without visible enemies, which will prevent you[CR]from leaving the place. If this happens, you can do one of the following[CR]options:[CR]- Try to walk around the place and go to the exit while walking to[CR]the opposite side where the combat mode is activated[CR]- Go to the debugmod[CR]option found in the pause / pocket secretary / unmarked down menu of the save[CR]/ load state option, and choose pick system; This option allows you to enter[CR]the matrix without the need of a data jack installed, and without the need to[CR]go to a cyber terminal. Once you have chosen a system and you are inside the[CR]matrix, simply disconnect and when you leave the matrix, you can leave the[CR]place where you were stuck.[CR]- And third option, save before entering the[CR]place of a mr. Johnson[CR]These are temporary solutions to this problem; A[CR]perfect solution would be to modify the option that prevents you from leaving[CR]a building when you are in combat or when an alarm is activated. Obviously, I[CR]have not been able to change that yet, but if you find a better solution or[CR]want to contribute, you can send me an email to my email adress:[CR]vapv71421@gmail.com, any kind of help will be appreciated, and thanks for[CR]downloading. Have fun!</plot>
    <genre>Text,Gameplay</genre>
    <studio>Vikfield</studio>
    <snapshot1>qLUF78h.png</snapshot1>
    <snapshot2>wH3lwqs.png</snapshot2>
  </game>
  <game name="Shining Force II - Hard Mode (X)">
    <description>Shining Force II - Hard Mode (X)</description>
    <title_clean>Shining Force II - Hard Mode</title_clean>
    <rom name="EmuROMHacks/ROM_Hacks_1.zip/Genesis%2FShining%20Force%20II%20-%20Hard%20Mode%20%28X%29.bin" size="2097664"/>
    <plot>This hack makes the monsters much stronger, and improves the weaker force[CR]members to better balance the team. Many members have new spells and[CR]abilities. Most monsters have double HP, 10% more attack and 10% more defense.[CR]Boss monsters are much harder. A comprehensive list of changes is included in[CR]the readme file. Version 1.01 (released 6/30/2008) further improves the Zeon[CR]battle. It is compatible with saves from previous versions, provided those[CR]saves weren't made during the Zeon battle.[CR]Read Me:[CR]Shining Force 2,[CR]Challenge Mode Hack[CR]Version 1.01[CR]By Obob[CR]obob912 at gmail dot[CR]com[CR]VERSION HISTORY:[CR]Version 1.01 (6/30/2008): Enhanced the difficulty[CR]of the Zeon battle. Made Zeons AI [CR]less exploitable.[CR]Version 1.0[CR](5/27/2008): Initial release.[CR]INSTALLATION INSTRUCTIONS:[CR]Apply the IPS[CR]patch to a .BIN version of the Shining Force 2 ROM. A common name for [CR]this[CR]ROM, and one that definitely works, is Shining Force 2 (U) [!].BIN. You can[CR]apply the IPS patch using a program such as IPSWin or Lunar IPS patcher.[CR]Then play [CR]the ROM on an emulator. I used Gens in all my[CR]playtesting.[CR]ABOUT THE HACK:[CR]This hack makes the game substantially[CR]harder than the regular game. However, it does[CR]serve as more of a middle[CR]ground between Super difficulty of the regular game and [CR]BigNailCows[CR]Hardtype Hack. Towards the end of the game, the regular monsters in[CR]this[CR]hack are generally much easier than those in the Hardtype Hack. Boss[CR]monsters, [CR]however, are generally much more difficult, although sometimes[CR]their defense scores [CR]are substantially lower. There is also no level[CR]building at any point: Bowie does [CR]not know egress, and angel wings are not[CR]buyable.[CR]I have strived for balance in this hack, to make it so that your[CR]entire party remains [CR]useful throughout the entire game. Peter was the only[CR]character that was nerfed, and [CR]only slightly at that (aside from nerfs[CR]that came from nerfing certain spells). The [CR]vast majority of the weaker[CR]characters have been improved. Chances are that only a [CR]few of the[CR]characters that you normally use were improved. I tried to improve all[CR]characters to the point that nobody is dead weight. Randolf and Eric are[CR]sufficiently[CR]improved that they are very good choices from Creeds. This[CR]should encourage much [CR]more diverse parties.[CR]It was also important to me[CR]to make it so that instant death abilities, while still [CR]good, are not the[CR]primary means of completing battles. This is accomplished by [CR]increasing[CR]regular monster HP only by a factor of two, so that for Kazin damaging[CR]spells are usually more MP-effective than desoul. Whereas in the Hardtype[CR]hack Kazin [CR]was undeniably better as a Wizard than as a Soreceror, in this[CR]hack the choice is much[CR]less clear.[CR]For the sake of balance, it is[CR]strongly intended that you PLAY THIS HACK ON OUCH, and [CR]PROMOTE ALL YOUR[CR]CHARACTERS AT 20, OR AS SOON AS POSSIBLE. You can buy all promotion [CR]items[CR]from the item store in Hassan, should you need them before you would get to[CR]them[CR]normally. The battles leading up to Creeds mansion, while doable, are[CR]difficult and [CR]tedious without promotion weapons. The later battles in the[CR]game are slightly [CR]trivialized by late promotion, and late promotion makes[CR]all the prepromoted characters[CR]relatively less useful. Also dont do silly[CR]things like abuse the Fairy Village[CR]special stage, etc. [CR]I have no[CR]reason to believe that the hack would be impossible on Super, especially if[CR]you do not promote at 20. But the hack was really not created with Super[CR]in mind, [CR]and you wont have very much fun playing it on super. Some of the[CR]later bosses are [CR]already as strong or stronger than their super[CR]equivalents in the original game, and [CR]adding another 25% to their attack[CR]would make things crazy. Boost is also less [CR]powerful now, which makes it[CR]even harder to cope with the huge attack values of Super.[CR]At any rate, here[CR]is the list of changes in this hack:[CR]MONSTERS:[CR]Most monsters have double[CR]HP.[CR]Monsters that dont use weapons have had their attack increased about[CR]10%.[CR]Monsters that use weapons have had their base attack increased by[CR]15-20%. This [CR]generally yields a total attack increase of about[CR]10%.[CR]Most monsters have had their defense increased by 10%. Some have[CR]slightly higher [CR]defense increases, but then lower HP. In the last few[CR]battles (Geshp and onwards), [CR]defense is typically increased by 20% to[CR]better compensate for mithril weapons and the[CR]stagnant defense values in[CR]the original game.[CR]Dedicated casters typically have double MP. Melee[CR]monsters that incidentally have [CR]some spells have the same amount of[CR]MP.[CR]Many healers have better heal spells, especially healers that used low[CR]level aura [CR]spells towards the end of the game.[CR]Bosses are now MUCH more[CR]difficult. Most have roughly triple HP, greatly increased [CR]attack,[CR]increased defense, increased MP when applicable, and some gain new spells or[CR]have their old spells improved. The all boss battle at the end will be[CR]VERY hard. [CR]Let me know if you beat it.[CR]CHARACTERS:[CR]Bowie does not[CR]know Egress.[CR]Chester now gets 5 extra defense as a pegasus knight instead[CR]of losing 5 defense. [CR]This is to make up for the land effect penalty. He[CR]should now be a decent candidate [CR]for a pegasus wing.[CR]All centaurs get[CR]attack increases after promotion. Their attack is now 6 points [CR]higher than[CR]it was by the end of the game. This makes Eric a good choice at Creeds,[CR]and makes the others do damage closer to that of a gladiator than an[CR]archer.[CR]Kazin learns Freeze instead of Muddle. He does so slowly though.[CR]Freeze 1 helps to [CR]cope with increased monster HP in the first third or so[CR]of the game. Freeze 3, which [CR]he gets at level 18 promoted, gives him a[CR]range 3 attack as a Wizard. He wont easily[CR]learn Freeze 4; he learns it at[CR]32 promoted.[CR]Kiwi has been greatly improved. He will gain on average 6 more[CR]attack before [CR]promotion compared to before. He will gain on average 14[CR]more defense after promotion[CR]compared to before, giving him the best[CR]defense in the game by 2 points. He starts [CR]the game knowing Dispel, and[CR]having enough MP to cast it a couple of times. After [CR]promo, he learns 4[CR]levels of his Breath spell. First level is exactly the same as his[CR]critical[CR]hit, and costs 8 MP. Incidentally, if he attacks and crits, using his[CR]breath, it will cost him 8 MP. If he has less than 8 MP when this happens,[CR]his MP [CR]becomes 0 but the attack still works. Breath 2 deals the same[CR]damage as Breath 1/his[CR]critical to 5 enemies at a range of 1 (really 4[CR]enemies since hes always in the area[CR]of effect), for 12 MP; he learns it at[CR]level 10 promoted. Breath 3 deals slightly [CR]more damage to 5 enemies at a[CR]range of 1 for 16 MP; he learns it at level 16. Breath [CR]4 deals Freeze[CR]4-caliber damage to one enemy at a range of 2 for 16 MP; hell learn it[CR]at[CR]level 22. His HP is still terrible, as before. Note that the icon for Breath[CR]is [CR]garbled and the spell will not show up on his character screen, only on[CR]the magic [CR]screen.[CR]Peters stats have been nerfed a little bit. He is[CR]still the strongest attacker in [CR]the game, and is a little more fragile. He[CR]is still debatably the best character on [CR]the force. If you can cast the[CR]Attack spell, this is less debatable.[CR]Luke and Skreech have both had slight[CR]boosts to their stats, and now learn 4 levels of[CR]Blast after promotion.[CR]They still arent great, but might make a good 10th-12th party[CR]member or so.[CR]Luke gets a little more MP than Skreech; Skreech gets a little more [CR]attack[CR]than Luke.[CR]All four archers have had slight boosts to their attack power to[CR]cope with improved [CR]monster defense. Elric and Janet have had larger boosts[CR]to their attack power, [CR]keeping them more competitive with May and Rhode.[CR]May still has the strongest attack [CR]power, but is no longer clearly the[CR]best archer. Provided you promote everyone [CR]immediately as intended, Janets[CR]4 extra prepromo levels may make her the best archer [CR]of them[CR]all.[CR]Randolfs stats have been boosted, so that he is actually slightly[CR]better than Jaha [CR]instead of strictly worse. He learns the Attack spell[CR]immediately after promotion [CR](keep in mind Attack cannot be cast on the[CR]caster). He is now a very viable pick from[CR]Creeds.[CR]All Barons gain some[CR]defense; the defense penalty of 10 for promoting to Baron vs [CR]Gladiator was[CR]too harsh. The penalty is now closer to 5.[CR]Tayas spell progression has been[CR]radically altered, to her benefit. She gains Atlas [CR]earlier than anybody[CR]else. She will gain Atlas 1 (which is improved to have range 3) [CR]at 14, and[CR]Atlas 2 at 26. She is the only character who can easily gain Atlas 2. [CR]She[CR]gets Neptune far too late to be of any real use, to compensate. Her defense,[CR]while still the worst in the game, is a little better than it was.[CR]Gyan[CR]learns Boost 1 and 2, and gains a very small amount of MP to cast them with.[CR]With the nerf to Boost (see below), this should give him some extra[CR]tactical [CR]usefulness without being too terribly abusable for experience.[CR]His stats are also [CR]boosted very slightly.[CR]Sheelas defense has been[CR]boosted slightly. Her spell progression is also slightly [CR]improved.[CR]Zynk[CR]has a laser attack as a spell. It does about 28 damage to 5 enemies at a range[CR]of 3, and costs 12 MP. He will start with enough MP to cast it once,[CR]eventually gain [CR]enough to cast it twice, and may get enough to cast it[CR]three times if you get his [CR]level around 30 or give him a Bright Honey.[CR]Unlike Kiwis breath critical, Zynks [CR]laser critical does not cost MP: in[CR]fact it is not even a spell at all, and just does[CR]extra physical damage.[CR]Note that the icon for Laser is garbled and the spell will not[CR]show up on[CR]his character screen, only on the magic screen.[CR]Claude now joins the party[CR]at level 16 instead of 14.[CR]Chaz learns Freeze 4 earlier, at 23. This makes[CR]him better in a no-egress game, which[CR]this essentially is.[CR]Lemons stats[CR]are boosted slightly.[CR]Resistance changes: Mages, Wizards and Sorcerers are[CR]now weakly resistant to [CR]Lightning, Ice, and Fire. Birdmen and promoted[CR]Peter are now weak to Wind. Brass [CR]Gunners and Zynk are now weak to[CR]Lightning. Claude is now weak to fire (instead of [CR]heavily resistant!),[CR]heavily resistant to ice, and weakly resistant to Bolt. Kiwi, [CR]once[CR]promoted, is weakly resistant to fire and weak to ice. All of these changes[CR]are [CR]motivated by enemy resistances: mages are usually resistant to the[CR]element they cast,[CR] all feather winged fliers other than pegasi are weak to[CR]wind, mechanical archers are [CR]weak to bolt, and golems are all weak to[CR]fire, heavily resistant to ice, and weakly [CR]resistant to bolt. Fire[CR]breathing enemies are always strong vs fire and weak vs[CR]ice.[CR]SPELLS:[CR]First of all keep in mind that adjustments to spells affect[CR]both you and the enemies. [CR]So if a spell is now better than it used to be[CR]and you dont take advantage of that [CR]fact, it is only helping the[CR]enemies.[CR]Heal and Aura spells have been rebalanced as follows:[CR]Spell[CR]Effect Range Radius MP[CR]Heal 1 15 1 1 3[CR]Heal 2 25 2 1 5[CR]Heal 3 35 3 1[CR]7[CR]Heal 4 255 3 1 15[CR]Aura 1 15 3 2 7[CR]Aura 2 25 3 3 11[CR]Aura 3 35 3 3[CR]15[CR]Aura 4 255 0 All 31[CR]In particular, Heal 2, 3, and 4 have all been[CR]improved. This helps to deal with the [CR]longer battles in this hack, and[CR]makes healers who dont have aura substantially [CR]better than healing items.[CR]Heal 4 is now range 3, instead of a pathetic 1 compared [CR]to Aura 4s[CR]infinite range. The Aura spells all cost 2x+1 MP, where x is the cost of[CR]the corresponding Heal spell, and heal the same amount as the[CR]corresponding heal [CR]spell. Aura 4 is now much more of a panic button than[CR]an extremely efficient healing [CR]spell. All healing amounts increase by 25%[CR]after promotion, as always.[CR]All the Detox spells have had their MP costs[CR]drastically lowered. It may now be more [CR]efficient to cure poison in long[CR]battles.[CR]Most of the status effect spells have been improved. Dispel has[CR]range 3 and radius 3.[CR]Muddle 1 has range 2, and Muddle 2 has range 3. Sleep[CR]has range 3 and radius 2. [CR]Slow 1 has range 2; Slow 2 has range 3.[CR]All[CR]summon spells have had their MP costs slightly reduced (by 2 or 3 points for[CR]all [CR]spells), to compensate for longer battles.[CR]Atlas 1 is now range 3,[CR]which gives Sorcerers a range 3 attack at an attainable level.[CR]Boost 1 now[CR]has range 2 and affects 1 ally, Boost 2 has Range 3 and affects 5[CR]allies.[CR]The damage of Katon 1 has been lowered slightly, to make Katon 2[CR]more useful.[CR]The casting cost of Desoul 2 has been increased to 15[CR]MP.[CR]Certain enemy-only attack spells have been improved.[CR]ITEMS:[CR]Angel[CR]wings are no longer buyable. There are thus 4 angel wings in the game (in[CR]Granseal castle, New Grans during the Peter sequence, the passage to[CR]Creeds, and [CR]Moun). You can use them as you see fit, if you need any extra[CR]levels along the way. [CR]Of course, if Bowie dies, you can gain more[CR]experience by exiting from the battle [CR]that way. Provided you promote[CR]everyone at 20, gaining extra experience from Bowie [CR]deaths should not[CR]seriously imbalance the game. The game should be beatable though [CR]without[CR]any Bowie deaths and using only 1 angel wing in the Zeon battle to resurrect[CR]after the Galam battle. Although technically, that shouldnt even be[CR]necessary. For [CR]the All Boss battle, it might be necessary to use any[CR]excess angel wings to level [CR]build first.[CR]Chaz now starts with a Light[CR]of Hope (restores full MP to all characters). If you [CR]plan on tackling the[CR]All Boss battle, it would be wise to save both the Light of Hope [CR]and any[CR]Healing Rains. It will not be an easy fight.[CR]Promotion items are now[CR]available for sale from the item shop in Hassan. This should [CR]allow you to[CR]promote everyone as soon as they reach level 20, unless perhaps if you[CR]power leveled Sarah to extreme levels. Its up to you to decide if you want[CR]to use [CR]multiple copies of each promotion item. Doing so wont unbalance the[CR]game much, as [CR]the special promotions arent that much better than the[CR]regular ones.[CR]The Quick Ring and Chirrup Sandals both give +1 MOV, in[CR]addition to their other [CR]"abilities."[CR]Cameelas Iron Ball no longer casts[CR]Blaze 3. Have fun finding out what it does cast![CR]Mystery Staves cannot be[CR]equipped by Vicars anymore. This was extremely abusable on [CR]Frayja and/or[CR]Karna, and made the obscene casting cost of Aura 4 less of an issue. [CR]Im[CR]not sure if it is possible to create a Mystery Staff by creating a mithril[CR]weapon [CR]for a Vicar, so be aware that you might get a weapon a Vicar cant[CR]equip if you make [CR]a mithril weapon for them. Wizards and Sorcerers can[CR]still use Mystery staves, since [CR]the ability is substantially less abusable[CR]on them.[CR]All sword users can now equip the Levanter, giving birdmen a[CR]better final equip and [CR]barons another option.[CR]MISC:[CR]A modified[CR]version of BNCs 3 numbers hack has been included in this hack, to avoid[CR]seeing ??s everywhere in the second half of the game. That hack appeared[CR]to [CR]introduce a bug with the caravan, in its attempt to fix the Caravan[CR]repair bug. I [CR]removed the introduced bug, but the Caravan repair bug still[CR]exists in this version.[CR]Incidentally, as you will find out, the hack still[CR]displays three question marks when [CR]monsters get into quadruple digit[CR]stats...[CR]POTENTIAL IMPROVEMENTS:[CR]Here is a short list of things I would[CR]like to add to the hack, but dont have the [CR]knowledge to[CR]implement:[CR]Enforce promotion at level 20. Make experience growth stop after[CR]level 20, as it [CR]does when an unpromoted character reaches level 40.[CR]Fix[CR]the icons for Kiwis breath spells and Zynks Laser spell. Also make these[CR]spells show up in the character description pages for Kiwi and Zynk. It is[CR]possible [CR]that a future version of the Caravan editor by BNC will allow[CR]this.[CR]CREDITS:[CR]Essentially 90+% of the credit for this hack should[CR]actually go to Bryan Murphree, [CR]for his amazing SF2 Editor program. Credit[CR]also goes out to BNC for the 3 numbers [CR]hack, and for inspiring me to make[CR]my own hack. Also props to my friend Dogbert for [CR]helping to playtest the[CR]hack and make balance changes.</plot>
    <genre>Levels,Gameplay</genre>
    <studio>Obob</studio>
    <snapshot1>ayzRQht.jpg</snapshot1>
    <snapshot2>YkRgfoO.png</snapshot2>
  </game>
  <game name="Shining Force II - Shining Tactics (X)">
    <description>Shining Force II - Shining Tactics (X)</description>
    <title_clean>Shining Force II - Shining Tactics</title_clean>
    <rom name="EmuROMHacks/ROM_Hacks_1.zip/Genesis%2FShining%20Force%20II%20-%20Shining%20Tactics%20%28X%29.bin" size="4194304"/>
  </game>
  <game name="Shinobi 3 - RoTNM (X)">
    <description>Shinobi 3 - RoTNM (X)</description>
    <title_clean>Shinobi 3 - RoTNM</title_clean>
    <rom name="EmuROMHacks/ROM_Hacks_1.zip/Genesis%2FShinobi%203%20-%20RoTNM%20%28X%29.bin" size="1048576"/>
  </game>
  <game name="Sonic - ERaZor (X)">
    <description>Sonic - ERaZor (X)</description>
    <title_clean>Sonic - ERaZor</title_clean>
    <rom name="EmuROMHacks/ROM_Hacks_1.zip/Genesis%2FSonic%20-%20ERaZor%20%28X%29.bin" size="1029703"/>
    <plot>This is a hack of Sonic the Hedgehog for the Sega Genesis. It redesigns many[CR]aspects of the original and adds new content. There are various cutscenes that[CR]play at various parts of the game. Levels are redesigned: there's new[CR]palettes, some new graphics, new music, new level names. Some new features are[CR]available such as respawn points after falling into a pit, rings expelling[CR]from enemies, and many other changes the author of the hack wants people to[CR]discover on their own. The patch is in xdelta format. The ROM should be in BIN[CR]format. 5th release * Updated all bosses! -- Added a hit counter. -- The Scar[CR]Night Place Bomb Boss is now the big one from Sonic CD. * 200% more[CR]explosions! -- Also improved camera shaking a lot. * Atmospheric Mode has been[CR]replaced with Nonstop Inhuman Mode, and it unlocks after finishing the game. *[CR]Put platforms over the tubes in the overworld so you can no longer[CR]accidentally fall into them. (Thanks to MarkeyJester!) * Revamped Crabmeat[CR]Boss music. (Thanks to Spanner!) * Story and tutorial texts have been edited.[CR](Thanks to Kaidan and Abcron!) * Bunch of other fixes and small changes, but[CR]nothing really noteworthy... 6th release * Uberhub Place added. * Minor bugs[CR]fixed.[CR]Read Me:[CR]Sonic ERaZor[CR]Credits: Selbi[CR]Thanks:[CR]MarkeyJester, vladikcomper, DalekSam, SOTI, Eduardo Knuckles[CR]Sonic ERaZor[CR]is a hack of Sonic the Hedgehog (16-bit). This hack is unlike many other[CR]hacks, featuring a heavy in-game story line, unique challenges, and never seen[CR]before gameplay mechanics. These elements are often somehow related to[CR]explosions, which is why this hack is sometimes called "What if Michael Bay[CR]directed Sonic 1".[CR]When first released back in early 2010, Selbi stated[CR]that this hack has no goal whatsoever and any ideas he came up with just went[CR]in. Todays releases have a lot more structure and thought out gameplay[CR]elements. The difficulty has been steadily decreased between the different[CR]versions, mostly due to some negative feedback regarding the first releases,[CR]although they all have an above average difficulty, and is therefore regarded[CR]by many as quite interesting and challenging, if not frustrating.[CR]A notable[CR]aspect about this hack is that it contains many cutscenes, chapter screens and[CR]story screens. The games first scene after the title screen is entirely a[CR]cutscene.[CR]Music list[CR]== Music list ==[CR]#81: Hockenheim-Ring - F1: Pole[CR]Position [SNES] (used in Night Hill Place)[CR]#82: Dr. Cossack Stage 2 - Mega[CR]Man 4 (used in Labyrinth Place)[CR]#83: Blades Theme - Eternal Champions (used[CR]in Ruined Place)[CR]#84: Title Screen - Mega Man IV (used in Scar Night Place[CR][Section 1])[CR]#85: Freeze Man Stage - Mega Man 7 (used in Uberhub[CR]Place)[CR]#86: Spark Mandrill - Megaman X (used in options menu)[CR]#87: Stage[CR]4-2 - Ninja Gaiden (used in Tutorial Place)[CR]#88: One up - Sonic 1[CR](unused)[CR]#89: Hidden Song - Tecmo Wrestling (used in Special Stage)[CR]#8A:[CR]Opening Sequence - Super Street Fighter 2 Turbo (used on title screen)[CR]#8B:[CR]Ending (Remix) - Sonic 1 (unused)[CR]#8C: Chaos Angel Act 1 - Sonic Advance 3[CR](used on Green Hill Place boss)[CR]#8D: Shutdown - Pulseman (used in Finalor[CR]Place [Intro] and Bomb cutscene)[CR]#8E: Act Clear - Sonic 1 (unused)[CR]#8F:[CR]Game Over - Sonic 1 (unused)[CR]#90: Continue - Sonic 1 (used in continue[CR]screen)[CR]#91: Ending Theme - Dangerous Seed (used for invincibility power-[CR]up)[CR]#92: Drowning - Sonic 1 (used for drowning music)[CR]#93: Emerald -[CR]Sonic 1 (used in Emerald)[CR]#94: Green Hill Zone - Sonic 1 (used in Green[CR]Hill Place)[CR]#95: Kens Theme - Street Fighter 2 (used in intro[CR]cutscene)[CR]#96: Stage 7: Orn Base - Thunder Force 3 (used in Scar Night[CR]Place [Section 2])[CR]#97: Opening - Gundam Wing: Endless Duel (used in[CR]credits)[CR]#98: Boss - Sonic Advance 3 (used at Crabmeat boss)[CR]#99:[CR]Darkman [Proto Man] Stages - Mega Man 5 (used in game introduction)[CR]#9A:[CR]Whirlwind - Shinobi 3 (used in Unreal Place)[CR]#98: Boss [Alternate] - Sonic[CR]Advance 3 (used in Walking Bomb boss)[CR]#9C: Spring Yard Zone - Sonic 1[CR](unused)[CR]#9D: Push! - Zillion Push (used in ending sequence)[CR]#9E: Final[CR]Boss - Sonic 3 (used in Finalor Place [Boss])[CR]#9F: Straight Ahead - Megaman[CR]Zero 4 (used in inhuman mode [S-Monitor])</plot>
    <genre>Graphics,Sound,Levels,Text,Gameplay</genre>
    <studio>Selbi</studio>
    <snapshot1>mj611kb.png</snapshot1>
    <snapshot2>ilgoZgJ.png</snapshot2>
  </game>
  <game name="Sonic - Into the Void (SHC 2015 Demo)">
    <description>Sonic - Into the Void (SHC 2015 Demo)</description>
    <title_clean>Sonic - Into the Void</title_clean>
    <rom name="EmuROMHacks/ROM_Hacks_1.zip/Genesis%2FSonic%20-%20Into%20the%20Void%20%28SHC%202015%20Demo%29.bin" size="1048576"/>
    <plot>Sonic: Into The Void is a hack of Sonic the Hedgehog (16-bit) for the Sega[CR]Mega Drive / Sega Genesis by Blueblur93 which features a complete overhaul of[CR]the game, including new artwork, new HUD, new abilities and many other things.[CR]The version 4.1 has now been released which includes even more of level[CR]changes, new music and sounds, edited/new sprite art, new act exclusive[CR]palettes, new zone and reworked bosses. (Note: The bosses are just mere[CR]concepts, future releases will have more tweaks to the bosses, ultimately[CR]leading to completely fresh looking bosses while using some of the original[CR]game's ideas.) * -STORY- NOTE: This story takes place directly after Sonic[CR]Generations. After Classic Sonic celebrates his 20th birthday with Modern[CR]Sonic and friends, Classic Sonic and Classic Tails jump into a portal which[CR]leads them into the Void. Both era's Eggmans are stuck in the White Space,[CR]however, they accidentally stumble upon an opening to the Void, seeing Classic[CR]Sonic and Tails soaring across. The Eggmans fire their laser pistols through[CR]the opening, hoping to hit Sonic and Tails, but their attempt failed and hits[CR]the Void. The Void then becomes highly aggravated and unstable, which splits[CR]Sonic and Tails up and sends them to their own time. However, expecting to[CR]return to his own time, Sonic ends up to what seems to be Green Hill Zone, but[CR]he could see that something was wrong. Green Hill Zone has transformed into a[CR]place called Azure Hills Zone. Due to the disturbance in the Void, the Time[CR]Continuum for Sonic has been completely distorted. Sonic thinks that maybe[CR]collecting all 6 Chaos Emeralds will restore the Time Continuum, but he does[CR]also notice that all these events involving traveling through generations and[CR]the Time Eater seem oddly connected in a diabolical way... Controls: * Jump =[CR]A, B, C. * Jump Dash = JUMP + A. * Homing Attack = JUMP + B. * Spin Dash =[CR]DOWN + C.</plot>
    <genre>Graphics,Sound,Levels,Text,Gameplay</genre>
    <studio>Blueblur93</studio>
    <snapshot1>J0TNi5h.png</snapshot1>
    <snapshot2>ZujK3F4.png</snapshot2>
  </game>
  <game name="Sonic - Megamix (X)">
    <description>Sonic - Megamix (X)</description>
    <title_clean>Sonic - Megamix</title_clean>
    <rom name="EmuROMHacks/ROM_Hacks_1.zip/Genesis%2FSonic%20-%20Megamix%20%28X%29.bin" size="1283224"/>
    <plot>Highlights for version 3.0: * All level layouts edited (some complete; others[CR]pending). * Each character now has a unique set of moves (though Sonic and[CR]Shadow share the homing attack). * Most levels (not all) have a small intro,[CR]ala S3K, where they perform some sort of action when starting the level i.e,[CR]running in from the left. * Loads of music edits. * There is now a[CR]"preferences" screen, where you can customize certain aspects of the game[CR](suggestions are welcome). * Cheat codes have been changed - figuring them out[CR]will grant you access to a new, special level select (which is a bit buggy -[CR]just don't hit left/right on zone selections =P). * "Original Mode" allows you[CR]to play the original levels from Sonic the Hedgehog, using all of the[CR]additions from Sonic Megamix (such as bug fixes, moves, preferences, etc).[CR]There is also a separate save slot for a character's original mode. * Title[CR]screen demos have been edited. Credits demos have not. * Super forms have been[CR]added. * Elemental shields, ala S3K, have been added. * Credits have been[CR]edited; each character has a unique end pose on the ending sequence. * Various[CR]other changes. See the [Wiki page](http://info.sonicretro.org/Sonic_1_Megamix)[CR]for more info. This is considered a "complete" release, although not "final".[CR]It was succeeded by an incomplete "4.0b", which was ported to SegaCD, and[CR]further changes have been implemented since, although a "final" release and[CR]its date are tentative. More information can be found on the Manual/Wiki page,[CR]located at here: . For a complete list of authors, please see: . Note: Apply[CR]xdelta patch to US Genesis Sonic 1 ROM. The patch is in xdelta format due to[CR]shifted data which resulted in a IPS patch almost the same size as the patched[CR]ROM.</plot>
    <genre>Graphics,Sound,Levels,Text,Gameplay</genre>
    <studio>Stealth, Tweaker</studio>
    <snapshot1>SCJfmPj.png</snapshot1>
    <snapshot2>XQt7pPN.png</snapshot2>
  </game>
  <game name="Sonic - Metal Sonic 2 (X)">
    <description>Sonic - Metal Sonic 2 (X)</description>
    <title_clean>Sonic - Metal Sonic 2</title_clean>
    <rom name="EmuROMHacks/ROM_Hacks_1.zip/Genesis%2FSonic%20-%20Metal%20Sonic%202%20%28X%29.bin" size="2097152"/>
    <plot>A full hack of Sonic the Hedgehog 1, with tons of features, brand new levels,[CR]playable characters, Sonic CD style gameplay (minus the extended camera), and[CR]more. I created this Sonic the hedgehog hack back in October 31, 2011[CR](Halloween), everything has been changed and feels like a completely new game.[CR]Changes since Hyperdrive v1.0: * Improved level designs and layouts * Extreme[CR]mode added * Extra characters have been updated * More bugfixes * A few[CR]soundtracks has been changed * Improved wall jump physics * etc Note: Patch to[CR]clean Sonic 1 ROM (REV00, the one with no moving clouds) with ".bin" as the[CR]extension or else, it may not work. The patch is in XDelta format due to[CR]shifted data which resulted in a IPS patch with copyrighted data in it. For a[CR]later version of the hack see [THIS[CR]link.](http://www.romhacking.net/hacks/1674/)[CR]Read Me:[CR]Metal Sonic[CR]Hyperdrive by Darkon360[CR]Patch to a clean Sonic 1 rom (REV00, the one with[CR]no moving clouds) with .bin as the extension or else, it may not[CR]work.[CR]Story [METAL]:[CR]One Day, after the defeat of DrEggman by the hands[CR]of Sonic. Eggman decided to build a Power Armor sult based off EggRobo and[CR]travel to Mobius to capture Sonic and Tails by sending them into a Cosmic[CR]portal to trap them, but luckily, Tails escaped. he knew that Sonic is missing[CR]and he decided to sneak into Eggmans HQ and grab the parts of Eggmans robots[CR]and pieces. Tails later go to his home in the Mystic Ruins and created a new[CR]robot, based off Metal Sonic classic model, Codename: METAL. with the ability[CR]to feel and behave almost exactly like Sonic, with a special move to directly[CR]Jumpdash in any direction, and Walljump through unreachable places. Tails was[CR]able to track Eggman to where hes heading by using his Radar, so Tails send[CR]Metal Sonic to Resort Isle, where Eggman was heading to. in hopes to find[CR]Sonic and Destory DrEggman once and for all.[CR]Note: Darkon, Kirby, and[CR]Somari are non canon to the Hyperdrive storyline, theyre just there for[CR]fun[CR]Eggman later decided to create a mystic portal into other worlds to[CR]make his Egg Empire bigger then before,[CR]sending his robots to Kirby,[CR]Somari, and Darkons Worlds attempting to destroy everything in its[CR]Path.[CR]the madness has just begun. [CR]Story [DARKON]:[CR]After defeating[CR]Zen, saving the world from nuclear war, and winning the ultimate prize and[CR]grand champion.[CR]Darkon saw a portal of Eggmans robots falling from the sky,[CR]causing mass destruction through the city. Darkon and few of his Friends[CR]decided to Kill them all, then Darkon realise the portal was about to close,[CR]he jumped through the portal and [CR]headed into Resort Isle. Darkon dont know[CR]where hes at so he decided to go forward and hunt the person whos responsible[CR]of sending the robots.[CR]Story [KIRBY]:[CR]Kirby was bored and fell alsleep[CR]after eating too much Rare Candys, until he heard a portal coming from the[CR]sky, a rain of Eggmans robots appear, Kirby knew hes in big trouble. until one[CR]of Eggmans Badniks pushed Kirby into the portal. later, Kirby woke up and he[CR]is in Resort Isle. Kirby dont know what is going on so he decided to explore[CR]the place and find the one whos causing a rain of robots in his home[CR]world.[CR]Story [SOMARI]:[CR]A NES Cart of Somari was found by the hands of[CR]Eggmans Badniks. after attempting to insert it into the NES Console, Somari[CR]poped out of the screen, and killed one of the Badniks, not knowing that the[CR]NES Console is corrupted with unknown magic. Somari was later trapped by one[CR]of Eggmans robots and send him back to prison in Resort Isle, Somari luckliy[CR]escaped the prison cell and off to get his revenge.[CR]Story [SONIC]:[CR]Sonic[CR]was captured by Eggman in the sky, he broke free and attempts countless Homing[CR]Attacks on Eggman but [CR]it wont work, due to Eggmans new battle armor.[CR]Eggman later smashed away Sonic into the air and escapes.[CR]Sonic landed on[CR]Resort Isle, he woked up and realise hes in a New World, Sonic decided to[CR]search for Eggman and put a stop to him and his mess for good. [CR]Hints:[CR]How to get the Chaos Emeralds?: [CR]After grabbing 50 or more[CR]Rings into the Signpost, Jump into the Giant Ring, you will automaticity gain[CR]1 Emerald. the max is 6 Emeralds. this is also useful for getting the secret[CR]ending.[CR]How to become SUPER Sonic?:[CR]Get all Chaos Emeralds and press Up[CR]+ A in mid air to transform, only METAL can become Super.</plot>
    <genre>Graphics,Sound,Levels,Text,Gameplay</genre>
    <studio>Lone Devil</studio>
    <snapshot1>vgfil71.png</snapshot1>
    <snapshot2>J3Zcd7P.png</snapshot2>
  </game>
  <game name="Sonic - Metal Sonic Hyperdrive (X)">
    <description>Sonic - Metal Sonic Hyperdrive (X)</description>
    <title_clean>Sonic - Metal Sonic Hyperdrive</title_clean>
    <rom name="EmuROMHacks/ROM_Hacks_1.zip/Genesis%2FSonic%20-%20Metal%20Sonic%20Hyperdrive%20%28X%29.bin" size="2097152"/>
    <plot>Metal Sonic Hyperdrive is a heavy modification of Sonic the Hedgehog (1991) by[CR]Darkon360 for the Sega Genesis. with brand new Zones, Sonic CD style gameplay,[CR]Music, Playable Characters, and Modes. Starting Metal Sonic, taking Sonic's[CR]role as the main protagonist to stop Dr.Robotnik's greatest inventions yet.[CR]Also starting special guests such as Kirby, and Somari. Story: One day, after[CR]the defeat of Dr.Robotnik by the hands of Sonic. Robotnik decided to rebuild[CR]Eggrobo to travel Mobius to search for the Chaos Emeralds. Eggrobo kidnapped[CR]Tails in the Mystic Ruins, by sending him into Metallic Madness, but luckily,[CR]Tails escaped. he decided to sneak into Robotnik's lab and grab the parts of[CR]his robots and pieces. Tails later go to his home in the Mystic Ruins and[CR]created a new robot, based off Metal Sonic's classic model, Codename: METAL.[CR]with the ability to feel and behave almost exactly like Sonic. Tails was able[CR]to track Eggrobo to where hes heading by using his Radar, so Tails sent Metal[CR]Sonic to Robotic Isle, where Eggrobo is heading to. in hopes to find the Chaos[CR]Emeralds and destroy Dr.Eggman's plans once and for all. Obtaining Chaos[CR]Emeralds: To obtain all 6 emeralds, find and destroy emerald monitors to[CR]enable the Giant Ring. (no Special Stages required) Level Select: Hint: Sonic[CR]CD North America Release date. Extras Menu: Press C button on the Title Screen[CR]to access the special extra features, including character selection and[CR]Survival Mode. [Genesis/Megadrive covers and cartstickers ready for print[CR]here.](http://darkon.sonicgamesdimension.net/Boxarts/)</plot>
    <genre>Graphics,Sound,Levels,Text,Gameplay</genre>
    <studio>Lone Devil</studio>
    <snapshot1>Fn6DIz6.png</snapshot1>
    <snapshot2>igfsGK1.png</snapshot2>
  </game>
  <game name="Sonic - Rockman Chaos (X)">
    <description>Sonic - Rockman Chaos (X)</description>
    <title_clean>Sonic - Rockman Chaos</title_clean>
    <rom name="EmuROMHacks/ROM_Hacks_1.zip/Genesis%2FSonic%20-%20Rockman%20Chaos%20%28X%29.bin" size="1339818"/>
  </game>
  <game name="Sonic - SFactor Sonia &amp;amp; Silver (X)">
    <description>Sonic - SFactor Sonia &amp;amp; Silver (X)</description>
    <title_clean>Sonic - SFactor Sonia &amp;amp; Silver</title_clean>
    <rom name="EmuROMHacks/ROM_Hacks_1.zip/Genesis%2FSonic%20-%20SFactor%20Sonia%20%26%20Silver%20%28X%29.bin" size="4194304"/>
    <plot>This is a hack of Sonic the Hedgehog for the Sega Genesis. It changes[CR]graphics, music, and layout of most levels. Some levels re-use previous[CR]artwork but much of it is original. Two characters are playable; Sonia,[CR]Sonic's sister from the SatAM cartoon series, Silver the Hedgehog from Sonic[CR]the Hedgehog (2006), and Scourge, a character from the US Sonic the Hedgehog[CR]comic series. Each character plays different from each other and have some[CR]moves unique to each character. A move list can be found in the readme. The[CR]game features Eggman Nega, Eggman's evil descendant from the same time period[CR]as Silver. He is the nemesis of the heroes of this hack. The patch is in[CR]xdelta format. The ROM should be in BIN format.[CR]Read Me:[CR]The S[CR]Factor: Sonia and Silver[CR]Credits: Aquaslash and Pals[CR]The S Factor: Sonia[CR]and Silver is an multi-level hack of Sonic the Hedgehog on the Sega Mega[CR]Drive/Genesis. The game allows players to choose between two characters, Sonia[CR]and Silver and offers several moves attributed to those[CR]characters.[CR]==Story==[CR]The citizens of Mobius just cant seem to catch a[CR]break. Dr. Robotnik (AKA Eggman) is yet again up to his no good tricks.[CR]Factories and pollution are spreading like wildfire as hes once again trying[CR]to take over the world. Fortunately, the Sonic Heroes are never at rest, and[CR]once again wage their battle to defeat Eggmans evil forces.[CR]However, the[CR]heroes have landed in double jeopardy. Eggmans madman descendant, Eggman Nega,[CR]has escaped from the Ifrits dimension, and is wreaking his usual havoc in an[CR]effort to destroy the world. Hes even captured Eggmans top three lieutenants,[CR]the ruthless Team Metallix, and reprogrammed them to do his even more evil[CR]bidding.[CR]Unlike previous instances of Negas destruction, Eggman is not[CR]fazed. He figures that once hes in control of the world, he can take care of[CR]Eggman Nega as he pleases. Unfortunately for Eggman, Sonic the Hedgehog isnt[CR]having that. Before he can decide who to dispatch where, he receives a call[CR]through the communicator Tails gave him. The message: someones already on the[CR]case. Not just someone, but someones![CR]Apparently, Sonics very own sister,[CR]Sonia the Hedgehog has already caught wind of Negas evil and is out to stop[CR]him. Sonic is a bit eased, knowing full well of his sisters strength and[CR]agility. She also lets him know that she has found and teamed up with a[CR]mysterious young hedgehog who can move things with his mind. Sonic instantly[CR]recognizes that Sonia is with his newest ally: Silver the Hedgehog. Silver has[CR]once again traveled through time to ensure that the future is free of Negas[CR]tampering (though he really ought to just stay here in the present, you know).[CR]Knowing that the two hedgehogs are more than capable of handling the[CR]situation, Sonic leaves it to them, and resumes dealing with Eggman.[CR]Eggman[CR]Nega is well aware that Sonic is busy with his dimwitted ancestor. However,[CR]hed do best not to overlook a certain factor. The S Factor, Sonia and Silver![CR]Its up to you to lead the unlikely tag team of the physically powerful Sonia,[CR]and the psychokinetic Silver on their quest to right the wrongs of the evil[CR]Eggman Nega![CR]==Characters==[CR]===Sonia the Hedgehog===[CR]The younger[CR]sister of the world famous hero, Sonic the Hedgehog. While she doesnt have his[CR]super speed, she makes up for it with quick moves, and incredible strength.[CR]Though she tends to be quite high maintenance, and a bit bossy, Sonia is[CR]incredibly agile, and a capable fighter to boot. She has a special move called[CR]the Super Twirl that allows her to accelerate into a powerful[CR]cyclone.[CR]===Silver the Hedgehog===[CR]One of the newest recruits to the[CR]Sonic Heroes, Silver is from a world in the distant future. Because of his[CR]strong determination to uphold the ways of truth and justice, Silver often[CR]finds himself chasing the time and dimension hopping Eggman Nega. Silvers most[CR]powerful asset is his mind. He wields amazing psychokinetic ability! He can[CR]move nearly anything, even himself, by just thinking about it! It is this[CR]trait that gives him his unusual flight abilities.[CR]Rush eggman[CR]nega.png[CR]===Eggman Nega===[CR]Eggmans evil descendant from the same time[CR]period as Silver. Rejected by scientists because his ancestors failures,[CR]Eggman Nega traveled back in time and tried to replace him and gain honor to[CR]the Robotnik name. His plans were thwarted, and now he wants revenge. If he[CR]cant rule the world, hell simply destroy it and find somewhere else to rule.[CR]Negas presence usually requires Sonics and Eggmans troops to team up, but[CR]Eggman has different ideas this time. Can Sonia and Silver stop his plans for[CR]world destruction?[CR]===Team Metallix===[CR]Dr. Eggmans top henchbots have[CR]been reprogrammed by Eggman Nega and attack our heroes in the White Blaster[CR]Zone![CR]===A.N.N.===[CR]The "voice" of Team Metallix as shes the only one[CR]with speech capabilities. A fanatic of Eggmans work who willingly subjected[CR]herself to roboticization. She specializes in flight. Watch out for her energy[CR]attacks![CR]===Metal Knuckles===[CR]Eggmans pulled this older machine out of[CR]storage and upgraded it into a more battle hardy configuration. As a[CR]doppelganger of Knuckles, he specializes in brute strength. Beware of his[CR]sharp "knuckles" and missile attacks.[CR]===Metal Sonic===[CR]The tactical[CR]leader of the team, Metal Sonic is the one android that all of the heroes know[CR]too well. Like his namesake, he specializes in supersonic speed. However, his[CR]frame seems to have problems accommodating that super speed...[CR]===The Sonic[CR]Heroes===[CR]The group of young heroes led by the fleet footed speed demon,[CR]Sonic the Hedgehog. Theyve got their hand full with dealing with Eggmans plan[CR]to one up Eggman Nega. Fulfill certain conditions, and you might be able to[CR]help them on their quest. Which ones? Play the game and find[CR]out![CR]==Controls==[CR]===All Characters===[CR]Directional Pad Left or Right:[CR]Move - Hold either button to accelerate. Press the opposite direction to[CR]brake.[CR]Directional Pad Up: Look - get a view of your upper[CR]surroundings.[CR]Directional Pad Down: Crouch - get a view of your lower[CR]surroundings.[CR]C: Spin Attack - use the hedgehogs main defensive move to[CR]gain speed on slopes and destroy enemies![CR]Jump + Hold A + C (thats jump,[CR]hold A and press C): Mission Power - Complete all of the secret missions to[CR]unlock this "super" move of great justice![CR]===Unique to Sonia===[CR]Hold A:[CR]Super Twirl - Accelerate into a whirlwind tornado! Grants temporary[CR]invincibility and increased acceleration, but you cant jump. Let go of the[CR]button for a burst of speed.[CR]Jump + C: Power Axe - this spinning axe kick[CR]increases Sonias attack range and reflects most projectile attacks.[CR]Power[CR]Skill - As Sonia is a strength oriented character, she can access various[CR]shortcuts that other characters cant with little effort.[CR]===Unique to[CR]Silver===[CR]Hold A: Psychokinesis - Silvers signature skill. Control various[CR]objects and use them to destroy enemies and access shortcuts.[CR]Jump + C:[CR]Levitation - glide through the air with your psychic powers. Hold A to sustain[CR]altitude, and move with the directional pad. Use it carefully as it only lasts[CR]a short while.</plot>
    <genre>Graphics,Sound,Levels,Text,Gameplay</genre>
    <studio>Aquaslash</studio>
    <snapshot1>hgWSy42.png</snapshot1>
    <snapshot2>qazV6Vf.png</snapshot2>
  </game>
  <game name="Sonic - Scorched Quest (SHC2016 Demo)">
    <description>Sonic - Scorched Quest (SHC2016 Demo)</description>
    <title_clean>Sonic - Scorched Quest</title_clean>
    <rom name="EmuROMHacks/ROM_Hacks_1.zip/Genesis%2FSonic%20-%20Scorched%20Quest%20%28SHC2016%20Demo%29.bin" size="2097152"/>
  </game>
  <game name="Sonic - Sonic 3 &amp;amp; Amy Rose (X)">
    <description>Sonic - Sonic 3 &amp;amp; Amy Rose (X)</description>
    <title_clean>Sonic - Sonic 3 &amp;amp; Amy Rose</title_clean>
    <rom name="EmuROMHacks/ROM_Hacks_1.zip/Genesis%2FSonic%20-%20Sonic%203%20%26%20Amy%20Rose%20%28X%29.bin" size="3410554"/>
    <plot>This is a hack which replaces Sonic the Hedgehog with Amy in Sonic the[CR]Hedgehog 3 and Knuckles for Genesis. This is Sonic 3 and Sonic and Knuckles[CR]locked onto each other. Amy in the hack is classic Amy designed after her[CR]Sonic CD appearance. Amy's moves are inspired by those used in her Sonic[CR]Advance appearance. She is slower than Sonic, can't use spin attack but has[CR]other moves. An attack button has been added and other moves can also be[CR]performed by using combinations of buttons and directional pad presses. A[CR]complete move list is found in the readme. The ROM should be in BIN format. It[CR]has not been tested for compatibility on other formats. The patch is in xdelta[CR]format due to shifted data resulting in IPS patches containing original code.[CR]Version 1.4 * Added remaining few missing sprites, plus a Bonus Stage slot[CR]picture and title screen animation. * Fixed clunky break mechanism for Ice Cap[CR]walls. * Tails now appears when entering Ice Cap via normal route (he's still[CR]absent via Knuckles' entrance however). * Tails now runs at the same pace as[CR]Amy, meaning no annoying skidding every time the COM overtakes[CR]her.[CR]Read Me:[CR]Sonic 3 and Amy Rose[CR]Credits: E-122-Psi[CR]Big[CR]thanks to: Tiddles, ChelseaCatGirl, Gsuki[CR]==Controls==[CR]Amys abilities[CR]mirror those she utilized in the Sonic Advance series. She is slower than[CR]Sonic and cant use spin attacks, however has a number of abilities (mostly[CR]using her Piko Piko Hammer) to gain manueverability and access areas Sonic had[CR]difficulty reaching:[CR]*Hammer Attack: Press A and Amy swings her hammer,[CR]damaging enemies. In addition, Amy can use her hammer to smash obstacles such[CR]as walls and hit springs.[CR]*Hammer Jump: Press Down + A on the ground and[CR]Amy smashes the hammer into the ground, launching her into the air.[CR]*Hammer[CR]Whirl: Press Down + A in the air and Amy swirls down toward the ground. If an[CR]enemy is hit Amy will bounce up again.[CR]*Upward Dash: Hold Down + B/C while[CR]on the ground and Amy will rev her feet on the spot as opposed to a spin dash.[CR]Let go of Down to charge full throttle in the facing direction. Be careful[CR]though, Amy is vulnerable to blockading obstacles and enemies. [CR]In[CR]addition, Amy can use her hammer attacks to enter Knuckles blocked pathways,[CR]allowing her to proceed through the game with either Sonic or Knuckles routes.</plot>
    <genre>Graphics,Gameplay</genre>
    <studio>E-122-Psi</studio>
    <snapshot1>MIUKug0.png</snapshot1>
    <snapshot2>7ZddiHL.png</snapshot2>
  </game>
  <game name="Sonic - Sonic 3 Complete (X)">
    <description>Sonic - Sonic 3 Complete (X)</description>
    <title_clean>Sonic - Sonic 3 Complete</title_clean>
    <rom name="EmuROMHacks/ROM_Hacks_1.zip/Genesis%2FSonic%20-%20Sonic%203%20Complete%20%28X%29.bin" size="3932160"/>
    <plot>This is a hack of Sonic the Hedgehog 3 and Knuckles. It is a new feature,[CR]Sonic 3-ification, and bugfix patch. The game has been altered to restore[CR]changes made to Sonic 3 levels so the levels play and sound like they did in[CR]Sonic 3. There is also a game selection screen allowing for Sonic 3 Alone,[CR]Sonic and Knuckles, Sonic 3 and Knuckles, and Blue Sphere to be played.[CR]Several bugs have been fixed and there is a option screen to reverse some[CR]changes made. The hack can be modified further with the included ips patches.[CR]Cheat codes can be found in the read me. It is encouraged to read the readme[CR]as it has an exhaustive list of changes made in this hack. The patch is in[CR]xdelta format due to shifted data resulting in IPS patches containing original[CR]code. Make sure to use the Sonic and Knuckles and Sonic 3 ROM which is about[CR]4,096 kb in size. The ROM should be in BIN format.[CR]Read Me:[CR]Sonic 3[CR]Complete[CR]Credits: Tiddles;[CR]Additional contributions from flamewing, That[CR]One Jig, Neo, Hayate, shobiz, Tribeam, MoDule and LOst[CR]Sonic 3 Complete is[CR]a hack of Sonic 3 and Knuckles. It began primarily as an alteration of the[CR]musical configuration of that game to to more closely resemble that of the[CR]original Sonic 3. It also contains bugfixes and other additional features, and[CR]provides versions of Sonic 3, Sonic and Knuckles and Blue Sphere with these[CR]same additions and fixes, essentially providing a console version of Sonic and[CR]Knuckles Collection. Additional menu options and ROM patches are available to[CR]reverse some of these changes, or make others, to provide a version to match[CR]the players own preference.[CR]==Additions (Sonic 3-ification)==[CR]==Full[CR]List of Changes and Options==[CR]===Sonic 3-ification===[CR]*Tracks for title[CR]screen, invincibility, Knuckles theme, miniboss, 1UP, Sonic 3 ending,[CR]continue/race results, and data select are the Sonic 3 versions by[CR]default.[CR]*Various music cues are flipped around to work with[CR]this:[CR]**Marble Garden 2 boss for Knuckles plays the standard zone boss[CR]theme.[CR]**Flying Battery 2 sub-boss plays the Sonic and Knuckles miniboss[CR]theme.[CR]**Hidden Palace plays Sonic 3 miniboss for Knuckles fight, Sonic and[CR]Knuckles miniboss for Emerald theft.[CR]**The Sonic 3 credits music plays[CR]during the ending before the main credits begin (replacing Sky[CR]Sanctuary)[CR]**The Blue Sphere difficulty screen now plays the Gumball Bonus[CR]music.[CR]*Many of the Sonic 3 levels use their original Sonic 3 object[CR]layouts by default, most notably Hydrocity 2 and Launch Base.[CR]**Knuckles[CR]routes in these layouts were incomplete, but additions have been made to allow[CR]them to be played through.[CR]*Sonic 1-3-style monitor behaviour - jumping[CR]under the base of a monitor will make it fall.[CR]*Music no longer fades out[CR]before the Got Through screen[CR]*Act music no longer resumes after the Got[CR]Through screen before a zone transition.[CR]*Credits music has been replaced[CR]with the Sonic 3C prototype 0517 version.[CR]*Sonic/Tails have their final[CR]Launch Base 2 boss restored, with its Sonic 3 sweeping behaviour.[CR]**The[CR]ability to hit characters out of their super form has not been[CR]reintroduced.[CR]**In a Sonic and Tails game, Tails does not appear for the[CR]final Launch Base bosses. Player 2 can press a button to make him[CR]appear.[CR]**Knuckles version is unaffected.[CR]*The Special Stage results[CR]screen for Chaos Emerald stages is now styled much more like the version from[CR]Sonic 3 alone. (The background color is white rather than grey.)[CR]*The[CR]Continue screen uses title card-style text as it did in Sonic 3, rather than[CR]end credits-style text as it did in Sonic and Knuckles.[CR]*Flying Battery[CR]shows up with its unused Sonic 3 icon in Data Select.[CR]*Mushroom Hill is now[CR]named Mushroom Valley, as it was in the Sonic 3 level select screen.[CR]*All[CR]references to "&amp; Knuckles" removed, title screen positioning realigned to[CR]original setup. Zone title cards restored to Sonic 3s style.[CR]*The logo in[CR]the all-super emeralds ending now drops in from the top of the screen as in[CR]the Sonic 3 credits[CR]*Playing as Sonic and Tails, Tails now arrives slightly[CR]later at the start of AIZ and faces right, as in Sonic 3, and cannot move[CR]until Sonic can.[CR]*The save screen for Complete mode no longer shows counts[CR]of lives and continues (though these are still saved and loaded); its format[CR]has been made more compact, like the original Sonic 3 save[CR]screen.[CR]*Emeralds on the save screen now use the Sonic 3-style flash cycle[CR]in all modes.[CR]===Features and Tweaks===[CR]*Before the original title[CR]screen appears, a game menu has been inserted to select between Sonic 3[CR]Complete, Sonic 3, Sonic and Knuckles and Blue Sphere.[CR]**Pressing B from[CR]the title screens of any of these games will return you to this game[CR]menu.[CR]*An Options menu has been provided to reconfigure many aspects of the[CR]game.[CR]**The originally-conceived zone order can be activated using the[CR]options menu, placing Flying Battery between Carnival Night and Icecap.[CR]**A[CR]"beta" palette of Flying Batterys indoor section can be put in place, which[CR]matches up with the previously unused Sonic 3 save icon.[CR]**Sonic Jams Easy[CR]and Normal modes are available, complete with their unique features and level[CR]layouts.[CR]**Music from Sonic and Knuckles Collection converted by ValleyBell[CR]can be swapped in, as can imports of Masato Nakamuras main themes from the[CR]previous games.[CR]**Many of the music changes designed to make the game more[CR]Sonic 3-like can be altered.[CR]**Level layout can be switched between Sonic 3[CR]and Sonic and Knuckles versions.[CR]**The game can be set to boot straight[CR]into one of the game modes, bypassing the game selection title[CR]screen.[CR]*Knuckles introductory cutscene now plays in Angel Island rather[CR]than Sonic and Knuckles first zone, and feeds directly into the level rather[CR]than fading out and restarting.[CR]*Tails now has an introduction sequence,[CR]continue screen, and his own colours in the results screens.[CR]*Added an[CR]extra cutscene after Launch Base, showing the Death Egg crashing, based on the[CR]Sonic and Knuckles title screen.[CR]*Player 1 in a Sonic+Tails game can now[CR]put Tails into flight mode and direct him when being carried.[CR]**This is[CR]activated as in Sonic 1 2013 (up+jump in midair).[CR]**When Tails is carrying[CR]Sonic, use up/down/left/right to direct Tails, as in the Marble Garden[CR]boss.[CR]***Alternatively, you can set the controls in this state to work as[CR]in Sonic 1 2013 through the options menu.[CR]**Unless this feature is[CR]disabled, the fire shield dash will not activate while the up button is being[CR]held, to allow the characters to connect more easily.[CR]*Super Sonic now has[CR]a full set of distinct sprites (for the default S3 look only).[CR]**Some of[CR]these are based on flamewings Sonic Classic Heroes sprites with tweaks by That[CR]One Jig; others have been drawn by Neo.[CR]*Knuckles has improved and more[CR]consistent underwater colours.[CR]*Knuckles special moves now respect[CR]underwater physics.[CR]*Hyper Sonic, Super Tails and Super/Hyper Knuckles now[CR]have distinct underwater palettes.[CR]*The Mushroom Valley demo sequence now[CR]plays as one of the Sonic 3 demos.[CR]*Sonics Angel Island intro can now be[CR]skipped using the Start button (only until Knuckles interjects).[CR]*For[CR]Super/Hyper forms to be invoked, you must press any button to jump, followed[CR]by a different button to double-jump.[CR]**To transform with debug mode[CR]enabled, you need to double-jump by pressing B while C is held down.[CR]**This[CR]allows Tails/Knuckles to play without powering up after having all[CR]emeralds.[CR]**Sonic can now transform even if he has a barrier.[CR]**Using[CR]the super transformation move while already transformed will allow you to turn[CR]back to normal.[CR]*While in super or hyper form, sped-up level music plays[CR]instead of invincibility music.[CR]*Super music changes now consistently have[CR]no effect during bosses.[CR]*Speed shoes monitors now have no effect when[CR]collected in super or hyper form.[CR]*You now need to collect 50 rings within[CR]the slot machine bonus stage itself to get a continue.[CR]**Rings lost within[CR]the bonus stage will not take away from your collection total for the[CR]continue.[CR]**You can now do this in every slot machine bonus stage.[CR]Originally, you needed to wait until a new act or lose your rings in the main[CR]level.[CR]*Added a HUD element to the Slot Machine bonus stage to show[CR]progress towards a continue.[CR]*The rotation in the slot machine bonus stage[CR]is now smoother (thanks to Cinossu).[CR]*Separate title card icons for each[CR]zone, by Neo.[CR]*After Hidden Palace, Knuckles is replaced by Robotnik on[CR]Sonics continue screen[CR]*Super/Hyper characters detransform if they are[CR]killed.[CR]*Minor alterations to the Icecap intro to maintain day-night cycle[CR]consistency.[CR]*The screen now pulls up after Carnival Night 1s miniboss, to[CR]make the signpost easier to control.[CR]*New credits font designed to better[CR]fit with the title card style.[CR]*The existing Sonic 3 and Knuckles cheats[CR]work, plus:[CR]**rightleftleftleftright on Sonic 3/Sonic and Knuckles title[CR]screen menu switches region graphics (Tails/Miles, TM[CR]signs)[CR]**leftleftrightrightleftleftleftleft on the Sonic 3 or Sonic and[CR]Knuckles title screen menu enables level select.[CR]**01 03 05 07 on sound[CR]test enables debug[CR]***With debug enabled, all restrictions on zone access[CR]and character choice are lifted, even in Sonic 3 and Sonic and Knuckles[CR]modes.[CR]**02 04 05 06 on sound test gives all Chaos Emeralds[CR]***This will[CR]not reset the status of anything done with Hidden Palace Zone/Super[CR]Emeralds[CR]**12 14 15 16 on sound test gives all super emeralds[CR]**When[CR]paused and level select is enabled, the A button now exits to different[CR]places:[CR]***1P level/Special Stage: level select[CR]***Grand Prix: GP[CR]results[CR]***Match Race: Match Race setup[CR]***Time Attack: Time Attack[CR]setup[CR]*"DEATHEGG" and "THE DOOMSDAY" changed to the more sensible "DEATH[CR]EGG" and "DOOMSDAY" in level select.[CR]*Level Select now has the Data Select[CR]background, replacing the Sonic 2 SONIC/MILES pattern.[CR]**In Sonic and[CR]Knuckles mode, the Blue Sphere background is used instead.[CR]*Added entries[CR]to Level Select for the Gumball Bonus Stage and the Hidden Palace Special[CR]Stage entryway.[CR]*Level Select has been rearranged to better reflect the[CR]actual zone arrangement.[CR]*New icons have been added to the level select[CR]screen to better display character selection.[CR]*New level select and data[CR]select font, designed to be similar in style to the title card font.[CR]**This[CR]rectifies text spacing issues when displaying the final zones in data[CR]select.[CR]*Sound effect E3 will now speed up music as if speed shoes were[CR]active when used in the level select.[CR]**E4 returns to normal speed, as does[CR]starting another track.[CR]*The sound test will always play Sonic 3 tracks[CR]from their original slots. The alternative versions can be played from entry[CR]F0 upwards.[CR]*All monitor types are now available in debug[CR]mode.[CR]===Bugfixes===[CR]*Knuckles appears in the same colours throughout[CR]the game, both in cutscenes and as a playable character.[CR]*Knuckles now[CR]fights EggRobo in Flying Battery 2.[CR]*Workaround added to Mushroom Valley 2[CR]and Sandopolis 2 bosses to prevent Knuckles from sometimes seeing Robotnik[CR]instead of the EggRobo.[CR]*You will no longer lose shields if hit from the[CR]blue spinning platforms in Marble Garden.[CR]*Knuckles is no longer blocked[CR]from his normal Carnival Night exit when arriving from above[CR]*The correct[CR]music will always resume when coming back from a special stage or bonus stage[CR](Angel Island Zone 1, IceCap Zone 1).[CR]*Fixed Knuckles being unable to jump[CR]off underwater objects[CR]*Fixed the HUD shadow colour in Angel[CR]Island.[CR]*The underwater character palette now reverts properly when Tails[CR]or Knuckles lose their super form.[CR]*When the lights go out in Carnival[CR]Night, the underwater palette also changes to reflect this (thanks to[CR]Neo).[CR]*The slot machine bonus stage now awards a continue through rings[CR]collected in the slot machine as well as around the sides.[CR]*Many player[CR]sprite and mapping issues have been fixed, and remaining Sonic 2-alike sprites[CR]have been replaced.[CR]**Thanks go to That One Jig for these sprite[CR]improvements.[CR]*Fixed a number of issues involving speed being incorrectly[CR]set when water and/or super sneakers and/or super transformations were[CR]involved (thanks to MoDule).[CR]*It is no longer possible to confuse the[CR]camera by ducking and jumping in a wrapped level, thereby moving through[CR]objects (thanks to flamewing and redhotsonic).[CR]*Rings attracted by the[CR]lightning shield are no longer confused by level wrapping (thanks to[CR]flamewing).[CR]*The lightning shield can now successfully attract rings when[CR]the player is at the extreme top or left of the level (thanks to[CR]flamewing).[CR]*Knuckles no longer shifts forward a pixel when looking[CR]up.[CR]*The boss music gives way to the act music at the end of Sandopolis 1[CR]and Lava Reef 2.[CR]*The correct music will resume after a drown timer while[CR]fighting the Hydrocity bosses.[CR]*Fixed issues with Tails flying Sonic into[CR]various objects and/or their areas of effect.[CR]*Tails carrying Sonic to the[CR]floor no longer results in Sonic being able to walk around during level[CR]results.[CR]*Fixed underwater tired animation selection for Tails carrying[CR]Sonic[CR]*Sonic will no longer gain strange physics when Tails smashes an ice[CR]block from under him.[CR]*Fixed occasional glitched graphics/animations for[CR]Sonic when Tails places him on the ground.[CR]*The camera vertical offset will[CR]now reset when Tails carries Sonic.[CR]*Fixed sprite misalignment when Tails[CR]carries Sonic in Sonic alone mode[CR]*Stopped running animation being[CR]displayed in place of victory or super transform animation when in front of a[CR]solid object[CR]*Fix for some giant rings in Mushroom Valley/Hill not[CR]appearing when continuing a save imported from Sonic 3.[CR]*Tails no longer[CR]trails along in flying animation when landing on objects (thanks to[CR]redhotsonic)[CR]*Tails tails also flash when he is invulnerable (thanks to[CR]redhotsonic)[CR]*Fixed spindash cancellation on screen boundaries and when[CR]jumping immediately (thanks to flamewing)[CR]*Tails alone no longer has extra[CR]tails in the Launch Base Zone 2 ending cutscene. [CR]*Tails tails no longer[CR]disappear while he is jumping after the credits[CR]*Fixed Super Sonic[CR]appearing in the wrong pose when dropped by Tails (visible during the final[CR]Marble Garden boss).[CR]*2P Tails is less prone to suicide before the final[CR]battles of Launch Base Zone.[CR]*Fire dashing or spindashing into the Death[CR]Egg boss area no longer causes collision issues.[CR]*In certain circumstances,[CR]it is possible to break Launch Base pipes containing water without following[CR]the water through the tube. Going offscreen would cause the water jet to be[CR]lost, rendering further progress impossible. The water jets now respawn[CR]correctly.[CR]*The initial restart locations for Act 2 of Angel Island,[CR]Hydrocity, Launch Base and Lava Reef now better reflect the act 1 finish[CR]positions, making time results more comparable.[CR]*Attached platforms and[CR]objects are removed after the Launch Base building collapses.[CR]*The capsule[CR]at the end of Hydrocity is now correctly centred for Sonic and[CR]Tails.[CR]*SONIC text is no longer backwards when the Tornado flies left[CR]during the ending.[CR]*Sonics exit from Lava Reef to Hidden Palace is now blue[CR]rather than red.[CR]*The music tempo glitch at the beginning of Doomsday has[CR]been removed.[CR]*Collecting extra lives will not increase the counter past[CR]99.[CR]*Fixed possible Marble Garden 2 boss corruption after killing a Spiker[CR]with hyper dash.[CR]*The normal super transformation sound effect is now used[CR]in Doomsday.[CR]*Fixed bugs relating to the Icecap act transition: you can no[CR]longer fly over the boss, and dying without having hit a starpost will[CR]correctly return you to the start of Icecap 1.[CR]*Fixed spring artwork[CR]occasionally not being loaded for the Gumball Bonus Stage.[CR]*It is no longer[CR]possible to gain additional lives for having 100 and 200 rings in the Lava[CR]Reef boss area if those lives were already earned earlier in act 2.[CR]*The[CR]Lava Reef and Death Egg boss areas will remember their starting timer if you[CR]die and restart (unless you die from a time over)[CR]*Robotniks bald shine on[CR]the save screen is no longer red.[CR]*The Launch Base music now only restarts[CR]once after Knuckles defeats the Act 1 boss.[CR]*Drowning timer resets when[CR]turning hyper, along with music if necessary[CR]*Knuckles no longer turns into[CR]Sonic at the end of the slot machine bonus stage.[CR]*Various double jump[CR]fixes for Sonic, mostly involving unintentionally going into a slow bubble[CR]bounce by double jumping right before a bubble shield activated.[CR]*Fixed bug[CR]where a time over would not restart the starpost timer after continuing from a[CR]game over.[CR]*Fixed final Launch Base boss code to release Sonic from the arm[CR]after the boss is defeated - this was firing in the wrong situation, making[CR]Sonic always drop to standing after clearing the boss, but leaving him stuck[CR]if Tails killed the boss while Sonic was held.[CR]*Fixed object and ring[CR]layout oddities in various zones, including the infamous double ring in Angel[CR]Island 1 and the improperly retracting spikes in Carnival Night 2.[CR]*Super[CR]Tails flickies no longer ruin the Sandopolis miniboss or the first Death Egg 2[CR]boss.[CR]*Fixed duff palette cycle when retransforming into super/hyper[CR]form[CR]*Fixed Tails using the wrong sprite when hit by the boulder in Lava[CR]Reef.[CR]*The Death Egg no longer appears in the background of Lava Reef when[CR]playing as Knuckles.[CR]*Tails will drop out of flight mode if he is tired and[CR]hits a diagonal spring in Carnival Night, preventing him from getting[CR]stuck.[CR]*Insta-shield now deflects projectiles, as appears to have been[CR]intended all along[CR]*Tails flight now only deflects projectiles if they hit[CR]his tails. (Previously he could deflect anywhere, but only if[CR]falling.)[CR]*Prevented super transformation during snowboard[CR]sequence[CR]*Fixed odd palette on HUD lives numbers in some levels[CR]*Fixed[CR]issue with continues not being saved unless a special stage is[CR]completed[CR]*Fixed occasional misalignment of continue screen[CR]*Fixed wrong[CR]tiles on Continue screen if you hit Game Over with Super/Hyper Sonic[CR]*Fire[CR]sprites no longer appear underwater in Angel Island[CR]*It is no longer[CR]possible to repeatedly double-jump in the Hydrocity fan tubes[CR]*Incorrect[CR]grabber arm sprite on DEZ final boss fixed - now uses the latched rather than[CR]open variant.[CR]*Fixed jittering screen lock after Marble Garden 1[CR]miniboss[CR]*Workaround added to avoid occasional loss of music track change[CR]if requested during the 1up sting.[CR]*Added MoDules bugfixes for jumping out[CR]of shallow water, roll jump hitbox and Tails camera height[CR]*Fixed a number[CR]of cases where Sonic or Tails would stay in midair and gain odd physics if a[CR]pillar was smashed from beneath them[CR]*Stopped 2P Tails from being able to[CR]misfire the cannon at the end of CNZ.[CR]*Tails now shows his full victory[CR]animation on the Blue Sphere difficulty screen.[CR]*Fixed players standing in[CR]the ground during their victory animations if they were previously[CR]rolling.[CR]*Fixed control improperly unlocking if a hurt player falls in a[CR]Carnival Night cannon[CR]*Sonic and Tails can no longer use super powers to[CR]break the switch back into Knuckles route at the end of Launch Base.[CR]*In a[CR]Sonic alone game, Tails no longer gets stuck jumping on the ground after[CR]flying Sonic in.[CR]*Fixed rare issue where the AIZ2 cutscene bridge collapse[CR]would trigger too soon.[CR]*Fixed a rare situation that could freeze the[CR]player in place if transforming just as the timer expires (thanks to[CR]flamewing).[CR]*Fixed Knuckles socks and pink palette in continue icon in[CR]Super Emerald special stage results[CR]*Fixed wrong colours on Super Emerald 6[CR](the leftmost one) as Sonic or Tails in Special Stage results[CR]*The Sky[CR]Sanctuary main melody is no longer muted by ring collection.[CR]*It is no[CR]longer impossible for Knuckles to defeat the Death Egg miniboss.[CR]*Fixed[CR]sprite misalignment on Flying Battery midboss and Knuckles waving off[CR]animation in Sky Sanctuary[CR]*Fixed CNZ vacuum tube whose art was pointing in[CR]the wrong direction.[CR]*Follower Tails now behaves more sensibly at the end[CR]of Mushroom Valley/Hill.[CR]*Fixed abrupt/unsynced camera/music transition at[CR]the end of Sandopolis 2.[CR]*The rumbling sound during the closing sequence of[CR]Flying Battery is no longer missing when restarting from the final[CR]starpost.[CR]*The falling animation is used after the Mushroom Valley/Hill[CR]Knuckles cutscene instead of the walking animation.[CR]*Fixed odd palette[CR]cycle stop point on Super/Hyper Knuckles during his ending.[CR]*Fixed Sonic[CR]incorrectly appearing as Hyper Sonic briefly during the ending when he[CR]shouldnt be able to.[CR]*Jump height off Hydrocity rotating cylinders is now[CR]appropriately reduced when underwater.[CR]*Level music no longer double-[CR]restarts before final boss in Death Egg[CR]*Competition music no longer[CR]restarts while navigating competition menus.[CR]*Debug: Hyper Knuckles can now[CR]wall smash when turned hyper by a monitor.[CR]*Debug: Tails ring counter now[CR]falls in Doomsday.[CR]*Debug: Characters other than Sonic appear correctly in[CR]Doomsday.[CR]*Debug: Knuckles exits Doomsday to the title screen instead of a[CR]broken Sonic ending.[CR]*Debug: Going into debug when dead now restarts object[CR]processing.[CR]*Debug: The debug cursor now respects screen[CR]locking.[CR]===Changes specific to Blue Sphere===[CR]*Tails has been added as[CR]a playable character in Blue Sphere.[CR]*While playing a special stage through[CR]Blue Sphere, pressing B while paused will return to the Blue Sphere select[CR]screen.[CR]*Pressing B on the Blue Sphere menu screen will now return to the[CR]title screen. Your progress will be retained until you reset or turn off the[CR]game.[CR]===Changes specific to Sonic 3===[CR]*The included Sonic 3 runs[CR]completely on top of Sonic 3 Completes engine, and hence inherits all relevant[CR]improvements from Sonic 3 and Knuckles and Sonic 3 Complete, while retaining[CR]its own layouts, save files, bonus stage structure, etc.[CR]* The credits list[CR]used is from Sonic 3 and Knuckles to reflect the integration of the games in[CR]this collection.[CR]*On the "Try Again" ending screen, the emeralds juggled by[CR]Knuckles are now coloured correctly.[CR]*The Death Eggs behaviour at the end[CR]of the game has been slightly altered to match the complete story.[CR]*Tails[CR]retains his unique game clear icons on the save screen.[CR]*If no saves are[CR]present for Sonic 3 mode, the game will attempt to import data from the[CR]complete game where appropriate.[CR]===Changes specific to Sonic and[CR]Knuckles===[CR]* The credits list used is from Sonic 3 and Knuckles to reflect[CR]the integration of the games in this collection.[CR]===Options===[CR]====Menu[CR]Options====[CR]*Skip the game select screen and start one of the individual[CR]games immediately on boot up.[CR]*Play through the "Easy" and "Normal"[CR]versions of the game introduced in Sonic Jam.[CR]*Use the full set of Sonic 3[CR]or Sonic and Knuckles level layouts.[CR]*Play Flying Battery in its original[CR]position between Carnival Night and Icecap, and/or with an earlier colour[CR]scheme design.[CR]*Disable the added ability for Sonic to control Tails[CR]flight, or swap the carrying controls for those used in Sonic 1[CR]2013.[CR]*Choose between the various soundtrack options for individual tracks,[CR]including Sonic and Knuckles Collection and Nakamura themes, or configure the[CR]game to use different soundtracks in each mode.[CR]*Go back to using the[CR]invincibility music for super/hyper transformations, or use the unused PC[CR]track for this purpose.[CR]*Disable all music (useful to set a gameplay video[CR]to an alternative soundtrack)[CR]*Change the moves and abilities available, so[CR]that the game plays more like other classic Sonic games.[CR]*Use the original[CR]Sonic 3 and Knuckles double-jump/transformation button setup (any double-jump[CR]invokes a super form transformation, if available, unless Sonic has a shield,[CR]which prevents transformation).[CR]*Disable the ability to cancel out of super[CR]or hyper forms.[CR]===Known Issues in the Current Release===[CR]*The menu[CR]setting to change the S3 Credits music to the Sonic and Knuckles Collection[CR]version does not affect the final credits if the customiser patch is used to[CR]place this track in that position. This will be resolved in a future release.[CR]This does not affect anything in plain, uncustomised builds.[CR]*Changes made[CR]in the Options menu will not be saved to or loaded from SRAM when using the[CR]Regen emulator. This is seemingly due to Regen limiting the size of SRAM and[CR]does not affect flashcarts or any other tested emulators. It is still possible[CR]to use the menus if desired, but changes will not be saved after a hard reset[CR]or closing the emulator. Savestates may be used to preserve selected[CR]options.[CR]*The emulators Generator and Genesis Plus (non-GX) appear to treat[CR]banked SRAM incorrectly, leading to part of the game becoming corrupted. The[CR]effects vary from build to build, as the damage is isolated to a particular[CR]ROM location which contains different data in different versions. As of[CR]version 130810, this causes Mushroom Valley to be severely damaged and[CR]essentially unplayable. Once again, this issue does not affect usage on real[CR]hardware or other tested emulators. If you like Genesis Plus, note that[CR]emulators based on Genesis Plus GX do not exhibit this issue.[CR]*Many known[CR]issues in Sonic 3 and Knuckles continue to be present.</plot>
    <genre>Sound,Levels</genre>
    <studio>Tiddles</studio>
    <snapshot1>iGB9s28.png</snapshot1>
    <snapshot2>FJnW5LN.png</snapshot2>
  </game>
  <game name="Sonic - Zeta Overdrive (X)">
    <description>Sonic - Zeta Overdrive (X)</description>
    <title_clean>Sonic - Zeta Overdrive</title_clean>
    <rom name="EmuROMHacks/ROM_Hacks_1.zip/Genesis%2FSonic%20-%20Zeta%20Overdrive%20%28X%29.bin" size="2359296"/>
    <plot>This is a hack of Sonic the Hedgehog 2 for the Sega Genesis. The hack features[CR]new level layout, new palette, new music, some new artwork, adds new moves for[CR]characters, and also adds Bean the Dynamite as a playable character. A[CR]exhaustive movelist is in the readme. The patch is in xdelta format. The ROM[CR]should be in BIN format.[CR]Read Me:[CR]Sonic Zeta Overdrive[CR]Credits:[CR]Mikel, various[CR]Sonic Zeta Overdrive is a hack of Sonic the Hedgehog 2 for[CR]the Sega Mega Drive.[CR]==Features==[CR]*New level layouts.[CR]*New[CR]palettes.[CR]*New music.[CR]*11 levels.[CR]*Sonic 2 clone driver.[CR]*Flying[CR]for Tails.[CR]*Super peel-out, and jump dash for Sonic.[CR]*New level[CR]art.[CR]*Bean the Dynamite as a playable character.[CR]==Controls==[CR]===For[CR]All Characters===[CR]*Down + A/B/C - spin dash, used for rolling at fast[CR]speeds, Press any button to increase Speed.[CR]===For Sonic Only===[CR]*Up +[CR]A/B/C - super peel-out, used for running at fast speeds, unlike the Spin Dash,[CR]you can only press any button once, since the Peel-Out is not[CR]chargeable.[CR]*Jump + A/B/C - jump dash.[CR]===For Tails Only==[CR]*Jump +[CR]A/B/C - flying, fly at anytime, but dont fly for too long, flying for too long[CR]can cause Tails to get tired.[CR]*Jump + A/B/C if underwater - swimming, swim[CR]at anytime, but dont swim for too long, swimming for too long can cause Tails[CR]to get tired.[CR]===For Bean Only===[CR]*B - high speed dash, Bean can do a[CR]instant spindash at the touch of the B Button.[CR]==Known Bugs==[CR]*When you[CR]are playing this hack on real hardware, you may notice when you press down[CR]while standing, the game will crash, but not the music.[CR]*When you are[CR]fighting the MTZ3 boss as Tails, hitting the boss while flying can cause the[CR]boss to explode like an enemy, and the level will not be completable with[CR]Tails.[CR]*When you are fighting the ARZ2 boss as Tails, Eggman cannot get hit[CR]from the bottom of the eggpod.[CR]==Credits==[CR]*Nineko - for xm2smps,[CR]xm3smps, the boss tune from Granada, the F-Zero ending theme, and the boss[CR]theme from Sonic 2 Master System.[CR]*Tweaker - for the Sonic 2 Clone[CR]Driver.[CR]*Puto - for xm4smps, and Bridge Zones music from Sonic 1 Master[CR]System.[CR]*roxahris - for the Metal Gear 2 - Frequency 140.85[CR]tune.[CR]*Xenowhirl - for the Sonic 2 2007 Disassembly.[CR]*Ollie, JcFerggy,[CR]DNXDelta, ShadowFire and the SCAA - for compressed art.[CR]*Dr. Kylstien - for[CR]the Peel-Out code.[CR]*SMTP and drx - for the Tails Flying Code.[CR]*Selbi -[CR]for the Jump Dash code.[CR]*Stealth - for SonED2.[CR]*sonichackman1/steven the[CR]human, Peruant, and UtopiaUK - for beta testing.[CR]*UtopiaUK - for the MTZ1,[CR]MTZ2 layouts, and the MTZ Background art.[CR]*DalekSam - for many songs that I[CR]converted from XMs, such as the Sonic CD Speed Shoes music, and Gravity[CR]Bettles theme from Mega Man X3.[CR]*DeoxysKyorge - for the Bean sprites that I[CR]built upon by adding more sprites.[CR]*Xeric - for the Bean sprite sheet that[CR]he contributed on, and for Beans life icon from that sprite sheet.</plot>
    <genre>Graphics,Sound,Levels,Text,Gameplay</genre>
    <studio>Mikel</studio>
    <snapshot1>0MDUQwi.png</snapshot1>
    <snapshot2>yJ6Qj8u.png</snapshot2>
  </game>
  <game name="Sonic 1 - Egg Factory Zone (v.1.3)">
    <description>Sonic 1 - Egg Factory Zone (v.1.3)</description>
    <title_clean>Sonic 1 - Egg Factory Zone</title_clean>
    <rom name="EmuROMHacks/ROM_Hacks_1.zip/Genesis%2FSonic%201%20-%20Egg%20Factory%20Zone%20%28v.1.3%29.bin" size="1048576"/>
  </game>
  <game name="Sonic 1 Megahack - Ultra Edition (v.1.0)">
    <description>Sonic 1 Megahack - Ultra Edition (v.1.0)</description>
    <title_clean>Sonic 1 Megahack - Ultra Edition</title_clean>
    <rom name="EmuROMHacks/ROM_Hacks_1.zip/Genesis%2FSonic%201%20Megahack%20-%20Ultra%20Edition%20%28v.1.0%29.gen" size="4194304"/>
  </game>
  <game name="Sonic 2 - Advanced Edit (v.3.0 Beta)">
    <description>Sonic 2 - Advanced Edit (v.3.0 Beta)</description>
    <title_clean>Sonic 2 - Advanced Edit</title_clean>
    <rom name="EmuROMHacks/ROM_Hacks_1.zip/Genesis%2FSonic%202%20-%20Advanced%20Edit%20%28v.3.0%20Beta%29.bin" size="1349194"/>
    <plot>Take a look on what could be the most time-consuming hack ever. Completely new[CR]levels to explore makes this hack innovative. Also new graphics have been[CR]added into this large hack. A 3.0 with only 3 levels is available on Sonic[CR]Retro.</plot>
    <genre>Graphics,Levels</genre>
    <studio>rika_chou</studio>
    <snapshot1>zYnyC31.png</snapshot1>
    <snapshot2>uG85tqd.png</snapshot2>
  </game>
  <game name="Sonic 2 - Delta (X)">
    <description>Sonic 2 - Delta (X)</description>
    <title_clean>Sonic 2 - Delta</title_clean>
    <rom name="EmuROMHacks/ROM_Hacks_1.zip/Genesis%2FSonic%202%20-%20Delta%20%28X%29.bin" size="2097152"/>
    <plot>Sonic 2 Delta is one of those rare hacks that is actually better than the[CR]original game. The original zones, with a few exceptions, are untouched; this[CR]hack restores zones that were cut during development. While two of these zones[CR](Wood and Hidden Palace) are available in the prototype ROM floating around[CR]the net, they're in an unfinished and nearly unplayable state. One zone, Dust[CR]Hill, was restored based on a single mock-up screenshot; Winter Hill was based[CR]on an interview. Even Casino Night, which received a makeover since its beta[CR]state, has been restored to its former (very pink) look. The only zone that is[CR]incomplete in this hack is Genocide City, which is merely Chemical Plant with[CR]a different background and palette. Enemies from early revisions have also[CR]been restored In addition to restoring cut zones, the hack adds a few new[CR]features: The ring counter now shows how many rings remain in a zone, the[CR]level select menu has been updated to allow access to the new zones, some[CR]Sonic 3 graphics have been ported, and even Knuckles has been ported from[CR]Sonic and Knuckles! This is one of those hacks that simply must be played, its[CR]only flaws are the somewhat amateur-feeling level designs for the new zones[CR]and the fact it does not work on the real Genesis hardware. The latest version[CR]is based off the revision 02 which was extracted from the Sonic Compilation[CR]for Sega Genesis. The ROM is called Sonic the Hedgehog 2 (W) (REVSC02). The[CR]ROM should be in BIN format. The patch is in xdelta format due to shifted data[CR]resulting in IPS patches containing original code. Levels * Green Hill Zone:[CR]Sonic the Hedgehog level. * Emerald Hill Zone: Prototype layout elements and[CR]Coconut monkey enemies are replaced with the scrapped Snail enemies. * Winter[CR]Hill Zone: Scrapped level. * Wood Zone: The graphics are similar to what is[CR]seen in the Simon Wai prototype. Scrapped level. * Dust Hill Zone: Graphics[CR]similar to those featured in the mockup screenshot that was featured in many[CR]magazines. Scrapped level. * Chemical Plant Zone: Small minor alterations were[CR]made, such as the loops having slanted corners as seen in prototype media. *[CR]Labyrinth Zone: Sonic the Hedgehog level. * Neo Green Hill Zone: Prototype[CR]name, and music. * Star Light Zone: Sonic the Hedgehog level. * Casino Night[CR]Zone: Redesigned to look like the prototype level which had lots of pink. *[CR]Marble Zone: Sonic the Hedgehog level. * Hill Top Zone * Spring Yard Zone:[CR]Sonic the Hedgehog level. * Mystic Cave Zone * Hidden Palace Zone: Graphics[CR]and layout are the same as in the Nick Arcade prototype. Scrapped level * Oil[CR]Ocean Zone: Redesigned to look like the prototype. Features ride-able balls[CR]which were found in the betas. * Metropolis Zone * Genocide City Zone:[CR]Scrapped level. * Scrap Brain Sonic the Hedgehog level. * Final Zone: Sonic[CR]the Hedgehog level. * Sky Fortress Zone * Sky Chase Zone * Death Egg Zone:[CR]Three rings added to the beginning of the level. V.25 * Objects now uses Sonic[CR]3/K Style Status Table ($4A size). * Level layouts uses Y indexed like Sonic[CR]3/K. (Some improvements on tiles loading). * Level Select Menu now Has[CR]separated pages for Sonic 1 and Sonic 2 Levels. * Fixed some bugs from[CR]previous version, like rotating pallete for Sonic in Sonic 1 Special Stage. *[CR]All objects was manually edited to new SST. * Improved some code (ex:[CR]Centisecond now uses a table, previous versions uses divs).</plot>
    <genre>Graphics,Sound,Levels,Text</genre>
    <studio>Esrael</studio>
    <snapshot1>BTRBUB1.png</snapshot1>
    <snapshot2>RXgYXe1.png</snapshot2>
  </game>
  <game name="Sonic 2 -Return of Shadow (SHC 2015 Build)">
    <description>Sonic 2 -Return of Shadow (SHC 2015 Build)</description>
    <title_clean>Sonic 2 -Return of Shadow</title_clean>
    <rom name="EmuROMHacks/ROM_Hacks_1.zip/Genesis%2FSonic%202%20-Return%20of%20Shadow%20%28SHC%202015%20Build%29.bin" size="3765328"/>
    <plot>This is a hack of Sonic the Hedgehog for the Sega Genesis. It places the main[CR]character at the end of the level with the objective to work their way through[CR]to the beginning. Levels take on a different feeling as the player must work[CR]their way left to the start of the levels. Levels have been redesigned to[CR]allow backtracking. The patch is in xdelta format due to shifted data[CR]resulting in IPS patches containing original code. The ROM should be in BIN[CR]format.</plot>
    <genre>Gameplay</genre>
    <studio>carretero</studio>
    <snapshot1>0GO8jQQ.png</snapshot1>
    <snapshot2>sukgVKC.png</snapshot2>
  </game>
  <game name="Sonic 2 Delta (Rev 0.24a)">
    <description>Sonic 2 Delta (Rev 0.24a)</description>
    <title_clean>Sonic 2 Delta</title_clean>
    <rom name="EmuROMHacks/ROM_Hacks_1.zip/Genesis%2FSonic%202%20Delta%20%28Rev%200.24a%29.bin" size="2097152"/>
    <plot>Sonic 2 Delta is one of those rare hacks that is actually better than the[CR]original game. The original zones, with a few exceptions, are untouched; this[CR]hack restores zones that were cut during development. While two of these zones[CR](Wood and Hidden Palace) are available in the prototype ROM floating around[CR]the net, they're in an unfinished and nearly unplayable state. One zone, Dust[CR]Hill, was restored based on a single mock-up screenshot; Winter Hill was based[CR]on an interview. Even Casino Night, which received a makeover since its beta[CR]state, has been restored to its former (very pink) look. The only zone that is[CR]incomplete in this hack is Genocide City, which is merely Chemical Plant with[CR]a different background and palette. Enemies from early revisions have also[CR]been restored In addition to restoring cut zones, the hack adds a few new[CR]features: The ring counter now shows how many rings remain in a zone, the[CR]level select menu has been updated to allow access to the new zones, some[CR]Sonic 3 graphics have been ported, and even Knuckles has been ported from[CR]Sonic and Knuckles! This is one of those hacks that simply must be played, its[CR]only flaws are the somewhat amateur-feeling level designs for the new zones[CR]and the fact it does not work on the real Genesis hardware. The latest version[CR]is based off the revision 02 which was extracted from the Sonic Compilation[CR]for Sega Genesis. The ROM is called Sonic the Hedgehog 2 (W) (REVSC02). The[CR]ROM should be in BIN format. The patch is in xdelta format due to shifted data[CR]resulting in IPS patches containing original code. Levels * Green Hill Zone:[CR]Sonic the Hedgehog level. * Emerald Hill Zone: Prototype layout elements and[CR]Coconut monkey enemies are replaced with the scrapped Snail enemies. * Winter[CR]Hill Zone: Scrapped level. * Wood Zone: The graphics are similar to what is[CR]seen in the Simon Wai prototype. Scrapped level. * Dust Hill Zone: Graphics[CR]similar to those featured in the mockup screenshot that was featured in many[CR]magazines. Scrapped level. * Chemical Plant Zone: Small minor alterations were[CR]made, such as the loops having slanted corners as seen in prototype media. *[CR]Labyrinth Zone: Sonic the Hedgehog level. * Neo Green Hill Zone: Prototype[CR]name, and music. * Star Light Zone: Sonic the Hedgehog level. * Casino Night[CR]Zone: Redesigned to look like the prototype level which had lots of pink. *[CR]Marble Zone: Sonic the Hedgehog level. * Hill Top Zone * Spring Yard Zone:[CR]Sonic the Hedgehog level. * Mystic Cave Zone * Hidden Palace Zone: Graphics[CR]and layout are the same as in the Nick Arcade prototype. Scrapped level * Oil[CR]Ocean Zone: Redesigned to look like the prototype. Features ride-able balls[CR]which were found in the betas. * Metropolis Zone * Genocide City Zone:[CR]Scrapped level. * Scrap Brain Sonic the Hedgehog level. * Final Zone: Sonic[CR]the Hedgehog level. * Sky Fortress Zone * Sky Chase Zone * Death Egg Zone:[CR]Three rings added to the beginning of the level. V.25 * Objects now uses Sonic[CR]3/K Style Status Table ($4A size). * Level layouts uses Y indexed like Sonic[CR]3/K. (Some improvements on tiles loading). * Level Select Menu now Has[CR]separated pages for Sonic 1 and Sonic 2 Levels. * Fixed some bugs from[CR]previous version, like rotating pallete for Sonic in Sonic 1 Special Stage. *[CR]All objects was manually edited to new SST. * Improved some code (ex:[CR]Centisecond now uses a table, previous versions uses divs).</plot>
    <genre>Graphics,Sound,Levels,Text</genre>
    <studio>Esrael</studio>
    <snapshot1>BTRBUB1.png</snapshot1>
    <snapshot2>RXgYXe1.png</snapshot2>
  </game>
  <game name="Sonic 2 Retro Remix (SAGE 2011)">
    <description>Sonic 2 Retro Remix (SAGE 2011)</description>
    <title_clean>Sonic 2 Retro Remix</title_clean>
    <rom name="EmuROMHacks/ROM_Hacks_1.zip/Genesis%2FSonic%202%20Retro%20Remix%20%28SAGE%202011%29.bin" size="1748212"/>
  </game>
  <game name="Sonic 2 XL (v.1.0)">
    <description>Sonic 2 XL (v.1.0)</description>
    <title_clean>Sonic 2 XL</title_clean>
    <rom name="EmuROMHacks/ROM_Hacks_1.zip/Genesis%2FSonic%202%20XL%20%28v.1.0%29.bin" size="4194304"/>
    <plot>This is a hack which adds levels that were scrapped from Sonic the Hedgehog 2[CR]for Sega Genesis. The levels in the hack are listed below: * Emerald Hill Zone[CR]* Chemical Plant Zone * Aquatic Ruin Zone * Casino Night Zone * Hill Top Zone[CR]* Wood Zone: (scrapped from final release) * Dust Hill Zone: This version[CR]switches between both desert and winter settings. It's probably meant to be a[CR]fusion of Dust Hill Zone and the Winter level. (scrapped from final release) *[CR]Oil Ocean Zone * Genocide City Zone: Original graphics. (scrapped from final[CR]release) * Hidden Palace Zone: (scrapped from final release) * Metropolis Zone[CR]* Sky Chase Zone * Wing Fortress Zone * Death Egg Zone: (original level) The[CR]archive contains two patches, one for Sonic and Tails, and one for Knuckles as[CR]playable characters. The patch is in xdelta format due to shifted data[CR]resulting in IPS patches containing original code. The ROM should be in BIN[CR]format.[CR]Read Me:[CR]Sonic 2 Long Version[CR]Credits - Main Programer:[CR]Sonic Hachelle-Bee, Tile and Level Design: Esrael[CR]Sonic 2 Long Version is a[CR]more complete version of Sonic 2, which makes it somewhat similar to Sonic 2[CR]Delta. This hack features four levels originally scrapped during Sonic 2s[CR]development. Few levels have been changed, four are added. This hack was[CR]written in hex, without the aid of any special hacking programs, because the[CR]creator uses a Mac, and no hacking tools had been released on that platform at[CR]the time of development.[CR]==Levels==[CR]In order according to the level[CR]select menu, Sonic 2 Long Versions levels include:[CR]*Emerald Hill[CR]Zone[CR]*Chemical Plant Zone[CR]*Aquatic Ruin Zone[CR]*Casino Night[CR]Zone[CR]*Hill Top Zone[CR]*Wood Zone: The graphics are similar to what is seen[CR]in the Simon Wai prototype. It uses different background music (2 player[CR]Emerald Hill Zone). The boss is the same as Aquatic Ruin Zones boss, but the[CR]stone columns are replaced with wooden totem poles and an extra pit has been[CR]added.[CR]*Mystic Cave Zone[CR]*Dust Hill Zone: Uses graphics similar to the[CR]mockup screenshot of Dust Hill Zone which was featured in many magazines. This[CR]version switches between both desert and winter settings. Its probably meant[CR]to be a fusion of Dust Hill Zone and the Winter level. The BGM used is from 2[CR]player Mystic Cave Zone. The Emerald Hill Zone boss is reused for this level[CR]with no alterations, other than the animal ribs on the ground which act as[CR]spikes.[CR]*Oil Ocean Zone[CR]*Genocide City Zone: The graphics used are[CR]completely original to a Sonic game. The level has a night time setting with[CR]water on the bottom to replicate an underground city sewer. The BGM is[CR]different than what was on the Nick Arcade prototype (it is in fact the 2[CR]player Casino Night Zone). This level is actually only one act repeated twice,[CR]with a boss at the end of Act 2. The Chemical Plant Zone boss is reused with[CR]no alterations made to him.[CR]*Hidden Palace Zone: The graphics and layout[CR]are the same as those found in the Nick Arcade prototype. The BGM used is the[CR]same that was used in the Final version of Sonic 2. The Mystic Cave Zone boss[CR]is reused with no alterations made.[CR]*Metropolis Zone[CR]*Sky Chase[CR]Zone[CR]*Wing Fortress Zone[CR]*Death Egg Zone: Act 1 and Act 2 use the exact[CR]level layout and graphics from Chemical Plant Zone, but with a space[CR]background. Act 3 is Act 1 of the released version.</plot>
    <genre>Graphics,Levels</genre>
    <studio>Sonic Hachelle-Bee</studio>
    <snapshot1>oYCebTq.png</snapshot1>
    <snapshot2>xnsfxBK.png</snapshot2>
  </game>
  <game name="Sonic 3 &amp;amp; Knuckles - Master Edition 2 (Extra Mode)">
    <description>Sonic 3 &amp;amp; Knuckles - Master Edition 2 (Extra Mode)</description>
    <title_clean>Sonic 3 &amp;amp; Knuckles - Master Edition 2</title_clean>
    <rom name="EmuROMHacks/ROM_Hacks_1.zip/Genesis%2FSonic%203%20%26%20Knuckles%20-%20Master%20Edition%202%20%28Extra%20Mode%29.bin" size="3317958"/>
  </game>
  <game name="Sonic 3 &amp;amp; Knuckles - Master Edition 2 (v.2.4)">
    <description>Sonic 3 &amp;amp; Knuckles - Master Edition 2 (v.2.4)</description>
    <title_clean>Sonic 3 &amp;amp; Knuckles - Master Edition 2</title_clean>
    <rom name="EmuROMHacks/ROM_Hacks_1.zip/Genesis%2FSonic%203%20%26%20Knuckles%20-%20Master%20Edition%202%20%28v.2.4%29.bin" size="4194304"/>
  </game>
  <game name="Sonic 4-in-1 (SHC2016 Build)">
    <description>Sonic 4-in-1 (SHC2016 Build)</description>
    <title_clean>Sonic 4-in-1</title_clean>
    <rom name="EmuROMHacks/ROM_Hacks_1.zip/Genesis%2FSonic%204-in-1%20%28SHC2016%20Build%29.bin" size="6291456"/>
    <plot>This is a hack that fixes some bugs in the original Sonic the Hedgehog for[CR]Genesis. Refer to the Readme for details on what was fixed. Make sure you use[CR]a clean ROM. The project contains two patches: one for the US/EU version and[CR]the other has changes from the Japanese version. Only one patch should be[CR]applied, and the original ROM to apply them to must be the US/EU version for[CR]both.[CR]Read Me:[CR]SONIC 1 BUGFIX[CR]+-+-+-+-+-+-+-[CR]By[CR]lory1990[CR]November 14th, 2016[CR]Version[CR]1.0[CR]=======================================[CR]OVERVIEW[CR]=======================================[CR]Refer[CR]to the changelog below for the list of all the bug fixes. I used the various[CR]guides on Sonic Retro[CR]so credit goes to the people who posted them, and[CR]those who found and fixed the bugs. Heres the[CR]link:[CR]http://info.sonicretro.org/SCHG_How-[CR]to:Guide[CR]=======================================[CR]HOW TO APPLY THE[CR]PATCHES[CR]=======================================[CR]The patches are in IPS[CR]format. To apply them, use a program such as Lunar IPS. [CR]One patch is for[CR]the US/EU version, while the other contains changes from the Japanese version.[CR]You need to use one patch only; if you want to use the other one, make[CR]sure to use a clean ROM.[CR]The original ROM to apply the patches to is the[CR]US/European version of Sonic the Hedgehog, even for the rev1 patch. [CR]If[CR]your ROM has the .smd extension, you need a program to convert it to .bin[CR]format as the .smd one contains[CR]an extra header. To be sure you have the[CR]right version of the original ROM, you need a program such [CR]as RomHasher to[CR]determine if the info is the same as that in the Rom/Iso Information field[CR]found in the main page for[CR]this[CR]hack.[CR]=======================================[CR]CHANGELOG[CR]=======================================[CR]v1.0[CR]----[CR]-[CR]Fixed crash that happens when looking down at the end of act 1 and 2 of[CR]Labyrinth Zone.[CR]- Now the Press Start Button text appears on the title[CR]screen.[CR]- Fixed level order in the Level Select menu.[CR]- Now youre[CR]correctly awarded 100 points instead of 10 when hitting the 100 point [CR]marker after the signpost at the end of the level.[CR] [CR]- Fixed[CR]disappearance of scattered rings for levels that have vertical wrapping.[CR]-[CR]Lost rings shared the same timer before disappearing. If you lost the[CR]rings[CR] while there were others scattered previously, these will stay around[CR]longer[CR] until the newly scattered rings disappeared. Now every lost ring is[CR]independent.[CR] [CR]- Fixed Sonic using his walking animation while jumping[CR]or drowning when standing[CR] next to some objects.[CR] [CR]- Fixed drowning[CR]bugs when Sonic gets hurt.[CR]- Fixed Sonic disappearing when he dies and ends[CR]up above the top boundary of the level.[CR]- Fixed timer HUD not blinking at[CR]the 9th minute when you have rings.[CR]- Fixed Level Select graphics bug.[CR]-[CR]Sonic no longer takes damage from spikes when hes temporarily[CR]invulnerable.[CR]- Fixed scattered rings physics when underwater.[CR]- Fixed[CR]physics when Sonic gets into water in hurt state.[CR]- Fixed Sonics jump[CR]height being really low when jumping out of shallow[CR]water.[CR]=======================================[CR]CREDITS[CR]=======================================[CR]-[CR]Members of Sonic Retro for all the fixes.</plot>
    <genre>Gameplay</genre>
    <studio>lory1990</studio>
    <snapshot1>S5c7ACo.png</snapshot1>
    <snapshot2>ovLEOMe.png</snapshot2>
  </game>
  <game name="Sonic Bash! (v.2.0)">
    <description>Sonic Bash! (v.2.0)</description>
    <title_clean>Sonic Bash!</title_clean>
    <rom name="EmuROMHacks/ROM_Hacks_1.zip/Genesis%2FSonic%20Bash%21%20%28v.2.0%29.bin" size="524288"/>
  </game>
  <game name="Sonic Boom (Demo)">
    <description>Sonic Boom (Demo)</description>
    <title_clean>Sonic Boom</title_clean>
    <rom name="EmuROMHacks/ROM_Hacks_1.zip/Genesis%2FSonic%20Boom%20%28Demo%29.bin" size="1506720"/>
  </game>
  <game name="Sonic ERaZor (v.5.0)">
    <description>Sonic ERaZor (v.5.0)</description>
    <title_clean>Sonic ERaZor</title_clean>
    <rom name="EmuROMHacks/ROM_Hacks_1.zip/Genesis%2FSonic%20ERaZor%20%28v.5.0%29.bin" size="1029703"/>
    <plot>This is a hack of Sonic the Hedgehog for the Sega Genesis. It redesigns many[CR]aspects of the original and adds new content. There are various cutscenes that[CR]play at various parts of the game. Levels are redesigned: there's new[CR]palettes, some new graphics, new music, new level names. Some new features are[CR]available such as respawn points after falling into a pit, rings expelling[CR]from enemies, and many other changes the author of the hack wants people to[CR]discover on their own. The patch is in xdelta format. The ROM should be in BIN[CR]format. 5th release * Updated all bosses! -- Added a hit counter. -- The Scar[CR]Night Place Bomb Boss is now the big one from Sonic CD. * 200% more[CR]explosions! -- Also improved camera shaking a lot. * Atmospheric Mode has been[CR]replaced with Nonstop Inhuman Mode, and it unlocks after finishing the game. *[CR]Put platforms over the tubes in the overworld so you can no longer[CR]accidentally fall into them. (Thanks to MarkeyJester!) * Revamped Crabmeat[CR]Boss music. (Thanks to Spanner!) * Story and tutorial texts have been edited.[CR](Thanks to Kaidan and Abcron!) * Bunch of other fixes and small changes, but[CR]nothing really noteworthy... 6th release * Uberhub Place added. * Minor bugs[CR]fixed.[CR]Read Me:[CR]Sonic ERaZor[CR]Credits: Selbi[CR]Thanks:[CR]MarkeyJester, vladikcomper, DalekSam, SOTI, Eduardo Knuckles[CR]Sonic ERaZor[CR]is a hack of Sonic the Hedgehog (16-bit). This hack is unlike many other[CR]hacks, featuring a heavy in-game story line, unique challenges, and never seen[CR]before gameplay mechanics. These elements are often somehow related to[CR]explosions, which is why this hack is sometimes called "What if Michael Bay[CR]directed Sonic 1".[CR]When first released back in early 2010, Selbi stated[CR]that this hack has no goal whatsoever and any ideas he came up with just went[CR]in. Todays releases have a lot more structure and thought out gameplay[CR]elements. The difficulty has been steadily decreased between the different[CR]versions, mostly due to some negative feedback regarding the first releases,[CR]although they all have an above average difficulty, and is therefore regarded[CR]by many as quite interesting and challenging, if not frustrating.[CR]A notable[CR]aspect about this hack is that it contains many cutscenes, chapter screens and[CR]story screens. The games first scene after the title screen is entirely a[CR]cutscene.[CR]Music list[CR]== Music list ==[CR]#81: Hockenheim-Ring - F1: Pole[CR]Position [SNES] (used in Night Hill Place)[CR]#82: Dr. Cossack Stage 2 - Mega[CR]Man 4 (used in Labyrinth Place)[CR]#83: Blades Theme - Eternal Champions (used[CR]in Ruined Place)[CR]#84: Title Screen - Mega Man IV (used in Scar Night Place[CR][Section 1])[CR]#85: Freeze Man Stage - Mega Man 7 (used in Uberhub[CR]Place)[CR]#86: Spark Mandrill - Megaman X (used in options menu)[CR]#87: Stage[CR]4-2 - Ninja Gaiden (used in Tutorial Place)[CR]#88: One up - Sonic 1[CR](unused)[CR]#89: Hidden Song - Tecmo Wrestling (used in Special Stage)[CR]#8A:[CR]Opening Sequence - Super Street Fighter 2 Turbo (used on title screen)[CR]#8B:[CR]Ending (Remix) - Sonic 1 (unused)[CR]#8C: Chaos Angel Act 1 - Sonic Advance 3[CR](used on Green Hill Place boss)[CR]#8D: Shutdown - Pulseman (used in Finalor[CR]Place [Intro] and Bomb cutscene)[CR]#8E: Act Clear - Sonic 1 (unused)[CR]#8F:[CR]Game Over - Sonic 1 (unused)[CR]#90: Continue - Sonic 1 (used in continue[CR]screen)[CR]#91: Ending Theme - Dangerous Seed (used for invincibility power-[CR]up)[CR]#92: Drowning - Sonic 1 (used for drowning music)[CR]#93: Emerald -[CR]Sonic 1 (used in Emerald)[CR]#94: Green Hill Zone - Sonic 1 (used in Green[CR]Hill Place)[CR]#95: Kens Theme - Street Fighter 2 (used in intro[CR]cutscene)[CR]#96: Stage 7: Orn Base - Thunder Force 3 (used in Scar Night[CR]Place [Section 2])[CR]#97: Opening - Gundam Wing: Endless Duel (used in[CR]credits)[CR]#98: Boss - Sonic Advance 3 (used at Crabmeat boss)[CR]#99:[CR]Darkman [Proto Man] Stages - Mega Man 5 (used in game introduction)[CR]#9A:[CR]Whirlwind - Shinobi 3 (used in Unreal Place)[CR]#98: Boss [Alternate] - Sonic[CR]Advance 3 (used in Walking Bomb boss)[CR]#9C: Spring Yard Zone - Sonic 1[CR](unused)[CR]#9D: Push! - Zillion Push (used in ending sequence)[CR]#9E: Final[CR]Boss - Sonic 3 (used in Finalor Place [Boss])[CR]#9F: Straight Ahead - Megaman[CR]Zero 4 (used in inhuman mode [S-Monitor])</plot>
    <genre>Graphics,Sound,Levels,Text,Gameplay</genre>
    <studio>Selbi</studio>
    <snapshot1>mj611kb.png</snapshot1>
    <snapshot2>ilgoZgJ.png</snapshot2>
  </game>
  <game name="Sonic Tetris (SHC 2014 Build)">
    <description>Sonic Tetris (SHC 2014 Build)</description>
    <title_clean>Sonic Tetris</title_clean>
    <rom name="EmuROMHacks/ROM_Hacks_1.zip/Genesis%2FSonic%20Tetris%20%28SHC%202014%20Build%29.bin" size="753664"/>
    <plot>It's Tetris! And Sonic! Together for the first (and probably only) time! *[CR]Play traditional Tetris modes, such as Marathon or 40 Lines! * Play through[CR]Sonic the Hedgehog with Tetris Special Stages! * Enjoy some rad remixes of the[CR]original Sonic music! * SRAM score backup! So mash that download button and[CR]get to playing!</plot>
    <genre>Graphics,Sound,Levels,Text,Gameplay</genre>
    <studio>Crash</studio>
    <snapshot1>YcgpSid.png</snapshot1>
    <snapshot2>H6VlBw1.png</snapshot2>
  </game>
  <game name="Sonic VR (v.1.0)">
    <description>Sonic VR (v.1.0)</description>
    <title_clean>Sonic VR</title_clean>
    <rom name="EmuROMHacks/ROM_Hacks_1.zip/Genesis%2FSonic%20VR%20%28v.1.0%29.bin" size="6291456"/>
    <plot>This is a hack of Sonic the Hedgehog 2 for the Sega Genesis. It is a VR high-[CR]tech themed hack with an old-school PC looking interface used for level[CR]selecting. The graphics, level design, pallette, and music are all original.[CR]Some objects from both Sonic 1 and Sonic 2 are used. There are 40 levels[CR](.bin) available over 4 sections (filesystems). Sections 2-4 are unlocked by[CR]completing most of the levels of the previous section. When highlighting a[CR]level the levels name is displayed on the bottom. All but the last level[CR]revolves around a specific theme. For example, jumping, platforming, enemies[CR]used, etc.. Clearing a level is marked on the level select menu by a *.[CR]Pressing Start then A will exit a level. SRAM is available to allow progress[CR]to be saved and resumed later. The patch is in xdelta format. The ROM should[CR]be in BIN format.[CR]Read Me:[CR]Sonic VR[CR]Credits: ColinC10[CR]Sonic VR[CR]is a hack of Sonic the Hedgehog 2 for the Sega Mega Drive, which contains[CR]elements from both Sonic the Hedgehog and Sonic the Hedgehog 2, combined into[CR]40 mini-levels.[CR]==Gameplay==[CR]By the words of ColinC10 himself, "no[CR]rings, lives, time limits or bosses, just virtual-themed artwork and music by[CR]Anamanaguchi". The game is separated into four sections of ten levels[CR]("filesystems"). Filesystems 2 through 4 must be unlocked by completing most[CR]of the previous filesystems levels. Once the game is loaded, the player is[CR]presented with a text menu listing each filesystem. Once the player chooses a[CR]section, its background music begins to play and another menu is displayed[CR]listing each level in the form of "levelXXX.bin", with the title displayed at[CR]the bottom of the menu.[CR]Each level is based on a monochromatic high tech[CR]theme, where the player must reach an exit ring to clear the level. Most[CR]levels usually involve a good knowledge of Sonics physics and may require the[CR]player to solve a puzzle and do the right moves at the right time. Except for[CR]the last level, each level revolves around a specific theme, such as jumping[CR]or platforming, or the badniks involved (e.g. in the "debugging" level all the[CR]badniks are bugs). There are no ranks and no ending screens: clearing a level[CR]simply adds a star next to its name in the level select ("filesystem") menu,[CR]which is saved into SRAM to resume playing at a later time.[CR]If the player[CR]no longer wants to play a particular level, they can pause the game and press[CR]A to return to the level select menu.[CR]==Soundtrack and[CR]compatibility==[CR]Sonic VRs soundtrack makes use of edited PCM samples and a[CR]bank switching technique to break the "classic" limit of 4 megabytes to load[CR]the 6 necessary to store the huge amount of music data. Because of this,[CR]support in various emulators may vary (in particular the sound isnt quite[CR]right in Gens, and will not load in Gensoid), and therefore Kega Fusion is[CR]recommended.[CR]===Tracklist===[CR]All songs are performed by Anamanaguchi,[CR]but edited due to file size restraints.[CR]*Filesystem 0 - "Helix[CR]Nebula"[CR]*Filesystem 1 - "Mermaid"[CR]*Filesystem 2 - "Blackout[CR]City"[CR]*Filesystem 3 - "Mess</plot>
    <genre>Graphics,Sound,Levels,Text,Gameplay</genre>
    <studio>ColinC10</studio>
    <snapshot1>MTPm865.png</snapshot1>
    <snapshot2>urQprp5.png</snapshot2>
  </game>
  <game name="Sonic Zoom (SHC 2015 Build)">
    <description>Sonic Zoom (SHC 2015 Build)</description>
    <title_clean>Sonic Zoom</title_clean>
    <rom name="EmuROMHacks/ROM_Hacks_1.zip/Genesis%2FSonic%20Zoom%20%28SHC%202015%20Build%29.bin" size="596288"/>
    <plot>This is a hack that fixes some bugs in the original Sonic the Hedgehog for[CR]Genesis. Refer to the Readme for details on what was fixed. Make sure you use[CR]a clean ROM. The project contains two patches: one for the US/EU version and[CR]the other has changes from the Japanese version. Only one patch should be[CR]applied, and the original ROM to apply them to must be the US/EU version for[CR]both.[CR]Read Me:[CR]SONIC 1 BUGFIX[CR]+-+-+-+-+-+-+-[CR]By[CR]lory1990[CR]November 14th, 2016[CR]Version[CR]1.0[CR]=======================================[CR]OVERVIEW[CR]=======================================[CR]Refer[CR]to the changelog below for the list of all the bug fixes. I used the various[CR]guides on Sonic Retro[CR]so credit goes to the people who posted them, and[CR]those who found and fixed the bugs. Heres the[CR]link:[CR]http://info.sonicretro.org/SCHG_How-[CR]to:Guide[CR]=======================================[CR]HOW TO APPLY THE[CR]PATCHES[CR]=======================================[CR]The patches are in IPS[CR]format. To apply them, use a program such as Lunar IPS. [CR]One patch is for[CR]the US/EU version, while the other contains changes from the Japanese version.[CR]You need to use one patch only; if you want to use the other one, make[CR]sure to use a clean ROM.[CR]The original ROM to apply the patches to is the[CR]US/European version of Sonic the Hedgehog, even for the rev1 patch. [CR]If[CR]your ROM has the .smd extension, you need a program to convert it to .bin[CR]format as the .smd one contains[CR]an extra header. To be sure you have the[CR]right version of the original ROM, you need a program such [CR]as RomHasher to[CR]determine if the info is the same as that in the Rom/Iso Information field[CR]found in the main page for[CR]this[CR]hack.[CR]=======================================[CR]CHANGELOG[CR]=======================================[CR]v1.0[CR]----[CR]-[CR]Fixed crash that happens when looking down at the end of act 1 and 2 of[CR]Labyrinth Zone.[CR]- Now the Press Start Button text appears on the title[CR]screen.[CR]- Fixed level order in the Level Select menu.[CR]- Now youre[CR]correctly awarded 100 points instead of 10 when hitting the 100 point [CR]marker after the signpost at the end of the level.[CR] [CR]- Fixed[CR]disappearance of scattered rings for levels that have vertical wrapping.[CR]-[CR]Lost rings shared the same timer before disappearing. If you lost the[CR]rings[CR] while there were others scattered previously, these will stay around[CR]longer[CR] until the newly scattered rings disappeared. Now every lost ring is[CR]independent.[CR] [CR]- Fixed Sonic using his walking animation while jumping[CR]or drowning when standing[CR] next to some objects.[CR] [CR]- Fixed drowning[CR]bugs when Sonic gets hurt.[CR]- Fixed Sonic disappearing when he dies and ends[CR]up above the top boundary of the level.[CR]- Fixed timer HUD not blinking at[CR]the 9th minute when you have rings.[CR]- Fixed Level Select graphics bug.[CR]-[CR]Sonic no longer takes damage from spikes when hes temporarily[CR]invulnerable.[CR]- Fixed scattered rings physics when underwater.[CR]- Fixed[CR]physics when Sonic gets into water in hurt state.[CR]- Fixed Sonics jump[CR]height being really low when jumping out of shallow[CR]water.[CR]=======================================[CR]CREDITS[CR]=======================================[CR]-[CR]Members of Sonic Retro for all the fixes.</plot>
    <genre>Gameplay</genre>
    <studio>lory1990</studio>
    <snapshot1>S5c7ACo.png</snapshot1>
    <snapshot2>ovLEOMe.png</snapshot2>
  </game>
  <game name="Sonic the Hedgehog - Next Level (SHC 2015 Build)">
    <description>Sonic the Hedgehog - Next Level (SHC 2015 Build)</description>
    <title_clean>Sonic the Hedgehog - Next Level</title_clean>
    <rom name="EmuROMHacks/ROM_Hacks_1.zip/Genesis%2FSonic%20the%20Hedgehog%20-%20Next%20Level%20%28SHC%202015%20Build%29.bin" size="3964388"/>
  </game>
  <game name="Sonic the Hedgehog - The Lost Worlds (v.1.0)">
    <description>Sonic the Hedgehog - The Lost Worlds (v.1.0)</description>
    <title_clean>Sonic the Hedgehog - The Lost Worlds</title_clean>
    <rom name="EmuROMHacks/ROM_Hacks_1.zip/Genesis%2FSonic%20the%20Hedgehog%20-%20The%20Lost%20Worlds%20%28v.1.0%29.bin" size="1048576"/>
    <plot>Despite the hack name, this is a hack of Sonic the Hedgehog 2 for the Sega[CR]Genesis and not a hack of Sonic 1. The hack incorporates levels which were[CR]scrapped before the game was released. The levels are recreated using[CR]information gathered from either prototype ROM releases, scrapped data from[CR]the final ROM, information found in interviews, game screenshots, or concept[CR]art. Unlike other lost level restoration hacks this hack only incorporates the[CR]lost levels and no other levels are included aside from the prototype version[CR]of Casino Night Zone. Levels * Dust Hill Zone: Based off the single mock-up[CR]image found in magazines. * Rock Zone: Based off info found in a piece of[CR]concept art. * Wood Zone: Based off the design found in a prototype. * Winter[CR]Zone: Based off info from an interview. Includes Christmas trees. * Hidden[CR]Palace Zone: Based off design found in a prototype. Uses the intended music[CR]found in the final version of the game. * Casino Night Zone: Based off the[CR]design found in a prototype. Uses the music found in the prototype. * Cyber[CR]City Zone: Based off a piece of concept art.[CR]Read Me:[CR]Sonic the[CR]Hedgehog - The Lost Worlds[CR]Credits: ExecByte[CR]Sonic The Hedgehog: The[CR]Lost Worlds is a hack of Sonic the Hedgehog 2. This hack features all of the[CR]zones that were cut from Sonic 2 during development. Some zones have been[CR]ported from the Sonic 2 Simon Wai prototype and then finished up, and some[CR]have been created based on magazine pictures and information from interviews[CR]with people who worked on Sonic 2.[CR]==Levels==[CR]*Dust Hill Zone[CR]*Rock[CR]Zone - The music is Mystic Cave Zone 2 player.[CR]*Wood Zone - The music is[CR]the beta version of Metropolis Zone.[CR]*Winter Zone[CR]*Hidden Palace Zone -[CR]Background music is the intended music for the level. Mystic Cave boss is used[CR]with the only alteration that the sequence of picks and rocks is omitted.[CR]Also, the bat badniks are utilized, which ended up being unused in the final[CR]Sonic 2.[CR]*Casino Night Zone (Sonic 2 beta style) - Music is the beta[CR]music.[CR]*Cyber City Zone - The music is 2 player Casino Night Zone.</plot>
    <genre>Graphics,Levels</genre>
    <studio>ExecByte</studio>
    <snapshot1>x9IBukS.png</snapshot1>
    <snapshot2>jjO8Cwn.png</snapshot2>
  </game>
  <game name="Sonic the Hedgehog 1 and 2 (Rev 1)">
    <description>Sonic the Hedgehog 1 and 2 (Rev 1)</description>
    <title_clean>Sonic the Hedgehog 1 and 2</title_clean>
    <rom name="EmuROMHacks/ROM_Hacks_1.zip/Genesis%2FSonic%20the%20Hedgehog%201%20and%202%20%28Rev%201%29.bin" size="2097152"/>
    <plot>This is a hack for Sonic the Hedgehog 2 for Sega Genesis. It combines the[CR]levels of Sonic the Hedgehog and Sonic the Hedgehog 2 to make one large game.[CR]Special stages from both games are accessible and are entered via each game's[CR]special stage original entry method. This means Giant rings at the end of[CR]stages when retaining 50 rings in Sonic 1 and jumping into a circle of stars[CR]after passing checkpoints with enough rings in Sonic 2. There are 6 Chaos[CR]Emeralds in the Sonic 1 special stages and 7 in the Sonic 2 special stages.[CR]Super Sonic is not available until all Chaos Emeralds are obtained from both[CR]kinds of special stages. Progress is saved automatically to SRAM. Pressing[CR]Start and the A button while playing any stage will return the player to the[CR]title screen. Also, level select is available by holding A button then[CR]pressing Start at the title screen. Arena mode is playable which has time[CR]challenges that can be completed to increase the players ranking. Higher[CR]rankings are obtainable in harder levels and have shorter time limits. Some[CR]features of this game were later incorporated in flamewing's [Sonic Classic[CR]Heroes](http://www.romhacking.net/hacks/1038/) hack. The patch is in xdelta[CR]format due to shifted data resulting in IPS patches containing original code.[CR]The ROM should be in BIN format.[CR]Read Me:[CR]Sonic 1 and 2[CR]Credits:[CR]ColinC10[CR]Sonic 1 and 2 is a hack of Sonic the Hedgehog 2 for the Sega[CR]Genesis. In addition to all Zones usually featured in Sonic the Hedgehog 2,[CR]this hack features all Zones from Sonic the Hedgehog (Sega Genesis), which[CR]have been ported, resulting in a continuous game experience from Green Hill[CR]Zone to Death Egg Zone. Both games different kinds of Special Stages are[CR]available in all regular Acts, and they are accessed through their usual[CR]method (Giant Rings for Sonic 1, star post checkpoints for Sonic 2). The[CR]player must clear all Special Stages from each game, thus collecting Chaos[CR]Emeralds, 6 in Sonic 1 and 7 in Sonic 2, in order to become Super[CR]Sonic.[CR]==Features==[CR]*A full game of Sonic 1 and 2 starts in Green Hill[CR]Zone and ends as Sonic or Tails destroys and escapes from Death Egg[CR]Zone.[CR]*Sonic 1s Final Zone has been renamed to a second 3rd act of Scrap[CR]Brain (even though it is listed as Act 4 in Level Select) as it is obviously[CR]no longer the final zone. A normal act ending has been added to Final Zone[CR]just as if was any other zone. No ending is shown for Sonic 1; gameplay[CR]proceeds immediately to Emerald Hill Zone as though this battle with Robotnik[CR]were simply a normal boss battle.[CR]*The Special Stages from Sonic 1 are[CR]available through Giant Rings at the end of every non-boss Act if the player[CR]has 50 rings. Also included are the special stages of Sonic 2. Star Post[CR]checkpoints in the Sonic 1 levels have been changed to those of Sonic 2,[CR]enabling entry to Sonic 2s Special Stages in levels from either game if the[CR]player has enough rings when passing a checkpoint. The player needs all six[CR]Sonic 1 emeralds and all seven Sonic 2 emeralds to become Super[CR]Sonic.[CR]*Progress is automatically saved to SRAM. It is possible to[CR]enable/disable this, or start a new game, from the options menu. Said menu[CR]also now enables the player to resume from the latest-accessed act with a[CR]different character or characters.[CR]*It is possible to return to the title[CR]screen by pausing the game and pressing A[CR]*The Level Select screen can be[CR]accessed by holding A at the title screen[CR]*Arena Mode: Attempt to increase[CR]your rank by completing time attack challenges. Higher ranks mean harder[CR]levels and shorter time limits. [CR]==Limitations==[CR]*If both Sonic and[CR]Tails are on screen, and there are a large number of objects active, the[CR]framerate can drop somewhat. This is most noticeable in Sonic 1 levels, which[CR]is to be expected as the original game did not make any consideration of Tails[CR]and the consequent increased number of sprites.[CR]*ColinC10 had to implement[CR]a lot of trickery to circumvent palette limitations, so some slight[CR]differences from the original games may be noticeable.</plot>
    <genre>Levels</genre>
    <studio>ColinC10</studio>
    <snapshot1>MTKr5Cj.png</snapshot1>
    <snapshot2>NtRnNKo.png</snapshot2>
  </game>
  <game name="Sonic the Hedgehog 2 - Bug Fixes (v.1.1)">
    <description>Sonic the Hedgehog 2 - Bug Fixes (v.1.1)</description>
    <title_clean>Sonic the Hedgehog 2 - Bug Fixes</title_clean>
    <rom name="EmuROMHacks/ROM_Hacks_1.zip/Genesis%2FSonic%20the%20Hedgehog%202%20-%20Bug%20Fixes%20%28v.1.1%29.bin" size="1048576"/>
  </game>
  <game name="Sonic the Hedgehog 2 Long Version (v1.8.1)">
    <description>Sonic the Hedgehog 2 Long Version (v1.8.1)</description>
    <title_clean>Sonic the Hedgehog 2 Long Version</title_clean>
    <rom name="EmuROMHacks/ROM_Hacks_1.zip/Genesis%2FSonic%20the%20Hedgehog%202%20Long%20Version%20%28v1.8.1%29.bin" size="1453056"/>
    <plot>Sonic the Hedgehog 2 XL is a joke hack which adds a new gameplay gimmick. The[CR]standard rings the player normally collect have been replaced by onion rings.[CR]The more onion rings the player collects the fatter he gets. As he gets fatter[CR]he gets slower, jumps shorter, and becomes unable to roll. If the player eats[CR]too many onion rings the player will die. The player can burn off the fat by[CR]running or by breaking the ? monitors found throughout the levels. Facts about[CR]the hack * It takes about 5 rings to to go up a level in fatness. * Spin[CR]dashing and normal spinning is lost at fat level 5. * It takes about 30 rings[CR]to die of fatness. * The fatter the player gets the less the player is able to[CR]look up and down, and gives up at level 6. * If using debug mode to finish[CR]Death Egg Zone as while fat the player goes down to fat level 3. * If breaking[CR]a "?" box, Sonic will lose weight instantly. The patch is in xdelta format due[CR]to shifted data resulting in IPS patches containing original code. The ROM[CR]should be in BIN format.[CR]Read Me:[CR]Sonic the Hedgehog 2[CR]XL[CR]Credits: Captain Bozo, Ranger[CR]==Gameplay==[CR]Sonic 2 XL takes after[CR]other hacks that penalize the player for collecting rings, [CR]such as OMG THE[CR]RED RINGS, a Sonic the Hedgehog hack. The fatter Sonic is, the [CR]slower he[CR]runs and the shorter he jumps. With enough onion rings, Sonic is unable [CR]to[CR]roll properly, and if he gets too fat, he dies. Sonic can burn off the fat by[CR]running, or by hitting the "?" monitors strategically scattered through[CR]levels.[CR]==Facts about the games fat feature==[CR]*It takes about 5 rings to[CR]to go up a level in fatness.[CR]*You lose spindashing and normal spinning all[CR]together at fat level 5.[CR]*It takes about 30 rings to die of[CR]fatness.[CR]*The fatter you get, the less effort Sonic puts into looking up[CR]and down until [CR]he gives up (Level 6).[CR]*If you use debug mode to finish[CR]Death Egg Zone as fat Sonic, he goes down to [CR]fat level 3.[CR]*If you break[CR]a 10 ring box, Sonic will become fat instantly.[CR]*If you break a "?" box,[CR]Sonic will lose weight instantly.</plot>
    <genre>Graphics,Gameplay</genre>
    <studio>Captain Bozo</studio>
    <snapshot1>hNcboqP.png</snapshot1>
    <snapshot2>epsVlmr.png</snapshot2>
  </game>
  <game name="Sonic the Hedgehog 3 &amp;amp; Amy Rose (Rev.1.4)">
    <description>Sonic the Hedgehog 3 &amp;amp; Amy Rose (Rev.1.4)</description>
    <title_clean>Sonic the Hedgehog 3 &amp;amp; Amy Rose</title_clean>
    <rom name="EmuROMHacks/ROM_Hacks_1.zip/Genesis%2FSonic%20the%20Hedgehog%203%20%26%20Amy%20Rose%20%28Rev.1.4%29.bin" size="3410554"/>
    <plot>This is a hack which replaces Sonic the Hedgehog with Amy in Sonic the[CR]Hedgehog 3 and Knuckles for Genesis. This is Sonic 3 and Sonic and Knuckles[CR]locked onto each other. Amy in the hack is classic Amy designed after her[CR]Sonic CD appearance. Amy's moves are inspired by those used in her Sonic[CR]Advance appearance. She is slower than Sonic, can't use spin attack but has[CR]other moves. An attack button has been added and other moves can also be[CR]performed by using combinations of buttons and directional pad presses. A[CR]complete move list is found in the readme. The ROM should be in BIN format. It[CR]has not been tested for compatibility on other formats. The patch is in xdelta[CR]format due to shifted data resulting in IPS patches containing original code.[CR]Version 1.4 * Added remaining few missing sprites, plus a Bonus Stage slot[CR]picture and title screen animation. * Fixed clunky break mechanism for Ice Cap[CR]walls. * Tails now appears when entering Ice Cap via normal route (he's still[CR]absent via Knuckles' entrance however). * Tails now runs at the same pace as[CR]Amy, meaning no annoying skidding every time the COM overtakes[CR]her.[CR]Read Me:[CR]Sonic 3 and Amy Rose[CR]Credits: E-122-Psi[CR]Big[CR]thanks to: Tiddles, ChelseaCatGirl, Gsuki[CR]==Controls==[CR]Amys abilities[CR]mirror those she utilized in the Sonic Advance series. She is slower than[CR]Sonic and cant use spin attacks, however has a number of abilities (mostly[CR]using her Piko Piko Hammer) to gain manueverability and access areas Sonic had[CR]difficulty reaching:[CR]*Hammer Attack: Press A and Amy swings her hammer,[CR]damaging enemies. In addition, Amy can use her hammer to smash obstacles such[CR]as walls and hit springs.[CR]*Hammer Jump: Press Down + A on the ground and[CR]Amy smashes the hammer into the ground, launching her into the air.[CR]*Hammer[CR]Whirl: Press Down + A in the air and Amy swirls down toward the ground. If an[CR]enemy is hit Amy will bounce up again.[CR]*Upward Dash: Hold Down + B/C while[CR]on the ground and Amy will rev her feet on the spot as opposed to a spin dash.[CR]Let go of Down to charge full throttle in the facing direction. Be careful[CR]though, Amy is vulnerable to blockading obstacles and enemies. [CR]In[CR]addition, Amy can use her hammer attacks to enter Knuckles blocked pathways,[CR]allowing her to proceed through the game with either Sonic or Knuckles routes.</plot>
    <genre>Graphics,Gameplay</genre>
    <studio>E-122-Psi</studio>
    <snapshot1>MIUKug0.png</snapshot1>
    <snapshot2>7ZddiHL.png</snapshot2>
  </game>
  <game name="Sonic the Hedgehog 3 - D.A. Garden Edition (v.1.02)">
    <description>Sonic the Hedgehog 3 - D.A. Garden Edition (v.1.02)</description>
    <title_clean>Sonic the Hedgehog 3 - D.A. Garden Edition</title_clean>
    <rom name="EmuROMHacks/ROM_Hacks_1.zip/Genesis%2FSonic%20the%20Hedgehog%203%20-%20D.A.%20Garden%20Edition%20%28v.1.02%29.bin" size="3316534"/>
  </game>
  <game name="Sonic the Hedgehog 3 - Resort Island (SHC 2015 Demo)">
    <description>Sonic the Hedgehog 3 - Resort Island (SHC 2015 Demo)</description>
    <title_clean>Sonic the Hedgehog 3 - Resort Island</title_clean>
    <rom name="EmuROMHacks/ROM_Hacks_1.zip/Genesis%2FSonic%20the%20Hedgehog%203%20-%20Resort%20Island%20%28SHC%202015%20Demo%29.bin" size="3332384"/>
  </game>
  <game name="Sonic the Hedgehog 3 Complete (v.130810)">
    <description>Sonic the Hedgehog 3 Complete (v.130810)</description>
    <title_clean>Sonic the Hedgehog 3 Complete</title_clean>
    <rom name="EmuROMHacks/ROM_Hacks_1.zip/Genesis%2FSonic%20the%20Hedgehog%203%20Complete%20%28v.130810%29.gen" size="3932160"/>
    <plot>This is a hack of Sonic the Hedgehog 3 and Knuckles. It is a new feature,[CR]Sonic 3-ification, and bugfix patch. The game has been altered to restore[CR]changes made to Sonic 3 levels so the levels play and sound like they did in[CR]Sonic 3. There is also a game selection screen allowing for Sonic 3 Alone,[CR]Sonic and Knuckles, Sonic 3 and Knuckles, and Blue Sphere to be played.[CR]Several bugs have been fixed and there is a option screen to reverse some[CR]changes made. The hack can be modified further with the included ips patches.[CR]Cheat codes can be found in the read me. It is encouraged to read the readme[CR]as it has an exhaustive list of changes made in this hack. The patch is in[CR]xdelta format due to shifted data resulting in IPS patches containing original[CR]code. Make sure to use the Sonic and Knuckles and Sonic 3 ROM which is about[CR]4,096 kb in size. The ROM should be in BIN format.[CR]Read Me:[CR]Sonic 3[CR]Complete[CR]Credits: Tiddles;[CR]Additional contributions from flamewing, That[CR]One Jig, Neo, Hayate, shobiz, Tribeam, MoDule and LOst[CR]Sonic 3 Complete is[CR]a hack of Sonic 3 and Knuckles. It began primarily as an alteration of the[CR]musical configuration of that game to to more closely resemble that of the[CR]original Sonic 3. It also contains bugfixes and other additional features, and[CR]provides versions of Sonic 3, Sonic and Knuckles and Blue Sphere with these[CR]same additions and fixes, essentially providing a console version of Sonic and[CR]Knuckles Collection. Additional menu options and ROM patches are available to[CR]reverse some of these changes, or make others, to provide a version to match[CR]the players own preference.[CR]==Additions (Sonic 3-ification)==[CR]==Full[CR]List of Changes and Options==[CR]===Sonic 3-ification===[CR]*Tracks for title[CR]screen, invincibility, Knuckles theme, miniboss, 1UP, Sonic 3 ending,[CR]continue/race results, and data select are the Sonic 3 versions by[CR]default.[CR]*Various music cues are flipped around to work with[CR]this:[CR]**Marble Garden 2 boss for Knuckles plays the standard zone boss[CR]theme.[CR]**Flying Battery 2 sub-boss plays the Sonic and Knuckles miniboss[CR]theme.[CR]**Hidden Palace plays Sonic 3 miniboss for Knuckles fight, Sonic and[CR]Knuckles miniboss for Emerald theft.[CR]**The Sonic 3 credits music plays[CR]during the ending before the main credits begin (replacing Sky[CR]Sanctuary)[CR]**The Blue Sphere difficulty screen now plays the Gumball Bonus[CR]music.[CR]*Many of the Sonic 3 levels use their original Sonic 3 object[CR]layouts by default, most notably Hydrocity 2 and Launch Base.[CR]**Knuckles[CR]routes in these layouts were incomplete, but additions have been made to allow[CR]them to be played through.[CR]*Sonic 1-3-style monitor behaviour - jumping[CR]under the base of a monitor will make it fall.[CR]*Music no longer fades out[CR]before the Got Through screen[CR]*Act music no longer resumes after the Got[CR]Through screen before a zone transition.[CR]*Credits music has been replaced[CR]with the Sonic 3C prototype 0517 version.[CR]*Sonic/Tails have their final[CR]Launch Base 2 boss restored, with its Sonic 3 sweeping behaviour.[CR]**The[CR]ability to hit characters out of their super form has not been[CR]reintroduced.[CR]**In a Sonic and Tails game, Tails does not appear for the[CR]final Launch Base bosses. Player 2 can press a button to make him[CR]appear.[CR]**Knuckles version is unaffected.[CR]*The Special Stage results[CR]screen for Chaos Emerald stages is now styled much more like the version from[CR]Sonic 3 alone. (The background color is white rather than grey.)[CR]*The[CR]Continue screen uses title card-style text as it did in Sonic 3, rather than[CR]end credits-style text as it did in Sonic and Knuckles.[CR]*Flying Battery[CR]shows up with its unused Sonic 3 icon in Data Select.[CR]*Mushroom Hill is now[CR]named Mushroom Valley, as it was in the Sonic 3 level select screen.[CR]*All[CR]references to "&amp; Knuckles" removed, title screen positioning realigned to[CR]original setup. Zone title cards restored to Sonic 3s style.[CR]*The logo in[CR]the all-super emeralds ending now drops in from the top of the screen as in[CR]the Sonic 3 credits[CR]*Playing as Sonic and Tails, Tails now arrives slightly[CR]later at the start of AIZ and faces right, as in Sonic 3, and cannot move[CR]until Sonic can.[CR]*The save screen for Complete mode no longer shows counts[CR]of lives and continues (though these are still saved and loaded); its format[CR]has been made more compact, like the original Sonic 3 save[CR]screen.[CR]*Emeralds on the save screen now use the Sonic 3-style flash cycle[CR]in all modes.[CR]===Features and Tweaks===[CR]*Before the original title[CR]screen appears, a game menu has been inserted to select between Sonic 3[CR]Complete, Sonic 3, Sonic and Knuckles and Blue Sphere.[CR]**Pressing B from[CR]the title screens of any of these games will return you to this game[CR]menu.[CR]*An Options menu has been provided to reconfigure many aspects of the[CR]game.[CR]**The originally-conceived zone order can be activated using the[CR]options menu, placing Flying Battery between Carnival Night and Icecap.[CR]**A[CR]"beta" palette of Flying Batterys indoor section can be put in place, which[CR]matches up with the previously unused Sonic 3 save icon.[CR]**Sonic Jams Easy[CR]and Normal modes are available, complete with their unique features and level[CR]layouts.[CR]**Music from Sonic and Knuckles Collection converted by ValleyBell[CR]can be swapped in, as can imports of Masato Nakamuras main themes from the[CR]previous games.[CR]**Many of the music changes designed to make the game more[CR]Sonic 3-like can be altered.[CR]**Level layout can be switched between Sonic 3[CR]and Sonic and Knuckles versions.[CR]**The game can be set to boot straight[CR]into one of the game modes, bypassing the game selection title[CR]screen.[CR]*Knuckles introductory cutscene now plays in Angel Island rather[CR]than Sonic and Knuckles first zone, and feeds directly into the level rather[CR]than fading out and restarting.[CR]*Tails now has an introduction sequence,[CR]continue screen, and his own colours in the results screens.[CR]*Added an[CR]extra cutscene after Launch Base, showing the Death Egg crashing, based on the[CR]Sonic and Knuckles title screen.[CR]*Player 1 in a Sonic+Tails game can now[CR]put Tails into flight mode and direct him when being carried.[CR]**This is[CR]activated as in Sonic 1 2013 (up+jump in midair).[CR]**When Tails is carrying[CR]Sonic, use up/down/left/right to direct Tails, as in the Marble Garden[CR]boss.[CR]***Alternatively, you can set the controls in this state to work as[CR]in Sonic 1 2013 through the options menu.[CR]**Unless this feature is[CR]disabled, the fire shield dash will not activate while the up button is being[CR]held, to allow the characters to connect more easily.[CR]*Super Sonic now has[CR]a full set of distinct sprites (for the default S3 look only).[CR]**Some of[CR]these are based on flamewings Sonic Classic Heroes sprites with tweaks by That[CR]One Jig; others have been drawn by Neo.[CR]*Knuckles has improved and more[CR]consistent underwater colours.[CR]*Knuckles special moves now respect[CR]underwater physics.[CR]*Hyper Sonic, Super Tails and Super/Hyper Knuckles now[CR]have distinct underwater palettes.[CR]*The Mushroom Valley demo sequence now[CR]plays as one of the Sonic 3 demos.[CR]*Sonics Angel Island intro can now be[CR]skipped using the Start button (only until Knuckles interjects).[CR]*For[CR]Super/Hyper forms to be invoked, you must press any button to jump, followed[CR]by a different button to double-jump.[CR]**To transform with debug mode[CR]enabled, you need to double-jump by pressing B while C is held down.[CR]**This[CR]allows Tails/Knuckles to play without powering up after having all[CR]emeralds.[CR]**Sonic can now transform even if he has a barrier.[CR]**Using[CR]the super transformation move while already transformed will allow you to turn[CR]back to normal.[CR]*While in super or hyper form, sped-up level music plays[CR]instead of invincibility music.[CR]*Super music changes now consistently have[CR]no effect during bosses.[CR]*Speed shoes monitors now have no effect when[CR]collected in super or hyper form.[CR]*You now need to collect 50 rings within[CR]the slot machine bonus stage itself to get a continue.[CR]**Rings lost within[CR]the bonus stage will not take away from your collection total for the[CR]continue.[CR]**You can now do this in every slot machine bonus stage.[CR]Originally, you needed to wait until a new act or lose your rings in the main[CR]level.[CR]*Added a HUD element to the Slot Machine bonus stage to show[CR]progress towards a continue.[CR]*The rotation in the slot machine bonus stage[CR]is now smoother (thanks to Cinossu).[CR]*Separate title card icons for each[CR]zone, by Neo.[CR]*After Hidden Palace, Knuckles is replaced by Robotnik on[CR]Sonics continue screen[CR]*Super/Hyper characters detransform if they are[CR]killed.[CR]*Minor alterations to the Icecap intro to maintain day-night cycle[CR]consistency.[CR]*The screen now pulls up after Carnival Night 1s miniboss, to[CR]make the signpost easier to control.[CR]*New credits font designed to better[CR]fit with the title card style.[CR]*The existing Sonic 3 and Knuckles cheats[CR]work, plus:[CR]**rightleftleftleftright on Sonic 3/Sonic and Knuckles title[CR]screen menu switches region graphics (Tails/Miles, TM[CR]signs)[CR]**leftleftrightrightleftleftleftleft on the Sonic 3 or Sonic and[CR]Knuckles title screen menu enables level select.[CR]**01 03 05 07 on sound[CR]test enables debug[CR]***With debug enabled, all restrictions on zone access[CR]and character choice are lifted, even in Sonic 3 and Sonic and Knuckles[CR]modes.[CR]**02 04 05 06 on sound test gives all Chaos Emeralds[CR]***This will[CR]not reset the status of anything done with Hidden Palace Zone/Super[CR]Emeralds[CR]**12 14 15 16 on sound test gives all super emeralds[CR]**When[CR]paused and level select is enabled, the A button now exits to different[CR]places:[CR]***1P level/Special Stage: level select[CR]***Grand Prix: GP[CR]results[CR]***Match Race: Match Race setup[CR]***Time Attack: Time Attack[CR]setup[CR]*"DEATHEGG" and "THE DOOMSDAY" changed to the more sensible "DEATH[CR]EGG" and "DOOMSDAY" in level select.[CR]*Level Select now has the Data Select[CR]background, replacing the Sonic 2 SONIC/MILES pattern.[CR]**In Sonic and[CR]Knuckles mode, the Blue Sphere background is used instead.[CR]*Added entries[CR]to Level Select for the Gumball Bonus Stage and the Hidden Palace Special[CR]Stage entryway.[CR]*Level Select has been rearranged to better reflect the[CR]actual zone arrangement.[CR]*New icons have been added to the level select[CR]screen to better display character selection.[CR]*New level select and data[CR]select font, designed to be similar in style to the title card font.[CR]**This[CR]rectifies text spacing issues when displaying the final zones in data[CR]select.[CR]*Sound effect E3 will now speed up music as if speed shoes were[CR]active when used in the level select.[CR]**E4 returns to normal speed, as does[CR]starting another track.[CR]*The sound test will always play Sonic 3 tracks[CR]from their original slots. The alternative versions can be played from entry[CR]F0 upwards.[CR]*All monitor types are now available in debug[CR]mode.[CR]===Bugfixes===[CR]*Knuckles appears in the same colours throughout[CR]the game, both in cutscenes and as a playable character.[CR]*Knuckles now[CR]fights EggRobo in Flying Battery 2.[CR]*Workaround added to Mushroom Valley 2[CR]and Sandopolis 2 bosses to prevent Knuckles from sometimes seeing Robotnik[CR]instead of the EggRobo.[CR]*You will no longer lose shields if hit from the[CR]blue spinning platforms in Marble Garden.[CR]*Knuckles is no longer blocked[CR]from his normal Carnival Night exit when arriving from above[CR]*The correct[CR]music will always resume when coming back from a special stage or bonus stage[CR](Angel Island Zone 1, IceCap Zone 1).[CR]*Fixed Knuckles being unable to jump[CR]off underwater objects[CR]*Fixed the HUD shadow colour in Angel[CR]Island.[CR]*The underwater character palette now reverts properly when Tails[CR]or Knuckles lose their super form.[CR]*When the lights go out in Carnival[CR]Night, the underwater palette also changes to reflect this (thanks to[CR]Neo).[CR]*The slot machine bonus stage now awards a continue through rings[CR]collected in the slot machine as well as around the sides.[CR]*Many player[CR]sprite and mapping issues have been fixed, and remaining Sonic 2-alike sprites[CR]have been replaced.[CR]**Thanks go to That One Jig for these sprite[CR]improvements.[CR]*Fixed a number of issues involving speed being incorrectly[CR]set when water and/or super sneakers and/or super transformations were[CR]involved (thanks to MoDule).[CR]*It is no longer possible to confuse the[CR]camera by ducking and jumping in a wrapped level, thereby moving through[CR]objects (thanks to flamewing and redhotsonic).[CR]*Rings attracted by the[CR]lightning shield are no longer confused by level wrapping (thanks to[CR]flamewing).[CR]*The lightning shield can now successfully attract rings when[CR]the player is at the extreme top or left of the level (thanks to[CR]flamewing).[CR]*Knuckles no longer shifts forward a pixel when looking[CR]up.[CR]*The boss music gives way to the act music at the end of Sandopolis 1[CR]and Lava Reef 2.[CR]*The correct music will resume after a drown timer while[CR]fighting the Hydrocity bosses.[CR]*Fixed issues with Tails flying Sonic into[CR]various objects and/or their areas of effect.[CR]*Tails carrying Sonic to the[CR]floor no longer results in Sonic being able to walk around during level[CR]results.[CR]*Fixed underwater tired animation selection for Tails carrying[CR]Sonic[CR]*Sonic will no longer gain strange physics when Tails smashes an ice[CR]block from under him.[CR]*Fixed occasional glitched graphics/animations for[CR]Sonic when Tails places him on the ground.[CR]*The camera vertical offset will[CR]now reset when Tails carries Sonic.[CR]*Fixed sprite misalignment when Tails[CR]carries Sonic in Sonic alone mode[CR]*Stopped running animation being[CR]displayed in place of victory or super transform animation when in front of a[CR]solid object[CR]*Fix for some giant rings in Mushroom Valley/Hill not[CR]appearing when continuing a save imported from Sonic 3.[CR]*Tails no longer[CR]trails along in flying animation when landing on objects (thanks to[CR]redhotsonic)[CR]*Tails tails also flash when he is invulnerable (thanks to[CR]redhotsonic)[CR]*Fixed spindash cancellation on screen boundaries and when[CR]jumping immediately (thanks to flamewing)[CR]*Tails alone no longer has extra[CR]tails in the Launch Base Zone 2 ending cutscene. [CR]*Tails tails no longer[CR]disappear while he is jumping after the credits[CR]*Fixed Super Sonic[CR]appearing in the wrong pose when dropped by Tails (visible during the final[CR]Marble Garden boss).[CR]*2P Tails is less prone to suicide before the final[CR]battles of Launch Base Zone.[CR]*Fire dashing or spindashing into the Death[CR]Egg boss area no longer causes collision issues.[CR]*In certain circumstances,[CR]it is possible to break Launch Base pipes containing water without following[CR]the water through the tube. Going offscreen would cause the water jet to be[CR]lost, rendering further progress impossible. The water jets now respawn[CR]correctly.[CR]*The initial restart locations for Act 2 of Angel Island,[CR]Hydrocity, Launch Base and Lava Reef now better reflect the act 1 finish[CR]positions, making time results more comparable.[CR]*Attached platforms and[CR]objects are removed after the Launch Base building collapses.[CR]*The capsule[CR]at the end of Hydrocity is now correctly centred for Sonic and[CR]Tails.[CR]*SONIC text is no longer backwards when the Tornado flies left[CR]during the ending.[CR]*Sonics exit from Lava Reef to Hidden Palace is now blue[CR]rather than red.[CR]*The music tempo glitch at the beginning of Doomsday has[CR]been removed.[CR]*Collecting extra lives will not increase the counter past[CR]99.[CR]*Fixed possible Marble Garden 2 boss corruption after killing a Spiker[CR]with hyper dash.[CR]*The normal super transformation sound effect is now used[CR]in Doomsday.[CR]*Fixed bugs relating to the Icecap act transition: you can no[CR]longer fly over the boss, and dying without having hit a starpost will[CR]correctly return you to the start of Icecap 1.[CR]*Fixed spring artwork[CR]occasionally not being loaded for the Gumball Bonus Stage.[CR]*It is no longer[CR]possible to gain additional lives for having 100 and 200 rings in the Lava[CR]Reef boss area if those lives were already earned earlier in act 2.[CR]*The[CR]Lava Reef and Death Egg boss areas will remember their starting timer if you[CR]die and restart (unless you die from a time over)[CR]*Robotniks bald shine on[CR]the save screen is no longer red.[CR]*The Launch Base music now only restarts[CR]once after Knuckles defeats the Act 1 boss.[CR]*Drowning timer resets when[CR]turning hyper, along with music if necessary[CR]*Knuckles no longer turns into[CR]Sonic at the end of the slot machine bonus stage.[CR]*Various double jump[CR]fixes for Sonic, mostly involving unintentionally going into a slow bubble[CR]bounce by double jumping right before a bubble shield activated.[CR]*Fixed bug[CR]where a time over would not restart the starpost timer after continuing from a[CR]game over.[CR]*Fixed final Launch Base boss code to release Sonic from the arm[CR]after the boss is defeated - this was firing in the wrong situation, making[CR]Sonic always drop to standing after clearing the boss, but leaving him stuck[CR]if Tails killed the boss while Sonic was held.[CR]*Fixed object and ring[CR]layout oddities in various zones, including the infamous double ring in Angel[CR]Island 1 and the improperly retracting spikes in Carnival Night 2.[CR]*Super[CR]Tails flickies no longer ruin the Sandopolis miniboss or the first Death Egg 2[CR]boss.[CR]*Fixed duff palette cycle when retransforming into super/hyper[CR]form[CR]*Fixed Tails using the wrong sprite when hit by the boulder in Lava[CR]Reef.[CR]*The Death Egg no longer appears in the background of Lava Reef when[CR]playing as Knuckles.[CR]*Tails will drop out of flight mode if he is tired and[CR]hits a diagonal spring in Carnival Night, preventing him from getting[CR]stuck.[CR]*Insta-shield now deflects projectiles, as appears to have been[CR]intended all along[CR]*Tails flight now only deflects projectiles if they hit[CR]his tails. (Previously he could deflect anywhere, but only if[CR]falling.)[CR]*Prevented super transformation during snowboard[CR]sequence[CR]*Fixed odd palette on HUD lives numbers in some levels[CR]*Fixed[CR]issue with continues not being saved unless a special stage is[CR]completed[CR]*Fixed occasional misalignment of continue screen[CR]*Fixed wrong[CR]tiles on Continue screen if you hit Game Over with Super/Hyper Sonic[CR]*Fire[CR]sprites no longer appear underwater in Angel Island[CR]*It is no longer[CR]possible to repeatedly double-jump in the Hydrocity fan tubes[CR]*Incorrect[CR]grabber arm sprite on DEZ final boss fixed - now uses the latched rather than[CR]open variant.[CR]*Fixed jittering screen lock after Marble Garden 1[CR]miniboss[CR]*Workaround added to avoid occasional loss of music track change[CR]if requested during the 1up sting.[CR]*Added MoDules bugfixes for jumping out[CR]of shallow water, roll jump hitbox and Tails camera height[CR]*Fixed a number[CR]of cases where Sonic or Tails would stay in midair and gain odd physics if a[CR]pillar was smashed from beneath them[CR]*Stopped 2P Tails from being able to[CR]misfire the cannon at the end of CNZ.[CR]*Tails now shows his full victory[CR]animation on the Blue Sphere difficulty screen.[CR]*Fixed players standing in[CR]the ground during their victory animations if they were previously[CR]rolling.[CR]*Fixed control improperly unlocking if a hurt player falls in a[CR]Carnival Night cannon[CR]*Sonic and Tails can no longer use super powers to[CR]break the switch back into Knuckles route at the end of Launch Base.[CR]*In a[CR]Sonic alone game, Tails no longer gets stuck jumping on the ground after[CR]flying Sonic in.[CR]*Fixed rare issue where the AIZ2 cutscene bridge collapse[CR]would trigger too soon.[CR]*Fixed a rare situation that could freeze the[CR]player in place if transforming just as the timer expires (thanks to[CR]flamewing).[CR]*Fixed Knuckles socks and pink palette in continue icon in[CR]Super Emerald special stage results[CR]*Fixed wrong colours on Super Emerald 6[CR](the leftmost one) as Sonic or Tails in Special Stage results[CR]*The Sky[CR]Sanctuary main melody is no longer muted by ring collection.[CR]*It is no[CR]longer impossible for Knuckles to defeat the Death Egg miniboss.[CR]*Fixed[CR]sprite misalignment on Flying Battery midboss and Knuckles waving off[CR]animation in Sky Sanctuary[CR]*Fixed CNZ vacuum tube whose art was pointing in[CR]the wrong direction.[CR]*Follower Tails now behaves more sensibly at the end[CR]of Mushroom Valley/Hill.[CR]*Fixed abrupt/unsynced camera/music transition at[CR]the end of Sandopolis 2.[CR]*The rumbling sound during the closing sequence of[CR]Flying Battery is no longer missing when restarting from the final[CR]starpost.[CR]*The falling animation is used after the Mushroom Valley/Hill[CR]Knuckles cutscene instead of the walking animation.[CR]*Fixed odd palette[CR]cycle stop point on Super/Hyper Knuckles during his ending.[CR]*Fixed Sonic[CR]incorrectly appearing as Hyper Sonic briefly during the ending when he[CR]shouldnt be able to.[CR]*Jump height off Hydrocity rotating cylinders is now[CR]appropriately reduced when underwater.[CR]*Level music no longer double-[CR]restarts before final boss in Death Egg[CR]*Competition music no longer[CR]restarts while navigating competition menus.[CR]*Debug: Hyper Knuckles can now[CR]wall smash when turned hyper by a monitor.[CR]*Debug: Tails ring counter now[CR]falls in Doomsday.[CR]*Debug: Characters other than Sonic appear correctly in[CR]Doomsday.[CR]*Debug: Knuckles exits Doomsday to the title screen instead of a[CR]broken Sonic ending.[CR]*Debug: Going into debug when dead now restarts object[CR]processing.[CR]*Debug: The debug cursor now respects screen[CR]locking.[CR]===Changes specific to Blue Sphere===[CR]*Tails has been added as[CR]a playable character in Blue Sphere.[CR]*While playing a special stage through[CR]Blue Sphere, pressing B while paused will return to the Blue Sphere select[CR]screen.[CR]*Pressing B on the Blue Sphere menu screen will now return to the[CR]title screen. Your progress will be retained until you reset or turn off the[CR]game.[CR]===Changes specific to Sonic 3===[CR]*The included Sonic 3 runs[CR]completely on top of Sonic 3 Completes engine, and hence inherits all relevant[CR]improvements from Sonic 3 and Knuckles and Sonic 3 Complete, while retaining[CR]its own layouts, save files, bonus stage structure, etc.[CR]* The credits list[CR]used is from Sonic 3 and Knuckles to reflect the integration of the games in[CR]this collection.[CR]*On the "Try Again" ending screen, the emeralds juggled by[CR]Knuckles are now coloured correctly.[CR]*The Death Eggs behaviour at the end[CR]of the game has been slightly altered to match the complete story.[CR]*Tails[CR]retains his unique game clear icons on the save screen.[CR]*If no saves are[CR]present for Sonic 3 mode, the game will attempt to import data from the[CR]complete game where appropriate.[CR]===Changes specific to Sonic and[CR]Knuckles===[CR]* The credits list used is from Sonic 3 and Knuckles to reflect[CR]the integration of the games in this collection.[CR]===Options===[CR]====Menu[CR]Options====[CR]*Skip the game select screen and start one of the individual[CR]games immediately on boot up.[CR]*Play through the "Easy" and "Normal"[CR]versions of the game introduced in Sonic Jam.[CR]*Use the full set of Sonic 3[CR]or Sonic and Knuckles level layouts.[CR]*Play Flying Battery in its original[CR]position between Carnival Night and Icecap, and/or with an earlier colour[CR]scheme design.[CR]*Disable the added ability for Sonic to control Tails[CR]flight, or swap the carrying controls for those used in Sonic 1[CR]2013.[CR]*Choose between the various soundtrack options for individual tracks,[CR]including Sonic and Knuckles Collection and Nakamura themes, or configure the[CR]game to use different soundtracks in each mode.[CR]*Go back to using the[CR]invincibility music for super/hyper transformations, or use the unused PC[CR]track for this purpose.[CR]*Disable all music (useful to set a gameplay video[CR]to an alternative soundtrack)[CR]*Change the moves and abilities available, so[CR]that the game plays more like other classic Sonic games.[CR]*Use the original[CR]Sonic 3 and Knuckles double-jump/transformation button setup (any double-jump[CR]invokes a super form transformation, if available, unless Sonic has a shield,[CR]which prevents transformation).[CR]*Disable the ability to cancel out of super[CR]or hyper forms.[CR]===Known Issues in the Current Release===[CR]*The menu[CR]setting to change the S3 Credits music to the Sonic and Knuckles Collection[CR]version does not affect the final credits if the customiser patch is used to[CR]place this track in that position. This will be resolved in a future release.[CR]This does not affect anything in plain, uncustomised builds.[CR]*Changes made[CR]in the Options menu will not be saved to or loaded from SRAM when using the[CR]Regen emulator. This is seemingly due to Regen limiting the size of SRAM and[CR]does not affect flashcarts or any other tested emulators. It is still possible[CR]to use the menus if desired, but changes will not be saved after a hard reset[CR]or closing the emulator. Savestates may be used to preserve selected[CR]options.[CR]*The emulators Generator and Genesis Plus (non-GX) appear to treat[CR]banked SRAM incorrectly, leading to part of the game becoming corrupted. The[CR]effects vary from build to build, as the damage is isolated to a particular[CR]ROM location which contains different data in different versions. As of[CR]version 130810, this causes Mushroom Valley to be severely damaged and[CR]essentially unplayable. Once again, this issue does not affect usage on real[CR]hardware or other tested emulators. If you like Genesis Plus, note that[CR]emulators based on Genesis Plus GX do not exhibit this issue.[CR]*Many known[CR]issues in Sonic 3 and Knuckles continue to be present.</plot>
    <genre>Sound,Levels</genre>
    <studio>Tiddles</studio>
    <snapshot1>iGB9s28.png</snapshot1>
    <snapshot2>FJnW5LN.png</snapshot2>
  </game>
  <game name="Sonic the Hedgehog Classic Heroes (v.0.10.008a)">
    <description>Sonic the Hedgehog Classic Heroes (v.0.10.008a)</description>
    <title_clean>Sonic the Hedgehog Classic Heroes</title_clean>
    <rom name="EmuROMHacks/ROM_Hacks_1.zip/Genesis%2FSonic%20the%20Hedgehog%20Classic%20Heroes%20%28v.0.10.008a%29.bin" size="4194304"/>
    <plot>This is a hack of Sonic the Hedgehog 2 which allows Sonic, Tails, and Knuckles[CR]to play simultaneously in any level from Sonic 1 and 2. All characters retain[CR]their moves and abilities from Sonic 3 and Knuckles. Save game and shield[CR]abilities from Sonic 3 and Knuckles are also present. The original shield[CR]gives Sonic the ability to perform a air/dash by pressing jump while in the[CR]air. Sega Multitap compatibility is implemented allowing up to 3 people to[CR]play at once. An extensive list of features of the hack can be found in the[CR]readme. The game was formerly known as Sonic 2 Heroes before ColinC10 became[CR]involved and helped port over Sonic 1 levels. Some features of this hack were[CR]first seen in ColinC10's [Sonic 1 and[CR]2](http://www.romhacking.net/hacks/1053/). The patch is in xdelta format due[CR]to shifted data resulting in IPS patches containing original code. v0.10.008a[CR]Version 0.10.008a adds the ability to play as Espio, Charmy, and Vector from[CR]Knuckles Chaotix.[CR]Read Me:[CR]Sonic the Hedgehog Classic Heroes[CR]Main[CR]programmer: flamewing, Assistance from: ColinC10[CR]Homepage:[CR]http://info.sonicretro.org/Sonic_Classic_Heroes[CR]==Characters==[CR]Players[CR]can choose to use one, two, or three characters. When using more than one[CR]character, the first player[CR]controls the character who is leading the[CR]group. The leading character can be changed at any time, using[CR]the[CR]additional buttons on the six-button Control Pad or the A[CR]button.[CR]*The cpu-controlled partner characters will often match certain[CR]attributes of the lead character in order to[CR]keep up. For example, Super[CR]Tails and Super Knuckles will match Super Sonics extreme jump height and[CR]speed[CR]while Super Sonic is in the lead, and Charmy will gain a jump, spin[CR]attack, spin-dash, etc. while not in the[CR]lead.[CR]*Up to three players can[CR]play co-operatively, via the Team Player multi-tap. Special Stages will be[CR]playable[CR]in this way, too. Moreover, the player can disable all but player[CR]1 in Special Stages; this is intended to help[CR]players who dont like CPU-[CR]controlled characters losing their rings.[CR]===Team Sonic===[CR]The classic[CR]trio of Sonic the Hedgehog, Miles "Tails" Prower, and Knuckles the Echidna[CR]star as this games[CR]default team.[CR]===Team Chaotix===[CR]This team[CR]consists of Espio the Chameleon, Vector the Crocodile, and Charmy the Bee.[CR]Their movesets are[CR]similar to their Knuckles Chaotix[CR]moveset.[CR]==Items==[CR]*Power-ups are awarded collectively to all of the[CR]players characters when a monitor is broken. However,[CR]shields are lost[CR]individually: if a character is hit, only they will lose their shield, whereas[CR]the other[CR]character(s) will retain their individual shields until they are[CR]hit.[CR]*Elemental shields from Sonic 3 have been added. The standard blue[CR]shield from Sonic 2 remains and has been[CR]upgraded so that, like the[CR]elemental shields, it deflects projectiles and it awards Sonic a power while[CR]he[CR]has it: in this case, the Homing Attack.[CR]==Other==[CR]*Physics[CR]imported from Sonic 3 and Knuckles.[CR]*Projectiles bounce off of Tails tails[CR]and from Knuckles when gliding, as well as from shields, as they did[CR]in[CR]Sonic 3 and Knuckles.[CR]*Graphics imported from Sonic 3 and Knuckles,[CR]particularly when they could be used to reduce the VRAM footprint.[CR]*A new[CR]HUD frees VRAM for Knuckles.[CR]*Amy Rose makes a cameo appearance flying the[CR]Tornado in Sky Chase Zone and Wing Fortress Zone, and in the[CR]pictures[CR]during the ending sequence. [CR]==Controls==[CR]*Return to title screen: while[CR]the game is paused, press A.[CR]*Kill self: Players 2 and 3 can kill[CR]themselves to force a respawn by pressing C while the game is[CR]paused.[CR]*Change character: Pressing A or X changes the character being[CR]controlled by the player to another character.[CR]Only players being[CR]controlled by the CPU are eligible for swap, unless the other player is[CR]holding A or X[CR]as well.[CR]*Spindash/super peelout: Several characters can[CR]execute either a spindash, a super peel-out or both. While[CR]ducking or[CR]looking up, press B or C to charge a spindash or a super peelout. If a[CR]character can use both the[CR]spindash and the super peel-out, he will charge[CR]a peelout while looking up and a spindash while ducking;[CR]otherwise, the[CR]character will charge whatever move he has in either case.[CR]*Jump: In[CR]general, pressing B or C will make you jump; some characters override this[CR]default behavior, so be[CR]sure to check their descriptions below.[CR]*Jump[CR]action: While a character is in the air (whether from jumping, from walking[CR]off a ledge, or from[CR]bouncing off a spring) and is either moving downwards[CR]or not moving too fast upwards, you can press B or C[CR]to execute a special[CR]action. These actions change depending on the character, so be sure to check[CR]below.[CR]Unless otherwise noted, executing any jump actions will allow you to[CR]regain control if you jump from a[CR]rolling state.</plot>
    <genre>Levels,Gameplay</genre>
    <studio>flamewing</studio>
    <snapshot1>DdY7Sj4.png</snapshot1>
    <snapshot2>siBiwX5.png</snapshot2>
  </game>
  <game name="Sonic the Hedgehog Megamix (v.3.0)">
    <description>Sonic the Hedgehog Megamix (v.3.0)</description>
    <title_clean>Sonic the Hedgehog Megamix</title_clean>
    <rom name="EmuROMHacks/ROM_Hacks_1.zip/Genesis%2FSonic%20the%20Hedgehog%20Megamix%20%28v.3.0%29.bin" size="1283224"/>
    <plot>Highlights for version 3.0: * All level layouts edited (some complete; others[CR]pending). * Each character now has a unique set of moves (though Sonic and[CR]Shadow share the homing attack). * Most levels (not all) have a small intro,[CR]ala S3K, where they perform some sort of action when starting the level i.e,[CR]running in from the left. * Loads of music edits. * There is now a[CR]"preferences" screen, where you can customize certain aspects of the game[CR](suggestions are welcome). * Cheat codes have been changed - figuring them out[CR]will grant you access to a new, special level select (which is a bit buggy -[CR]just don't hit left/right on zone selections =P). * "Original Mode" allows you[CR]to play the original levels from Sonic the Hedgehog, using all of the[CR]additions from Sonic Megamix (such as bug fixes, moves, preferences, etc).[CR]There is also a separate save slot for a character's original mode. * Title[CR]screen demos have been edited. Credits demos have not. * Super forms have been[CR]added. * Elemental shields, ala S3K, have been added. * Credits have been[CR]edited; each character has a unique end pose on the ending sequence. * Various[CR]other changes. See the [Wiki page](http://info.sonicretro.org/Sonic_1_Megamix)[CR]for more info. This is considered a "complete" release, although not "final".[CR]It was succeeded by an incomplete "4.0b", which was ported to SegaCD, and[CR]further changes have been implemented since, although a "final" release and[CR]its date are tentative. More information can be found on the Manual/Wiki page,[CR]located at here: . For a complete list of authors, please see: . Note: Apply[CR]xdelta patch to US Genesis Sonic 1 ROM. The patch is in xdelta format due to[CR]shifted data which resulted in a IPS patch almost the same size as the patched[CR]ROM.</plot>
    <genre>Graphics,Sound,Levels,Text,Gameplay</genre>
    <studio>Stealth, Tweaker</studio>
    <snapshot1>SCJfmPj.png</snapshot1>
    <snapshot2>XQt7pPN.png</snapshot2>
  </game>
  <game name="Streets of Rage - Syndicate Wars (X)">
    <description>Streets of Rage - Syndicate Wars (X)</description>
    <title_clean>Streets of Rage - Syndicate Wars</title_clean>
    <rom name="EmuROMHacks/ROM_Hacks_1.zip/Genesis%2FStreets%20of%20Rage%20-%20Syndicate%20Wars%20%28X%29.bin" size="2967446"/>
  </game>
  <game name="The S Factor - Sonia and Silver (v.1.0)">
    <description>The S Factor - Sonia and Silver (v.1.0)</description>
    <title_clean>The S Factor - Sonia and Silver</title_clean>
    <rom name="EmuROMHacks/ROM_Hacks_1.zip/Genesis%2FThe%20S%20Factor%20-%20Sonia%20and%20Silver%20%28v.1.0%29.bin" size="4194304"/>
    <plot>This is a hack of Sonic the Hedgehog for the Sega Genesis. It changes[CR]graphics, music, and layout of most levels. Some levels re-use previous[CR]artwork but much of it is original. Two characters are playable; Sonia,[CR]Sonic's sister from the SatAM cartoon series, Silver the Hedgehog from Sonic[CR]the Hedgehog (2006), and Scourge, a character from the US Sonic the Hedgehog[CR]comic series. Each character plays different from each other and have some[CR]moves unique to each character. A move list can be found in the readme. The[CR]game features Eggman Nega, Eggman's evil descendant from the same time period[CR]as Silver. He is the nemesis of the heroes of this hack. The patch is in[CR]xdelta format. The ROM should be in BIN format.[CR]Read Me:[CR]The S[CR]Factor: Sonia and Silver[CR]Credits: Aquaslash and Pals[CR]The S Factor: Sonia[CR]and Silver is an multi-level hack of Sonic the Hedgehog on the Sega Mega[CR]Drive/Genesis. The game allows players to choose between two characters, Sonia[CR]and Silver and offers several moves attributed to those[CR]characters.[CR]==Story==[CR]The citizens of Mobius just cant seem to catch a[CR]break. Dr. Robotnik (AKA Eggman) is yet again up to his no good tricks.[CR]Factories and pollution are spreading like wildfire as hes once again trying[CR]to take over the world. Fortunately, the Sonic Heroes are never at rest, and[CR]once again wage their battle to defeat Eggmans evil forces.[CR]However, the[CR]heroes have landed in double jeopardy. Eggmans madman descendant, Eggman Nega,[CR]has escaped from the Ifrits dimension, and is wreaking his usual havoc in an[CR]effort to destroy the world. Hes even captured Eggmans top three lieutenants,[CR]the ruthless Team Metallix, and reprogrammed them to do his even more evil[CR]bidding.[CR]Unlike previous instances of Negas destruction, Eggman is not[CR]fazed. He figures that once hes in control of the world, he can take care of[CR]Eggman Nega as he pleases. Unfortunately for Eggman, Sonic the Hedgehog isnt[CR]having that. Before he can decide who to dispatch where, he receives a call[CR]through the communicator Tails gave him. The message: someones already on the[CR]case. Not just someone, but someones![CR]Apparently, Sonics very own sister,[CR]Sonia the Hedgehog has already caught wind of Negas evil and is out to stop[CR]him. Sonic is a bit eased, knowing full well of his sisters strength and[CR]agility. She also lets him know that she has found and teamed up with a[CR]mysterious young hedgehog who can move things with his mind. Sonic instantly[CR]recognizes that Sonia is with his newest ally: Silver the Hedgehog. Silver has[CR]once again traveled through time to ensure that the future is free of Negas[CR]tampering (though he really ought to just stay here in the present, you know).[CR]Knowing that the two hedgehogs are more than capable of handling the[CR]situation, Sonic leaves it to them, and resumes dealing with Eggman.[CR]Eggman[CR]Nega is well aware that Sonic is busy with his dimwitted ancestor. However,[CR]hed do best not to overlook a certain factor. The S Factor, Sonia and Silver![CR]Its up to you to lead the unlikely tag team of the physically powerful Sonia,[CR]and the psychokinetic Silver on their quest to right the wrongs of the evil[CR]Eggman Nega![CR]==Characters==[CR]===Sonia the Hedgehog===[CR]The younger[CR]sister of the world famous hero, Sonic the Hedgehog. While she doesnt have his[CR]super speed, she makes up for it with quick moves, and incredible strength.[CR]Though she tends to be quite high maintenance, and a bit bossy, Sonia is[CR]incredibly agile, and a capable fighter to boot. She has a special move called[CR]the Super Twirl that allows her to accelerate into a powerful[CR]cyclone.[CR]===Silver the Hedgehog===[CR]One of the newest recruits to the[CR]Sonic Heroes, Silver is from a world in the distant future. Because of his[CR]strong determination to uphold the ways of truth and justice, Silver often[CR]finds himself chasing the time and dimension hopping Eggman Nega. Silvers most[CR]powerful asset is his mind. He wields amazing psychokinetic ability! He can[CR]move nearly anything, even himself, by just thinking about it! It is this[CR]trait that gives him his unusual flight abilities.[CR]Rush eggman[CR]nega.png[CR]===Eggman Nega===[CR]Eggmans evil descendant from the same time[CR]period as Silver. Rejected by scientists because his ancestors failures,[CR]Eggman Nega traveled back in time and tried to replace him and gain honor to[CR]the Robotnik name. His plans were thwarted, and now he wants revenge. If he[CR]cant rule the world, hell simply destroy it and find somewhere else to rule.[CR]Negas presence usually requires Sonics and Eggmans troops to team up, but[CR]Eggman has different ideas this time. Can Sonia and Silver stop his plans for[CR]world destruction?[CR]===Team Metallix===[CR]Dr. Eggmans top henchbots have[CR]been reprogrammed by Eggman Nega and attack our heroes in the White Blaster[CR]Zone![CR]===A.N.N.===[CR]The "voice" of Team Metallix as shes the only one[CR]with speech capabilities. A fanatic of Eggmans work who willingly subjected[CR]herself to roboticization. She specializes in flight. Watch out for her energy[CR]attacks![CR]===Metal Knuckles===[CR]Eggmans pulled this older machine out of[CR]storage and upgraded it into a more battle hardy configuration. As a[CR]doppelganger of Knuckles, he specializes in brute strength. Beware of his[CR]sharp "knuckles" and missile attacks.[CR]===Metal Sonic===[CR]The tactical[CR]leader of the team, Metal Sonic is the one android that all of the heroes know[CR]too well. Like his namesake, he specializes in supersonic speed. However, his[CR]frame seems to have problems accommodating that super speed...[CR]===The Sonic[CR]Heroes===[CR]The group of young heroes led by the fleet footed speed demon,[CR]Sonic the Hedgehog. Theyve got their hand full with dealing with Eggmans plan[CR]to one up Eggman Nega. Fulfill certain conditions, and you might be able to[CR]help them on their quest. Which ones? Play the game and find[CR]out![CR]==Controls==[CR]===All Characters===[CR]Directional Pad Left or Right:[CR]Move - Hold either button to accelerate. Press the opposite direction to[CR]brake.[CR]Directional Pad Up: Look - get a view of your upper[CR]surroundings.[CR]Directional Pad Down: Crouch - get a view of your lower[CR]surroundings.[CR]C: Spin Attack - use the hedgehogs main defensive move to[CR]gain speed on slopes and destroy enemies![CR]Jump + Hold A + C (thats jump,[CR]hold A and press C): Mission Power - Complete all of the secret missions to[CR]unlock this "super" move of great justice![CR]===Unique to Sonia===[CR]Hold A:[CR]Super Twirl - Accelerate into a whirlwind tornado! Grants temporary[CR]invincibility and increased acceleration, but you cant jump. Let go of the[CR]button for a burst of speed.[CR]Jump + C: Power Axe - this spinning axe kick[CR]increases Sonias attack range and reflects most projectile attacks.[CR]Power[CR]Skill - As Sonia is a strength oriented character, she can access various[CR]shortcuts that other characters cant with little effort.[CR]===Unique to[CR]Silver===[CR]Hold A: Psychokinesis - Silvers signature skill. Control various[CR]objects and use them to destroy enemies and access shortcuts.[CR]Jump + C:[CR]Levitation - glide through the air with your psychic powers. Hold A to sustain[CR]altitude, and move with the directional pad. Use it carefully as it only lasts[CR]a short while.</plot>
    <genre>Graphics,Sound,Levels,Text,Gameplay</genre>
    <studio>Aquaslash</studio>
    <snapshot1>hgWSy42.png</snapshot1>
    <snapshot2>qazV6Vf.png</snapshot2>
  </game>
  <game name="Thunderbolt II">
    <description>Thunderbolt II</description>
    <title_clean>Thunderbolt II</title_clean>
    <rom name="EmuROMHacks/ROM_Hacks_1.zip/Genesis%2FThunderbolt%20II.bin" size="524288"/>
  </game>
  <game name="Untitled Sonic 1 Hack (SHC2016 Build)">
    <description>Untitled Sonic 1 Hack (SHC2016 Build)</description>
    <title_clean>Untitled Sonic 1 Hack</title_clean>
    <rom name="EmuROMHacks/ROM_Hacks_1.zip/Genesis%2FUntitled%20Sonic%201%20Hack%20%28SHC2016%20Build%29.bin" size="1048576"/>
  </game>
  <game name="Warsong (X)">
    <description>Warsong (X)</description>
    <title_clean>Warsong</title_clean>
    <rom name="EmuROMHacks/ROM_Hacks_1.zip/Genesis%2FWarsong%20%28X%29.bin" size="524288"/>
  </game>
  <game name="Zombies Ate My Neighbors (X)">
    <description>Zombies Ate My Neighbors (X)</description>
    <title_clean>Zombies Ate My Neighbors</title_clean>
    <rom name="EmuROMHacks/ROM_Hacks_1.zip/Genesis%2FZombies%20Ate%20My%20Neighbors%20%28X%29.bin" size="1057280"/>
  </game>
</datafile>
