<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<datafile>
    <header>
        <emu_name>Sega Genesis Translations</emu_name>
        <emu_description>Sega Genesis</emu_description>
        <emu_category>Sega, 1980s, Console, 16 Bit, Translations</emu_category>
        <emu_version>10152019</emu_version>
        <emu_date>10/15/2019</emu_date>
        <emu_author>Zach Morris</emu_author>
        <emu_visibility>visible</emu_visibility>
        <emu_homepage>http://www.no-intro.org</emu_homepage>
        <emu_baseurl>http://archive.org/download/</emu_baseurl>
        <emu_launcher>retroplayer</emu_launcher>
        <emu_default_addon>none</emu_default_addon>
        <emu_ext_launch_cmd>none</emu_ext_launch_cmd>
        <emu_downloadpath>default</emu_downloadpath>
        <emu_postdlaction>unzip_rom</emu_postdlaction>
        <emu_comment>A fan translation is an unofficial translation of a video game made by fans. This is a list of just some of the Sega Genesis / Mega Drive translations available today.</emu_comment>
        <emu_thumb>s3VSnJ6.jpg</emu_thumb>
        <emu_banner>0rsZC3d.jpg</emu_banner>
        <emu_fanart>yMDOmLe.jpg</emu_fanart>
        <emu_logo>JPK7hvX.png</emu_logo>
        <emu_trailer></emu_trailer>
    </header>
  <game name="Advanced Busterhawk Gleylancer (Japan) [T-En by MIJET v20061023]">
    <description>Advanced Busterhawk Gleylancer (Japan) [T-En by MIJET v20061023]</description>
    <title_clean>Advanced Busterhawk Gleylancer</title_clean>
    <rom name="MaybeIntroTEn20121007/Maybe-Intro%20%5BT-En%5D%20%2820121007%29.zip/Sega%20Mega%20Drive%20%5BT-En%5D%2FAdvanced%20Busterhawk%20Gleylancer%20%28Japan%29%20%5BT-En%20by%20MIJET%20v20061023%5D.zip" size="789252"/>
    <plot>Gley Lancer is an Action game, developed and published by NCS,which was released in Japan in 1992.</plot>
    <genre>Action,Shooter,Scrolling</genre>
    <studio>Nebelwurfer HQ</studio>
    <releasedate>21/07/2008</releasedate>
    <gamefaqs_url>http://www.gamefaqs.com/genesis/578841-gley-lancer</gamefaqs_url>
    <boxart1>pY16BMB.png</boxart1>
    <snapshot1>0uCZi4S.png</snapshot1>
    <boxart2>RSDrJHB.jpg</boxart2>
    <snapshot2>u3W0swl.png</snapshot2>
  </game>
  <game name="Advanced Daisenryaku - Deutsch Dengeki Sakusen (Japan) (Rev A) [T-En by Nebelwurfer v0.95] [i]">
    <description>Advanced Daisenryaku - Deutsch Dengeki Sakusen (Japan) (Rev A) [T-En by Nebelwurfer v0.95] [i]</description>
    <title_clean>Advanced Daisenryaku - Deutsch Dengeki Sakusen</title_clean>
    <rom name="MaybeIntroTEn20121007/Maybe-Intro%20%5BT-En%5D%20%2820121007%29.zip/Sega%20Mega%20Drive%20%5BT-En%5D%2FAdvanced%20Daisenryaku%20-%20Deutsch%20Dengeki%20Sakusen%20%28Japan%29%20%28Rev%20A%29%20%5BT-En%20by%20Nebelwurfer%20v0.95%5D%20%5Bi%5D.zip" size="747190"/>
  </game>
  <game name="Bare Knuckle III ~ Streets of Rage 3 (Japan) [T-En by Twilight Translations v1.00] [n]">
    <description>Bare Knuckle III ~ Streets of Rage 3 (Japan) [T-En by Twilight Translations v1.00] [n]</description>
    <title_clean>Bare Knuckle III ~ Streets of Rage 3</title_clean>
    <rom name="MaybeIntroTEn20121007/Maybe-Intro%20%5BT-En%5D%20%2820121007%29.zip/Sega%20Mega%20Drive%20%5BT-En%5D%2FBare%20Knuckle%20III%20~%20Streets%20of%20Rage%203%20%28Japan%29%20%5BT-En%20by%20Twilight%20Translations%20v1.00%5D%20%5Bn%5D.zip" size="1771446"/>
    <plot>Streets of Rage 3 is an action beat 'em up game for the Sega[CR]Genesis.[CR]Read Me:[CR]Bare Knuckle 3[CR]English Patch[CR]Version[CR]1.00[CR]Initial Release: Feb. 15, 2009[CR]by Twilight[CR]Translations[CR]--------------------------------------[CR]1.[CR]Introduction[CR]2. Development[CR]3. Notes[CR]4. Patch History[CR]5.[CR]Credits[CR]6. Acknowledgements[CR]--------------------------------------[CR]1.[CR]Introduction[CR]--------------------------------------[CR]Released on March 3,[CR]1994, Bare Knuckle 3 (or Streets of Rage 3 as it came to be known[CR]outside[CR]Japan) is the third and final entry in the classic beatem up Mega Drive[CR]series[CR]Bare Knuckle.[CR]When BK3 was translated and released as Streets of[CR]Rage 3, Sega -- for whatever[CR]reason -- significantly altered the content of[CR]the game. The most obvious change was[CR]the story, or lack thereof. The[CR]entire introduction sequence was removed along with[CR]other scenes in the[CR]game. In addition to this, the difficulty in SoR3 was ramped up to[CR]insane[CR]levels, making SoR3s hard mode comparable to BK3s Very Hard mode. However,[CR]the[CR]most perplexing change was the characters palettes. Instead of wearing[CR]his usual[CR]white T-shirt and blue jeans, Axel was sporting jet black pants[CR]and a yellow shirt,[CR]reminiscent of Adams attire. The other characters[CR]suffered similar "improvements."[CR]The full list of changes made is well-[CR]documented and can be easily found online,[CR]so I wont dwell on the negative[CR]any further. What we have instead is a game that is[CR]a deserving successor[CR]to the Bare Knuckle/Streets of Rage legacy. This is hands down one[CR]of the[CR]greatest beatem ups released during the[CR]era.[CR]--------------------------------------[CR]2.[CR]Development[CR]--------------------------------------[CR]Ill be honest.[CR]Streets of Rage 2 is probably my hands-down favorite game of all time.[CR]I[CR]cant tell you how many hours of my youth were spent playing that game. So my[CR]interest[CR]in BK3 probably stems from there.[CR]The exact date I began[CR]working on BK3 with the intention to translate it isnt very clear,[CR]but the[CR]oldest file and emails related to this date back to early May 2006. Yeah,[CR]this[CR]projects been going on for a long time. I remember vaguely how it[CR]began, though. A group[CR]of hackers by the name of g8z_et_al (AKA z80_gaiden[CR]AKA Guest) had posted on RHDN concerning[CR]a Mega Drive game. Once I[CR]expressed my interest in BK3, they sent me a build of their modded[CR]version[CR]of Gens and the location of the Japanese font.[CR]So, I spent a few days (or[CR]weeks; Im not sure) studying the code to make sure that I was[CR]even capable[CR]of hacking a Mega Drive game. All of my experience up to this point had been[CR]on[CR]the NES and SNES and the MD was entirely different beast. In retrospect,[CR]Im actually kind[CR]of surprised that I didnt give up on the game. Anyway, I[CR]wrote a custom dumper and[CR]extracted the script. Then I contacted Anton[CR]Berglin, who had written a translation of[CR]BK3s text for Streets of Rage[CR]Online. He worked on it for a few months and finally sent[CR]me the script[CR]back around late November 2006. Thats where the long period of[CR]uncertainty[CR]began.[CR]Id like to think I produce only quality translations.[CR]To me, that typically means using a[CR]Variable Width-Font (VWF) where[CR]necessary and ensuring the script looks and sounds good in[CR]English. Both of[CR]these were necessary for BK3, but the former would prove much[CR]more[CR]difficult to implement than the latter. You see, I had no ASM[CR]experience with the MD or any[CR]68000-based system, nor was there a suitable[CR]68k assembler available. No, if I wanted the[CR]game to have a VWF I would[CR]have to make the assembler myself. Enter SEKAS.[CR]SEKAS (short for Sixty[CR]Eight K ASsembler) is a modified version of byuus excellent xkas[CR]with[CR]support added for the 68k processor (obviously). Creating SEKAS and testing it[CR]took[CR]easily a year of my life. I restarted the project twice that I know[CR]of, but Im almost[CR]certain the current build is the result of a third[CR]reboot. The first versions were the[CR]results of my attempting to write an[CR]assembler from scratch, on my own. The final version[CR]was a result of[CR]working directly with xkass source code. There are still a few bugs[CR]in[CR]SEKAS, which I discovered while working a demo of my own. Once these are[CR]fixed, I intend[CR]to release SEKAS.[CR]That puts us at late 2007 (work on[CR]SEKAS began in early December 2006) when work on BK3[CR]could finally resume.[CR]Due to lack of time and debugging Live-A-Live (another patch that[CR]I am[CR]extremely proud of) for Aeon Genesis, I dont think I started working on the[CR]VWF for[CR]BK3 until about February 2008. Once work finally began, it only[CR]took a month or so to get[CR]the VWF up and running perfectly. That left only[CR]the script editing.[CR]A fellow by the name of Valkyrie_Ace (AKA Roy_Fokker)[CR]volunteered to edit the script in[CR]early March 2008. Unfortunately, real[CR]life got in the way and it took VA until early[CR]November to get the first[CR]draft of the script back to me. I hooked back up with Anton[CR]to look over[CR]the script and let him voice any of his concerns...and thats the last I[CR]heard[CR]from either of them. Im not sure what happened. Alas. Hoping they[CR]would resurface to finish[CR]the script, I let the first draft sit on my[CR]harddrive until early January 2009 when I[CR]decided I would finish the[CR]editing myself. And that brings us to today.[CR]Beta testing is in progress as[CR]I type this. Sliver X has run through the game and has only[CR]found two[CR]typos. Christuserloser is running through the game with his flashcart to[CR]ensure[CR]there are no problems with the various platforms he has access to. I[CR]ran through the game[CR]earlier on my model 2 Genesis with no problems.[CR]In[CR]closing, Id just like to say that I hope you all enjoy this patch. This[CR]project in some[CR]form or another has been a huge part of my life for the[CR]past 3 years, and Im almost sad to[CR]see it come to an end. Fortunately my[CR]happiness overshadows my sadness. Grab a buddy and[CR]enjoy some old school[CR]beatem up action on me.[CR]--------------------------------------[CR]3.[CR]Notes[CR]--------------------------------------[CR]If youve followed along[CR]with this project, youll know that Ive contemplated releasing two[CR]patches:[CR]one using the original Bare Knuckle 3 names and another using the Streets of[CR]Rage 3[CR]names (Skate instead of Sammy, Roo, not Victy, etc) and title[CR]screen. In the end I decided[CR]against this for two reason. First, importing[CR]the title screen is a significant amount of work[CR]that I dont want to do.[CR]Second, where do I draw the line on the names? Only player characters[CR]or do[CR]I change the enemy names too to be consistent with SoR1 and SoR2? I couldnt[CR]come up with[CR]an answer, so Ive chosen to release only one patch. Besides,[CR]now when the pirates sell RARE L@@K[CR]copies of ENGLISH BARE KNUCKLE 3 on[CR]eBay, Ill know exactly how much money someone has made off of my[CR]work.[CR]--------------------------------------[CR]4. Patch[CR]History[CR]--------------------------------------[CR]-Version 1.00[CR] All the[CR]text in the game has been translated. This includes both dialogue in the story[CR]mode[CR] and the win/lose quotes in the Battle mode, and the Engrish in the[CR]battle mode has been fixed.[CR] The patch has been thoroughly tested and works[CR]on the hardware. If you find a platform it[CR] doesnt work on, let me[CR]know.[CR] Included files:[CR] *bk3_100.ips - The English translation.[CR]Overall, Im extremely happy with the quality of the patch. This is probably[CR]the cleanest[CR] code Ive ever hacked into a game. Everything about this patch[CR]was fun to do, and hopefully[CR] that shows.[CR] [CR] There are currently no[CR]known bugs. Please note, however, that the patch has only been tested[CR] on[CR]an American Sega Genesis Model 2. The code has been written in such a way that[CR]it should[CR] work on all models, though.[CR]--------------------------------------[CR]5.[CR]Credits[CR]--------------------------------------[CR]Bare Knuckle[CR]3[CR]Translation Team:[CR]RedComet - Programmer (me)[CR]Anton Berglin -[CR]Translator[CR]Sheex - Translator[CR]Valkyrie_Ace - Editor[CR]Testing and QA[CR]Team:[CR]Sliver[CR]X[CR]Christuserloser[CR]--------------------------------------[CR]6.[CR]Acknowledgements[CR]--------------------------------------[CR]In addition to[CR]the people listed in the Credits section, a few people deserve a[CR]special[CR]mention, without whom, this project would never have been[CR]completed:[CR]* g8z_et_al - You guys have helped me so much. Without you I[CR]probably wouldnt be the hacker[CR] I am today. I hope you know how much I[CR]appreciate it![CR]* Suzaku - A partner in crime and more importantly a friend,[CR]whos helped out with on[CR] the spot translations and editing advice.[CR]* The[CR]fans - The encouragement from members of various online communities (Sega-16,[CR]Streets[CR] of Rage Remake, Streets of Rage Online, and more) has been[CR]overwhelmingly[CR] positive even in the projects darkest hours. The praise and[CR]doubt kept me[CR] going. Thanks guys.[CR] [CR]And lastly all the people whose[CR]names Ive forgotten. Thank you very much.</plot>
    <studio>Twilight Translations</studio>
    <snapshot1>T1QBcQf.jpg</snapshot1>
    <snapshot2>b4Ci9Vb.png</snapshot2>
  </game>
  <game name="Battle Mania Daiginjou ~ Trouble Shooter Vintage (Japan, Korea) [T-En by MIJET v20061029] (Battle Mania Mode) [n]">
    <description>Battle Mania Daiginjou ~ Trouble Shooter Vintage (Japan, Korea) [T-En by MIJET v20061029] (Battle Mania Mode) [n]</description>
    <title_clean>Battle Mania Daiginjou ~ Trouble Shooter Vintage</title_clean>
    <rom name="MaybeIntroTEn20121007/Maybe-Intro%20%5BT-En%5D%20%2820121007%29.zip/Sega%20Mega%20Drive%20%5BT-En%5D%2FBattle%20Mania%20Daiginjou%20~%20Trouble%20Shooter%20Vintage%20%28Japan%2C%20Korea%29%20%5BT-En%20by%20MIJET%20v20061029%5D%20%28Battle%20Mania%20Mode%29%20%5Bn%5D.zip" size="722378"/>
    <plot>Battle Mania Daiginjou is the sequel to the game we got stateside known as[CR]Trouble Shooter, and, like all good things in the video game world, it was[CR]left in Japan. Looks fun though.[CR]Read Me:[CR]Patch version 061029[CR](yymmdd)[CR]Readme version 070121 (yymmdd)[CR] Battle Mania Daiginjou /[CR]Trouble Shooter Vintage[CR] English Translation Patch[CR] by M.I.J.E.T.[CR]History[CR]-----------------------------------------------------------------------------[CR]061029[CR]Initial release[CR]Overview[CR]-----------------------------------------------------------------------------[CR]This[CR]is a translation patch for the Mega Drive game "Battle Mania Daiginjou".[CR]In[CR]what has become a MIJET trademark, this is a "dual-language" patch,[CR]meaning[CR]that it supports both Japanese and English. However, it goes far[CR]beyond[CR]simply supporting both English and the original Japanese; it contains[CR]two[CR]different English translations and a selection of three English fonts.[CR]This[CR]patch is contained within two different IPS files, but the only[CR]differences[CR]between the two are the default script and font to use if none[CR]are selected[CR]by the user. Thats correct; it is possible to select the[CR]desired script and[CR]font by holding down certain combinations of buttons prior[CR]to the Sega logo[CR]appearing.[CR] Applying the[CR]Patch[CR]-----------------------------------------------------------------------------[CR]Hopefully[CR]included with this document are two patch files in the IPS format.[CR]You can[CR]use any program that supports this file format to apply one of the[CR]patches[CR]to your ROM file.[CR]Alternatively, you can use the supplied executable[CR]program to apply the[CR]patch. The program supports all currently available[CR]MIJET translations.[CR]It will check the ROM file (de-interleaving it if[CR]necessary) and will give[CR]you an error message if something went wrong. A[CR]normal IPS program cannot[CR]do this as it has no idea what it is patching.[CR]The program has not been[CR]extensively tested, so if you have problems (or[CR]simply dont trust a foreign[CR]executable) you always have the option of using[CR]a different program.[CR]There are two versions of this game that I am aware[CR]of: one released in 1993[CR]and one released in 1995. The two versions are[CR]practically identical, except[CR]that the 1995 version gives incorrect results[CR]during the system test screen.[CR]There are also numerous hacks and one[CR]damaged file circulating around the[CR]internet. This patch will properly[CR]overwrite all the hacked versions that[CR]Ive encountered, but not the damaged[CR]file. It will also revert the 1995[CR]version back to the superior 1993[CR]edition.[CR]It is recommended that you use the supplied program to patch your[CR]ROM file,[CR]because it performs lots of error checking. It now supports all[CR]MIJET[CR]translations; just make sure that all your files are up-to-[CR]date.[CR]Please note that you are morally obligated to own an original copy of[CR]this[CR]game in order to use the ROM file. At the time of this writing, the[CR]price[CR]of honesty was over $100. One thing you dont get from this patch is[CR]the[CR]manual, which has some good stuff in it; the short manga is pretty[CR]funny,[CR]even if you cant read Japanese.[CR] Playing the[CR]Game[CR]-----------------------------------------------------------------------------[CR]Once[CR]youve patched the ROM file, simply load it up in your favorite[CR]Genesis /[CR]Mega Drive emulator, console copier, or flash cartridge.[CR]The game will[CR]detect the country code of your machine (real or emulated) and[CR]then switch[CR]to English or Japanese mode accordingly. The script and font[CR]that are used[CR]will depend on which of the two patches you applied. However,[CR]you can[CR]change the default behavior (and override the country code) by[CR]holding down[CR]certain buttons while the game is powering up or resetting:[CR]A + Start[CR]Original Japanese script[CR]B + Start Battle Mania Daiginjou English[CR]script[CR]C + Start Trouble Shooter Vintage English script[CR]Left + Start[CR]All-capital indigenous font[CR]Right + Start All-capital indigenous font[CR](thicker)[CR]Up + Start Upper- and lower-case font[CR]ABC + Start Normally[CR]youd have to unplug your pad to see this...[CR]You can combine buttons to[CR]change both the script and the font. As you can[CR]see, you must always hold[CR]down the start button to get any effect.[CR]You should hear a sound effect if[CR]the trick worked (and sometimes even if[CR]it didnt, in case you pressed the[CR]wrong buttons). Thats your cue to[CR]release the buttons if you want to see[CR]the introductory material (otherwise[CR]youll skip straight to the title[CR]screen).[CR] Patch[CR]Differences[CR]-----------------------------------------------------------------------------[CR]The[CR]"Trouble Shooter Vintage" version was intended to look and feel like[CR]an[CR]official English translation. It follows the naming conventions of[CR]"Trouble[CR]Shooter" (which was the official translation of the first game in[CR]the series)[CR]and defaults to using an all-capital font, just like in the[CR]original. Some[CR]of the language was also toned down a bit, which was typical[CR]for games in[CR]that time period. A little bit of stuff (not in the script)[CR]got thrown out[CR]as would have undoubtedly happened in an official[CR]localization at that time.[CR]The credits sequence should have been axed as[CR]well, as it would not have made[CR]it overseas, but I wanted to have two[CR]different versions of the credits too.[CR]The translation is also quite a bit[CR]"looser", although it is still much more[CR]accurate than Trouble Shooter was;[CR]although some English idioms were used,[CR]no Western culture references were[CR]permitted in this script.[CR]The "Battle Mania Daiginjou" patch was intended[CR]to be much more accurate,[CR]even to the point that you might not understand[CR]parts of it if you dont[CR]know anything about Japanese culture. To be honest,[CR]you might not fully[CR]understand it even if you are a Japanese native, as a[CR]few of the allusions[CR]are somewhat obscure. Many of the graphics were[CR]subtitled in this version[CR]and the original names were used.[CR]The[CR]differences are significant enough that you will probably enjoy[CR]playing[CR]both versions at least once.[CR]BTW, if you are too hasty you might[CR]miss some of the text in the weapon[CR]selection scenes. The length of the[CR]both the text and the pauses varies[CR]so be patient before you start pressing[CR]buttons or you might miss something.[CR] Q and[CR]A[CR]-----------------------------------------------------------------------------[CR]Q:[CR]Which of the two patch files should I use?[CR]A: It doesnt really matter; they[CR]are basically identical internally; the[CR] only difference is that one[CR]defaults to "Battle Mania" mode and the other[CR] other defaults to "Trouble[CR]Shooter" mode. See the above section for more[CR] details on the differences.[CR]The Trouble Shooter version will probably[CR] be preferred by the majority of[CR]people though.[CR]Q: This patch doesnt work! What do I do?[CR]A: Make sure[CR]your ROM file is not in an interleaved format. Its also[CR] possible that[CR]there is more than one version of the game, or that your[CR] copy is corrupt.[CR]If you have problems, try using the program that I wrote[CR] to apply the[CR]patch; it checks for the above issues. If my program doesnt[CR] work for some[CR]reason, you can try a different IPS patching program, but[CR] you will lose[CR]the benefit of having your ROM file checked.[CR]Q: It doesnt work with my[CR]copier / flash cartridge! Why not?[CR] This was tested on a real Genesis so[CR]you shouldnt have any problems in[CR] that respect. The most likely reason is[CR]that something went wrong during[CR] the patching process. See the previous[CR]question and try it in an emulator[CR] to see if that works.[CR] Another[CR]possibility is that you are using a PAL Mega Drive; this game was[CR] designed[CR]for NTSC systems and I didnt make any changes in that respect.[CR] It should[CR]still run (probably at the wrong speed), but you never know...[CR] In any[CR]case, let me know about the problem and Ill try to fix it.[CR]Q: Is your[CR]patcher program safe?[CR]A: No. Anyone could replace it with a trojan and[CR]rewrite this readme to[CR] make it seem safe. Thats one reason why I dont[CR]include it with the[CR] patch itself. Its up to you to decide which program to[CR]use to apply[CR] the patch, but unless you wrote the program yourself, theres[CR]always[CR] some risk involved.[CR]Q: Why is the text in Japanese?!?[CR]A: This[CR]is a dual-language translation patch; if it detects that it is[CR] running on[CR]a Japanese system it will use the original game script.[CR] If you are using[CR]an emulator, make sure the country code is set to USA.[CR] Also, the game can[CR]be configured to run in any mode, regardless of[CR] the machines country code,[CR]by holding down certain buttons as the[CR] game starts. See the relevant[CR]section for details.[CR]Q: Why are the credits written sideways??[CR]A:[CR]Although English is more esthetically pleasing when written vertically,[CR] it[CR]is much easier to read when printed sideways. If you doubt this, just[CR]visit a library and examine the spines of the books. This is a lesson[CR] many[CR]subtitlers have yet to learn, unfortunately.[CR]Q: Why was Manias name changed[CR]to Madison?[CR]A: Manias name was changed to Madison when Battle Mania was[CR]localized for[CR] the Western market as Trouble Shooter. The "Trouble Shooter[CR]Vintage"[CR] version of this patch tries to maintain consistency with the[CR]original[CR] translation of Trouble Shooter, whereas the "Battle Mania[CR]Daiginjou"[CR] version uses the original names and spellings.[CR] If youre[CR]wondering why they changed her name in Trouble Shooter, it[CR] was because[CR]"Mania" would be seen as a rather odd name by Occidental[CR] audiences.[CR]Q:[CR]Why was Marias name changed to Crystal in the original Trouble Shooter?[CR]A:[CR]Maria is certainly a normal-sounding name, but I think they might have[CR]changed it so it would be the same size as "Madison" in the intro.[CR] Maria[CR]is the blue-haired girl, in case you were wondering... (her name is[CR] not[CR]used anywhere in this game).[CR]Q: "She"?? (this question applies to "Battle[CR]Mania Daiginjou" only)[CR]A: This is correct. Its very difficult to properly[CR]translate certain[CR] phrases without using gender pronouns (which arent[CR]normally used in[CR] Japanese), but the pronouns used always accurately[CR]represent the[CR] characters perceptions.[CR]Q: Why arent the kanji / kana in[CR]the in-game backgrounds translated?[CR]A: Its a lot of work, its difficult to[CR]redraw them while maintaining[CR] anything close to their original meanings,[CR]it detracts from their original[CR] beauty, it could be distracting, and it[CR]wouldnt provide much additional[CR] meaning anyway. Translations for some of[CR]them are included in this file,[CR] for those who are interested, so see[CR]below.[CR]Q: What does the text just before you fight Kikokusai mean?[CR]A:[CR]Something like "Kikokusai arrives".[CR]Q: What does the text on the Hard Mode[CR]ending screen mean?[CR]A: Something along the lines of "Ohtorii Party".[CR]Q:[CR]Why dont you acknowledge trademarks?[CR]A: Acknowledgment of trademarks, along[CR]with "no warranty" clauses,[CR] are good examples of how the legal professions[CR]has managed to[CR] increase its power by fooling the populace at large, who[CR]eventually[CR] came to believe that the "legalese" they were reading[CR]actually[CR] carried some sort of legal weight. With a few rare[CR]exceptions,[CR] anyone who acknowledges trademarks in some sort of written[CR]material[CR] is either naive or a coward, and often both.[CR] Do your research[CR]and start thinking critically, people! Oh, and[CR] that official-sounding "no[CR]warranty" disclaimer isnt going to do[CR] anything either, except intimidate[CR]people, one of the prime uses of[CR] modern law...[CR]Q: Why is this readme[CR]file so short?[CR]A: For additional fascinating reading and social commentary,[CR]see the notes[CR] for the (updated!) King Colossus patch. Much of the general[CR]information[CR] applies to this translation as well, in case you are wondering[CR]about[CR] things like accuracy and the methods used.[CR]A: Best compiler ever[CR]made.[CR]Q: What is SAS/C?[CR] List of Changes (not[CR]exhaustive)[CR]-----------------------------------------------------------------------------[CR]Fixed[CR]a rare bug in the original text routines[CR]Fixed a text alignment error in[CR]stage 9 in the original[CR]Original Japanese title screen logo was[CR]centered[CR]User-configurable fonts and game mode (Battle Mania or Trouble[CR]Shooter)[CR]The Vic Tokai screen was translated / subtitled two different[CR]ways[CR]Text sprites in the recap animation were translated[CR]The giant logo[CR]in the intro was expanded and translated two different ways[CR]Two English[CR]title screens, one for each version[CR]Minor fixes to the advertisement and[CR]options screens[CR]Text routines were modified for 8x8 fonts[CR]The entire[CR]game script was translated two different ways[CR]Subtitled the logo that[CR]appears between certain stages (BMD only)[CR]The English credits font is[CR]dynamically rotated[CR]The credits were translated two different ways[CR]Transliteration[CR]Notes[CR]-----------------------------------------------------------------------------[CR]The[CR]following table shows how the various names were translated[CR]or[CR]transliterated. The first column shows the original names while[CR]the[CR]other columns represent the names used in the two translations.[CR]They were[CR]based in part on the first game: Battle Mania / Trouble[CR]Shooter.[CR]BATORUMANIA Daiginjou Battle Mania Daiginjou Trouble Shooter[CR]Vintage[CR]--------------------- ----------------------[CR]-----------------------[CR]DON MORUGUSUTEIN * Don Morgstein[CR]Blackball[CR]Ootorii MANIA Mania Ohtorii ** Madison[CR]MANIyan (nickname)[CR]Mani-yan Madison[CR]Haneda MARIA Maria Haneda Crystal[CR]PATCHI Taisa Colonel[CR]Patch Col. Patch[CR]KIKOKUSAI Kikokusai Pure Ghost Wail ***[CR]* Due to[CR]technical limitations, the game spells this TEI, but it was written[CR]in the[CR]manual as TE+I (little I).[CR]** This spelling is for consistency with Battle[CR]Mania, where the "oo" in[CR]Ootorii is romanized as "oh", which is an[CR]acceptable alternative.[CR]*** A rough translation of the kanji that make up[CR]this name. A perfect[CR]translation is absolutely impossible, of course.[CR]According to the[CR]instruction booklet, Kikokusai is the characters given[CR]name; the full name[CR]is Kikoku Kikokusai (surname first). They most likely[CR]did this to be[CR]funny / annoying (same thing for Kikokukyou).[CR]Please note[CR]that many of the above names are not actually used in the game[CR]itself, so[CR]dont be surprised if you dont see them in the translation.[CR] Cultural Notes[CR](not[CR]exhaustive)[CR]-----------------------------------------------------------------------------[CR]Baania[CR](Vernier) [CR]The word "vernier" is sometimes used to refer to small rockets[CR]or other[CR]propulsion devices used to make small adjustments to a flying[CR]objects[CR]trajectory. The term as used in Gundam and other Japanese[CR]creations[CR]seems to have a somewhat different meaning, however, but still[CR]refers[CR]to a type of propulsion device. Here, it was translated as "jet[CR]pack".[CR]Benten[CR]Benten is a Japanese goddess associated with the island of[CR]Enoshima. She[CR]originated in Hinduism and was introduced to Japan by[CR]Buddhist monks while[CR]they were ruining Japans indigenous culture. She is[CR]also called Benzaiten.[CR]Enoshima[CR]Enoshima refers to both a Japanese[CR]seaside town and a nearby small island.[CR]Aside from the Benten connection,[CR]which is not important to the story anyway,[CR]theres not a lot to say about[CR]it except that it has nice beaches. Maria[CR]wants to go swimming while they[CR]are there, but Mania is disappointed that[CR]they dont have enough money left[CR]to buy much in the way of treats.[CR]Gachapin[CR]Gachapin seems to be a kind[CR]of spokesperson for Japanese television[CR]channel(s). He is a green dinosaur[CR]that appears occasionally in cultural or[CR]sports-related contexts. He is[CR]played by a person wearing a costume,[CR]but Gachapin doesnt look much like a[CR]dinosaur to me, at least not from[CR]the front.[CR]Food[CR]There are lots of[CR]Japanese foods / restaurants listed near the end of the[CR]credits. Presumably[CR]these are places where the team ate at during[CR]development.[CR]Garage[CR]Kits[CR]This term refers to hobby items, such as plastic models.[CR]Heisei[CR]Babylon, 1995[CR]This bit of text establishes the initial setting for the[CR]game. Heisei is the[CR]name of the current (as of 2006) Japanese era, so the[CR]time is 1995 AD and[CR]"Babylon" is the location. The short manga in the[CR]instruction booklet has[CR]Morgstein telling Mania that hes waiting for her at[CR]"Heisei Babylon" and[CR]goes on to explain that it refers to the offices of[CR]the Tokyo Government.[CR]Inflatables[CR]In the apartment, Maria is wearing a[CR]swim suit and carrying an inflatable[CR]alligator (or some similar reptile),[CR]while the portrait shows her holding[CR]an inner-tube. Shes ready to go[CR]swimming at Enoshima.[CR]Moon[CR]Supposedly a reference to Sailor Moon. The[CR]sentence it is used in is a[CR]parody of a line from one of the episodes, or[CR]so Ive been told.[CR]Tamegoro-[CR]Tamegoro- is a pretend character (i.e. never[CR]actually appearing on the show,[CR]much like Vern) from a 1960s television[CR]show called GEBAGEBA90Fun. The[CR]phrase "atto odoroku TAMEGORO-" was often[CR]used during the show and it became[CR]something of a pop culture saying,[CR]although its fairly obscure today.[CR]It was spelled "Tamegoro" in the[CR]translation, but including the "dash" is[CR]the correct way to write[CR]it.[CR]Uterundesu[CR]It isnt clear exactly what this is referring to. It might[CR]be a somewhat[CR]obscure reference to some sort of comedy act, or it could be[CR]a misspelling[CR]of utsurundesu. In the latter case it could refer to several[CR]things,[CR]including a brand of camera or a manga. (The former is supposedly a[CR]play[CR]on words of the same camera brand, if my information is correct.)[CR]Contact[CR]-----------------------------------------------------------------------------[CR]tougi_ou@yahoo.com[CR]I[CR]cannot guarantee a timely reply; this address is sometimes not checked[CR]for[CR]weeks or months at a time, depending on recent activity levels.[CR]And[CR]on the web:[CR]http://www.geocities.com/tougi_ou/</plot>
    <studio>M.I.J.E.T.</studio>
    <snapshot1>EQlEOls.png</snapshot1>
    <snapshot2>PI6F3cA.png</snapshot2>
  </game>
  <game name="Battle Mania Daiginjou ~ Trouble Shooter Vintage (Japan, Korea) [T-En by MIJET v20061029] (Trouble Shooter Mode) [n]">
    <description>Battle Mania Daiginjou ~ Trouble Shooter Vintage (Japan, Korea) [T-En by MIJET v20061029] (Trouble Shooter Mode) [n]</description>
    <title_clean>Battle Mania Daiginjou ~ Trouble Shooter Vintage</title_clean>
    <rom name="MaybeIntroTEn20121007/Maybe-Intro%20%5BT-En%5D%20%2820121007%29.zip/Sega%20Mega%20Drive%20%5BT-En%5D%2FBattle%20Mania%20Daiginjou%20~%20Trouble%20Shooter%20Vintage%20%28Japan%2C%20Korea%29%20%5BT-En%20by%20MIJET%20v20061029%5D%20%28Trouble%20Shooter%20Mode%29%20%5Bn%5D.zip" size="722386"/>
    <plot>Battle Mania Daiginjou is the sequel to the game we got stateside known as[CR]Trouble Shooter, and, like all good things in the video game world, it was[CR]left in Japan. Looks fun though.[CR]Read Me:[CR]Patch version 061029[CR](yymmdd)[CR]Readme version 070121 (yymmdd)[CR] Battle Mania Daiginjou /[CR]Trouble Shooter Vintage[CR] English Translation Patch[CR] by M.I.J.E.T.[CR]History[CR]-----------------------------------------------------------------------------[CR]061029[CR]Initial release[CR]Overview[CR]-----------------------------------------------------------------------------[CR]This[CR]is a translation patch for the Mega Drive game "Battle Mania Daiginjou".[CR]In[CR]what has become a MIJET trademark, this is a "dual-language" patch,[CR]meaning[CR]that it supports both Japanese and English. However, it goes far[CR]beyond[CR]simply supporting both English and the original Japanese; it contains[CR]two[CR]different English translations and a selection of three English fonts.[CR]This[CR]patch is contained within two different IPS files, but the only[CR]differences[CR]between the two are the default script and font to use if none[CR]are selected[CR]by the user. Thats correct; it is possible to select the[CR]desired script and[CR]font by holding down certain combinations of buttons prior[CR]to the Sega logo[CR]appearing.[CR] Applying the[CR]Patch[CR]-----------------------------------------------------------------------------[CR]Hopefully[CR]included with this document are two patch files in the IPS format.[CR]You can[CR]use any program that supports this file format to apply one of the[CR]patches[CR]to your ROM file.[CR]Alternatively, you can use the supplied executable[CR]program to apply the[CR]patch. The program supports all currently available[CR]MIJET translations.[CR]It will check the ROM file (de-interleaving it if[CR]necessary) and will give[CR]you an error message if something went wrong. A[CR]normal IPS program cannot[CR]do this as it has no idea what it is patching.[CR]The program has not been[CR]extensively tested, so if you have problems (or[CR]simply dont trust a foreign[CR]executable) you always have the option of using[CR]a different program.[CR]There are two versions of this game that I am aware[CR]of: one released in 1993[CR]and one released in 1995. The two versions are[CR]practically identical, except[CR]that the 1995 version gives incorrect results[CR]during the system test screen.[CR]There are also numerous hacks and one[CR]damaged file circulating around the[CR]internet. This patch will properly[CR]overwrite all the hacked versions that[CR]Ive encountered, but not the damaged[CR]file. It will also revert the 1995[CR]version back to the superior 1993[CR]edition.[CR]It is recommended that you use the supplied program to patch your[CR]ROM file,[CR]because it performs lots of error checking. It now supports all[CR]MIJET[CR]translations; just make sure that all your files are up-to-[CR]date.[CR]Please note that you are morally obligated to own an original copy of[CR]this[CR]game in order to use the ROM file. At the time of this writing, the[CR]price[CR]of honesty was over $100. One thing you dont get from this patch is[CR]the[CR]manual, which has some good stuff in it; the short manga is pretty[CR]funny,[CR]even if you cant read Japanese.[CR] Playing the[CR]Game[CR]-----------------------------------------------------------------------------[CR]Once[CR]youve patched the ROM file, simply load it up in your favorite[CR]Genesis /[CR]Mega Drive emulator, console copier, or flash cartridge.[CR]The game will[CR]detect the country code of your machine (real or emulated) and[CR]then switch[CR]to English or Japanese mode accordingly. The script and font[CR]that are used[CR]will depend on which of the two patches you applied. However,[CR]you can[CR]change the default behavior (and override the country code) by[CR]holding down[CR]certain buttons while the game is powering up or resetting:[CR]A + Start[CR]Original Japanese script[CR]B + Start Battle Mania Daiginjou English[CR]script[CR]C + Start Trouble Shooter Vintage English script[CR]Left + Start[CR]All-capital indigenous font[CR]Right + Start All-capital indigenous font[CR](thicker)[CR]Up + Start Upper- and lower-case font[CR]ABC + Start Normally[CR]youd have to unplug your pad to see this...[CR]You can combine buttons to[CR]change both the script and the font. As you can[CR]see, you must always hold[CR]down the start button to get any effect.[CR]You should hear a sound effect if[CR]the trick worked (and sometimes even if[CR]it didnt, in case you pressed the[CR]wrong buttons). Thats your cue to[CR]release the buttons if you want to see[CR]the introductory material (otherwise[CR]youll skip straight to the title[CR]screen).[CR] Patch[CR]Differences[CR]-----------------------------------------------------------------------------[CR]The[CR]"Trouble Shooter Vintage" version was intended to look and feel like[CR]an[CR]official English translation. It follows the naming conventions of[CR]"Trouble[CR]Shooter" (which was the official translation of the first game in[CR]the series)[CR]and defaults to using an all-capital font, just like in the[CR]original. Some[CR]of the language was also toned down a bit, which was typical[CR]for games in[CR]that time period. A little bit of stuff (not in the script)[CR]got thrown out[CR]as would have undoubtedly happened in an official[CR]localization at that time.[CR]The credits sequence should have been axed as[CR]well, as it would not have made[CR]it overseas, but I wanted to have two[CR]different versions of the credits too.[CR]The translation is also quite a bit[CR]"looser", although it is still much more[CR]accurate than Trouble Shooter was;[CR]although some English idioms were used,[CR]no Western culture references were[CR]permitted in this script.[CR]The "Battle Mania Daiginjou" patch was intended[CR]to be much more accurate,[CR]even to the point that you might not understand[CR]parts of it if you dont[CR]know anything about Japanese culture. To be honest,[CR]you might not fully[CR]understand it even if you are a Japanese native, as a[CR]few of the allusions[CR]are somewhat obscure. Many of the graphics were[CR]subtitled in this version[CR]and the original names were used.[CR]The[CR]differences are significant enough that you will probably enjoy[CR]playing[CR]both versions at least once.[CR]BTW, if you are too hasty you might[CR]miss some of the text in the weapon[CR]selection scenes. The length of the[CR]both the text and the pauses varies[CR]so be patient before you start pressing[CR]buttons or you might miss something.[CR] Q and[CR]A[CR]-----------------------------------------------------------------------------[CR]Q:[CR]Which of the two patch files should I use?[CR]A: It doesnt really matter; they[CR]are basically identical internally; the[CR] only difference is that one[CR]defaults to "Battle Mania" mode and the other[CR] other defaults to "Trouble[CR]Shooter" mode. See the above section for more[CR] details on the differences.[CR]The Trouble Shooter version will probably[CR] be preferred by the majority of[CR]people though.[CR]Q: This patch doesnt work! What do I do?[CR]A: Make sure[CR]your ROM file is not in an interleaved format. Its also[CR] possible that[CR]there is more than one version of the game, or that your[CR] copy is corrupt.[CR]If you have problems, try using the program that I wrote[CR] to apply the[CR]patch; it checks for the above issues. If my program doesnt[CR] work for some[CR]reason, you can try a different IPS patching program, but[CR] you will lose[CR]the benefit of having your ROM file checked.[CR]Q: It doesnt work with my[CR]copier / flash cartridge! Why not?[CR] This was tested on a real Genesis so[CR]you shouldnt have any problems in[CR] that respect. The most likely reason is[CR]that something went wrong during[CR] the patching process. See the previous[CR]question and try it in an emulator[CR] to see if that works.[CR] Another[CR]possibility is that you are using a PAL Mega Drive; this game was[CR] designed[CR]for NTSC systems and I didnt make any changes in that respect.[CR] It should[CR]still run (probably at the wrong speed), but you never know...[CR] In any[CR]case, let me know about the problem and Ill try to fix it.[CR]Q: Is your[CR]patcher program safe?[CR]A: No. Anyone could replace it with a trojan and[CR]rewrite this readme to[CR] make it seem safe. Thats one reason why I dont[CR]include it with the[CR] patch itself. Its up to you to decide which program to[CR]use to apply[CR] the patch, but unless you wrote the program yourself, theres[CR]always[CR] some risk involved.[CR]Q: Why is the text in Japanese?!?[CR]A: This[CR]is a dual-language translation patch; if it detects that it is[CR] running on[CR]a Japanese system it will use the original game script.[CR] If you are using[CR]an emulator, make sure the country code is set to USA.[CR] Also, the game can[CR]be configured to run in any mode, regardless of[CR] the machines country code,[CR]by holding down certain buttons as the[CR] game starts. See the relevant[CR]section for details.[CR]Q: Why are the credits written sideways??[CR]A:[CR]Although English is more esthetically pleasing when written vertically,[CR] it[CR]is much easier to read when printed sideways. If you doubt this, just[CR]visit a library and examine the spines of the books. This is a lesson[CR] many[CR]subtitlers have yet to learn, unfortunately.[CR]Q: Why was Manias name changed[CR]to Madison?[CR]A: Manias name was changed to Madison when Battle Mania was[CR]localized for[CR] the Western market as Trouble Shooter. The "Trouble Shooter[CR]Vintage"[CR] version of this patch tries to maintain consistency with the[CR]original[CR] translation of Trouble Shooter, whereas the "Battle Mania[CR]Daiginjou"[CR] version uses the original names and spellings.[CR] If youre[CR]wondering why they changed her name in Trouble Shooter, it[CR] was because[CR]"Mania" would be seen as a rather odd name by Occidental[CR] audiences.[CR]Q:[CR]Why was Marias name changed to Crystal in the original Trouble Shooter?[CR]A:[CR]Maria is certainly a normal-sounding name, but I think they might have[CR]changed it so it would be the same size as "Madison" in the intro.[CR] Maria[CR]is the blue-haired girl, in case you were wondering... (her name is[CR] not[CR]used anywhere in this game).[CR]Q: "She"?? (this question applies to "Battle[CR]Mania Daiginjou" only)[CR]A: This is correct. Its very difficult to properly[CR]translate certain[CR] phrases without using gender pronouns (which arent[CR]normally used in[CR] Japanese), but the pronouns used always accurately[CR]represent the[CR] characters perceptions.[CR]Q: Why arent the kanji / kana in[CR]the in-game backgrounds translated?[CR]A: Its a lot of work, its difficult to[CR]redraw them while maintaining[CR] anything close to their original meanings,[CR]it detracts from their original[CR] beauty, it could be distracting, and it[CR]wouldnt provide much additional[CR] meaning anyway. Translations for some of[CR]them are included in this file,[CR] for those who are interested, so see[CR]below.[CR]Q: What does the text just before you fight Kikokusai mean?[CR]A:[CR]Something like "Kikokusai arrives".[CR]Q: What does the text on the Hard Mode[CR]ending screen mean?[CR]A: Something along the lines of "Ohtorii Party".[CR]Q:[CR]Why dont you acknowledge trademarks?[CR]A: Acknowledgment of trademarks, along[CR]with "no warranty" clauses,[CR] are good examples of how the legal professions[CR]has managed to[CR] increase its power by fooling the populace at large, who[CR]eventually[CR] came to believe that the "legalese" they were reading[CR]actually[CR] carried some sort of legal weight. With a few rare[CR]exceptions,[CR] anyone who acknowledges trademarks in some sort of written[CR]material[CR] is either naive or a coward, and often both.[CR] Do your research[CR]and start thinking critically, people! Oh, and[CR] that official-sounding "no[CR]warranty" disclaimer isnt going to do[CR] anything either, except intimidate[CR]people, one of the prime uses of[CR] modern law...[CR]Q: Why is this readme[CR]file so short?[CR]A: For additional fascinating reading and social commentary,[CR]see the notes[CR] for the (updated!) King Colossus patch. Much of the general[CR]information[CR] applies to this translation as well, in case you are wondering[CR]about[CR] things like accuracy and the methods used.[CR]A: Best compiler ever[CR]made.[CR]Q: What is SAS/C?[CR] List of Changes (not[CR]exhaustive)[CR]-----------------------------------------------------------------------------[CR]Fixed[CR]a rare bug in the original text routines[CR]Fixed a text alignment error in[CR]stage 9 in the original[CR]Original Japanese title screen logo was[CR]centered[CR]User-configurable fonts and game mode (Battle Mania or Trouble[CR]Shooter)[CR]The Vic Tokai screen was translated / subtitled two different[CR]ways[CR]Text sprites in the recap animation were translated[CR]The giant logo[CR]in the intro was expanded and translated two different ways[CR]Two English[CR]title screens, one for each version[CR]Minor fixes to the advertisement and[CR]options screens[CR]Text routines were modified for 8x8 fonts[CR]The entire[CR]game script was translated two different ways[CR]Subtitled the logo that[CR]appears between certain stages (BMD only)[CR]The English credits font is[CR]dynamically rotated[CR]The credits were translated two different ways[CR]Transliteration[CR]Notes[CR]-----------------------------------------------------------------------------[CR]The[CR]following table shows how the various names were translated[CR]or[CR]transliterated. The first column shows the original names while[CR]the[CR]other columns represent the names used in the two translations.[CR]They were[CR]based in part on the first game: Battle Mania / Trouble[CR]Shooter.[CR]BATORUMANIA Daiginjou Battle Mania Daiginjou Trouble Shooter[CR]Vintage[CR]--------------------- ----------------------[CR]-----------------------[CR]DON MORUGUSUTEIN * Don Morgstein[CR]Blackball[CR]Ootorii MANIA Mania Ohtorii ** Madison[CR]MANIyan (nickname)[CR]Mani-yan Madison[CR]Haneda MARIA Maria Haneda Crystal[CR]PATCHI Taisa Colonel[CR]Patch Col. Patch[CR]KIKOKUSAI Kikokusai Pure Ghost Wail ***[CR]* Due to[CR]technical limitations, the game spells this TEI, but it was written[CR]in the[CR]manual as TE+I (little I).[CR]** This spelling is for consistency with Battle[CR]Mania, where the "oo" in[CR]Ootorii is romanized as "oh", which is an[CR]acceptable alternative.[CR]*** A rough translation of the kanji that make up[CR]this name. A perfect[CR]translation is absolutely impossible, of course.[CR]According to the[CR]instruction booklet, Kikokusai is the characters given[CR]name; the full name[CR]is Kikoku Kikokusai (surname first). They most likely[CR]did this to be[CR]funny / annoying (same thing for Kikokukyou).[CR]Please note[CR]that many of the above names are not actually used in the game[CR]itself, so[CR]dont be surprised if you dont see them in the translation.[CR] Cultural Notes[CR](not[CR]exhaustive)[CR]-----------------------------------------------------------------------------[CR]Baania[CR](Vernier) [CR]The word "vernier" is sometimes used to refer to small rockets[CR]or other[CR]propulsion devices used to make small adjustments to a flying[CR]objects[CR]trajectory. The term as used in Gundam and other Japanese[CR]creations[CR]seems to have a somewhat different meaning, however, but still[CR]refers[CR]to a type of propulsion device. Here, it was translated as "jet[CR]pack".[CR]Benten[CR]Benten is a Japanese goddess associated with the island of[CR]Enoshima. She[CR]originated in Hinduism and was introduced to Japan by[CR]Buddhist monks while[CR]they were ruining Japans indigenous culture. She is[CR]also called Benzaiten.[CR]Enoshima[CR]Enoshima refers to both a Japanese[CR]seaside town and a nearby small island.[CR]Aside from the Benten connection,[CR]which is not important to the story anyway,[CR]theres not a lot to say about[CR]it except that it has nice beaches. Maria[CR]wants to go swimming while they[CR]are there, but Mania is disappointed that[CR]they dont have enough money left[CR]to buy much in the way of treats.[CR]Gachapin[CR]Gachapin seems to be a kind[CR]of spokesperson for Japanese television[CR]channel(s). He is a green dinosaur[CR]that appears occasionally in cultural or[CR]sports-related contexts. He is[CR]played by a person wearing a costume,[CR]but Gachapin doesnt look much like a[CR]dinosaur to me, at least not from[CR]the front.[CR]Food[CR]There are lots of[CR]Japanese foods / restaurants listed near the end of the[CR]credits. Presumably[CR]these are places where the team ate at during[CR]development.[CR]Garage[CR]Kits[CR]This term refers to hobby items, such as plastic models.[CR]Heisei[CR]Babylon, 1995[CR]This bit of text establishes the initial setting for the[CR]game. Heisei is the[CR]name of the current (as of 2006) Japanese era, so the[CR]time is 1995 AD and[CR]"Babylon" is the location. The short manga in the[CR]instruction booklet has[CR]Morgstein telling Mania that hes waiting for her at[CR]"Heisei Babylon" and[CR]goes on to explain that it refers to the offices of[CR]the Tokyo Government.[CR]Inflatables[CR]In the apartment, Maria is wearing a[CR]swim suit and carrying an inflatable[CR]alligator (or some similar reptile),[CR]while the portrait shows her holding[CR]an inner-tube. Shes ready to go[CR]swimming at Enoshima.[CR]Moon[CR]Supposedly a reference to Sailor Moon. The[CR]sentence it is used in is a[CR]parody of a line from one of the episodes, or[CR]so Ive been told.[CR]Tamegoro-[CR]Tamegoro- is a pretend character (i.e. never[CR]actually appearing on the show,[CR]much like Vern) from a 1960s television[CR]show called GEBAGEBA90Fun. The[CR]phrase "atto odoroku TAMEGORO-" was often[CR]used during the show and it became[CR]something of a pop culture saying,[CR]although its fairly obscure today.[CR]It was spelled "Tamegoro" in the[CR]translation, but including the "dash" is[CR]the correct way to write[CR]it.[CR]Uterundesu[CR]It isnt clear exactly what this is referring to. It might[CR]be a somewhat[CR]obscure reference to some sort of comedy act, or it could be[CR]a misspelling[CR]of utsurundesu. In the latter case it could refer to several[CR]things,[CR]including a brand of camera or a manga. (The former is supposedly a[CR]play[CR]on words of the same camera brand, if my information is correct.)[CR]Contact[CR]-----------------------------------------------------------------------------[CR]tougi_ou@yahoo.com[CR]I[CR]cannot guarantee a timely reply; this address is sometimes not checked[CR]for[CR]weeks or months at a time, depending on recent activity levels.[CR]And[CR]on the web:[CR]http://www.geocities.com/tougi_ou/</plot>
    <studio>M.I.J.E.T.</studio>
    <snapshot1>EQlEOls.png</snapshot1>
    <snapshot2>PI6F3cA.png</snapshot2>
  </game>
  <game name="Beyond Oasis (USA) [T-En by Eien Ni Hen+Husky v1.0]">
    <description>Beyond Oasis (USA) [T-En by Eien Ni Hen+Husky v1.0]</description>
    <title_clean>Beyond Oasis</title_clean>
    <rom name="MaybeIntroTEn20121007/Maybe-Intro%20%5BT-En%5D%20%2820121007%29.zip/Sega%20Mega%20Drive%20%5BT-En%5D%2FBeyond%20Oasis%20%28USA%29%20%5BT-En%20by%20Eien%20Ni%20Hen%2BHusky%20v1.0%5D.zip" size="1803546"/>
    <plot>On the mystical island of Oasis, Prince Ali embarks on a crusade against evil. The warrior prince must unleash the powers of the four Wild Spirits to stop the resurrection of a ruthless sorcerer and save the empire! As Ali, you can call on the powers of the four wild spirits to battle the evil minions of Agito. Fight off enemies with Ali's weapons, punches and kicks... or dig deeper to discover the Hidden Super Moves...a Sega first! Flip switches, trigger plates, and use what's left of your brain to solve mind-boggling puzzles that lead to Huge Bosses... like the Fire-breathing Red Dragon!</plot>
    <releasedate>08/12/1994</releasedate>
    <genre>Role-Playing,Action RPG</genre>
    <gamefaqs_url>http://www.gamefaqs.com/genesis/586061-beyond-oasis</gamefaqs_url>
    <rating>4.19</rating>
    <nplayers>1</nplayers>
    <boxart1>syudAYO.png</boxart1>
    <clearlogo1>LcYjvHQ.png</clearlogo1>
    <snapshot1>AYiR1ZZ.png</snapshot1>
    <fanart1>xAalS3c.jpg</fanart1>
    <boxart2>lh0NXhB.jpg</boxart2>
    <snapshot2>u0oDXT8.png</snapshot2>
    <boxart3>VJE5ZOD.jpg</boxart3>
    <boxart4>4fK9NCJ.jpg</boxart4>
    <boxart5>NKcJCXo.jpg</boxart5>
    <boxart6>fO1qs3L.png</boxart6>
  </game>
  <game name="Brave Battle Saga - Legend of the Magic Warrior (China) (Unl) [T-En by Djinn+Steve Martin v1.00] [n]">
    <description>Brave Battle Saga - Legend of the Magic Warrior (China) (Unl) [T-En by Djinn+Steve Martin v1.00] [n]</description>
    <title_clean>Brave Battle Saga - Legend of the Magic Warrior</title_clean>
    <rom name="MaybeIntroTEn20121007/Maybe-Intro%20%5BT-En%5D%20%2820121007%29.zip/Sega%20Mega%20Drive%20%5BT-En%5D%2FBrave%20Battle%20Saga%20-%20Legend%20of%20the%20Magic%20Warrior%20%28China%29%20%28Unl%29%20%5BT-En%20by%20Djinn%2BSteve%20Martin%20v1.00%5D%20%5Bn%5D.zip" size="1065606"/>
    <plot>Barver Battle Saga: Tai Kong Zhan Shi is a role playing game for the Sega[CR]Genesis.[CR]Read Me:[CR]******Brave Battle Saga - Legend The Magic Warrior[CR]English patch******[CR] 2009/2010[CR]Version[CR]history[CR]---------------[CR]21.02.2010: 1.00[CR] - Not beta anymore![CR] -[CR]Fixed original game bug when[CR] selling items from the bottom[CR] of a[CR]list.[CR] - Fixed some typos.[CR] - Fixed original game bug while[CR]switching spells places in list.[CR]02.01.2010: 0.99 beta 4[CR] - Fixed[CR]freezing when scrolling to the[CR] bottom of the spell list to sell.[CR] -[CR]Fixed text control codes which were[CR] preventing player to go further in[CR]game.[CR] - Fixed some typos and text formating[CR] in some dialogs.[CR] -[CR]SRAM initialization fixed.[CR]02.01.2010: 0.99 beta 3[CR] - Fixed output of[CR]spell and item list in battle.[CR] - Spell "See" renamed to "Analyze" and[CR]fixed information output when it is used.[CR] - Fixed routine of numbers[CR]output.[CR] - Fixed output of characters names when[CR] switching their places[CR]in menu.[CR]01.01.2010: 0.99 beta 2[CR] - Text reinserted with correct[CR]encoding.[CR] All em dashes are back to normal.[CR]31.01.2009: 0.99 beta[CR] -[CR]Initial release.[CR]About the game[CR]------------[CR]Released in 1996 in[CR]Taiwan as Barver Battle Saga - Tai Kong Zhan Shi - [CR]Mo Fa Zhan Shi, by[CR]ChuanPu Technology. The main title, Tai Kong Zhan Shi[CR](literally translated[CR]as Space Warrior) is what Final Fantasy is called in[CR]Taiwan, a clear[CR]attempt the makers made in order to catch peoples attention.[CR]After all,[CR]Final Fantasy on the Genesis sounds pretty nice :)[CR]The game was later[CR]pirated in Russia under the name Final Fantasy. Unfortunately[CR]the company[CR]who produced that version were apparently not well versed in Russian,[CR]as[CR]the resulting translation is notoriously bad, possibly indicating an[CR]automatic translator was used. While making a translation of the Russian[CR]version[CR]maight have been a much simpler task than its Taiwanese original,[CR]due to how horrible the[CR]Russian was it just wouldnt have been[CR]possible.[CR]Like many unlicensed Taiwanese Megadrive games, the game uses a[CR]lot of copied content[CR]from other games, among other things numerous[CR]graphics, or "inspriration", from Seiken[CR]Densetsu 3 and Romancing Saga 3[CR]for the SNES. The sound engine is also assumingly[CR]stolen directly from Data[CR]Easts High Seas Havoc, the biggest giveaway being that engines[CR]trademark[CR]organ sound. This same sound engine is actually used in quite a[CR]few other Taiwanese originals :)[CR]The game engine itself also is reused in[CR]other unlicensed titles.[CR]About the patch[CR]~~~~~~~~~~~~~[CR]This is a 100%[CR]translation from Chinese to English. The whole[CR]game has gone through a huge[CR]process to get where it is now, including in order:[CR]-Disassembly and[CR]reassembly of the WHOLE game code [CR]-Insertion of 3 new fonts. One for[CR]dialogs and menus, a smaller one for [CR]items and magic, and a separate one[CR]for the intro text. [CR]-Completely working new VWF [CR]-Code modifications of[CR]the dialog, intro, shops, inns and battle text routines [CR]-Modified text[CR]windows [CR]-Modified Z80 code [CR]-Insertion of new title screen [CR]The most[CR]common circulating dump of the game, which can be found in the GoodGen set,[CR]has a bug that[CR]prevents the DAC drum channel from playing correctly. This[CR]translation was built off [CR]of a fixed version that has been ciculating[CR]throughout Chinese sites for awhile, so[CR]patching it on the common dump[CR]found on the net will not only translate it, but will also[CR]fix that[CR]glitch.[CR]Usage[CR]********[CR]The patch has been tested and works with the[CR]following ROM:[CR]Barver Battle Saga - The Space Fighter[CR](Chinese).bin[CR]Usage with other versions might cause[CR]glitching.[CR]Credits[CR]@@@@@@@@@@[CR]Romhacking - Jinny -[CR]www.magicteam.net[CR]Translation - SteveMartin[CR]Proofreading -[CR]zera9924[CR]Titlescreen art - taizou[CR]Special[CR]Thanks[CR]^^^^^^^^^^^^^^[CR]Many people have helped and showed their support[CR]for this project. Many thanks to all of the[CR]following:[CR]108[CR]Stars[CR]aishsha[CR]Gil_[CR]Next gen[CR]Cowboy[CR]Pennywise[CR]Redcomet[CR]saito[CR]taizou[CR]The romhacking.net[CR]forums[CR]Zebbe[CR]...and anyone else who ever showed their support!</plot>
    <studio>Djinn</studio>
    <snapshot1>CRRknTQ.png</snapshot1>
  </game>
  <game name="Dragon Ball Z - L'Appel du Destin (France) [T-En by Saiya Translations v0.95a] [i]">
    <description>Dragon Ball Z - L'Appel du Destin (France) [T-En by Saiya Translations v0.95a] [i]</description>
    <title_clean>Dragon Ball Z - L'Appel du Destin</title_clean>
    <rom name="MaybeIntroTEn20121007/Maybe-Intro%20%5BT-En%5D%20%2820121007%29.zip/Sega%20Mega%20Drive%20%5BT-En%5D%2FDragon%20Ball%20Z%20-%20L%27Appel%20du%20Destin%20%28France%29%20%5BT-En%20by%20Saiya%20Translations%20v0.95a%5D%20%5Bi%5D.zip" size="1481626"/>
    <plot>Dragon Ball Z: Buyuu Retsuden is an action fighting game for the Sega Genesis.[CR]Based on a manga/anime of Dragon Ball Z. There's a story mode in which you use[CR]any of the game's eleven fighters, and depending on who you choose, the battle[CR]order will be different and you will not face two characters. When the two[CR]fighters start getting far from each other, the screen splits, but you can[CR]track just how close you are to the other fighter by using the map below your[CR]energy / ki meters [all these three have been present in the Super Famicom DBZ[CR]games as well].</plot>
    <studio>DBZ Game</studio>
    <boxart1>CJDcSFQ.png</boxart1>
    <snapshot1>ikCzPxx.png</snapshot1>
    <snapshot2>uPvx55x.png</snapshot2>
  </game>
  <game name="Dynamite Headdy (Japan) [T-En by MIJET v20070428]">
    <description>Dynamite Headdy (Japan) [T-En by MIJET v20070428]</description>
    <title_clean>Dynamite Headdy</title_clean>
    <rom name="MaybeIntroTEn20121007/Maybe-Intro%20%5BT-En%5D%20%2820121007%29.zip/Sega%20Mega%20Drive%20%5BT-En%5D%2FDynamite%20Headdy%20%28Japan%29%20%5BT-En%20by%20MIJET%20v20070428%5D.zip" size="1399944"/>
    <plot>Hot-headed Headdy gets into some real head-banging to thwart the Dark Demon's devious deeds. This wacky headcase is up to his neck in surprises! Switch heads to match the job! Over 15 heads to choose from! Bash heavy objects with Slammer Head! Suck up foes with Vacuum Head! Stick it to your enemies with Spike Head! Headdy's spring-loaded head gets him where he's gotta go! Use it to swing over ledges, grab onto objects and shoot hoops in the basketball bonus round. Use your head to whiz through a radical variety of play! Action, shooting and strategy speed you on to a surprise ending!</plot>
    <genre>Action,Platformer,2D</genre>
    <studio>M.I.J.E.T.</studio>
    <releasedate>04/08/1994</releasedate>
    <gamefaqs_url>http://www.gamefaqs.com/genesis/586154-dynamite-headdy</gamefaqs_url>
    <rating>3.94</rating>
    <nplayers>1</nplayers>
    <boxart1>ujV55fr.png</boxart1>
    <banner1>YlcFA4n.jpg</banner1>
    <clearlogo1>886nXQ9.png</clearlogo1>
    <snapshot1>eTVeEwF.png</snapshot1>
    <fanart1>lQx9foe.jpg</fanart1>
    <boxart2>eywDNUg.jpg</boxart2>
    <snapshot2>QtmR3dS.png</snapshot2>
    <boxart3>LfwZNTo.jpg</boxart3>
    <boxart4>8EAGBKs.png</boxart4>
    <boxart5>CyRJ1yK.png</boxart5>
  </game>
  <game name="King Colossus (Japan) [T-En by MIJET v20061030] (Family Friendly Edition) [n]">
    <description>King Colossus (Japan) [T-En by MIJET v20061030] (Family Friendly Edition) [n]</description>
    <title_clean>King Colossus</title_clean>
    <rom name="MaybeIntroTEn20121007/Maybe-Intro%20%5BT-En%5D%20%2820121007%29.zip/Sega%20Mega%20Drive%20%5BT-En%5D%2FKing%20Colossus%20%28Japan%29%20%5BT-En%20by%20MIJET%20v20061030%5D%20%28Family%20Friendly%20Edition%29%20%5Bn%5D.zip" size="625061"/>
    <plot>King Colossus is a role playing game for the Sega Genesis.[CR]Read[CR]Me:[CR]Patch version 061030 (yymmdd)[CR]Readme version 061030 (yymmdd)[CR]King Colossus[CR] English Translation Patch[CR] by M.I.J.E.T.[CR]History[CR]-----------------------------------------------------------------------------[CR]061030[CR]Works on a real Genesis now. Script revised slightly.[CR]060114 Fixed checksum[CR]error.[CR]060108 Now works with a hacked version of the rom file.[CR]051203[CR]Fixed a compatibility problem. Q and A section updated.[CR]051123 Initial[CR]release.[CR]Overview[CR]-----------------------------------------------------------------------------[CR]This[CR]is a translation patch for the Mega Drive game "King Colossus", by Sega.[CR]It[CR]is a very high quality patch, both in the translation and[CR]hacking[CR]departments, and is perhaps the first "dual-language" (i.e. it[CR]supports both[CR]Japanese and English) fan translation of a video game.[CR]Applying the[CR]Patch[CR]-----------------------------------------------------------------------------[CR]Hopefully[CR]included with this document is a patch file in the pretentiously-[CR]named IPS[CR]format. You can use any program that supports this file format[CR]to apply the[CR]patch to your ROM file.[CR]Alternatively, you can use the supplied executable[CR]program to apply the[CR]patch. The program will read the IPS file (which[CR]should be kept in the same[CR]directory as the program) and will open two file[CR]requesters: one for loading[CR]the original ROM file and one for saving the[CR]patched ROM file. It will[CR]check the ROM file (de-interleaving it if[CR]necessary) and will fail if there[CR]is something wrong with the file. A[CR]normal IPS program cannot do this as[CR]it has no idea what it is patching.[CR]The program has not been extensively[CR]tested, so if you have problems (or[CR]simply dont trust a foreign executable[CR]file) you always have the option of[CR]using a different program. Another[CR]reason you might want to use an[CR]alternative program is because it is not[CR]compatible with your[CR]computer...[CR]Please note that you are morally obligated to own an original[CR]copy of this[CR]game in order to use the "ROM file". I got my copy for around[CR]$10, and Id[CR]definitely say that its worth the price.[CR] Playing the[CR]Game[CR]-----------------------------------------------------------------------------[CR]Once[CR]youve patched the ROM file, simply load it up in your favorite[CR]Genesis /[CR]Mega Drive emulator, console copier, or flash cartridge.[CR]Since this is a[CR]dual-language game, you must set the country code to USA[CR]to play it in[CR]English. If you want to play it in the original Japanese,[CR]set the country[CR]code to Japan. Note that in this mode it will not be[CR]identical to the[CR]original Japanese version; the windows are larger, some bugs[CR]have been[CR]fixed, and many name limitations were changed. Also, some of the[CR]non-script[CR]text will still be in English.[CR]Statistics[CR]-----------------------------------------------------------------------------[CR]IPS[CR]File Size 62484 B (61.0 kB)[CR] Patches 391[CR] Data 60521 B (59.1[CR]kB)[CR]Simple Patches (no large data blocks, no assembled code)[CR] Lines in[CR]File 545 (includes comments and whitespace)[CR] Size of File 13,806 B (13.4[CR]kB) (CRLF format)[CR] Code and Data Patches Combined[CR] Number 330[CR] Total[CR]Size 736 B[CR] Code Patches Only (these are generally &lt; 4 instructions, not[CR]assembled)[CR] Number 245[CR] Total Size 496 B[CR]Assembly Code (not including[CR]simple code patches [less than 4 instructions])[CR] Subroutines 41[CR]Instructions 566 (excludes non-instructions, like data constants)[CR] Lines in[CR]File 1,665 (includes comments, whitespace, and data constants)[CR] Source Size[CR]19,608 B (19.1 kB) (LF format)[CR] Binary Size 2,910 B (2.8 kB)[CR] Code Size[CR]1,978 B (1.9 kB)[CR] Data Size 932 B (mostly font data)[CR]Script[CR] Banks[CR]5[CR] Original 35,309 B (34.5 kB) (double it for approx. size in JIS[CR]format)[CR] Translated 53,443 B (52.2 kB) (again, this is as formatted in the[CR]ROM)[CR] Characters Hiragana, Katakana, Alphanumeric (upper and lower),[CR]symbols[CR]Other Text ~2 kB[CR]Readme File[CR] Size 35,639 B (34.8 kB) (CRLF[CR]format)[CR] Lines 839[CR]Most impressive is the number of code patches (245).[CR]This means the code[CR]was patched in 245 different locations. Some of these[CR]are hooks into my[CR]41 assembly language subroutines, which were necessary[CR]when the original[CR]code couldnt simply be overwritten.[CR] List of Changes[CR](not[CR]exhaustive)[CR]-----------------------------------------------------------------------------[CR]Name[CR]limit increased from 4 to 8 bytes ([han]dakuten characters take 2[CR]bytes)[CR]Changed various string size limitations[CR]Added or changed several[CR]characters in the font[CR]Added a new control code to make use of the last[CR]line of text w/o limitations[CR]Increased the size of the normal text[CR]window[CR]Increased the size of the location name window[CR]Increased the size[CR]of the arena rankings window[CR]Increased the size of the weapon rental[CR]window[CR]Arena rankings now have an appropriate suffix (i.e. "1st" instead of[CR]"No. 1")[CR]Many modifications to the name entry screen[CR] Lower-case[CR]characters can now be used[CR] Starting location changed[CR] All kana[CR]characters are still available[CR] Added katakana VU (voiced U) just for[CR]fun[CR]Many modifications to the pause menus[CR] Changed the size and location[CR]of the windows[CR] Translated the text[CR] Fixes to the window movement and[CR]overlapping[CR]Workaround for unlimited string bank sizes[CR]Subtitled the[CR]kanji in the opening credits[CR]Fixed some spelling errors in the ending[CR]credits (required additional fonts)[CR]Auto-detects the country code and shows[CR]English / Japanese text accordingly[CR] Translation[CR]Accuracy[CR]-----------------------------------------------------------------------------[CR]The[CR]script was translated by a native speaker of English with the help of[CR]a[CR]native speaker of Japanese, who has lived in America for around five[CR]years.[CR]Although I translated everything, I could not have completed this[CR]project[CR]without the help of my Japanese friend, who checked my work and[CR]helped me[CR]with the parts I didnt understand. Thanks to him, the script is[CR]so much[CR]more robust than it would have been, as he explained many of the[CR]unstated[CR]implications and subtleties contained with the text and provided[CR]much more[CR]natural-sounding English translations, as opposed to my dry,[CR]literal ones.[CR]A lot of editing was performed on the script. I often edited[CR]a single[CR]string a half-dozen times or more until I was satisfied with the[CR]results.[CR]While editing, I normally checked the string in-game, as text that[CR]looks[CR]OK in my editor sometimes doesnt "work" during the game.[CR]Anyway,[CR]due to all of the above, youd definitely see some differences if[CR]you[CR]compared the two scripts side-by-side. This is normal for a good[CR]translation[CR]of such disparate languages and should not be misconstrued as[CR]evidence of[CR]inaccuracy; if the tenses are "wrong" or some superfluous[CR]adverbs are missing[CR]it is not because we didnt understand the original.[CR]Rest assured that I[CR]was especially careful when translating the most[CR]important parts of the[CR]script and always had my Japanese associate check[CR]them (and his translations[CR]were often far more liberal than mine because he[CR]would render it the way he[CR]would have said it in English; in other words,[CR]he would translate the idea,[CR]rather than the literal meaning). No important[CR]information was "lost in[CR]translation".[CR]In conclusion, I hope you find[CR]this translation to be of very high quality.[CR]I believe it to be both[CR]accurate and well-written and I hope that you enjoy[CR]it as much as I[CR]have.[CR] Translation[CR]Notes[CR]-----------------------------------------------------------------------------[CR]The[CR]following is a list of certain things that I consider inappropriate for[CR]a[CR]translation, with examples from commercially translated games[CR](although[CR]many unofficial translations contain them as well) that I recall.[CR]You may[CR]or may not agree with me, but I encourage translators to at least[CR]consider[CR]the suitability of the following items for their work.[CR]My[CR]translation does not contain...[CR] - inside jokes (Legend of Mana: Cafe[CR]"Sorry Carl!")[CR] - pop culture references (Chrono Trigger: Ozzie, Flea, and[CR]Slash)[CR] - inappropriate allusions (Legend of Mana: "El Hazardous")[CR] -[CR]name changes (within the limits of transliteration, of course)[CR] - colorful[CR]accents (especially not British punk accents, ugh)[CR] - anachronisms (usually[CR]these are unintentional)[CR] - censorship (not that I care, but some people[CR]make a big deal out of it)[CR] (and not that there was much worth censoring[CR]anyway)[CR]And I tried to avoid...[CR] - idioms (a few were unavoidable, and[CR]some are actual translations)[CR] - spelling errors[CR] - grammatical[CR]errors[CR] - punctuation errors[CR] - spacing and alignment errors[CR] -[CR]inconsistencies (these are tough to check, especially in large[CR]scripts)[CR]Obviously no one would intentionally make errors, but I wanted to[CR]show[CR]the things that I checked for and was careful about; Ive seen way[CR]too[CR]many sloppy translations. Actually, there ARE a few intentional[CR]grammatical[CR]errors in the script, in order to make it sound more natural.[CR]There arent[CR]many and you probably wont notice them, unless you are well[CR]acquainted with[CR]the rules of grammar, as they are very minor and would[CR]sound normal to a[CR]native speaker of English. Please bear in mind that the[CR]script represents[CR]spoken dialogue, not formal writing.[CR] Transliteration[CR]Notes[CR]-----------------------------------------------------------------------------[CR]When[CR]transliterating names I normally took a direct romanization and then[CR]tried[CR]to make it look and sound better for English speakers. I generally[CR]used[CR]whichever I felt was the better choice for the r/l, b/v, and s/th pairs[CR]and[CR]dropped extraneous vowels. Occasionally the letter h was used to[CR]help[CR]clarify pronunciation and ph was often used in place of f.[CR]Finally,[CR]once or twice I replaced long a vowels with ar. Other than that,[CR]I[CR]rarely changed the vowels, so they should generally be given a[CR]Japanese[CR]pronunciation, if you know how. This even applies to oo, which is[CR]NOT the[CR]rather ill-conceived romanization of ou but represents o-.[CR]The[CR]following names were translated, rather than simply transliterated,[CR]and[CR]should be pronounced as in English[CR] DEZAIA Desire[CR] SHIRIOSU[CR]Sirius[CR] GANI-ME Ganyme(de)[CR] KURISU Kris[CR]...and some that are[CR](probably) French (pronounced as in English, however).[CR] ROA-RU Loire[CR]PARISU Paris[CR]Finally, it wasnt clear whether or not they meant Orpheus for[CR]this one, as[CR]the pronunciations are significantly different, so I just[CR]transliterated it.[CR] ORUFESU Orphus[CR]That was one of the few vowel[CR]changes; I didnt like "Orphes" or "Orfes".[CR]And speaking of vowel changes,[CR]heres the other major one:[CR] KARURIMU Carleem[CR]As with Orphus, I imagine[CR]most people would instinctively give the word[CR]the correct pronunciation,[CR]based on the way it looks.[CR]Oh, and yes, Iria is the exact romanization for[CR]that particular name.[CR] Hacking[CR]Notes[CR]-----------------------------------------------------------------------------[CR]This[CR]hack required a lot of work. I had to do quite a bit of disassembly[CR]and[CR]ended up getting pretty familiar with the inner workings of the code.[CR]It[CR]took about two weeks of full-time (all day, every day) hacking, not[CR]to[CR]mention a few days worth of minor bug fixing and adjustments during[CR]the[CR]translation phase.[CR]One of the more annoying aspects of this[CR]translation hack was the excessive[CR]amount of inlining and hard-coding[CR]employed by the original programmers.[CR]For example, the code for the save[CR]menu uses the SAME VALUE hard-coded in[CR]SIX different places! And from a[CR]quick look at my patch source file, I[CR]can see that those changes only[CR]amount to about half of what needed to be[CR]changed for that particular menu,[CR]not including the hooks into my assembly[CR]language subroutines. Another[CR]example is that there are probably half-a-[CR]dozen text decoding routines,[CR]all with minor variations. And simply[CR]changing the size of a window was[CR]never sufficient; there were always two[CR]to six subroutines for actually[CR]rendering that specific window that needed[CR]to be changed as[CR]well.[CR]Attention to detail ended up requiring many additional days of work.[CR]You[CR]cannot imagine the amount of effort it took to get everything[CR]"perfect". The[CR]pause menus alone probably took half of a week to finish, as[CR]so many things[CR]had to be changed, even the way the windows scroll. Many of[CR]the things I[CR]fixed probably would not even have been noticed, but I am[CR]something of a[CR]perfectionist; I could have taken the easy route and not[CR]bothered to increase[CR]the window sizes and string length limits, which[CR]probably would have saved me[CR]a week of overtime hours working on this[CR]hack.[CR]Another problem was the overuse of buffers. I had to fix several[CR]buffer[CR]overflow errors cause by the increased size of the strings. In many[CR]cases[CR]there was no practical reason for some of the strings to be copied[CR]to[CR]memory (or sometimes even the cartridge RAM!) Rather than increasing[CR]the[CR]size of the buffers (and risking address conflicts), I used some[CR]clever[CR]code hacks to increase the limits without changing the sizes of the[CR]original[CR]buffers.[CR]On the positive side, the credits and the "game over"[CR]screen were already[CR]in English, although I still ended up having to fix a[CR]few things. The[CR]ending credits were particularly annoying because of the[CR]variable width[CR]font; I had to make some additional character combinations[CR]in order to[CR]correct their English. Anyway, please dont think that Im[CR]complaining about[CR]all this; I just want to show that "reinserting" a[CR]translated script is often[CR]no way near as simple as it sounds, especially[CR]when it is done properly.[CR]So far Ive found at least four different[CR]compression schemes used in this[CR]game; it seems like every kind of data has[CR]its own compression method.[CR]I didnt bother trying to recompress anything as[CR]there was plenty of free[CR]space left in the ROM. I ripped all the[CR]decompression code, which came[CR]in handy several times.[CR]My code is[CR]usually pretty efficient, but you might notice some seemingly[CR]unnecessary[CR]stuff. The reason is because I always try to be as careful[CR]as possible when[CR]patching foreign programs, so there is some code in there[CR]to emulate[CR]calculations that my subroutines didnt need. I also refused to[CR]trash any[CR]registers unless the original code was obviously doing so[CR]immediately after[CR]me. Even the upper word of data registers was preserved[CR]and if the original[CR]programmers felt it necessary to clear an entire[CR]register, so did I. In my[CR]opinion, its not worth the risk of introducing[CR]subtle bugs just to save a[CR]few bytes or make the program run unnoticeably[CR]faster.[CR]Sadly, there was[CR]one thing I missed and that was the fact that certain[CR]control codes mixed[CR]in with some of the strings are read as words instead[CR]of bytes. This can[CR]cause misalignment errors, a misfeature of the 68000[CR]which will crash the[CR]game on a real console and can cause problems on[CR]some emulators. The[CR]original developers handled this by inserting a dummy[CR]byte for alignment[CR]purposes, when necessary, but this was a very poor[CR]solution to the problem.[CR]Since my emulator completely ignores misaligned[CR]accesses I was unaware that[CR]some of my translated strings had the control[CR]codes in the wrong places.[CR]Now that the game has been tested on a real[CR]Genesis I hope that my patch is[CR]now error free. Alignment errors are an[CR]amateurish mistake, so this is[CR]somewhat embarrassing, although the way it[CR]occurred in the data could have[CR]been missed by any expert. It was very[CR]unfortunate that things worked out[CR]this way, because if it werent for[CR]those stupid control codes being treated[CR]as words my patch would have[CR]been perfect upon its initial release; the[CR]only practical difference[CR]between the first release and this final[CR](hopefully) version is that a few[CR]of the strings were padded for alignment[CR]purposes. No other problems[CR]were ever brought to my attention.[CR]Consistency[CR]Notes[CR]-----------------------------------------------------------------------------[CR]Much[CR]of what Ive written could be construed as advice to other hackers[CR]and[CR]translators. With that in mind, here is a partial list of the[CR]consistency[CR]checks I performed after the script was translated and edited.[CR]Hopefully[CR]they will prove useful. Inconsistencies often go unnoticed, but[CR]eliminating[CR]them makes your work look much more professional.[CR] all proper names[CR]inconsistent stuttering (search for -)[CR] inconsistent capitalization of[CR]names. For example...[CR] Castle  but "the castle of X"[CR] King , else king[CR](lowercase) (same with prince(ss) and queen)[CR] "The" (e.g. The ) vs.[CR]"the"[CR]Inconsistent alternate spellings[CR] Goodbye vs. Good-bye (both are[CR]considered correct, at least by some)[CR] OK Ok ok okay[CR] (For the next two,[CR]I use both spellings for their different nuances)[CR] alright (more of an[CR]expression) vs. all right ("allright" is wrong)[CR] anytime vs. any time[CR]anymore (from now on, at present) vs. any more (additional meanings)[CR]Spell-[CR]checkers cant catch typos that are correctly spelled[CR] your youre[CR] its[CR]its[CR] their there theyre[CR] were where were[CR] then than[CR] unintentional[CR]double spaces[CR] comma not followed by a space[CR] repeated words (e.g. the[CR]the) (make sure the spell-checker does this)[CR] that that (not all spell-[CR]checkers check this; it can be legitimate)[CR] repeated words between lines[CR](line breaks can mess up spell-checkers)[CR]There are many, many more[CR]homophones (as well as homonyms and homographs) in[CR]English, but there isnt[CR]much point in listing them; I only included the[CR]most common ones that I[CR]could think of.[CR]Some of those checks require manually searching for and[CR]checking every[CR]instance of a word, which can be tedious. All in all, I[CR]probably found[CR]less than half-a-dozen typos or inconsistencies during this[CR]phase, but[CR]that was after lots of editing; your mileage may "very"[CR];)[CR]"How to Stutter Correctly"[CR]Well, stutter however you want, just be[CR]consistent... ;)[CR]Right Wrong[CR]Sound[CR]-----------------------------[CR]W-Who not Wh-Who (hu sound) (note[CR]the irregularity of this one)[CR]Wh-What not W-What (wh sound)[CR]Th-This not[CR]T-This (th sound)[CR]Sh-She not S-She (sh sound)[CR]Th-That not Th-that (watch[CR]out for inconsistent capitalization)[CR]I, I not I-I (personal pronoun I is a[CR]special case)[CR]I, Im not I-Im (same with d, ll, etc.)[CR]I-It not I, It (ih[CR]sound)[CR] Original[CR]Bugs[CR]-----------------------------------------------------------------------------[CR]These[CR]are all the bugs in the original game that I have found. Please check[CR]this[CR]section carefully before reporting a bug; if it is in here already then[CR]its[CR]probably never going to get fixed...[CR]Note that there are a few minor plot[CR]spoilers in this section.[CR]In the very beginning, if you try to leave the[CR]room before talking to Muuk,[CR]the color of the text will be wrong. This is a[CR]bug in the game flow, not the[CR]script, and is not trivial to fix.[CR]Theres[CR]another one at the end of the first chapter, when Muuk speaks to[CR]Flora as[CR]you are leaving.[CR]Before you fight Desire, her text is green at one[CR]point.[CR]Its actually not an original bug, but there is a slight textual[CR]error[CR]during the "second audience" scene. You probably wouldnt notice it,[CR]even[CR]if you were looking for it, and it was necessary to make the text[CR]appear the[CR]way I wanted it. Id be pretty impressed if anyone found[CR]it...[CR]The statues in the shrine will give you garbage messages if you[CR]return[CR]there later on. Sometimes theyll give you real messages too; the[CR]game is[CR]reading the right string number in the wrong bank. Actually,[CR]sometimes it[CR]will read from the correct bank, which might explain why this[CR]bug went[CR]unnoticed.[CR] I fixed some of the garbage by adding extra strings[CR]to one of the banks that[CR]it reads from, but I couldnt do this for the other[CR]bank because there was[CR]already a string assigned to that number. Hence you[CR]will get to read part[CR]of the ending...[CR] As with the color errors listed[CR]above, theres no easy way to fix this[CR]because the error is probably in the[CR]games data, which is likely compressed,[CR]and would require a lot of reverse[CR]engineering. Since there is no reason[CR]to go back to that area anyway and[CR]since most people probably dont know how[CR]to retrigger these messages, I[CR]dont think its worth the time to try and[CR]fix this bug.[CR]Everyone in[CR]Sirius gives garbage messages later in the game. Once again,[CR]the strings[CR]are being read out of the wrong bank. I was able to fix the[CR]strings for[CR]everyone except the dead guy; his string is the same as the[CR]old mans so[CR]theres nothing I can easily do about that.[CR]Update: talking to anyone in[CR]Sirius later in the game will also screw up[CR]the messages for just about[CR]everyone else! To fix this, talk to anyone[CR]in Distaria or get the "gate is[CR]firmly shut" message in Distaria Coliseum.[CR]As with all of the above, this[CR]is an original bug and Im very pessimistic[CR]about fixing it. Based on what I[CR]know, the problem is probably in the[CR]games data, and it could take weeks to[CR]figure out how the internal[CR]structures are arranged. Im usually not too[CR]enthusiastic about fixing[CR]other peoples bugs...[CR]When there is more than[CR]one color of text being displayed simultaneously,[CR]all the text will be the[CR]same color as the last one used, when the lines are[CR]scrolled out of the[CR]window. My script has been arranged to avoid this.[CR]Moving off of "other[CR]items" onto a valid item wont print the string.[CR]You cant normally get[CR]enough items to do this anyway, so its no big deal.[CR]Actually, I seem to[CR]have inadvertently fixed this...[CR]The pause menu is too short and the sword[CR]pointer overlaps part of it.[CR]The original game designers didnt seem to[CR]care, and fixing this would be a[CR]lot of trouble due to the way the menu is[CR]rolled up and moved around.[CR]In the ending, it looks as if some of the[CR]scenes are cut off. This was[CR]intentional; if you pay attention, youll[CR]notice that each scene shows[CR]less and less on both the top and bottom.[CR]Quite an interesting bit of[CR]direction, especially considering that its a[CR]game, and an old one at that.[CR]---------------------------------------------------------------------------[CR]|[CR]The rest of these are things that probably wouldnt get blamed on me, but[CR]|[CR]| have been documented for your interest anyway. |[CR]---------------------------------------------------------------------------[CR]Sometimes[CR]sprites will change position slightly during the cutscenes.[CR]Its possible to[CR]get a character who is following you (but not closely)[CR]to walk through[CR]solid walls.[CR]It is also possible to attack through solid walls.[CR]The way[CR]the game handles tile overlays (i.e. either on a second plane or[CR]using[CR]sprites) isnt perfect. You can occasionally see parts of your[CR]weapons[CR]appear when going through an underpass. You can also see similar[CR]effects[CR]if you jump in certain places, such as the first cave.[CR]It is[CR]possible to place the Lost Eyes in the statue without triggering[CR]the[CR]message. The door opens, however, and you can elicit the message[CR]later,[CR]if you want.[CR]In Kazard, it isnt necessary to light the torches if[CR]you jump correctly.[CR]It isnt a big help and it might have other[CR]consequences, so I wouldnt[CR]recommend skipping that part. Also, once you[CR]jump to the other side, its[CR]possible to enter the kings chamber by jumping[CR]diagonally on either side[CR]of the walkway near the door. This is absolutely[CR]no help, since you can[CR]just walk through the door once youre across, but[CR]its interesting.[CR]In Lufelia, some of the sword pointers in the pause menu[CR]are gray, while[CR]others are not.[CR]Its possible to get trapped in Ganants[CR]hidden room if he isnt there to[CR]send you back out. You cant save, so if you[CR]dont have enough MP to cast[CR]Exodus theres nothing you can do.[CR]Theres a[CR]fake passage in Linas room later in the game. It seems to be the[CR]same as in[CR]the dragon cave; theres a hole in the wall, you just cant enter[CR]it. Also,[CR]earlier in the game it is possible to get underneath the throne[CR]in that[CR]room. I have a screen-shot of this, if anybody wants to see it.[CR]The ending[CR]credits are cued to the music, so they dont start for quite[CR]a while; the[CR]game has not crashed.[CR] Q and[CR]A[CR]-----------------------------------------------------------------------------[CR]Q:[CR]This patch doesnt work! What do I do?[CR]A: Make sure your ROM file is not in[CR]an interleaved format. Its also[CR] possible that there is more than one[CR]version of the game, or your copy is[CR] corrupt. If you have problems, try[CR]using the program that I wrote to[CR] apply the patch; it checks for the above[CR]issues. If my program doesnt[CR] work for some reason, you can try a different[CR]IPS patching program, but[CR] you will lose the benefit of having your ROM[CR]file checked.[CR] If there is more than one version of the game, let me know[CR]and Ill try to[CR] support it.[CR]Q: Why is the text in Japanese?!?[CR]A: This[CR]is a dual-language translation patch; if it detects that it is[CR] running on[CR]a Japanese system it will use the original game script.[CR] If you are using[CR]an emulator, make sure the country code is set to USA.[CR] If you really want[CR]to play this game, in English, on a real Japanese Mega[CR] Drive system, then[CR]contact me.[CR]Q: Are state files from the original Japanese version still[CR]compatible?[CR]A: No. They may work partially, but some stuff will definitely[CR]be missing.[CR] Ideally, you should save your game on the original version and[CR]use that[CR] same SRAM file for my version of the game, as saved games should[CR]still be[CR] compatible.[CR]Q: I found a spelling/grammatical/punctuation[CR]error! What should I do?[CR]A: Well, I hope there arent any errors, but if you[CR]do find one please[CR] let me know about it so I can correct it. Assuming it[CR]is a legitimate[CR] error, you will be credited for finding it.[CR] Note that[CR]there are a few grammatical errors that are intentional, usually[CR] with[CR]stock phrases. If youre sharp enough to notice them, then go ahead[CR] and[CR]report them anyway.[CR]Q: I found a bug! What do I do?[CR]A: There are several[CR]minor errors that exist in the original game. I have[CR] documented all the[CR]original bugs that I know of in another section of[CR] this file. If the bug[CR]youve found is not listed there, then please[CR] contact me so I can[CR]investigate it. This includes "color" errors (where[CR] the text appears in[CR]the wrong color), some of which are errors in the[CR] flow of the game, rather[CR]than the script. See the aforementioned section[CR] for details.[CR]Q: MAJOR[CR]BUG! Why is everyone giving me messages from earlier in the game?[CR]A: You[CR]went back to Sirius, didnt you...[CR] This is a bug in the original. I wrote[CR]more about it elsewhere in this[CR] file, but to fix it all you need to do is[CR]talk to anyone in Distaria, or[CR] attempt to enter Distaria Coliseum. Once[CR]any of these correct messages[CR] are displayed, everything will be back to[CR]normal.[CR] To avoid triggering this bug in the first place, dont talk to[CR]anyone in[CR] Sirius after you finished the Lufelia area. Not that they have[CR]anything[CR] interesting to say anyway...[CR]Q: May I suggest changes to your[CR]script?[CR]A: Sure. If you honestly believe it would improve the writing, I[CR]will be[CR] glad to consider it. However, I spent quite a lot of time editing[CR]the[CR] script and checking how it reads within the game, so you probably[CR]wont find too many awkward sentences and such. At least I hope not...[CR]Q: I[CR]see "ss" in your translation. Dont you know that youre supposed to[CR] leave[CR]off the _s_ of possessives for proper names which end in _s_?[CR]A: Although[CR]that practice is common in journalism, many authorities[CR] discourage its[CR]use. Strunk only prescribes it for certain classical[CR] names (e.g. Jesus)[CR]while Gregg recommends a pronunciation-based[CR] approach.[CR]Q: You put a[CR]comma after the final element in a series. Dont you know that[CR] youre not[CR]supposed to do that anymore?[CR]A: Yes, thats what my elementary school[CR]teacher said as well. However, as[CR] in the previous case, this is "newspaper[CR]grammar". It can cause ambiguity[CR] and it removes a valuable visual cue,[CR]just to save a little space.[CR] Garners book on usage has a nice discussion[CR]of this point.[CR]Q: Why are you dropping names and acting all professional,[CR]like some sort[CR] of English Major? What a jerk...[CR]A: Well, perhaps you[CR]might come to believe that some of the rules of English[CR] that you were[CR]taught (like the prohibition against ending a sentence with[CR] a preposition,[CR]for example) are actually questionable. Furthermore, you[CR] might want a more[CR]reliable reference than the readme file for a video game[CR] translation[CR]patch...[CR] You are correct, however, professionalism, formality, and elitism[CR]are[CR] silly. So are things like funerals, weddings, honor societies,[CR]and...[CR]Q: Shut up![CR]A: Sigh... Thats not a question, but lets move on to[CR]a different subject...[CR]Q: Who is Makoto Ogino? Is this based on a[CR]manga?[CR]A: Makoto Ogino is the author of the manga "Kujaku Ou", which[CR]translates as[CR] "Peacock King". Based on what Ive read of the game box and[CR]instruction[CR] booklet, it seems Makoto Ogino was brought in to direct and[CR]write the[CR] script for King Colossus, or "Tougi Ou". I am confident that it[CR]was a[CR] completely original work, at least at that time.[CR] Incidentally,[CR]there are rumors that this was a port from some unidentified[CR] 8-bit system.[CR]I believe this to be inaccurate information.[CR]Q: Why does my name get[CR]truncated sometimes?[CR]A: The name buffer is eight bytes, but the[CR](han)dakuten characters (the kana[CR] with accent marks) take up 2 bytes each,[CR]so it will truncate your name if[CR] necessary. If it does, you will see the[CR]truncated version in the[CR] confirmation window, so pay attention. If you are[CR]only using Roman[CR] (i.e. English) characters, as most people are likely to[CR]do, your name can[CR] be up to eight characters long and will never be[CR]truncated.[CR]Q: What is the main characters default name?[CR]A: There isnt[CR]one. The instruction booklet refers to him as "the hero of[CR] the story", or[CR]something like that. In the original game, if you select[CR] "END" without[CR]entering anything, you get four blank spaces for a name.[CR] This was fixed;[CR]now it is impossible to have a completely blank name.[CR]Q: I dont want to[CR]read your translation carefully. How can I speed it up?[CR]A: In addition to[CR]the normal speed-up activated by holding the C Button,[CR] you can hold down[CR]any direction on the D Pad to skip the pauses as well.[CR]Q: Is it OK to say[CR]"no" to people?[CR]A: Yes, if you want to give the obvious wrong answer to any[CR]of the "yes or[CR] no" questions in the game, go right ahead; it doesnt appear[CR]to have any[CR] drawbacks and youll get to see their reactions. As with many[CR]games, the[CR] plot wont continue until you give the correct answer. The only[CR]exception[CR] is at the end of the game; your answer determines the ending you[CR]get (and[CR] they are just different; there is no "good ending").[CR] I always[CR]wonder about this sort of thing myself, when playing a new game.[CR]Q: What is[CR]"Demiglace Sauce"?[CR]A: As you might be able to tell from the name, its a[CR]French term for a[CR] type of thick sauce.[CR]Q: What about the "Shura[CR]Sword"?[CR]A: _Shura_ doesnt translate well, particularly as the name of a[CR]sword.[CR] Its written using the same kanji as the word Ashura and is used[CR]in[CR] the titles of several other games, such as "Rushing Beat Shura" and[CR]"Shura no Mon." It definitely connotes violence, however.[CR]Q: And what do[CR]the kanji on the title screen mean?[CR]A: They are pronounced "Tougi Ou",[CR]which we translated in the game as[CR] "King Colossus", so the title screen is[CR]already "translated".[CR] I considered subtitling it, like I did with the[CR]opening credits, but[CR] I couldnt get it to look good; it either obscured the[CR]background too much[CR] or had an odd-looking location.[CR]Q: I cant enter[CR]Castle Lufelia! What do I do?[CR]A: Even though Lufelia dramatically appears[CR]on the map, youre not supposed[CR] to go there yet. In case you werent paying[CR]attention, first you must[CR] go to Kazard, which is east of Sirius (although[CR]you might not have known[CR] that, since it was previously "unselectable" or[CR]because you couldnt read[CR] the map in the instruction booklet).[CR]Q:[CR]Shields dont increase my defense, so what good are they?[CR]A: They can block[CR]certain attacks. When you arent attacking, your shield is[CR] raised. It comes[CR]in handy sometimes.[CR]Q: Is it possible to get all the items?[CR]A: Not the[CR]_item_ items, but all the equipment, yes. Assuming you didnt[CR] miss the[CR]articles in places that can never be returned to...[CR]Q: Shouldnt that guys[CR]name be "Orpheus"?[CR]A: Its possible that they were alluding to Orpheus, but[CR]the fact remains[CR] that the pronunciation is significantly different. If it[CR]is an allusion[CR] then this is quite appropriate, as blatant references are[CR]not good style.[CR] Also, please note that Orphus in this game has very little[CR]in common with[CR] the mythological Orpheus.[CR]Q: Why is this readme file so[CR]long? I dont want to read all this![CR]A: I was bored while awaiting the last[CR]bit of help I needed from my Japanese[CR] friend. I actually thought about[CR]chucking the entire thing, but then I[CR] remembered that there are a few[CR]important things about the patch in this[CR] file, so I decided to keep[CR]it.[CR]Q: Is your patcher program safe?[CR]A: No. Anyone could replace it with[CR]a trojan and rewrite this readme to[CR] make it seem safe. Thats one reason[CR]why I dont include it with the[CR] patch itself. Its up to you to decide which[CR]program to use to apply[CR] the patch, but unless you wrote the program[CR]yourself, theres always[CR] some risk involved. This goes nicely with the next[CR]Q and A...[CR]Q: How do I know your translation is accurate?[CR]A: You cant[CR]"know" anything! Life is all about belief and faith. Elsewhere[CR] in this[CR]document I discuss the accuracy of this translation; its up to[CR] you whether[CR]or not you believe it. Faith, in this case, would mean[CR] actually playing[CR]this game, thereby acting on your belief that it is[CR] accurate. Thats what I[CR]believe anyway...[CR]Q: Why are you acting like a philosopher now, you uptight[CR]freak?[CR]A: Im not trying to, I dont believe in philosophy and I...[CR]Q:[CR]Shut up, loser! You translate stupid, old video games![CR]A: Thats not[CR]a...[CR]Q: I said shut up![CR]A: ...[CR]Contact[CR]-----------------------------------------------------------------------------[CR]You[CR]can attempt to contact any of us regarding the King Colossus translation[CR]at[CR]the following email address:[CR]tougi_ou@yahoo.com[CR]I cannot guarantee a[CR]timely reply, or even that it will ever be read; check[CR]the date at the top[CR]of this page to see how old this is. The older the email[CR]address gets, the[CR]less frequently it will be checked.[CR]And on the[CR]web:[CR]http://www.geocities.com/tougi_ou/KingColossus.html</plot>
    <studio>M.I.J.E.T.</studio>
    <snapshot1>ALlwuB9.jpg</snapshot1>
  </game>
  <game name="King Colossus (Japan) [T-En by MIJET v20061030] [n]">
    <description>King Colossus (Japan) [T-En by MIJET v20061030] [n]</description>
    <title_clean>King Colossus</title_clean>
    <rom name="MaybeIntroTEn20121007/Maybe-Intro%20%5BT-En%5D%20%2820121007%29.zip/Sega%20Mega%20Drive%20%5BT-En%5D%2FKing%20Colossus%20%28Japan%29%20%5BT-En%20by%20MIJET%20v20061030%5D%20%5Bn%5D.zip" size="640160"/>
    <plot>King Colossus is a role playing game for the Sega Genesis.[CR]Read[CR]Me:[CR]Patch version 061030 (yymmdd)[CR]Readme version 061030 (yymmdd)[CR]King Colossus[CR] English Translation Patch[CR] by M.I.J.E.T.[CR]History[CR]-----------------------------------------------------------------------------[CR]061030[CR]Works on a real Genesis now. Script revised slightly.[CR]060114 Fixed checksum[CR]error.[CR]060108 Now works with a hacked version of the rom file.[CR]051203[CR]Fixed a compatibility problem. Q and A section updated.[CR]051123 Initial[CR]release.[CR]Overview[CR]-----------------------------------------------------------------------------[CR]This[CR]is a translation patch for the Mega Drive game "King Colossus", by Sega.[CR]It[CR]is a very high quality patch, both in the translation and[CR]hacking[CR]departments, and is perhaps the first "dual-language" (i.e. it[CR]supports both[CR]Japanese and English) fan translation of a video game.[CR]Applying the[CR]Patch[CR]-----------------------------------------------------------------------------[CR]Hopefully[CR]included with this document is a patch file in the pretentiously-[CR]named IPS[CR]format. You can use any program that supports this file format[CR]to apply the[CR]patch to your ROM file.[CR]Alternatively, you can use the supplied executable[CR]program to apply the[CR]patch. The program will read the IPS file (which[CR]should be kept in the same[CR]directory as the program) and will open two file[CR]requesters: one for loading[CR]the original ROM file and one for saving the[CR]patched ROM file. It will[CR]check the ROM file (de-interleaving it if[CR]necessary) and will fail if there[CR]is something wrong with the file. A[CR]normal IPS program cannot do this as[CR]it has no idea what it is patching.[CR]The program has not been extensively[CR]tested, so if you have problems (or[CR]simply dont trust a foreign executable[CR]file) you always have the option of[CR]using a different program. Another[CR]reason you might want to use an[CR]alternative program is because it is not[CR]compatible with your[CR]computer...[CR]Please note that you are morally obligated to own an original[CR]copy of this[CR]game in order to use the "ROM file". I got my copy for around[CR]$10, and Id[CR]definitely say that its worth the price.[CR] Playing the[CR]Game[CR]-----------------------------------------------------------------------------[CR]Once[CR]youve patched the ROM file, simply load it up in your favorite[CR]Genesis /[CR]Mega Drive emulator, console copier, or flash cartridge.[CR]Since this is a[CR]dual-language game, you must set the country code to USA[CR]to play it in[CR]English. If you want to play it in the original Japanese,[CR]set the country[CR]code to Japan. Note that in this mode it will not be[CR]identical to the[CR]original Japanese version; the windows are larger, some bugs[CR]have been[CR]fixed, and many name limitations were changed. Also, some of the[CR]non-script[CR]text will still be in English.[CR]Statistics[CR]-----------------------------------------------------------------------------[CR]IPS[CR]File Size 62484 B (61.0 kB)[CR] Patches 391[CR] Data 60521 B (59.1[CR]kB)[CR]Simple Patches (no large data blocks, no assembled code)[CR] Lines in[CR]File 545 (includes comments and whitespace)[CR] Size of File 13,806 B (13.4[CR]kB) (CRLF format)[CR] Code and Data Patches Combined[CR] Number 330[CR] Total[CR]Size 736 B[CR] Code Patches Only (these are generally &lt; 4 instructions, not[CR]assembled)[CR] Number 245[CR] Total Size 496 B[CR]Assembly Code (not including[CR]simple code patches [less than 4 instructions])[CR] Subroutines 41[CR]Instructions 566 (excludes non-instructions, like data constants)[CR] Lines in[CR]File 1,665 (includes comments, whitespace, and data constants)[CR] Source Size[CR]19,608 B (19.1 kB) (LF format)[CR] Binary Size 2,910 B (2.8 kB)[CR] Code Size[CR]1,978 B (1.9 kB)[CR] Data Size 932 B (mostly font data)[CR]Script[CR] Banks[CR]5[CR] Original 35,309 B (34.5 kB) (double it for approx. size in JIS[CR]format)[CR] Translated 53,443 B (52.2 kB) (again, this is as formatted in the[CR]ROM)[CR] Characters Hiragana, Katakana, Alphanumeric (upper and lower),[CR]symbols[CR]Other Text ~2 kB[CR]Readme File[CR] Size 35,639 B (34.8 kB) (CRLF[CR]format)[CR] Lines 839[CR]Most impressive is the number of code patches (245).[CR]This means the code[CR]was patched in 245 different locations. Some of these[CR]are hooks into my[CR]41 assembly language subroutines, which were necessary[CR]when the original[CR]code couldnt simply be overwritten.[CR] List of Changes[CR](not[CR]exhaustive)[CR]-----------------------------------------------------------------------------[CR]Name[CR]limit increased from 4 to 8 bytes ([han]dakuten characters take 2[CR]bytes)[CR]Changed various string size limitations[CR]Added or changed several[CR]characters in the font[CR]Added a new control code to make use of the last[CR]line of text w/o limitations[CR]Increased the size of the normal text[CR]window[CR]Increased the size of the location name window[CR]Increased the size[CR]of the arena rankings window[CR]Increased the size of the weapon rental[CR]window[CR]Arena rankings now have an appropriate suffix (i.e. "1st" instead of[CR]"No. 1")[CR]Many modifications to the name entry screen[CR] Lower-case[CR]characters can now be used[CR] Starting location changed[CR] All kana[CR]characters are still available[CR] Added katakana VU (voiced U) just for[CR]fun[CR]Many modifications to the pause menus[CR] Changed the size and location[CR]of the windows[CR] Translated the text[CR] Fixes to the window movement and[CR]overlapping[CR]Workaround for unlimited string bank sizes[CR]Subtitled the[CR]kanji in the opening credits[CR]Fixed some spelling errors in the ending[CR]credits (required additional fonts)[CR]Auto-detects the country code and shows[CR]English / Japanese text accordingly[CR] Translation[CR]Accuracy[CR]-----------------------------------------------------------------------------[CR]The[CR]script was translated by a native speaker of English with the help of[CR]a[CR]native speaker of Japanese, who has lived in America for around five[CR]years.[CR]Although I translated everything, I could not have completed this[CR]project[CR]without the help of my Japanese friend, who checked my work and[CR]helped me[CR]with the parts I didnt understand. Thanks to him, the script is[CR]so much[CR]more robust than it would have been, as he explained many of the[CR]unstated[CR]implications and subtleties contained with the text and provided[CR]much more[CR]natural-sounding English translations, as opposed to my dry,[CR]literal ones.[CR]A lot of editing was performed on the script. I often edited[CR]a single[CR]string a half-dozen times or more until I was satisfied with the[CR]results.[CR]While editing, I normally checked the string in-game, as text that[CR]looks[CR]OK in my editor sometimes doesnt "work" during the game.[CR]Anyway,[CR]due to all of the above, youd definitely see some differences if[CR]you[CR]compared the two scripts side-by-side. This is normal for a good[CR]translation[CR]of such disparate languages and should not be misconstrued as[CR]evidence of[CR]inaccuracy; if the tenses are "wrong" or some superfluous[CR]adverbs are missing[CR]it is not because we didnt understand the original.[CR]Rest assured that I[CR]was especially careful when translating the most[CR]important parts of the[CR]script and always had my Japanese associate check[CR]them (and his translations[CR]were often far more liberal than mine because he[CR]would render it the way he[CR]would have said it in English; in other words,[CR]he would translate the idea,[CR]rather than the literal meaning). No important[CR]information was "lost in[CR]translation".[CR]In conclusion, I hope you find[CR]this translation to be of very high quality.[CR]I believe it to be both[CR]accurate and well-written and I hope that you enjoy[CR]it as much as I[CR]have.[CR] Translation[CR]Notes[CR]-----------------------------------------------------------------------------[CR]The[CR]following is a list of certain things that I consider inappropriate for[CR]a[CR]translation, with examples from commercially translated games[CR](although[CR]many unofficial translations contain them as well) that I recall.[CR]You may[CR]or may not agree with me, but I encourage translators to at least[CR]consider[CR]the suitability of the following items for their work.[CR]My[CR]translation does not contain...[CR] - inside jokes (Legend of Mana: Cafe[CR]"Sorry Carl!")[CR] - pop culture references (Chrono Trigger: Ozzie, Flea, and[CR]Slash)[CR] - inappropriate allusions (Legend of Mana: "El Hazardous")[CR] -[CR]name changes (within the limits of transliteration, of course)[CR] - colorful[CR]accents (especially not British punk accents, ugh)[CR] - anachronisms (usually[CR]these are unintentional)[CR] - censorship (not that I care, but some people[CR]make a big deal out of it)[CR] (and not that there was much worth censoring[CR]anyway)[CR]And I tried to avoid...[CR] - idioms (a few were unavoidable, and[CR]some are actual translations)[CR] - spelling errors[CR] - grammatical[CR]errors[CR] - punctuation errors[CR] - spacing and alignment errors[CR] -[CR]inconsistencies (these are tough to check, especially in large[CR]scripts)[CR]Obviously no one would intentionally make errors, but I wanted to[CR]show[CR]the things that I checked for and was careful about; Ive seen way[CR]too[CR]many sloppy translations. Actually, there ARE a few intentional[CR]grammatical[CR]errors in the script, in order to make it sound more natural.[CR]There arent[CR]many and you probably wont notice them, unless you are well[CR]acquainted with[CR]the rules of grammar, as they are very minor and would[CR]sound normal to a[CR]native speaker of English. Please bear in mind that the[CR]script represents[CR]spoken dialogue, not formal writing.[CR] Transliteration[CR]Notes[CR]-----------------------------------------------------------------------------[CR]When[CR]transliterating names I normally took a direct romanization and then[CR]tried[CR]to make it look and sound better for English speakers. I generally[CR]used[CR]whichever I felt was the better choice for the r/l, b/v, and s/th pairs[CR]and[CR]dropped extraneous vowels. Occasionally the letter h was used to[CR]help[CR]clarify pronunciation and ph was often used in place of f.[CR]Finally,[CR]once or twice I replaced long a vowels with ar. Other than that,[CR]I[CR]rarely changed the vowels, so they should generally be given a[CR]Japanese[CR]pronunciation, if you know how. This even applies to oo, which is[CR]NOT the[CR]rather ill-conceived romanization of ou but represents o-.[CR]The[CR]following names were translated, rather than simply transliterated,[CR]and[CR]should be pronounced as in English[CR] DEZAIA Desire[CR] SHIRIOSU[CR]Sirius[CR] GANI-ME Ganyme(de)[CR] KURISU Kris[CR]...and some that are[CR](probably) French (pronounced as in English, however).[CR] ROA-RU Loire[CR]PARISU Paris[CR]Finally, it wasnt clear whether or not they meant Orpheus for[CR]this one, as[CR]the pronunciations are significantly different, so I just[CR]transliterated it.[CR] ORUFESU Orphus[CR]That was one of the few vowel[CR]changes; I didnt like "Orphes" or "Orfes".[CR]And speaking of vowel changes,[CR]heres the other major one:[CR] KARURIMU Carleem[CR]As with Orphus, I imagine[CR]most people would instinctively give the word[CR]the correct pronunciation,[CR]based on the way it looks.[CR]Oh, and yes, Iria is the exact romanization for[CR]that particular name.[CR] Hacking[CR]Notes[CR]-----------------------------------------------------------------------------[CR]This[CR]hack required a lot of work. I had to do quite a bit of disassembly[CR]and[CR]ended up getting pretty familiar with the inner workings of the code.[CR]It[CR]took about two weeks of full-time (all day, every day) hacking, not[CR]to[CR]mention a few days worth of minor bug fixing and adjustments during[CR]the[CR]translation phase.[CR]One of the more annoying aspects of this[CR]translation hack was the excessive[CR]amount of inlining and hard-coding[CR]employed by the original programmers.[CR]For example, the code for the save[CR]menu uses the SAME VALUE hard-coded in[CR]SIX different places! And from a[CR]quick look at my patch source file, I[CR]can see that those changes only[CR]amount to about half of what needed to be[CR]changed for that particular menu,[CR]not including the hooks into my assembly[CR]language subroutines. Another[CR]example is that there are probably half-a-[CR]dozen text decoding routines,[CR]all with minor variations. And simply[CR]changing the size of a window was[CR]never sufficient; there were always two[CR]to six subroutines for actually[CR]rendering that specific window that needed[CR]to be changed as[CR]well.[CR]Attention to detail ended up requiring many additional days of work.[CR]You[CR]cannot imagine the amount of effort it took to get everything[CR]"perfect". The[CR]pause menus alone probably took half of a week to finish, as[CR]so many things[CR]had to be changed, even the way the windows scroll. Many of[CR]the things I[CR]fixed probably would not even have been noticed, but I am[CR]something of a[CR]perfectionist; I could have taken the easy route and not[CR]bothered to increase[CR]the window sizes and string length limits, which[CR]probably would have saved me[CR]a week of overtime hours working on this[CR]hack.[CR]Another problem was the overuse of buffers. I had to fix several[CR]buffer[CR]overflow errors cause by the increased size of the strings. In many[CR]cases[CR]there was no practical reason for some of the strings to be copied[CR]to[CR]memory (or sometimes even the cartridge RAM!) Rather than increasing[CR]the[CR]size of the buffers (and risking address conflicts), I used some[CR]clever[CR]code hacks to increase the limits without changing the sizes of the[CR]original[CR]buffers.[CR]On the positive side, the credits and the "game over"[CR]screen were already[CR]in English, although I still ended up having to fix a[CR]few things. The[CR]ending credits were particularly annoying because of the[CR]variable width[CR]font; I had to make some additional character combinations[CR]in order to[CR]correct their English. Anyway, please dont think that Im[CR]complaining about[CR]all this; I just want to show that "reinserting" a[CR]translated script is often[CR]no way near as simple as it sounds, especially[CR]when it is done properly.[CR]So far Ive found at least four different[CR]compression schemes used in this[CR]game; it seems like every kind of data has[CR]its own compression method.[CR]I didnt bother trying to recompress anything as[CR]there was plenty of free[CR]space left in the ROM. I ripped all the[CR]decompression code, which came[CR]in handy several times.[CR]My code is[CR]usually pretty efficient, but you might notice some seemingly[CR]unnecessary[CR]stuff. The reason is because I always try to be as careful[CR]as possible when[CR]patching foreign programs, so there is some code in there[CR]to emulate[CR]calculations that my subroutines didnt need. I also refused to[CR]trash any[CR]registers unless the original code was obviously doing so[CR]immediately after[CR]me. Even the upper word of data registers was preserved[CR]and if the original[CR]programmers felt it necessary to clear an entire[CR]register, so did I. In my[CR]opinion, its not worth the risk of introducing[CR]subtle bugs just to save a[CR]few bytes or make the program run unnoticeably[CR]faster.[CR]Sadly, there was[CR]one thing I missed and that was the fact that certain[CR]control codes mixed[CR]in with some of the strings are read as words instead[CR]of bytes. This can[CR]cause misalignment errors, a misfeature of the 68000[CR]which will crash the[CR]game on a real console and can cause problems on[CR]some emulators. The[CR]original developers handled this by inserting a dummy[CR]byte for alignment[CR]purposes, when necessary, but this was a very poor[CR]solution to the problem.[CR]Since my emulator completely ignores misaligned[CR]accesses I was unaware that[CR]some of my translated strings had the control[CR]codes in the wrong places.[CR]Now that the game has been tested on a real[CR]Genesis I hope that my patch is[CR]now error free. Alignment errors are an[CR]amateurish mistake, so this is[CR]somewhat embarrassing, although the way it[CR]occurred in the data could have[CR]been missed by any expert. It was very[CR]unfortunate that things worked out[CR]this way, because if it werent for[CR]those stupid control codes being treated[CR]as words my patch would have[CR]been perfect upon its initial release; the[CR]only practical difference[CR]between the first release and this final[CR](hopefully) version is that a few[CR]of the strings were padded for alignment[CR]purposes. No other problems[CR]were ever brought to my attention.[CR]Consistency[CR]Notes[CR]-----------------------------------------------------------------------------[CR]Much[CR]of what Ive written could be construed as advice to other hackers[CR]and[CR]translators. With that in mind, here is a partial list of the[CR]consistency[CR]checks I performed after the script was translated and edited.[CR]Hopefully[CR]they will prove useful. Inconsistencies often go unnoticed, but[CR]eliminating[CR]them makes your work look much more professional.[CR] all proper names[CR]inconsistent stuttering (search for -)[CR] inconsistent capitalization of[CR]names. For example...[CR] Castle  but "the castle of X"[CR] King , else king[CR](lowercase) (same with prince(ss) and queen)[CR] "The" (e.g. The ) vs.[CR]"the"[CR]Inconsistent alternate spellings[CR] Goodbye vs. Good-bye (both are[CR]considered correct, at least by some)[CR] OK Ok ok okay[CR] (For the next two,[CR]I use both spellings for their different nuances)[CR] alright (more of an[CR]expression) vs. all right ("allright" is wrong)[CR] anytime vs. any time[CR]anymore (from now on, at present) vs. any more (additional meanings)[CR]Spell-[CR]checkers cant catch typos that are correctly spelled[CR] your youre[CR] its[CR]its[CR] their there theyre[CR] were where were[CR] then than[CR] unintentional[CR]double spaces[CR] comma not followed by a space[CR] repeated words (e.g. the[CR]the) (make sure the spell-checker does this)[CR] that that (not all spell-[CR]checkers check this; it can be legitimate)[CR] repeated words between lines[CR](line breaks can mess up spell-checkers)[CR]There are many, many more[CR]homophones (as well as homonyms and homographs) in[CR]English, but there isnt[CR]much point in listing them; I only included the[CR]most common ones that I[CR]could think of.[CR]Some of those checks require manually searching for and[CR]checking every[CR]instance of a word, which can be tedious. All in all, I[CR]probably found[CR]less than half-a-dozen typos or inconsistencies during this[CR]phase, but[CR]that was after lots of editing; your mileage may "very"[CR];)[CR]"How to Stutter Correctly"[CR]Well, stutter however you want, just be[CR]consistent... ;)[CR]Right Wrong[CR]Sound[CR]-----------------------------[CR]W-Who not Wh-Who (hu sound) (note[CR]the irregularity of this one)[CR]Wh-What not W-What (wh sound)[CR]Th-This not[CR]T-This (th sound)[CR]Sh-She not S-She (sh sound)[CR]Th-That not Th-that (watch[CR]out for inconsistent capitalization)[CR]I, I not I-I (personal pronoun I is a[CR]special case)[CR]I, Im not I-Im (same with d, ll, etc.)[CR]I-It not I, It (ih[CR]sound)[CR] Original[CR]Bugs[CR]-----------------------------------------------------------------------------[CR]These[CR]are all the bugs in the original game that I have found. Please check[CR]this[CR]section carefully before reporting a bug; if it is in here already then[CR]its[CR]probably never going to get fixed...[CR]Note that there are a few minor plot[CR]spoilers in this section.[CR]In the very beginning, if you try to leave the[CR]room before talking to Muuk,[CR]the color of the text will be wrong. This is a[CR]bug in the game flow, not the[CR]script, and is not trivial to fix.[CR]Theres[CR]another one at the end of the first chapter, when Muuk speaks to[CR]Flora as[CR]you are leaving.[CR]Before you fight Desire, her text is green at one[CR]point.[CR]Its actually not an original bug, but there is a slight textual[CR]error[CR]during the "second audience" scene. You probably wouldnt notice it,[CR]even[CR]if you were looking for it, and it was necessary to make the text[CR]appear the[CR]way I wanted it. Id be pretty impressed if anyone found[CR]it...[CR]The statues in the shrine will give you garbage messages if you[CR]return[CR]there later on. Sometimes theyll give you real messages too; the[CR]game is[CR]reading the right string number in the wrong bank. Actually,[CR]sometimes it[CR]will read from the correct bank, which might explain why this[CR]bug went[CR]unnoticed.[CR] I fixed some of the garbage by adding extra strings[CR]to one of the banks that[CR]it reads from, but I couldnt do this for the other[CR]bank because there was[CR]already a string assigned to that number. Hence you[CR]will get to read part[CR]of the ending...[CR] As with the color errors listed[CR]above, theres no easy way to fix this[CR]because the error is probably in the[CR]games data, which is likely compressed,[CR]and would require a lot of reverse[CR]engineering. Since there is no reason[CR]to go back to that area anyway and[CR]since most people probably dont know how[CR]to retrigger these messages, I[CR]dont think its worth the time to try and[CR]fix this bug.[CR]Everyone in[CR]Sirius gives garbage messages later in the game. Once again,[CR]the strings[CR]are being read out of the wrong bank. I was able to fix the[CR]strings for[CR]everyone except the dead guy; his string is the same as the[CR]old mans so[CR]theres nothing I can easily do about that.[CR]Update: talking to anyone in[CR]Sirius later in the game will also screw up[CR]the messages for just about[CR]everyone else! To fix this, talk to anyone[CR]in Distaria or get the "gate is[CR]firmly shut" message in Distaria Coliseum.[CR]As with all of the above, this[CR]is an original bug and Im very pessimistic[CR]about fixing it. Based on what I[CR]know, the problem is probably in the[CR]games data, and it could take weeks to[CR]figure out how the internal[CR]structures are arranged. Im usually not too[CR]enthusiastic about fixing[CR]other peoples bugs...[CR]When there is more than[CR]one color of text being displayed simultaneously,[CR]all the text will be the[CR]same color as the last one used, when the lines are[CR]scrolled out of the[CR]window. My script has been arranged to avoid this.[CR]Moving off of "other[CR]items" onto a valid item wont print the string.[CR]You cant normally get[CR]enough items to do this anyway, so its no big deal.[CR]Actually, I seem to[CR]have inadvertently fixed this...[CR]The pause menu is too short and the sword[CR]pointer overlaps part of it.[CR]The original game designers didnt seem to[CR]care, and fixing this would be a[CR]lot of trouble due to the way the menu is[CR]rolled up and moved around.[CR]In the ending, it looks as if some of the[CR]scenes are cut off. This was[CR]intentional; if you pay attention, youll[CR]notice that each scene shows[CR]less and less on both the top and bottom.[CR]Quite an interesting bit of[CR]direction, especially considering that its a[CR]game, and an old one at that.[CR]---------------------------------------------------------------------------[CR]|[CR]The rest of these are things that probably wouldnt get blamed on me, but[CR]|[CR]| have been documented for your interest anyway. |[CR]---------------------------------------------------------------------------[CR]Sometimes[CR]sprites will change position slightly during the cutscenes.[CR]Its possible to[CR]get a character who is following you (but not closely)[CR]to walk through[CR]solid walls.[CR]It is also possible to attack through solid walls.[CR]The way[CR]the game handles tile overlays (i.e. either on a second plane or[CR]using[CR]sprites) isnt perfect. You can occasionally see parts of your[CR]weapons[CR]appear when going through an underpass. You can also see similar[CR]effects[CR]if you jump in certain places, such as the first cave.[CR]It is[CR]possible to place the Lost Eyes in the statue without triggering[CR]the[CR]message. The door opens, however, and you can elicit the message[CR]later,[CR]if you want.[CR]In Kazard, it isnt necessary to light the torches if[CR]you jump correctly.[CR]It isnt a big help and it might have other[CR]consequences, so I wouldnt[CR]recommend skipping that part. Also, once you[CR]jump to the other side, its[CR]possible to enter the kings chamber by jumping[CR]diagonally on either side[CR]of the walkway near the door. This is absolutely[CR]no help, since you can[CR]just walk through the door once youre across, but[CR]its interesting.[CR]In Lufelia, some of the sword pointers in the pause menu[CR]are gray, while[CR]others are not.[CR]Its possible to get trapped in Ganants[CR]hidden room if he isnt there to[CR]send you back out. You cant save, so if you[CR]dont have enough MP to cast[CR]Exodus theres nothing you can do.[CR]Theres a[CR]fake passage in Linas room later in the game. It seems to be the[CR]same as in[CR]the dragon cave; theres a hole in the wall, you just cant enter[CR]it. Also,[CR]earlier in the game it is possible to get underneath the throne[CR]in that[CR]room. I have a screen-shot of this, if anybody wants to see it.[CR]The ending[CR]credits are cued to the music, so they dont start for quite[CR]a while; the[CR]game has not crashed.[CR] Q and[CR]A[CR]-----------------------------------------------------------------------------[CR]Q:[CR]This patch doesnt work! What do I do?[CR]A: Make sure your ROM file is not in[CR]an interleaved format. Its also[CR] possible that there is more than one[CR]version of the game, or your copy is[CR] corrupt. If you have problems, try[CR]using the program that I wrote to[CR] apply the patch; it checks for the above[CR]issues. If my program doesnt[CR] work for some reason, you can try a different[CR]IPS patching program, but[CR] you will lose the benefit of having your ROM[CR]file checked.[CR] If there is more than one version of the game, let me know[CR]and Ill try to[CR] support it.[CR]Q: Why is the text in Japanese?!?[CR]A: This[CR]is a dual-language translation patch; if it detects that it is[CR] running on[CR]a Japanese system it will use the original game script.[CR] If you are using[CR]an emulator, make sure the country code is set to USA.[CR] If you really want[CR]to play this game, in English, on a real Japanese Mega[CR] Drive system, then[CR]contact me.[CR]Q: Are state files from the original Japanese version still[CR]compatible?[CR]A: No. They may work partially, but some stuff will definitely[CR]be missing.[CR] Ideally, you should save your game on the original version and[CR]use that[CR] same SRAM file for my version of the game, as saved games should[CR]still be[CR] compatible.[CR]Q: I found a spelling/grammatical/punctuation[CR]error! What should I do?[CR]A: Well, I hope there arent any errors, but if you[CR]do find one please[CR] let me know about it so I can correct it. Assuming it[CR]is a legitimate[CR] error, you will be credited for finding it.[CR] Note that[CR]there are a few grammatical errors that are intentional, usually[CR] with[CR]stock phrases. If youre sharp enough to notice them, then go ahead[CR] and[CR]report them anyway.[CR]Q: I found a bug! What do I do?[CR]A: There are several[CR]minor errors that exist in the original game. I have[CR] documented all the[CR]original bugs that I know of in another section of[CR] this file. If the bug[CR]youve found is not listed there, then please[CR] contact me so I can[CR]investigate it. This includes "color" errors (where[CR] the text appears in[CR]the wrong color), some of which are errors in the[CR] flow of the game, rather[CR]than the script. See the aforementioned section[CR] for details.[CR]Q: MAJOR[CR]BUG! Why is everyone giving me messages from earlier in the game?[CR]A: You[CR]went back to Sirius, didnt you...[CR] This is a bug in the original. I wrote[CR]more about it elsewhere in this[CR] file, but to fix it all you need to do is[CR]talk to anyone in Distaria, or[CR] attempt to enter Distaria Coliseum. Once[CR]any of these correct messages[CR] are displayed, everything will be back to[CR]normal.[CR] To avoid triggering this bug in the first place, dont talk to[CR]anyone in[CR] Sirius after you finished the Lufelia area. Not that they have[CR]anything[CR] interesting to say anyway...[CR]Q: May I suggest changes to your[CR]script?[CR]A: Sure. If you honestly believe it would improve the writing, I[CR]will be[CR] glad to consider it. However, I spent quite a lot of time editing[CR]the[CR] script and checking how it reads within the game, so you probably[CR]wont find too many awkward sentences and such. At least I hope not...[CR]Q: I[CR]see "ss" in your translation. Dont you know that youre supposed to[CR] leave[CR]off the _s_ of possessives for proper names which end in _s_?[CR]A: Although[CR]that practice is common in journalism, many authorities[CR] discourage its[CR]use. Strunk only prescribes it for certain classical[CR] names (e.g. Jesus)[CR]while Gregg recommends a pronunciation-based[CR] approach.[CR]Q: You put a[CR]comma after the final element in a series. Dont you know that[CR] youre not[CR]supposed to do that anymore?[CR]A: Yes, thats what my elementary school[CR]teacher said as well. However, as[CR] in the previous case, this is "newspaper[CR]grammar". It can cause ambiguity[CR] and it removes a valuable visual cue,[CR]just to save a little space.[CR] Garners book on usage has a nice discussion[CR]of this point.[CR]Q: Why are you dropping names and acting all professional,[CR]like some sort[CR] of English Major? What a jerk...[CR]A: Well, perhaps you[CR]might come to believe that some of the rules of English[CR] that you were[CR]taught (like the prohibition against ending a sentence with[CR] a preposition,[CR]for example) are actually questionable. Furthermore, you[CR] might want a more[CR]reliable reference than the readme file for a video game[CR] translation[CR]patch...[CR] You are correct, however, professionalism, formality, and elitism[CR]are[CR] silly. So are things like funerals, weddings, honor societies,[CR]and...[CR]Q: Shut up![CR]A: Sigh... Thats not a question, but lets move on to[CR]a different subject...[CR]Q: Who is Makoto Ogino? Is this based on a[CR]manga?[CR]A: Makoto Ogino is the author of the manga "Kujaku Ou", which[CR]translates as[CR] "Peacock King". Based on what Ive read of the game box and[CR]instruction[CR] booklet, it seems Makoto Ogino was brought in to direct and[CR]write the[CR] script for King Colossus, or "Tougi Ou". I am confident that it[CR]was a[CR] completely original work, at least at that time.[CR] Incidentally,[CR]there are rumors that this was a port from some unidentified[CR] 8-bit system.[CR]I believe this to be inaccurate information.[CR]Q: Why does my name get[CR]truncated sometimes?[CR]A: The name buffer is eight bytes, but the[CR](han)dakuten characters (the kana[CR] with accent marks) take up 2 bytes each,[CR]so it will truncate your name if[CR] necessary. If it does, you will see the[CR]truncated version in the[CR] confirmation window, so pay attention. If you are[CR]only using Roman[CR] (i.e. English) characters, as most people are likely to[CR]do, your name can[CR] be up to eight characters long and will never be[CR]truncated.[CR]Q: What is the main characters default name?[CR]A: There isnt[CR]one. The instruction booklet refers to him as "the hero of[CR] the story", or[CR]something like that. In the original game, if you select[CR] "END" without[CR]entering anything, you get four blank spaces for a name.[CR] This was fixed;[CR]now it is impossible to have a completely blank name.[CR]Q: I dont want to[CR]read your translation carefully. How can I speed it up?[CR]A: In addition to[CR]the normal speed-up activated by holding the C Button,[CR] you can hold down[CR]any direction on the D Pad to skip the pauses as well.[CR]Q: Is it OK to say[CR]"no" to people?[CR]A: Yes, if you want to give the obvious wrong answer to any[CR]of the "yes or[CR] no" questions in the game, go right ahead; it doesnt appear[CR]to have any[CR] drawbacks and youll get to see their reactions. As with many[CR]games, the[CR] plot wont continue until you give the correct answer. The only[CR]exception[CR] is at the end of the game; your answer determines the ending you[CR]get (and[CR] they are just different; there is no "good ending").[CR] I always[CR]wonder about this sort of thing myself, when playing a new game.[CR]Q: What is[CR]"Demiglace Sauce"?[CR]A: As you might be able to tell from the name, its a[CR]French term for a[CR] type of thick sauce.[CR]Q: What about the "Shura[CR]Sword"?[CR]A: _Shura_ doesnt translate well, particularly as the name of a[CR]sword.[CR] Its written using the same kanji as the word Ashura and is used[CR]in[CR] the titles of several other games, such as "Rushing Beat Shura" and[CR]"Shura no Mon." It definitely connotes violence, however.[CR]Q: And what do[CR]the kanji on the title screen mean?[CR]A: They are pronounced "Tougi Ou",[CR]which we translated in the game as[CR] "King Colossus", so the title screen is[CR]already "translated".[CR] I considered subtitling it, like I did with the[CR]opening credits, but[CR] I couldnt get it to look good; it either obscured the[CR]background too much[CR] or had an odd-looking location.[CR]Q: I cant enter[CR]Castle Lufelia! What do I do?[CR]A: Even though Lufelia dramatically appears[CR]on the map, youre not supposed[CR] to go there yet. In case you werent paying[CR]attention, first you must[CR] go to Kazard, which is east of Sirius (although[CR]you might not have known[CR] that, since it was previously "unselectable" or[CR]because you couldnt read[CR] the map in the instruction booklet).[CR]Q:[CR]Shields dont increase my defense, so what good are they?[CR]A: They can block[CR]certain attacks. When you arent attacking, your shield is[CR] raised. It comes[CR]in handy sometimes.[CR]Q: Is it possible to get all the items?[CR]A: Not the[CR]_item_ items, but all the equipment, yes. Assuming you didnt[CR] miss the[CR]articles in places that can never be returned to...[CR]Q: Shouldnt that guys[CR]name be "Orpheus"?[CR]A: Its possible that they were alluding to Orpheus, but[CR]the fact remains[CR] that the pronunciation is significantly different. If it[CR]is an allusion[CR] then this is quite appropriate, as blatant references are[CR]not good style.[CR] Also, please note that Orphus in this game has very little[CR]in common with[CR] the mythological Orpheus.[CR]Q: Why is this readme file so[CR]long? I dont want to read all this![CR]A: I was bored while awaiting the last[CR]bit of help I needed from my Japanese[CR] friend. I actually thought about[CR]chucking the entire thing, but then I[CR] remembered that there are a few[CR]important things about the patch in this[CR] file, so I decided to keep[CR]it.[CR]Q: Is your patcher program safe?[CR]A: No. Anyone could replace it with[CR]a trojan and rewrite this readme to[CR] make it seem safe. Thats one reason[CR]why I dont include it with the[CR] patch itself. Its up to you to decide which[CR]program to use to apply[CR] the patch, but unless you wrote the program[CR]yourself, theres always[CR] some risk involved. This goes nicely with the next[CR]Q and A...[CR]Q: How do I know your translation is accurate?[CR]A: You cant[CR]"know" anything! Life is all about belief and faith. Elsewhere[CR] in this[CR]document I discuss the accuracy of this translation; its up to[CR] you whether[CR]or not you believe it. Faith, in this case, would mean[CR] actually playing[CR]this game, thereby acting on your belief that it is[CR] accurate. Thats what I[CR]believe anyway...[CR]Q: Why are you acting like a philosopher now, you uptight[CR]freak?[CR]A: Im not trying to, I dont believe in philosophy and I...[CR]Q:[CR]Shut up, loser! You translate stupid, old video games![CR]A: Thats not[CR]a...[CR]Q: I said shut up![CR]A: ...[CR]Contact[CR]-----------------------------------------------------------------------------[CR]You[CR]can attempt to contact any of us regarding the King Colossus translation[CR]at[CR]the following email address:[CR]tougi_ou@yahoo.com[CR]I cannot guarantee a[CR]timely reply, or even that it will ever be read; check[CR]the date at the top[CR]of this page to see how old this is. The older the email[CR]address gets, the[CR]less frequently it will be checked.[CR]And on the[CR]web:[CR]http://www.geocities.com/tougi_ou/KingColossus.html</plot>
    <studio>M.I.J.E.T.</studio>
    <snapshot1>ALlwuB9.jpg</snapshot1>
  </game>
  <game name="Langrisser (USA) [Text Hack by Derrick Sobodash v20010219] [Graphic Hack by MIJET v20070103] [n]">
    <description>Langrisser (USA) [Text Hack by Derrick Sobodash v20010219] [Graphic Hack by MIJET v20070103] [n]</description>
    <title_clean>Langrisser</title_clean>
    <rom name="MaybeIntroTEn20121007/Maybe-Intro%20%5BT-En%5D%20%2820121007%29.zip/Sega%20Mega%20Drive%20%5BT-En%5D%2FLangrisser%20%28USA%29%20%5BText%20Hack%20by%20Derrick%20Sobodash%20v20010219%5D%20%5BGraphic%20Hack%20by%20MIJET%20v20070103%5D%20%5Bn%5D.zip" size="290994"/>
    <plot>The Dalsis Empire has laid seige upon the Castle of Baltia to seize the legendary sword WARSONG. In a desperate attempt, King Alfador sends his only son, Prince Garett, into the countryside, away from impending death. Now Garett must rally his allies from across the kingdom, and lead their valiant armies in a battle against the Empire to retrieve the sacred sword! But, time is running short! Command troops and choose your mission commanders. Unite with loyal allies and charge into campaigns that forge the destiny of a realm. Between you and the path to victory lie dangerous rogues, the steel of Dalsis, and a confrontation in the ultimate showdown against evil!</plot>
    <releasedate>25/04/1991</releasedate>
    <genre>Strategy,Turn-Based,Fantasy</genre>
    <gamefaqs_url>http://www.gamefaqs.com/genesis/586591-warsong</gamefaqs_url>
    <boxart1>J5m10f8.png</boxart1>
    <snapshot1>wflPSwu.png</snapshot1>
    <boxart2>l1KDE7t.jpg</boxart2>
    <snapshot2>PwZ7DqX.png</snapshot2>
  </game>
  <game name="Langrisser II (Japan) (v1.1) [T-En by Hiryuu Honyaku+NoPrgress v20010321]">
    <description>Langrisser II (Japan) (v1.1) [T-En by Hiryuu Honyaku+NoPrgress v20010321]</description>
    <title_clean>Langrisser II</title_clean>
    <rom name="MaybeIntroTEn20121007/Maybe-Intro%20%5BT-En%5D%20%2820121007%29.zip/Sega%20Mega%20Drive%20%5BT-En%5D%2FLangrisser%20II%20%28Japan%29%20%28v1.1%29%20%5BT-En%20by%20Hiryuu%20Honyaku%2BNoPrgress%20v20010321%5D.zip" size="1054844"/>
    <plot>Langrisser II (ranguritsusa2) is a turn-based strategy game developed by CareerSoft and published by Masaya. Unlike the first Langrisser, Langrisser II was not released outside Asia (nor would any future sequel). Two translation groups translated the game: a nearly complete translation by Hiryuu Honyaku and NoPrgress was released in 2001-2004 before M.I.J.E.T. fully translated the game between 2008 and 2010.</plot>
    <genre>Strategy,Turn-Based,Fantasy</genre>
    <studio>Hiryuu Honyaku, NoPrgress</studio>
    <releasedate>26/08/1994</releasedate>
    <gamefaqs_url>http://www.gamefaqs.com/genesis/564392-langrisser-ii</gamefaqs_url>
    <rating>3.32</rating>
    <nplayers>1</nplayers>
    <boxart1>YCyFpYR.png</boxart1>
    <clearlogo1>xUjIk1Q.png</clearlogo1>
    <snapshot1>asSStFX.png</snapshot1>
    <boxart2>l5hAfGz.jpg</boxart2>
    <snapshot2>sa8bQmk.png</snapshot2>
    <boxart3>kSnQjJY.png</boxart3>
  </game>
  <game name="Langrisser II (Japan) (v1.2) [T-En by MIJET v20110701]">
    <description>Langrisser II (Japan) (v1.2) [T-En by MIJET v20110701]</description>
    <title_clean>Langrisser II</title_clean>
    <rom name="MaybeIntroTEn20121007/Maybe-Intro%20%5BT-En%5D%20%2820121007%29.zip/Sega%20Mega%20Drive%20%5BT-En%5D%2FLangrisser%20II%20%28Japan%29%20%28v1.2%29%20%5BT-En%20by%20MIJET%20v20110701%5D.zip" size="1091766"/>
    <plot>Langrisser II (ranguritsusa2) is a turn-based strategy game developed by CareerSoft and published by Masaya. Unlike the first Langrisser, Langrisser II was not released outside Asia (nor would any future sequel). Two translation groups translated the game: a nearly complete translation by Hiryuu Honyaku and NoPrgress was released in 2001-2004 before M.I.J.E.T. fully translated the game between 2008 and 2010.</plot>
    <genre>Strategy,Turn-Based,Fantasy</genre>
    <studio>Hiryuu Honyaku, NoPrgress</studio>
    <releasedate>26/08/1994</releasedate>
    <gamefaqs_url>http://www.gamefaqs.com/genesis/564392-langrisser-ii</gamefaqs_url>
    <rating>3.32</rating>
    <nplayers>1</nplayers>
    <boxart1>YCyFpYR.png</boxart1>
    <clearlogo1>xUjIk1Q.png</clearlogo1>
    <snapshot1>asSStFX.png</snapshot1>
    <boxart2>l5hAfGz.jpg</boxart2>
    <snapshot2>sa8bQmk.png</snapshot2>
    <boxart3>kSnQjJY.png</boxart3>
  </game>
  <game name="Monster World IV (Japan) [T-En by DeJap+Demiforce v1.02]">
    <description>Monster World IV (Japan) [T-En by DeJap+Demiforce v1.02]</description>
    <title_clean>Monster World IV</title_clean>
    <rom name="MaybeIntroTEn20121007/Maybe-Intro%20%5BT-En%5D%20%2820121007%29.zip/Sega%20Mega%20Drive%20%5BT-En%5D%2FMonster%20World%20IV%20%28Japan%29%20%5BT-En%20by%20DeJap%2BDemiforce%20v1.02%5D.zip" size="1003854"/>
    <plot>Monster World IV is a sequel to Wonder Boy 5: Monster World 3. The player controls Asha, the green-haired girlfriend of Shion, the hero of the previous game. One day, Asha was standing on a cliff near her home village, and suddenly heard a mysterious voice calling for help. She decided to leave the village and to embark on an adventure to discover the identity of this mysterious person.</plot>
    <genre>Action,Platformer,2D</genre>
    <studio>DeJap Translations, Demiforce</studio>
    <releasedate>10/05/2012</releasedate>
    <gamefaqs_url>http://www.gamefaqs.com/genesis/581776-monster-world-iv</gamefaqs_url>
    <rating>4.02</rating>
    <nplayers>1</nplayers>
    <boxart1>gfcRQQP.png</boxart1>
    <clearlogo1>rLTIlkv.png</clearlogo1>
    <snapshot1>0kyjYuD.png</snapshot1>
    <fanart1>kordTDz.jpg</fanart1>
    <boxart2>W0zvtCi.jpg</boxart2>
    <snapshot2>r2YQqSa.gif</snapshot2>
    <boxart3>fSjE8PR.jpg</boxart3>
    <boxart4>ShRxF0l.jpg</boxart4>
    <boxart5>j4nreR6.png</boxart5>
    <boxart6>92icAWh.png</boxart6>
  </game>
  <game name="Monster World IV (Japan) [T-En by Michele Di Somma v2.2]">
    <description>Monster World IV (Japan) [T-En by Michele Di Somma v2.2]</description>
    <title_clean>Monster World IV</title_clean>
    <rom name="MaybeIntroTEn20121007/Maybe-Intro%20%5BT-En%5D%20%2820121007%29.zip/Sega%20Mega%20Drive%20%5BT-En%5D%2FMonster%20World%20IV%20%28Japan%29%20%5BT-En%20by%20Michele%20Di%20Somma%20v2.2%5D.zip" size="1005944"/>
    <plot>Monster World IV is a sequel to Wonder Boy 5: Monster World 3. The player controls Asha, the green-haired girlfriend of Shion, the hero of the previous game. One day, Asha was standing on a cliff near her home village, and suddenly heard a mysterious voice calling for help. She decided to leave the village and to embark on an adventure to discover the identity of this mysterious person.</plot>
    <genre>Action,Platformer,2D</genre>
    <studio>DeJap Translations, Demiforce</studio>
    <releasedate>10/05/2012</releasedate>
    <gamefaqs_url>http://www.gamefaqs.com/genesis/581776-monster-world-iv</gamefaqs_url>
    <rating>4.02</rating>
    <nplayers>1</nplayers>
    <boxart1>gfcRQQP.png</boxart1>
    <clearlogo1>rLTIlkv.png</clearlogo1>
    <snapshot1>0kyjYuD.png</snapshot1>
    <fanart1>kordTDz.jpg</fanart1>
    <boxart2>W0zvtCi.jpg</boxart2>
    <snapshot2>r2YQqSa.gif</snapshot2>
    <boxart3>fSjE8PR.jpg</boxart3>
    <boxart4>ShRxF0l.jpg</boxart4>
    <boxart5>j4nreR6.png</boxart5>
    <boxart6>92icAWh.png</boxart6>
  </game>
  <game name="Nadia - The Secret of Blue Water (Japan) [T-En by KingMike Translations v1.1] [n]">
    <description>Nadia - The Secret of Blue Water (Japan) [T-En by KingMike Translations v1.1] [n]</description>
    <title_clean>Nadia - The Secret of Blue Water</title_clean>
    <rom name="MaybeIntroTEn20121007/Maybe-Intro%20%5BT-En%5D%20%2820121007%29.zip/Sega%20Mega%20Drive%20%5BT-En%5D%2FNadia%20-%20The%20Secret%20of%20Blue%20Water%20%28Japan%29%20%5BT-En%20by%20KingMike%20Translations%20v1.1%5D%20%5Bn%5D.zip" size="841905"/>
    <plot>The Pirates of Dark Water is an action platformer game for the Sega[CR]Genesis.[CR]Read Me:[CR]The Pirates of Dark Water (Mega[CR]Drive)[CR]Traduccion al Espanol v1.0 (05/10/2018)[CR](C) 2018 Wave[CR]Translations[CR]------------------------[CR]Notas y Fallos[CR]Conocidos[CR]------------------------[CR]Esta traduccion y hacking es[CR]completamente original.[CR]Si encuentras algun fallo puedes contactar conmigo[CR]y ver mis traducciones[CR]en[CR]traduccioneswave.blogspot.com[CR]------------------------[CR]Instrucciones[CR]de Parcheo[CR]------------------------[CR]En formato IPS, puedes usar LunarIPS[CR]o Floating IPS.[CR]Archivo utilizado:[CR]Pirates of Dark Water, The[CR](UE).bin[CR]MD5: eb0eda9027dd52008594b2755066df86[CR]SHA1:[CR]55496714f32eb7f57335201f90b3f437a1500c49[CR]CRC32: 0a62de34[CR]2.097.152[CR]bytes[CR]--------[CR]Creditos[CR]--------[CR]Wave - Hacking, traduccion y[CR]pruebas.[CR]-- FIN --</plot>
    <studio>Wave</studio>
    <snapshot1>B4zWwdt.png</snapshot1>
    <snapshot2>oiXj1u5.png</snapshot2>
  </game>
  <game name="Phantasy Star II (USA, Europe) (Rev A) [T-En by Naflign's Ego v1.0]">
    <description>Phantasy Star II (USA, Europe) (Rev A) [T-En by Naflign's Ego v1.0]</description>
    <title_clean>Phantasy Star II</title_clean>
    <rom name="MaybeIntroTEn20121007/Maybe-Intro%20%5BT-En%5D%20%2820121007%29.zip/Sega%20Mega%20Drive%20%5BT-En%5D%2FPhantasy%20Star%20II%20%28USA%2C%20Europe%29%20%28Rev%20A%29%20%5BT-En%20by%20Naflign%27s%20Ego%20v1.0%5D.zip" size="473228"/>
    <plot>The time: Space Century 3240. The place: The Algol Star System. It began when King Lassic turned evil and let hordes of hideous, magical creatures run amok on the three planets. When her brother was killed, Alis vowed to avenge his death and put an end to Lassic forever.[CR]Join her in a journey across time and space to worlds where creatures speak...where magic and science combine to take you on the ultimate video quest.[CR]The battle system is turn-based, allowing the player to choose commands for up to four characters. Each of the eight characters has a different set of preferred weapons and armor, as well as techniques, suited to the character's job. The player must defeat enemies in the overworld and in dungeons to advance in the game.</plot>
    <genre>Role-Playing,Console-style RPG</genre>
    <studio>Naflign's Ego</studio>
    <releasedate>18/10/1989</releasedate>
    <gamefaqs_url>http://www.gamefaqs.com/genesis/526675-phantasy-star-ii</gamefaqs_url>
    <rating>4.24</rating>
    <nplayers>1</nplayers>
    <boxart1>kgiRnTC.png</boxart1>
    <clearlogo1>bm5CyTn.png</clearlogo1>
    <snapshot1>ljgY4Wo.png</snapshot1>
    <fanart1>Sp8aJaY.jpg</fanart1>
    <boxart2>Bhqa9eZ.jpg</boxart2>
    <snapshot2>fpNL5P1.gif</snapshot2>
    <boxart3>PDP7CM3.png</boxart3>
    <boxart4>90ujXM1.jpg</boxart4>
  </game>
  <game name="Phantasy Star II (USA, Europe) [T-En by Naflign's Ego v1.0]">
    <description>Phantasy Star II (USA, Europe) [T-En by Naflign's Ego v1.0]</description>
    <title_clean>Phantasy Star II</title_clean>
    <rom name="MaybeIntroTEn20121007/Maybe-Intro%20%5BT-En%5D%20%2820121007%29.zip/Sega%20Mega%20Drive%20%5BT-En%5D%2FPhantasy%20Star%20II%20%28USA%2C%20Europe%29%20%5BT-En%20by%20Naflign%27s%20Ego%20v1.0%5D.zip" size="473215"/>
    <plot>The time: Space Century 3240. The place: The Algol Star System. It began when King Lassic turned evil and let hordes of hideous, magical creatures run amok on the three planets. When her brother was killed, Alis vowed to avenge his death and put an end to Lassic forever.[CR]Join her in a journey across time and space to worlds where creatures speak...where magic and science combine to take you on the ultimate video quest.[CR]The battle system is turn-based, allowing the player to choose commands for up to four characters. Each of the eight characters has a different set of preferred weapons and armor, as well as techniques, suited to the character's job. The player must defeat enemies in the overworld and in dungeons to advance in the game.</plot>
    <genre>Role-Playing,Console-style RPG</genre>
    <studio>Naflign's Ego</studio>
    <releasedate>18/10/1989</releasedate>
    <gamefaqs_url>http://www.gamefaqs.com/genesis/526675-phantasy-star-ii</gamefaqs_url>
    <rating>4.24</rating>
    <nplayers>1</nplayers>
    <boxart1>kgiRnTC.png</boxart1>
    <clearlogo1>bm5CyTn.png</clearlogo1>
    <snapshot1>ljgY4Wo.png</snapshot1>
    <fanart1>Sp8aJaY.jpg</fanart1>
    <boxart2>Bhqa9eZ.jpg</boxart2>
    <snapshot2>fpNL5P1.gif</snapshot2>
    <boxart3>PDP7CM3.png</boxart3>
    <boxart4>90ujXM1.jpg</boxart4>
  </game>
  <game name="Phantasy Star II - Amia's Adventure (Japan) (SegaNet) [T-En by MIJET v20100710]">
    <description>Phantasy Star II - Amia's Adventure (Japan) (SegaNet) [T-En by MIJET v20100710]</description>
    <title_clean>Phantasy Star II - Amia's Adventure</title_clean>
    <rom name="MaybeIntroTEn20121007/Maybe-Intro%20%5BT-En%5D%20%2820121007%29.zip/Sega%20Mega%20Drive%20%5BT-En%5D%2FPhantasy%20Star%20II%20-%20Amia%27s%20Adventure%20%28Japan%29%20%28SegaNet%29%20%5BT-En%20by%20MIJET%20v20100710%5D.zip" size="134830"/>
    <plot>Phantasy Star II: Amia's Adventure is an adventure game for the Sega[CR]Genesis.[CR]Read Me:[CR]Patch version 100710 (yymmdd)[CR]Readme[CR]version 100710 (yymmdd)[CR] Phantasy Star II: Amias Adventure[CR] English[CR]Translation Patch[CR] by M.I.J.E.T.[CR]History[CR]-----------------------------------------------------------------------------[CR]100710[CR]Initial release[CR]Overview[CR]-----------------------------------------------------------------------------[CR]This[CR]is a translation patch for the Mega Drive Sega Net game entitled[CR]"Phantasy[CR]Star II: Amias Adventure". It sports a variable-width font engine[CR]with[CR]kerning and, as usual, it is a "dual-language" patch, meaning that[CR]it[CR]supports both Japanese and English, depending on the country code of[CR]your[CR]machine.[CR] Applying the[CR]Patch[CR]-----------------------------------------------------------------------------[CR]Hopefully[CR]included with this document is a patch file in the IPS format.[CR]You can use[CR]any program that supports that file format to apply this[CR]translation patch[CR]to your ROM file.[CR]Alternatively, you can use the program from my website to[CR]apply the patch,[CR]but make sure that you have the latest version or it wont[CR]work. The program[CR]will check the ROM file (de-interleaving it if necessary)[CR]and will give[CR]you an error message if something went wrong. A normal IPS[CR]program cannot[CR]do this as it has no idea what it is patching. The program[CR]has not been[CR]extensively tested, so if you have problems (or simply dont[CR]trust a foreign[CR]executable) you always have the option of using a different[CR]program.[CR] Playing the[CR]Game[CR]-----------------------------------------------------------------------------[CR]Once[CR]youve patched the ROM file, simply load it up in your favorite[CR]Genesis /[CR]Mega Drive emulator, console copier, or flash cartridge.[CR]The game will[CR]detect the country code of your machine (real or emulated) and[CR]then switch[CR]to English or Japanese mode accordingly.[CR] Q and[CR]A[CR]-----------------------------------------------------------------------------[CR]Q:[CR]This patch doesnt work! What do I do?[CR]A: Make sure that your ROM file is[CR]not in an interleaved format. Its also[CR] possible that there is more than[CR]one version of the game, or that your[CR] copy is corrupt. If you have[CR]problems, try using the program that I wrote[CR] to apply the patch; it checks[CR]for the above issues. It is available on my[CR] website.[CR] Some emulators[CR]may also fail to run the program. Please make sure you try[CR] several of the[CR]most up-to-date emulators available.[CR]Q: It doesnt work with my copier /[CR]flash cartridge! Why not?[CR] This was tested on a real Genesis so you[CR]shouldnt have any problems in[CR] that respect. The most likely reason is that[CR]something went wrong during[CR] the patching process. See the previous[CR]question and try it in an emulator[CR] to see if that works.[CR] Another[CR]possibility is that you are using a PAL Mega Drive. This game was[CR] designed[CR]for NTSC systems and I didnt make any changes in that respect.[CR] It should[CR]still run (probably at the wrong speed), but you never know...[CR]Q: Is your[CR]patcher program safe?[CR]A: No. Anyone could replace it with a trojan and[CR]rewrite this readme to[CR] make it seem safe. Thats one reason why I dont[CR]include it with the[CR] patch itself. Its up to you to decide which program to[CR]use to apply[CR] the patch, but unless you wrote the program yourself theres[CR]always[CR] some risk involved.[CR]Q: Why is the text in Japanese?!?[CR]A: This[CR]is a dual-language translation patch. If it detects that it is[CR] running on[CR]a Japanese system, it will use the original game script.[CR] If you are using[CR]an emulator, make sure the country code is set to USA.[CR]Translation/Transliteration[CR]Notes[CR]-----------------------------------------------------------------------------[CR]The[CR]surnames are simply omitted, since there is no way to tell for sure how[CR]to[CR]properly transliterate/translate them. Unless someone can produce[CR]an[CR]official source, written in romaji, it is safer to just leave them[CR]out.[CR]The katakana renditions are available at various places online, for[CR]the[CR]curious, but dont trust their transliterations. For example, "Kinds"[CR]is[CR]commonly misspelled as "Kainz", even though the latter is the most[CR]logical[CR]transliteration. So you can see why its impossible to tell for[CR]sure.[CR] Hacking[CR]Notes[CR]-----------------------------------------------------------------------------[CR]Nothing[CR]interesting (fortunately). The usual techniques were employed and old[CR]code[CR]was modified and reused. The variable-width font engine was upgraded[CR]to[CR]handle groups and triplets (possibly a new invention in kerning[CR]technology).[CR]Contact[CR]-----------------------------------------------------------------------------[CR]mijeto@gmail.com[CR]I[CR]cannot guarantee a timely reply; this address is sometimes not checked[CR]for[CR]months at a time.[CR]http://mijet.eludevisibility.org/</plot>
    <studio>M.I.J.E.T.</studio>
    <snapshot1>iuEcAWW.png</snapshot1>
    <snapshot2>xm0pqPt.png</snapshot2>
  </game>
  <game name="Phantasy Star II - Anne's Adventure (Japan) (SegaNet) [T-En by MIJET v20100710]">
    <description>Phantasy Star II - Anne's Adventure (Japan) (SegaNet) [T-En by MIJET v20100710]</description>
    <title_clean>Phantasy Star II - Anne's Adventure</title_clean>
    <rom name="MaybeIntroTEn20121007/Maybe-Intro%20%5BT-En%5D%20%2820121007%29.zip/Sega%20Mega%20Drive%20%5BT-En%5D%2FPhantasy%20Star%20II%20-%20Anne%27s%20Adventure%20%28Japan%29%20%28SegaNet%29%20%5BT-En%20by%20MIJET%20v20100710%5D.zip" size="134266"/>
    <plot>Phantasy Star II: Anne's Adventure is an adventure game for the Sega[CR]Genesis.[CR]Read Me:[CR]Patch version 100710 (yymmdd)[CR]Readme[CR]version 100710 (yymmdd)[CR] Phantasy Star II: Annes Adventure[CR] English[CR]Translation Patch[CR] by M.I.J.E.T.[CR]History[CR]-----------------------------------------------------------------------------[CR]071024[CR]Initial release[CR]100710 Script rewritten, code updated, minor graphics fix,[CR]bug fixes[CR]Overview[CR]-----------------------------------------------------------------------------[CR]This[CR]is a translation patch for the Mega Drive Sega Net game entitled[CR]"Phantasy[CR]Star II: Annes Adventure". It sports a variable-width font engine[CR]with[CR]kerning and, as usual, it is a "dual-language" patch, meaning that[CR]it[CR]supports both Japanese and English, depending on the country code of[CR]your[CR]machine.[CR] Applying the[CR]Patch[CR]-----------------------------------------------------------------------------[CR]Hopefully[CR]included with this document is a patch file in the IPS format.[CR]You can use[CR]any program that supports that file format to apply this[CR]translation patch[CR]to your ROM file.[CR]Alternatively, you can use the program from my website to[CR]apply the patch,[CR]but make sure that you have the latest version or it wont[CR]work. The program[CR]will check the ROM file (de-interleaving it if necessary)[CR]and will give[CR]you an error message if something went wrong. A normal IPS[CR]program cannot[CR]do this as it has no idea what it is patching. The program[CR]has not been[CR]extensively tested, so if you have problems (or simply dont[CR]trust a foreign[CR]executable) you always have the option of using a different[CR]program.[CR] Playing the[CR]Game[CR]-----------------------------------------------------------------------------[CR]Once[CR]youve patched the ROM file, simply load it up in your favorite[CR]Genesis /[CR]Mega Drive emulator, console copier, or flash cartridge.[CR]The game will[CR]detect the country code of your machine (real or emulated) and[CR]then switch[CR]to English or Japanese mode accordingly.[CR] Q and[CR]A[CR]-----------------------------------------------------------------------------[CR]Q:[CR]This patch doesnt work! What do I do?[CR]A: Make sure that your ROM file is[CR]not in an interleaved format. Its also[CR] possible that there is more than[CR]one version of the game, or that your[CR] copy is corrupt. If you have[CR]problems, try using the program that I wrote[CR] to apply the patch; it checks[CR]for the above issues. It is available on my[CR] website.[CR] Some emulators[CR]may also fail to run the program. Please make sure you try[CR] several of the[CR]most up-to-date emulators available.[CR]Q: It doesnt work with my copier /[CR]flash cartridge! Why not?[CR] This was tested on a real Genesis so you[CR]shouldnt have any problems in[CR] that respect. The most likely reason is that[CR]something went wrong during[CR] the patching process. See the previous[CR]question and try it in an emulator[CR] to see if that works.[CR] Another[CR]possibility is that you are using a PAL Mega Drive. This game was[CR] designed[CR]for NTSC systems and I didnt make any changes in that respect.[CR] It should[CR]still run (probably at the wrong speed), but you never know...[CR]Q: Is your[CR]patcher program safe?[CR]A: No. Anyone could replace it with a trojan and[CR]rewrite this readme to[CR] make it seem safe. Thats one reason why I dont[CR]include it with the[CR] patch itself. Its up to you to decide which program to[CR]use to apply[CR] the patch, but unless you wrote the program yourself theres[CR]always[CR] some risk involved.[CR]Q: Why is the text in Japanese?!?[CR]A: This[CR]is a dual-language translation patch. If it detects that it is[CR] running on[CR]a Japanese system, it will use the original game script.[CR] If you are using[CR]an emulator, make sure the country code is set to USA.[CR]Translation/Transliteration[CR]Notes[CR]-----------------------------------------------------------------------------[CR]The[CR]surnames are simply omitted, since there is no way to tell for sure how[CR]to[CR]properly transliterate/translate them. Unless someone can produce[CR]an[CR]official source, written in romaji, it is safer to just leave them[CR]out.[CR]The katakana renditions are available at various places online, for[CR]the[CR]curious, but dont trust their transliterations. For example, "Kinds"[CR]is[CR]commonly misspelled as "Kainz", even though the latter is the most[CR]logical[CR]transliteration. So you can see why its impossible to tell for[CR]sure.[CR] Hacking[CR]Notes[CR]-----------------------------------------------------------------------------[CR]Nothing[CR]interesting (fortunately). The usual techniques were employed and old[CR]code[CR]was modified and reused. The variable-width font engine was upgraded[CR]to[CR]handle groups and triplets (possibly a new invention in kerning[CR]technology).[CR]Other than that, theres not much to say here, except a very[CR]special thanks[CR]to a very special guest.[CR]Contact[CR]-----------------------------------------------------------------------------[CR]mijeto@gmail.com[CR]I[CR]cannot guarantee a timely reply; this address is sometimes not checked[CR]for[CR]months at a time, depending on[CR]availability.[CR]http://mijet.eludevisibility.org/</plot>
    <studio>M.I.J.E.T.</studio>
    <snapshot1>tNnbKK0.png</snapshot1>
    <snapshot2>vCLSuUP.png</snapshot2>
  </game>
  <game name="Phantasy Star II - Eusis's Adventure (Japan) (SegaNet) [T-En by MIJET v20100710] [n]">
    <description>Phantasy Star II - Eusis's Adventure (Japan) (SegaNet) [T-En by MIJET v20100710] [n]</description>
    <title_clean>Phantasy Star II - Eusis's Adventure</title_clean>
    <rom name="MaybeIntroTEn20121007/Maybe-Intro%20%5BT-En%5D%20%2820121007%29.zip/Sega%20Mega%20Drive%20%5BT-En%5D%2FPhantasy%20Star%20II%20-%20Eusis%27s%20Adventure%20%28Japan%29%20%28SegaNet%29%20%5BT-En%20by%20MIJET%20v20100710%5D%20%5Bn%5D.zip" size="132353"/>
    <plot>Phantasy Star II: Yushis's Adventure is an adventure game for the Sega[CR]Genesis.[CR]Read Me:[CR]Patch version 100710 (yymmdd)[CR]Readme[CR]version 100710 (yymmdd)[CR] Phantasy Star II: Eusiss Adventure[CR] English[CR]Translation Patch[CR] by M.I.J.E.T.[CR]History[CR]-----------------------------------------------------------------------------[CR]100710[CR]Initial release[CR]Overview[CR]-----------------------------------------------------------------------------[CR]This[CR]is a translation patch for the Mega Drive Sega Net game entitled[CR]"Phantasy[CR]Star II: Eusiss Adventure" (also spelled Yushis and Yousis).[CR]It sports a[CR]variable-width font engine with kerning and, as usual, it is a[CR]"dual-[CR]language" patch, meaning that it supports both Japanese and[CR]English,[CR]depending on the country code of your machine.[CR] Applying the[CR]Patch[CR]-----------------------------------------------------------------------------[CR]Hopefully[CR]included with this document is a patch file in the IPS format.[CR]You can use[CR]any program that supports that file format to apply this[CR]translation patch[CR]to your ROM file.[CR]Alternatively, you can use the program from my website to[CR]apply the patch,[CR]but make sure that you have the latest version or it wont[CR]work. The program[CR]will check the ROM file (de-interleaving it if necessary)[CR]and will give[CR]you an error message if something went wrong. A normal IPS[CR]program cannot[CR]do this as it has no idea what it is patching. The program[CR]has not been[CR]extensively tested, so if you have problems (or simply dont[CR]trust a foreign[CR]executable) you always have the option of using a different[CR]program.[CR] Playing the[CR]Game[CR]-----------------------------------------------------------------------------[CR]Once[CR]youve patched the ROM file, simply load it up in your favorite[CR]Genesis /[CR]Mega Drive emulator, console copier, or flash cartridge.[CR]The game will[CR]detect the country code of your machine (real or emulated) and[CR]then switch[CR]to English or Japanese mode accordingly.[CR] Q and[CR]A[CR]-----------------------------------------------------------------------------[CR]Q:[CR]This patch doesnt work! What do I do?[CR]A: Make sure that your ROM file is[CR]not in an interleaved format. Its also[CR] possible that there is more than[CR]one version of the game, or that your[CR] copy is corrupt. If you have[CR]problems, try using the program that I wrote[CR] to apply the patch; it checks[CR]for the above issues. It is available on my[CR] website.[CR] Some emulators[CR]may also fail to run the program. Please make sure you try[CR] several of the[CR]most up-to-date emulators available.[CR]Q: It doesnt work with my copier /[CR]flash cartridge! Why not?[CR] This was tested on a real Genesis so you[CR]shouldnt have any problems in[CR] that respect. The most likely reason is that[CR]something went wrong during[CR] the patching process. See the previous[CR]question and try it in an emulator[CR] to see if that works.[CR] Another[CR]possibility is that you are using a PAL Mega Drive. This game was[CR] designed[CR]for NTSC systems and I didnt make any changes in that respect.[CR] It should[CR]still run (probably at the wrong speed), but you never know...[CR]Q: Is your[CR]patcher program safe?[CR]A: No. Anyone could replace it with a trojan and[CR]rewrite this readme to[CR] make it seem safe. Thats one reason why I dont[CR]include it with the[CR] patch itself. Its up to you to decide which program to[CR]use to apply[CR] the patch, but unless you wrote the program yourself theres[CR]always[CR] some risk involved.[CR]Q: Why is the text in Japanese?!?[CR]A: This[CR]is a dual-language translation patch. If it detects that it is[CR] running on[CR]a Japanese system, it will use the original game script.[CR] If you are using[CR]an emulator, make sure the country code is set to USA.[CR]Q: Why do you call[CR]the game "Eusiss Adventure" instead of "Yushis/Yousis"?[CR]A: That is the[CR]spelling used by the Mega CD version of the game, which was[CR] produced[CR]later, has fewer bugs, and is generally more reliable. The older[CR] Sega Net[CR]version isnt even internally consistent with its spellings.[CR] In case you[CR]were wondering, graphics from the CD version were patched in[CR] to make the[CR]title screen and logo read "Eusis".[CR] Translation/Transliteration[CR]Notes[CR]-----------------------------------------------------------------------------[CR]The[CR]surnames are simply omitted, since there is no way to tell for sure how[CR]to[CR]properly transliterate/translate them. Unless someone can produce[CR]an[CR]official source, written in romaji, it is safer to just leave them[CR]out.[CR]The katakana renditions are available at various places online, for[CR]the[CR]curious, but dont trust their transliterations. For example, "Kinds"[CR]is[CR]commonly misspelled as "Kainz", even though the latter is the most[CR]logical[CR]transliteration. So you can see why its impossible to tell for[CR]sure.[CR] Hacking[CR]Notes[CR]-----------------------------------------------------------------------------[CR]Nothing[CR]interesting (fortunately). The usual techniques were employed and old[CR]code[CR]was modified and reused. The variable-width font engine was upgraded[CR]to[CR]handle groups and triplets (possibly a new invention in kerning[CR]technology).[CR]Contact[CR]-----------------------------------------------------------------------------[CR]mijeto@gmail.com[CR]I[CR]cannot guarantee a timely reply; this address is sometimes not checked[CR]for[CR]months at a time.[CR]http://mijet.eludevisibility.org/</plot>
    <studio>M.I.J.E.T.</studio>
    <snapshot1>A2mROOu.png</snapshot1>
    <snapshot2>AMtmf8L.png</snapshot2>
  </game>
  <game name="Phantasy Star II - Huey's Adventure (Japan) (SegaNet) [T-En by MIJET v20100710]">
    <description>Phantasy Star II - Huey's Adventure (Japan) (SegaNet) [T-En by MIJET v20100710]</description>
    <title_clean>Phantasy Star II - Huey's Adventure</title_clean>
    <rom name="MaybeIntroTEn20121007/Maybe-Intro%20%5BT-En%5D%20%2820121007%29.zip/Sega%20Mega%20Drive%20%5BT-En%5D%2FPhantasy%20Star%20II%20-%20Huey%27s%20Adventure%20%28Japan%29%20%28SegaNet%29%20%5BT-En%20by%20MIJET%20v20100710%5D.zip" size="135428"/>
    <plot>Phantasy Star II: Huey's Adventure is an adventure game for the Sega[CR]Genesis.[CR]Read Me:[CR]Patch version 081106 (yymmdd)[CR]Readme[CR]version 081106 (yymmdd)[CR] Phantasy Star II: Hueys Adventure[CR] English[CR]Translation Patch[CR] by M.I.J.E.T.[CR]History[CR]-----------------------------------------------------------------------------[CR]081106[CR]Initial release[CR]Overview[CR]-----------------------------------------------------------------------------[CR]This[CR]is a translation patch for the Mega Drive Sega Net game entitled[CR]"Phantasy[CR]Star II: Hueys Adventure". It sports a variable-width font engine[CR]with[CR]kerning and, as usual, it is a "dual-language" patch, meaning that[CR]it[CR]supports both Japanese and English, depending on the country code of[CR]your[CR]machine.[CR] Applying the[CR]Patch[CR]-----------------------------------------------------------------------------[CR]Hopefully[CR]included with this document is a patch file in the IPS format.[CR]You can use[CR]any program that supports that file format to apply this[CR]translation patch[CR]to your ROM file.[CR]Alternatively, you can use the program from my website to[CR]apply the patch,[CR]but make sure that you have the latest version or it wont[CR]work. The program[CR]will check the ROM file (de-interleaving it if necessary)[CR]and will give[CR]you an error message if something went wrong. A normal IPS[CR]program cannot[CR]do this as it has no idea what it is patching. The program[CR]has not been[CR]extensively tested, so if you have problems (or simply dont[CR]trust a foreign[CR]executable) you always have the option of using a different[CR]program.[CR] Playing the[CR]Game[CR]-----------------------------------------------------------------------------[CR]Once[CR]youve patched the ROM file, simply load it up in your favorite[CR]Genesis /[CR]Mega Drive emulator, console copier, or flash cartridge.[CR]The game will[CR]detect the country code of your machine (real or emulated) and[CR]then switch[CR]to English or Japanese mode accordingly.[CR] Q and[CR]A[CR]-----------------------------------------------------------------------------[CR]Q:[CR]This patch doesnt work! What do I do?[CR]A: Make sure that your ROM file is[CR]not in an interleaved format. Its also[CR] possible that there is more than[CR]one version of the game, or that your[CR] copy is corrupt. If you have[CR]problems, try using the program that I wrote[CR] to apply the patch; it checks[CR]for the above issues. It is available on my[CR] website.[CR] Some emulators[CR]may also fail to run the program. Please make sure you try[CR] several of the[CR]most up-to-date emulators available.[CR]Q: It doesnt work with my copier /[CR]flash cartridge! Why not?[CR] This was tested on a real Genesis so you[CR]shouldnt have any problems in[CR] that respect. The most likely reason is that[CR]something went wrong during[CR] the patching process. See the previous[CR]question and try it in an emulator[CR] to see if that works.[CR] Another[CR]possibility is that you are using a PAL Mega Drive. This game was[CR] designed[CR]for NTSC systems and I didnt make any changes in that respect.[CR] It should[CR]still run (probably at the wrong speed), but you never know...[CR]Q: Is your[CR]patcher program safe?[CR]A: No. Anyone could replace it with a trojan and[CR]rewrite this readme to[CR] make it seem safe. Thats one reason why I dont[CR]include it with the[CR] patch itself. Its up to you to decide which program to[CR]use to apply[CR] the patch, but unless you wrote the program yourself theres[CR]always[CR] some risk involved.[CR]Q: Why is the text in Japanese?!?[CR]A: This[CR]is a dual-language translation patch. If it detects that it is[CR] running on[CR]a Japanese system, it will use the original game script.[CR] If you are using[CR]an emulator, make sure the country code is set to USA.[CR]Q: Why is this game[CR]buggy?[CR]A: Its a pre-release version of the game. The Game Can version[CR]fixes[CR] some, but not all, of the problems.[CR] Some advice for avoiding[CR]defects in the game:[CR] - Never talk to Rita with a full inventory.[CR] - Try[CR]not to get killed.[CR] - Dont reexamine things unnecessarily. (this one is not[CR]harmful)[CR] There are other bugs as well.[CR] Translation/Transliteration[CR]Notes[CR]-----------------------------------------------------------------------------[CR]The[CR]surnames are simply omitted, since there is no way to tell for sure how[CR]to[CR]properly transliterate/translate them. Unless someone can produce[CR]an[CR]official source, written in romaji, it is safer to just leave them[CR]out.[CR]The katakana renditions are available at various places online, for[CR]the[CR]curious, but dont trust their transliterations. For example, "Kinds"[CR]is[CR]commonly misspelled as "Kainz", even though the latter is the most[CR]logical[CR]transliteration. So you can see why its impossible to tell for[CR]sure.[CR] Hacking[CR]Notes[CR]-----------------------------------------------------------------------------[CR]Nothing[CR]interesting (fortunately). The usual techniques were employed and old[CR]code[CR]was modified and reused. The variable-width font engine was upgraded[CR]to[CR]handle groups and triplets (possibly a new invention in kerning[CR]technology).[CR]Other than that, theres not much to say here, except a very[CR]special thanks[CR]to a very special guest. ;)[CR]Contact[CR]-----------------------------------------------------------------------------[CR]mijeto@gmail.com[CR](preferred) or tougi_ou@yahoo.com[CR]I cannot guarantee a timely reply; this[CR]address is sometimes not checked for[CR]weeks or months at a time, depending[CR]on recent activity levels and Internet[CR]availability.[CR]And on the[CR]web:[CR]http://mijet.eludevisibility.org/[CR]http://www.geocities.com/tougi_ou/[CR](backup site)</plot>
    <studio>M.I.J.E.T.</studio>
    <snapshot1>yCA6wLs.png</snapshot1>
    <snapshot2>8oFk7wh.png</snapshot2>
  </game>
  <game name="Phantasy Star II - Kinds's Adventure (Japan) (SegaNet) [T-En by MIJET v20100710]">
    <description>Phantasy Star II - Kinds's Adventure (Japan) (SegaNet) [T-En by MIJET v20100710]</description>
    <title_clean>Phantasy Star II - Kinds's Adventure</title_clean>
    <rom name="MaybeIntroTEn20121007/Maybe-Intro%20%5BT-En%5D%20%2820121007%29.zip/Sega%20Mega%20Drive%20%5BT-En%5D%2FPhantasy%20Star%20II%20-%20Kinds%27s%20Adventure%20%28Japan%29%20%28SegaNet%29%20%5BT-En%20by%20MIJET%20v20100710%5D.zip" size="135624"/>
    <plot>Phantasy Star II: Kinds's Adventure is an adventure game for the Sega[CR]Genesis.[CR]Read Me:[CR]Patch version 081213 (yymmdd)[CR]Readme[CR]version 081213 (yymmdd)[CR] Phantasy Star II: Kindss Adventure[CR] English[CR]Translation Patch[CR] by M.I.J.E.T.[CR]History[CR]-----------------------------------------------------------------------------[CR]070607[CR]Initial release[CR]070805 A few script corrections, thanks to Bernd[CR]081213[CR]Script rewritten, corrections based on CD version, code updated[CR]Overview[CR]-----------------------------------------------------------------------------[CR]This[CR]is a translation patch for the Mega Drive Sega Net game entitled[CR]"Phantasy[CR]Star II: Kindss Adventure". It sports a variable-width font engine[CR]with[CR]kerning support and, as usual, it is a "dual-language" patch, meaning[CR]that[CR]it supports both Japanese and English, depending on the country code[CR]of[CR]your machine.[CR] Applying the[CR]Patch[CR]-----------------------------------------------------------------------------[CR]Hopefully[CR]included with this document is a patch file in the IPS format.[CR]You can use[CR]any program that supports that file format to apply this[CR]translation patch[CR]to your ROM file.[CR]Alternatively, you can use the program from my website to[CR]apply the patch,[CR]but make sure that you have the latest version or it wont[CR]work. The program[CR]will check the ROM file (de-interleaving it if necessary)[CR]and will give[CR]you an error message if something went wrong. A normal IPS[CR]program cannot[CR]do this as it has no idea what it is patching. The program[CR]has not been[CR]extensively tested, so if you have problems (or simply dont[CR]trust a foreign[CR]executable) you always have the option of using a different[CR]program.[CR] Playing the[CR]Game[CR]-----------------------------------------------------------------------------[CR]Once[CR]youve patched the ROM file, simply load it up in your favorite[CR]Genesis /[CR]Mega Drive emulator, console copier, or flash cartridge.[CR]The game will[CR]detect the country code of your machine (real or emulated) and[CR]then switch[CR]to English or Japanese mode accordingly.[CR] Q and[CR]A[CR]-----------------------------------------------------------------------------[CR]Q:[CR]This patch doesnt work! What do I do?[CR]A: Make sure that your ROM file is[CR]not in an interleaved format. Its also[CR] possible that there is more than[CR]one version of the game, or that your[CR] copy is corrupt. If you have[CR]problems, try using the program that I wrote[CR] to apply the patch; it checks[CR]for the above issues. It is available on my[CR] website.[CR] Some emulators[CR]may also fail to run the program. Please make sure you try[CR] several of the[CR]most up-to-date emulators available.[CR]Q: It doesnt work with my copier /[CR]flash cartridge! Why not?[CR] This was tested on a real Genesis so you[CR]shouldnt have any problems in[CR] that respect. The most likely reason is that[CR]something went wrong during[CR] the patching process. See the previous[CR]question and try it in an emulator[CR] to see if that works.[CR] Another[CR]possibility is that you are using a PAL Mega Drive. This game was[CR] designed[CR]for NTSC systems and I didnt make any changes in that respect.[CR] It should[CR]still run (probably at the wrong speed), but you never know...[CR]Q: Is your[CR]patcher program safe?[CR]A: No. Anyone could replace it with a trojan and[CR]rewrite this readme to[CR] make it seem safe. Thats one reason why I dont[CR]include it with the[CR] patch itself. Its up to you to decide which program to[CR]use to apply[CR] the patch, but unless you wrote the program yourself theres[CR]always[CR] some risk involved.[CR]Q: Why is the text in Japanese?!?[CR]A: This[CR]is a dual-language translation patch. If it detects that it is[CR] running on[CR]a Japanese system, it will use the original game script.[CR] If you are using[CR]an emulator, make sure the country code is set to USA.[CR]Translation/Transliteration[CR]Notes[CR]-----------------------------------------------------------------------------[CR]The[CR]surnames are simply omitted, since there is no way to tell for sure how[CR]to[CR]properly transliterate/translate them. Unless someone can produce[CR]an[CR]official source, written in romaji, it is safer to just leave them[CR]out.[CR]The katakana renditions are available at various places online, for[CR]the[CR]curious, but dont trust their transliterations. For example, "Kinds"[CR]is[CR]commonly misspelled as "Kainz", even though thats the most[CR]logical[CR]transliteration. So you can see why its impossible to tell for[CR]sure.[CR] Hacking[CR]Notes[CR]-----------------------------------------------------------------------------[CR]Nothing[CR]interesting (fortunately). The usual techniques were employed and old[CR]code[CR]was modified and reused. The variable-width font engine was upgraded[CR]to[CR]handle groups and triplets (possibly a new invention in kerning[CR]technology).[CR]Other than that, theres not much to say here, except a very[CR]special thanks[CR]to a very special guest. ;)[CR]Contact[CR]-----------------------------------------------------------------------------[CR]mijeto@gmail.com[CR](preferred) or tougi_ou@yahoo.com[CR]I cannot guarantee a timely reply; this[CR]address is sometimes not checked for[CR]weeks or months at a time, depending[CR]on recent activity levels and Internet[CR]availability.[CR]And on the[CR]web:[CR]http://mijet.eludevisibility.org/[CR]http://www.geocities.com/tougi_ou/[CR](backup site)</plot>
    <studio>M.I.J.E.T.</studio>
    <snapshot1>NolyTP6.png</snapshot1>
    <snapshot2>5g1lp9T.png</snapshot2>
  </game>
  <game name="Phantasy Star II - Nei's Adventure (Japan) (SegaNet) [T-En by MIJET v20100710]">
    <description>Phantasy Star II - Nei's Adventure (Japan) (SegaNet) [T-En by MIJET v20100710]</description>
    <title_clean>Phantasy Star II - Nei's Adventure</title_clean>
    <rom name="MaybeIntroTEn20121007/Maybe-Intro%20%5BT-En%5D%20%2820121007%29.zip/Sega%20Mega%20Drive%20%5BT-En%5D%2FPhantasy%20Star%20II%20-%20Nei%27s%20Adventure%20%28Japan%29%20%28SegaNet%29%20%5BT-En%20by%20MIJET%20v20100710%5D.zip" size="146885"/>
    <plot>Phantasy Star II: Nei's Adventure is an adventure game for the Sega[CR]Genesis.[CR]Read Me:[CR]Patch version 100710 (yymmdd)[CR]Readme[CR]version 100710 (yymmdd)[CR] Phantasy Star II: Neis Adventure[CR] English[CR]Translation Patch[CR] by M.I.J.E.T.[CR]History[CR]-----------------------------------------------------------------------------[CR]100710[CR]Initial release[CR]Overview[CR]-----------------------------------------------------------------------------[CR]This[CR]is a translation patch for the Mega Drive Sega Net game entitled[CR]"Phantasy[CR]Star II: Neis Adventure". It sports a variable-width font engine[CR]with[CR]kerning and, as usual, it is a "dual-language" patch, meaning that[CR]it[CR]supports both Japanese and English, depending on the country code of[CR]your[CR]machine.[CR] Applying the[CR]Patch[CR]-----------------------------------------------------------------------------[CR]Hopefully[CR]included with this document is a patch file in the IPS format.[CR]You can use[CR]any program that supports that file format to apply this[CR]translation patch[CR]to your ROM file.[CR]Alternatively, you can use the program from my website to[CR]apply the patch,[CR]but make sure that you have the latest version or it wont[CR]work. The program[CR]will check the ROM file (de-interleaving it if necessary)[CR]and will give[CR]you an error message if something went wrong. A normal IPS[CR]program cannot[CR]do this as it has no idea what it is patching. The program[CR]has not been[CR]extensively tested, so if you have problems (or simply dont[CR]trust a foreign[CR]executable) you always have the option of using a different[CR]program.[CR] Playing the[CR]Game[CR]-----------------------------------------------------------------------------[CR]Once[CR]youve patched the ROM file, simply load it up in your favorite[CR]Genesis /[CR]Mega Drive emulator, console copier, or flash cartridge.[CR]The game will[CR]detect the country code of your machine (real or emulated) and[CR]then switch[CR]to English or Japanese mode accordingly.[CR] Q and[CR]A[CR]-----------------------------------------------------------------------------[CR]Q:[CR]This patch doesnt work! What do I do?[CR]A: Make sure that your ROM file is[CR]not in an interleaved format. Its also[CR] possible that there is more than[CR]one version of the game, or that your[CR] copy is corrupt. If you have[CR]problems, try using the program that I wrote[CR] to apply the patch; it checks[CR]for the above issues. It is available on my[CR] website.[CR] Some emulators[CR]may also fail to run the program. Please make sure you try[CR] several of the[CR]most up-to-date emulators available.[CR]Q: It doesnt work with my copier /[CR]flash cartridge! Why not?[CR] This was tested on a real Genesis so you[CR]shouldnt have any problems in[CR] that respect. The most likely reason is that[CR]something went wrong during[CR] the patching process. See the previous[CR]question and try it in an emulator[CR] to see if that works.[CR] Another[CR]possibility is that you are using a PAL Mega Drive. This game was[CR] designed[CR]for NTSC systems and I didnt make any changes in that respect.[CR] It should[CR]still run (probably at the wrong speed), but you never know...[CR]Q: Is your[CR]patcher program safe?[CR]A: No. Anyone could replace it with a trojan and[CR]rewrite this readme to[CR] make it seem safe. Thats one reason why I dont[CR]include it with the[CR] patch itself. Its up to you to decide which program to[CR]use to apply[CR] the patch, but unless you wrote the program yourself theres[CR]always[CR] some risk involved.[CR]Q: Why is the text in Japanese?!?[CR]A: This[CR]is a dual-language translation patch. If it detects that it is[CR] running on[CR]a Japanese system, it will use the original game script.[CR] If you are using[CR]an emulator, make sure the country code is set to USA.[CR]Translation/Transliteration[CR]Notes[CR]-----------------------------------------------------------------------------[CR]The[CR]surnames are simply omitted, since there is no way to tell for sure how[CR]to[CR]properly transliterate/translate them. Unless someone can produce[CR]an[CR]official source, written in romaji, it is safer to just leave them[CR]out.[CR]The katakana renditions are available at various places online, for[CR]the[CR]curious, but dont trust their transliterations. For example, "Kinds"[CR]is[CR]commonly misspelled as "Kainz", even though the latter is the most[CR]logical[CR]transliteration. So you can see why its impossible to tell for[CR]sure.[CR] Hacking[CR]Notes[CR]-----------------------------------------------------------------------------[CR]Nothing[CR]interesting (fortunately). The usual techniques were employed and old[CR]code[CR]was modified and reused. The variable-width font engine was upgraded[CR]to[CR]handle groups and triplets (possibly a new invention in kerning[CR]technology).[CR]Contact[CR]-----------------------------------------------------------------------------[CR]mijeto@gmail.com[CR]I[CR]cannot guarantee a timely reply; this address is sometimes not checked[CR]for[CR]months at a time.[CR]http://mijet.eludevisibility.org/</plot>
    <studio>M.I.J.E.T.</studio>
    <snapshot1>G6q2fH2.png</snapshot1>
    <snapshot2>tBsNBdJ.png</snapshot2>
  </game>
  <game name="Phantasy Star II - Rudger's Adventure (Japan) (SegaNet) [T-En by MIJET v20100710]">
    <description>Phantasy Star II - Rudger's Adventure (Japan) (SegaNet) [T-En by MIJET v20100710]</description>
    <title_clean>Phantasy Star II - Rudger's Adventure</title_clean>
    <rom name="MaybeIntroTEn20121007/Maybe-Intro%20%5BT-En%5D%20%2820121007%29.zip/Sega%20Mega%20Drive%20%5BT-En%5D%2FPhantasy%20Star%20II%20-%20Rudger%27s%20Adventure%20%28Japan%29%20%28SegaNet%29%20%5BT-En%20by%20MIJET%20v20100710%5D.zip" size="133246"/>
    <plot>Phantasy Star II: Rudger's Adventure is an adventure game for the Sega[CR]Genesis.[CR]Read Me:[CR]Patch version 100710 (yymmdd)[CR]Readme[CR]version 100710 (yymmdd)[CR] Phantasy Star II: Rudgers Adventure[CR] English[CR]Translation Patch[CR] by M.I.J.E.T.[CR]History[CR]-----------------------------------------------------------------------------[CR]100710[CR]Initial release[CR]Overview[CR]-----------------------------------------------------------------------------[CR]This[CR]is a translation patch for the Mega Drive Sega Net game entitled[CR]"Phantasy[CR]Star II: Rudgers Adventure". It sports a variable-width font[CR]engine with[CR]kerning and, as usual, it is a "dual-language" patch, meaning[CR]that it[CR]supports both Japanese and English, depending on the country code[CR]of your[CR]machine.[CR] Applying the[CR]Patch[CR]-----------------------------------------------------------------------------[CR]Hopefully[CR]included with this document is a patch file in the IPS format.[CR]You can use[CR]any program that supports that file format to apply this[CR]translation patch[CR]to your ROM file.[CR]Alternatively, you can use the program from my website to[CR]apply the patch,[CR]but make sure that you have the latest version or it wont[CR]work. The program[CR]will check the ROM file (de-interleaving it if necessary)[CR]and will give[CR]you an error message if something went wrong. A normal IPS[CR]program cannot[CR]do this as it has no idea what it is patching. The program[CR]has not been[CR]extensively tested, so if you have problems (or simply dont[CR]trust a foreign[CR]executable) you always have the option of using a different[CR]program.[CR] Playing the[CR]Game[CR]-----------------------------------------------------------------------------[CR]Once[CR]youve patched the ROM file, simply load it up in your favorite[CR]Genesis /[CR]Mega Drive emulator, console copier, or flash cartridge.[CR]The game will[CR]detect the country code of your machine (real or emulated) and[CR]then switch[CR]to English or Japanese mode accordingly.[CR] Q and[CR]A[CR]-----------------------------------------------------------------------------[CR]Q:[CR]This patch doesnt work! What do I do?[CR]A: Make sure that your ROM file is[CR]not in an interleaved format. Its also[CR] possible that there is more than[CR]one version of the game, or that your[CR] copy is corrupt. If you have[CR]problems, try using the program that I wrote[CR] to apply the patch; it checks[CR]for the above issues. It is available on my[CR] website.[CR] Some emulators[CR]may also fail to run the program. Please make sure you try[CR] several of the[CR]most up-to-date emulators available.[CR]Q: It doesnt work with my copier /[CR]flash cartridge! Why not?[CR] This was tested on a real Genesis so you[CR]shouldnt have any problems in[CR] that respect. The most likely reason is that[CR]something went wrong during[CR] the patching process. See the previous[CR]question and try it in an emulator[CR] to see if that works.[CR] Another[CR]possibility is that you are using a PAL Mega Drive. This game was[CR] designed[CR]for NTSC systems and I didnt make any changes in that respect.[CR] It should[CR]still run (probably at the wrong speed), but you never know...[CR]Q: Is your[CR]patcher program safe?[CR]A: No. Anyone could replace it with a trojan and[CR]rewrite this readme to[CR] make it seem safe. Thats one reason why I dont[CR]include it with the[CR] patch itself. Its up to you to decide which program to[CR]use to apply[CR] the patch, but unless you wrote the program yourself theres[CR]always[CR] some risk involved.[CR]Q: Why is the text in Japanese?!?[CR]A: This[CR]is a dual-language translation patch. If it detects that it is[CR] running on[CR]a Japanese system, it will use the original game script.[CR] If you are using[CR]an emulator, make sure the country code is set to USA.[CR]Translation/Transliteration[CR]Notes[CR]-----------------------------------------------------------------------------[CR]The[CR]surnames are simply omitted, since there is no way to tell for sure how[CR]to[CR]properly transliterate/translate them. Unless someone can produce[CR]an[CR]official source, written in romaji, it is safer to just leave them[CR]out.[CR]The katakana renditions are available at various places online, for[CR]the[CR]curious, but dont trust their transliterations. For example, "Kinds"[CR]is[CR]commonly misspelled as "Kainz", even though the latter is the most[CR]logical[CR]transliteration. So you can see why its impossible to tell for[CR]sure.[CR] Hacking[CR]Notes[CR]-----------------------------------------------------------------------------[CR]Nothing[CR]interesting (fortunately). The usual techniques were employed and old[CR]code[CR]was modified and reused. The variable-width font engine was upgraded[CR]to[CR]handle groups and triplets (possibly a new invention in kerning[CR]technology).[CR]Contact[CR]-----------------------------------------------------------------------------[CR]mijeto@gmail.com[CR]I[CR]cannot guarantee a timely reply; this address is sometimes not checked[CR]for[CR]months at a time.[CR]http://mijet.eludevisibility.org/</plot>
    <studio>M.I.J.E.T.</studio>
    <snapshot1>7wZVSRO.png</snapshot1>
    <snapshot2>0ZMdna9.png</snapshot2>
  </game>
  <game name="Phantasy Star II - Shilka's Adventure (Japan) (SegaNet) [T-En by MIJET v20100710]">
    <description>Phantasy Star II - Shilka's Adventure (Japan) (SegaNet) [T-En by MIJET v20100710]</description>
    <title_clean>Phantasy Star II - Shilka's Adventure</title_clean>
    <rom name="MaybeIntroTEn20121007/Maybe-Intro%20%5BT-En%5D%20%2820121007%29.zip/Sega%20Mega%20Drive%20%5BT-En%5D%2FPhantasy%20Star%20II%20-%20Shilka%27s%20Adventure%20%28Japan%29%20%28SegaNet%29%20%5BT-En%20by%20MIJET%20v20100710%5D.zip" size="129440"/>
    <plot>Phantasy Star II: Shilka's Adventure is an adventure game for the Sega[CR]Genesis.[CR]Read Me:[CR]Patch version 070808 (yymmdd)[CR]Readme[CR]version 070808 (yymmdd)[CR] Phantasy Star II: Shilkas Adventure[CR] English[CR]Translation Patch[CR] by M.I.J.E.T.[CR]History[CR]-----------------------------------------------------------------------------[CR]070712[CR]Initial release[CR]070808 A script correction, thanks to Bernd[CR]Overview[CR]-----------------------------------------------------------------------------[CR]This[CR]is a translation patch for the Mega Drive Sega Net game entitled[CR]"Phantasy[CR]Star II: Shilkas Adventure". It sports a variable-width font engine[CR]with[CR]kerning and, as usual, it is a "dual-language" patch, meaning that[CR]it[CR]supports both Japanese and English, depending on the country code of[CR]your[CR]machine.[CR] Applying the[CR]Patch[CR]-----------------------------------------------------------------------------[CR]Hopefully[CR]included with this document is a patch file in the IPS format.[CR]You can use[CR]any program that supports that file format to apply this[CR]translation patch[CR]to your ROM file.[CR]Alternatively, you can use the program from my website to[CR]apply the patch,[CR]but make sure that you have the latest version or it wont[CR]work. The program[CR]will check the ROM file (de-interleaving it if necessary)[CR]and will give[CR]you an error message if something went wrong. A normal IPS[CR]program cannot[CR]do this as it has no idea what it is patching. The program[CR]has not been[CR]extensively tested, so if you have problems (or simply dont[CR]trust a foreign[CR]executable) you always have the option of using a different[CR]program.[CR] Playing the[CR]Game[CR]-----------------------------------------------------------------------------[CR]Once[CR]youve patched the ROM file, simply load it up in your favorite[CR]Genesis /[CR]Mega Drive emulator, console copier, or flash cartridge.[CR]The game will[CR]detect the country code of your machine (real or emulated) and[CR]then switch[CR]to English or Japanese mode accordingly.[CR] Q and[CR]A[CR]-----------------------------------------------------------------------------[CR]Q:[CR]This patch doesnt work! What do I do?[CR]A: Make sure that your ROM file is[CR]not in an interleaved format. Its also[CR] possible that there is more than[CR]one version of the game, or that your[CR] copy is corrupt. If you have[CR]problems, try using the program that I wrote[CR] to apply the patch; it checks[CR]for the above issues. It is available on my[CR] website.[CR] Some emulators[CR]may also fail to run the program. Please make sure you try[CR] several of the[CR]most up-to-date emulators available.[CR]Q: It doesnt work with my copier /[CR]flash cartridge! Why not?[CR] This was tested on a real Genesis so you[CR]shouldnt have any problems in[CR] that respect. The most likely reason is that[CR]something went wrong during[CR] the patching process. See the previous[CR]question and try it in an emulator[CR] to see if that works.[CR] Another[CR]possibility is that you are using a PAL Mega Drive. This game was[CR] designed[CR]for NTSC systems and I didnt make any changes in that respect.[CR] It should[CR]still run (probably at the wrong speed), but you never know...[CR]Q: Is your[CR]patcher program safe?[CR]A: No. Anyone could replace it with a trojan and[CR]rewrite this readme to[CR] make it seem safe. Thats one reason why I dont[CR]include it with the[CR] patch itself. Its up to you to decide which program to[CR]use to apply[CR] the patch, but unless you wrote the program yourself theres[CR]always[CR] some risk involved.[CR]Q: Why is the text in Japanese?!?[CR]A: This[CR]is a dual-language translation patch. If it detects that it is[CR] running on[CR]a Japanese system, it will use the original game script.[CR] If you are using[CR]an emulator, make sure the country code is set to USA.[CR]Q: Who is JDR?[CR]A:[CR]Some vandal.[CR] Translation/Transliteration[CR]Notes[CR]-----------------------------------------------------------------------------[CR]The[CR]surnames are simply omitted, since there is no way to tell for sure how[CR]to[CR]properly transliterate/translate them. Unless someone can produce[CR]an[CR]official source, written in romaji, it is safer to just leave them[CR]out.[CR]The katakana renditions are available at various places online, for[CR]the[CR]curious, but dont trust their transliterations. For example, "Kinds"[CR]is[CR]commonly misspelled as "Kainz", even though the latter is the most[CR]logical[CR]transliteration. So you can see why its impossible to tell for[CR]sure.[CR] Hacking[CR]Notes[CR]-----------------------------------------------------------------------------[CR]Nothing[CR]interesting (fortunately). The usual techniques were employed and old[CR]code[CR]was modified and reused. The variable-width font engine was upgraded[CR]to[CR]handle groups and triplets (possibly a new invention in kerning[CR]technology).[CR]Other than that, theres not much to say here, except a very[CR]special thanks[CR]to a very special guest. ;)[CR]Contact[CR]-----------------------------------------------------------------------------[CR]mijeto@gmail.com[CR](preferred) or tougi_ou@yahoo.com[CR]I cannot guarantee a timely reply; this[CR]address is sometimes not checked for[CR]weeks or months at a time, depending[CR]on recent activity levels and Internet[CR]availability.[CR]And on the[CR]web:[CR]http://mijet.eludevisibility.org/[CR]http://www.geocities.com/tougi_ou/[CR](backup site)</plot>
    <studio>M.I.J.E.T.</studio>
    <snapshot1>IWBVthX.png</snapshot1>
    <snapshot2>WCk3TVA.png</snapshot2>
  </game>
  <game name="Pulseman (Japan) [T-En by MIJET v20070226]">
    <description>Pulseman (Japan) [T-En by MIJET v20070226]</description>
    <title_clean>Pulseman</title_clean>
    <rom name="MaybeIntroTEn20121007/Maybe-Intro%20%5BT-En%5D%20%2820121007%29.zip/Sega%20Mega%20Drive%20%5BT-En%5D%2FPulseman%20%28Japan%29%20%5BT-En%20by%20MIJET%20v20070226%5D.zip" size="1279738"/>
    <plot>The world is connected by a network of eight ultra computers and the self-conscious final computer "Saint Anne". In 1999, the young Doctor Yoshiyama has created an artificial intelligence in the ultra computer Amabilis in Japan, which became a "C-Life". He fell in love with the C-Life girl he had created, so he digitized himself on the computer to stay with her. Later, he combined his DNA with her program core, and their union resulted in the Half C-Life, half human boy called Pulseman. Pulseman's dual nature allows him to freely travel through the real world and cyberspace, and he can control electricity.[CR]In the year 2015, the mysterious Galaxy Gang led by Doc Waruyama starts a series of crimes across the world to conquer the galaxy. Pulseman uses his abilities to stop the evil ambition of Doc Waruyama.</plot>
    <genre>Action,Platformer,2D</genre>
    <studio>Terminus Traduction</studio>
    <releasedate>13/07/2009</releasedate>
    <gamefaqs_url>http://www.gamefaqs.com/genesis/580016-pulseman</gamefaqs_url>
    <rating>3.80</rating>
    <nplayers>1</nplayers>
    <boxart1>aJu6W5R.png</boxart1>
    <clearlogo1>u2Yd5GQ.png</clearlogo1>
    <snapshot1>mFRBiF4.png</snapshot1>
    <fanart1>yejkyXD.jpg</fanart1>
    <boxart2>Aedk9XE.jpg</boxart2>
    <snapshot2>tivuB0R.jpg</snapshot2>
    <boxart3>SGVr5Ub.jpg</boxart3>
    <boxart4>L2xJlcE.png</boxart4>
    <boxart5>AQdQJ1I.png</boxart5>
  </game>
  <game name="Sonic Eraser (Japan) (SegaNet) [T-En by Derrick Sobodash v1.0]">
    <description>Sonic Eraser (Japan) (SegaNet) [T-En by Derrick Sobodash v1.0]</description>
    <title_clean>Sonic Eraser</title_clean>
    <rom name="MaybeIntroTEn20121007/Maybe-Intro%20%5BT-En%5D%20%2820121007%29.zip/Sega%20Mega%20Drive%20%5BT-En%5D%2FSonic%20Eraser%20%28Japan%29%20%28SegaNet%29%20%5BT-En%20by%20Derrick%20Sobodash%20v1.0%5D.zip" size="110645"/>
    <plot>Sonic Eraser (sonitsukuireiza) is a 1991 puzzle game that was downloadable for players that had Sega Game Toshokan, an online game downloading service for the Sega Mega Drive in Japan. Because the service is now long defunct, the game was unknown to much of the Sonic community for a time. The game was later released in 2004 on Sega of Japan's website, and it received more widespread attention as it was noticed by English-speaking Sonic fans this time around.</plot>
    <studio>D</studio>
    <rating>2.25</rating>
    <nplayers>2</nplayers>
    <releasedate>01/01/1991</releasedate>
    <boxart1>p1FZvGB.png</boxart1>
    <clearlogo1>u5e5MMW.png</clearlogo1>
    <snapshot1>hiJJgCU.png</snapshot1>
    <boxart2>PdZBvLG.png</boxart2>
    <snapshot2>0b28OGE.png</snapshot2>
    <boxart3>btiayQU.png</boxart3>
  </game>
  <game name="Sorcerian (Japan) [T-En by S.Seehorn v0.50] [i]">
    <description>Sorcerian (Japan) [T-En by S.Seehorn v0.50] [i]</description>
    <title_clean>Sorcerian</title_clean>
    <rom name="MaybeIntroTEn20121007/Maybe-Intro%20%5BT-En%5D%20%2820121007%29.zip/Sega%20Mega%20Drive%20%5BT-En%5D%2FSorcerian%20%28Japan%29%20%5BT-En%20by%20S.Seehorn%20v0.50%5D%20%5Bi%5D.zip" size="426908"/>
    <plot>Sorcerian is the fifth game in the Dragon Slayer series. It is set in the fantasy land known as Pentawa, whose inhabitants are in constant need of protection from ferocious creatures roaming the wilderness. The king of Pentawa hires a party of adventurers, and their first assignment is to retrieve a precious sceptre from a dungeon, where it is guarded by the evil demonic lord Ouks.[CR]The game is an RPG with an unusual side-scrolling perspective and action-based combat, somewhat of a cross between Wizardry and platform games. Despite being a Japanese game, Sorcerian resembles Western RPGs of its time, focusing more on character development than story. In the beginning, the player creates a party of four characters, choosing between fighter, wizard, elf, and dwarf (races and classes are not distinguished). Beside the usual inns and shops, there are many things that can be done in the towns of the game, including complex development of magical spells (up to 120 spells of different disciplines), training to raise personal skills (strength, intelligence, etc.), enchanting weapons with elemental magic, as well as looking for part-time jobs.[CR]The view switches to side-scrolling when the party ventures into a hostile area. Combat is performed in real time, with the player controlling the entire party at once. The lead character can be changed at any time, and battle actions will be carried out by whoever is in front. Melee attacks and magic spells are unleashed by pressing corresponding buttons. The characters can also jump and interact with objects by bumping into them. Dungeons are usually maze-like, and some contain simple puzzles such as finding and activating hidden switches to open doors.</plot>
    <genre>Role-Playing,Action RPG</genre>
    <studio>Naflign's Ego</studio>
    <releasedate>24/02/1990</releasedate>
    <gamefaqs_url>http://www.gamefaqs.com/genesis/579569-sorcerian</gamefaqs_url>
    <nplayers>1</nplayers>
    <boxart1>QlUkBnB.png</boxart1>
    <clearlogo1>PWFi9qY.png</clearlogo1>
    <snapshot1>XmHIAic.png</snapshot1>
    <fanart1>ipRf8VZ.jpg</fanart1>
    <boxart2>Xc0akM3.jpg</boxart2>
    <snapshot2>tBiyaFs.png</snapshot2>
    <boxart3>n3gYrhy.jpg</boxart3>
    <boxart4>6hPKzSK.jpg</boxart4>
  </game>
  <game name="Twinkle Tale (Japan) [T-En by MIJET v20070328]">
    <description>Twinkle Tale (Japan) [T-En by MIJET v20070328]</description>
    <title_clean>Twinkle Tale</title_clean>
    <rom name="MaybeIntroTEn20121007/Maybe-Intro%20%5BT-En%5D%20%2820121007%29.zip/Sega%20Mega%20Drive%20%5BT-En%5D%2FTwinkle%20Tale%20%28Japan%29%20%5BT-En%20by%20MIJET%20v20070328%5D.zip" size="546056"/>
    <plot>An overhead scrolling fantasy shoot 'em up, Twinkle Tale casts the player in the role of the young witch Saria, in a quest to rid her magical floating island of the evil creatures that have invaded it.[CR]Saria's offensive weapons come pre-defined as three different spells, which you can freely switch to at any time and level-up by collecting power stars, as well as screen-clearing bombs.</plot>
    <genre>Action,Shooter,Scrolling</genre>
    <studio>M.I.J.E.T.</studio>
    <releasedate>24/07/1992</releasedate>
    <gamefaqs_url>http://www.gamefaqs.com/genesis/567055-twinkle-tale</gamefaqs_url>
    <rating>3.62</rating>
    <nplayers>1</nplayers>
    <boxart1>6e4mHbq.png</boxart1>
    <clearlogo1>cPRnEWu.png</clearlogo1>
    <snapshot1>Q7MCFTL.gif</snapshot1>
    <boxart2>RPGhMNW.jpg</boxart2>
    <snapshot2>GBMzfXl.gif</snapshot2>
    <boxart3>tN5D3HZ.png</boxart3>
  </game>
  <game name="Undead Line (Japan) [T-En by MIJET v20070903]">
    <description>Undead Line (Japan) [T-En by MIJET v20070903]</description>
    <title_clean>Undead Line</title_clean>
    <rom name="MaybeIntroTEn20121007/Maybe-Intro%20%5BT-En%5D%20%2820121007%29.zip/Sega%20Mega%20Drive%20%5BT-En%5D%2FUndead%20Line%20%28Japan%29%20%5BT-En%20by%20MIJET%20v20070903%5D.zip" size="440578"/>
    <plot>Undead Line is a top-down arcade shooter with scrolling screens, like Commando and other games. The player controls a character that shoots projectiles at enemy monsters.[CR]The six levels available are presented in a menu and can be selected and played in any order. There is a boss battle at the end of each one.[CR]Chests with power-ups are scattered throughout the levels. They open when shot, and in the Genesis version it is possible to cycle through the available power-ups by keeping firing at them. The power-ups include armor and speed boosts, and several types of projectiles.</plot>
    <genre>Action,Shooter,Scrolling</genre>
    <studio>M.I.J.E.T.</studio>
    <releasedate>20/12/1991</releasedate>
    <gamefaqs_url>http://www.gamefaqs.com/genesis/581678-undead-line</gamefaqs_url>
    <rating>3.50</rating>
    <boxart1>DLdu7g3.png</boxart1>
    <clearlogo1>px2W4Ie.png</clearlogo1>
    <snapshot1>dsb63BO.png</snapshot1>
    <boxart2>ejxJHnL.jpg</boxart2>
    <snapshot2>UybymJy.png</snapshot2>
    <boxart3>RNHL8pW.png</boxart3>
    <videoid>CU0yBcpQQPo</videoid>
  </game>
  <game name="Yu Yu Hakusho - Makyou Toitsusen (Japan) [T-En by MIJET v20071113]">
    <description>Yu Yu Hakusho - Makyou Toitsusen (Japan) [T-En by MIJET v20071113]</description>
    <title_clean>Yu Yu Hakusho - Makyou Toitsusen</title_clean>
    <rom name="MaybeIntroTEn20121007/Maybe-Intro%20%5BT-En%5D%20%2820121007%29.zip/Sega%20Mega%20Drive%20%5BT-En%5D%2FYu%20Yu%20Hakusho%20-%20Makyou%20Toitsusen%20%28Japan%29%20%5BT-En%20by%20MIJET%20v20071113%5D.zip" size="1233954"/>
    <plot>Yuu Yuu Hakusho: Makyo Touitsusen is an action fighting game for the Sega[CR]Genesis.</plot>
    <studio>M.I.J.E.T.</studio>
    <boxart1>zOysY13.png</boxart1>
    <snapshot1>LeV9deO.png</snapshot1>
    <snapshot2>1rM5lsx.png</snapshot2>
  </game>
</datafile>
