<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<datafile>
	<header>
		<emu_name>MSX2</emu_name>
		<emu_description>MSX</emu_description>
		<emu_category>Microsoft, PC, 8 Bit, 1980s</emu_category>
		<emu_version>04012018</emu_version>
		<emu_date>09/06/2016</emu_date>
		<emu_author>Zach Morris</emu_author>
		<emu_visibility>visible</emu_visibility>
		<emu_homepage>http://www.no-intro.org</emu_homepage>
		<emu_baseurl>https://archive.org/download/</emu_baseurl>
		<emu_launcher>retroplayer</emu_launcher>
		<emu_default_addon>none</emu_default_addon>
		<emu_ext_launch_cmd>none</emu_ext_launch_cmd>
		<emu_downloadpath>default</emu_downloadpath>
		<emu_postdlaction>unzip_rom</emu_postdlaction>
		<emu_comment>MSX2 No Intro list.  Filtered to remove duplicates, betas, etc.[CR]MSX2 is the 2nd in 4 generations of computer based systems in the MSX line.[CR]The MSX is a standardized home computer architecture.  Despite Microsoft's involvement, the MSX-based machines were seldom released in the United States, but were popular in Asian countries like Japan and South Korea, South American countries like Brazil and Chile, and in the European market in countries like the Netherlands, France, Spain and Finland. To a lesser extent, the MSX platform was also popular in the former Soviet Union and Kuwait.[CR]Before the appearance and great success of Nintendo's Family Computer, MSX was the platform for which major Japanese game studios, such as Konami and Hudson Soft, produced video game titles. The Metal Gear series, for example, was originally written for MSX hardware.[CR]Developer:  ASCII Corporation[CR]Manufacturer :  Microsoft[CR]CPU:  Zilog Z80A running at 3.58 MHz[CR]Memory: 32 kB ROM / 8 kb RAM[CR]Graphics:  Yamaha V9938 128 KB[CR]Sound:  Yamaha YM2149[CR]Display:  512x212 (16 colors)[CR]Media:  Cartridge and Floppy</emu_comment>
		<emu_thumb>TpZm8xQ.jpg</emu_thumb>
		<emu_banner>Djv0i32.jpg</emu_banner>
		<emu_fanart>G61sggx.jpg</emu_fanart>
		<emu_logo>j1ocHrN.png</emu_logo>
		<emu_trailer>TOhcdKBlUzI</emu_trailer>
	</header>
		<game name="1942 (Japan)">
			<description>1942 (Japan)</description>
			<rom name="No-Intro-Collection_2016-09-06/Microsoft-Msx2.zip/1942%20%28Japan%29.zip" size="65191" />
			<title_clean>1942</title_clean>
			<plot>1942 is a vertically scrolling shooter for one or two players. The year is 1942, and you are a daring fighter pilot "Super Ace". You begin and end each of the numerous levels on an aircraft carrier and then fly your plane into battle against the enemy over both sea and land. After destroying certain plane formations you can collect several different power ups to increase your fire power and chances of survival.</plot>
			<genre>Shooter</genre>
			<studio>Capcom</studio>
			<nplayers>2</nplayers>
			<videoid>dXarj-ZWvXM</videoid>
			<wiki_url>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/1942_(video_game)</wiki_url>
			<boxart1>phWOyz3.png</boxart1>
			<snapshot1>NzYYzAZ.png</snapshot1>
			<snapshot2>VbwaWWX.png</snapshot2>
			<fanart1>qCGA0g5.jpg</fanart1>
			<clearlogo1>cwkAt88.png</clearlogo1>
		</game>
		<game name="AcroJet (Japan)">
			<description>AcroJet (Japan)</description>
			<rom name="No-Intro-Collection_2016-09-06/Microsoft-Msx2.zip/AcroJet%20%28Japan%29.zip" size="34650" />
			<title_clean>AcroJet</title_clean>
			<plot>The player flies a BD5J, a small agile jet. The player has to complete a series of eight stunt courses and routines with the jet. For example, in one set, the player has to fly the plane around a series of pylons. In another, the player must fly a figure eight. Stunts get harder as play progresses. Some game parameters, such as weather, are configurable.[CR]There are ten acrobatic events which can be played by up to four players at four levels of difficulty. In all ten events the player must fly over a series of obstacles.</plot>
			<releasedate>1/1/1988</releasedate>
			<year>1988</year>
			<genre>Flight Simulator</genre>
			<studio>MicroProse</studio>
			<nplayers>1</nplayers>
			<boxart1>C8GotER.png</boxart1>
			<snapshot1>bDMzvpU.png</snapshot1>
			<snapshot2>vXLC7Ru.png</snapshot2>
			<fanart1>VvXP7t2.jpg</fanart1>
		</game>
		<game name="Aleste (Japan)">
			<description>Aleste (Japan)</description>
			<rom name="No-Intro-Collection_2016-09-06/Microsoft-Msx2.zip/Aleste%20%28Japan%29.zip" size="116066" />
			<title_clean>Aleste</title_clean>
			<plot>The story of Aleste concerns the manmade supercomputer DIA 51, which has been infected by a hybrid virus that is spreading like wildfire, eventually leading DIA 51 to eliminate the human race. When Yuri, Ray's girlfriend, gets injured in DIA's assault, Raymond Waizen has all the reason in the world to get rid of DIA 51 once and for all in his Aleste fighter.[CR]Aleste is more or less the sequel to Zanac, as it features the same AI generated enemy waves and weapon system. It did, however, start a whole new plot - evil plant creatures were taking over the planet, so you fight against monstrous vines and other types of twisted vegetation. The scrolling is also much improved over the choppiness of the original Zanac MSX.</plot>
			<releasedate>29/2/1988</releasedate>
			<year>1988</year>
			<genre>Shooter</genre>
			<studio>Compile</studio>
			<nplayers>1</nplayers>
			<boxart1>dh3SLqd.jpg</boxart1>
			<boxart2>ZVaAU8b.jpg</boxart2>
			<boxart3>vgVeJ1s.png</boxart3>
			<boxart4>BFUfaIU.png</boxart4>
			<snapshot1>JM1Ctb3.png</snapshot1>
			<snapshot2>t7bn5bh.png</snapshot2>
			<fanart1>myFzrtw.jpg</fanart1>
			<clearlogo1>6IlGUkw.png</clearlogo1>
		</game>
		<game name="Aoki Ookami to Shiroki Mejika - Genchou Hishi (Japan)">
			<description>Aoki Ookami to Shiroki Mejika - Genchou Hishi (Japan)</description>
			<rom name="No-Intro-Collection_2016-09-06/Microsoft-Msx2.zip/Aoki%20Ookami%20to%20Shiroki%20Mejika%20-%20Genchou%20Hishi%20%28Japan%29.zip" size="649938" />
			<title_clean>Aoki Ookami to Shiroki Mejika - Genchou Hishi</title_clean>
			<plot>Aoki Ookami to Shiroki Mejika: Genchou Hishi is a Strategy game, developed and published by Koei, which was released in Japan in 1992.</plot>
			<genre>Strategy</genre>
			<studio>Koei</studio>
			<ESRB>Not Rated</ESRB>
			<videoid>xwJyB57Mg0o</videoid>
			<boxart1>rNejw6Z.png</boxart1>
			<boxart2>0DMl7Ud.png</boxart2>
			<boxart3>ZY3bB3W.png</boxart3>
			<snapshot1>MAPvda5.png</snapshot1>
			<snapshot2>qPijRAs.png</snapshot2>
		</game>
		<game name="Aoki Ookami to Shiroki Mejika - Genghis Khan (Japan)">
			<description>Aoki Ookami to Shiroki Mejika - Genghis Khan (Japan)</description>
			<rom name="No-Intro-Collection_2016-09-06/Microsoft-Msx2.zip/Aoki%20Ookami%20to%20Shiroki%20Mejika%20-%20Genghis%20Khan%20%28Japan%29.zip" size="345002" />
			<title_clean>Aoki Ookami to Shiroki Mejika - Genghis Khan</title_clean>
			<plot>Become Genghis Khan and lead the most fearsome army in the known world. Use your Land of Mongols to build an empire on the bodies of your enemies and the rubble of their conquered cities. With skill, cunning, diplomacy and luck, all of Europe and Asia could be yours. Failure means shame in the eyes of your princess, or even death! Victory on the battlefield requires bold strategy and clever planning. Outmaneuver your opponent with cavalry, lay siege to his castle with archers or even challenge him to a duel. But success also requires brilliant political tactics and a sharp eye for business during times of peace. Genghis Khan is based on actual history and offers a blend of strategy and role playing elements. Make history as you play the great Khan himself or his rivals, Richard the Lionhearted, Emperor Alexious III, or Shogun Minamoto of Japan.</plot>
			<genre>Strategy</genre>
			<studio>Koei</studio>
			<nplayers>1</nplayers>
			<rating>1.5</rating>
			<ESRB>Not Rated</ESRB>
			<boxart1>9AEzlg6.jpg</boxart1>
			<boxart2>eeQEtwr.jpg</boxart2>
			<boxart3>16xs202.png</boxart3>
			<snapshot1>Al2ciOc.png</snapshot1>
			<snapshot2>WcE04dZ.png</snapshot2>
		</game>
		<game name="Arkanoid II - Revenge of Doh (Japan)">
			<description>Arkanoid II - Revenge of Doh (Japan)</description>
			<rom name="No-Intro-Collection_2016-09-06/Microsoft-Msx2.zip/Arkanoid%20II%20-%20Revenge%20of%20Doh%20%28Japan%29.zip" size="52432" />
			<title_clean>Arkanoid II - Revenge of Doh</title_clean>
			<plot>Revenge of Doh is a direct sequel to the original arcade smash Arkanoid. Along with improved graphic engine, better sound and music, better hardware support and more levels, Revenge of Doh also features a built-in editor and allows you to create your own level sets![CR]A long time period passed and the dimension controlling force Doh has again come back to life. Occupying the huge starship Xorg, it has entered our universe from a different dimension. Mixtec, Arkanoid type spaceship, has lauched the craft Vaus II to make a preemptive attack on Xorg.</plot>
			<genre>Action; Puzzle</genre>
			<studio>Taito</studio>
			<nplayers>1</nplayers>
			<ESRB>Not Rated</ESRB>
			<boxart1>Jlto4yg.png</boxart1>
			<snapshot1>yffH6yY.png</snapshot1>
			<snapshot2>T2HpznV.png</snapshot2>
			<fanart1>Dgj88ta.jpg</fanart1>
			<clearlogo1>HuX3vMZ.png</clearlogo1>
		</game>
		<game name="AshGuine - Densetsu no Seisenshi (Japan)">
			<description>AshGuine - Densetsu no Seisenshi (Japan)</description>
			<rom name="No-Intro-Collection_2016-09-06/Microsoft-Msx2.zip/AshGuine%20-%20Densetsu%20no%20Seisenshi%20%28Japan%29.zip" size="63618" />
			<title_clean>AshGuine - Densetsu no Seisenshi</title_clean>
			<plot>The evil Banutracus had destroyed the great civilization of the planet Nepenthus and brought it down to a primitive state. War broke out between the planet's humble Eletrian people and Banutracus's barbarous Cooligan invaders. After a long struggle, the Eletrians got united under the powerful leadership of one they called the father and managed to obtain a momentary peace. Howerver, when Banutracus returned to his planet he killed the father and re-established his hold. One Cooligan Gea saw the evil nature of Banutracus and escaped with the father's only daughter Neshah to one of the great ruined Eletrian cities. There, they had a son. When the boy grew to be a strong young man, one of the Cooligan soldiers discovered their hideout and killed his escaped parents. From that day, the boy swore vengeance on Banutracus and to eventually restore peace to the planet.&#8221;</plot>
			<releasedate>1/1/1987</releasedate>
			<year>1987</year>
			<genre>Action; Adventure</genre>
			<studio>Bit2</studio>
			<nplayers>1</nplayers>
			<videoid>SnfBIq-QNkg</videoid>
			<boxart1>zzHdBRE.jpg</boxart1>
			<boxart2>UYYbWHX.jpg</boxart2>
			<snapshot1>PCkaNWr.png</snapshot1>
			<snapshot2>sasAxZD.png</snapshot2>
			<fanart1>FFiHGvh.jpg</fanart1>
			<clearlogo1>1vGqkcS.png</clearlogo1>
		</game>
		<game name="AshGuine Story II - Kokuu no Gajou (Japan)">
			<description>AshGuine Story II - Kokuu no Gajou (Japan)</description>
			<rom name="No-Intro-Collection_2016-09-06/Microsoft-Msx2.zip/AshGuine%20Story%20II%20-%20Kokuu%20no%20Gajou%20%28Japan%29.zip" size="132179" />
			<title_clean>AshGuine Story II - Kokuu no Gajou</title_clean>
			<plot>An action RPG for MSX released in 1987 and published by T&amp;E Soft. The story of AshGuine II can be viewed as being set up in an alternate universe to and not a direct sequel to AshGuine I.</plot>
			<genre>Action; Role-Playing</genre>
			<studio>T&amp;E Soft</studio>
			<nplayers>1</nplayers>
			<ESRB>Not Rated</ESRB>
			<boxart1>GY7QIQN.jpg</boxart1>
			<boxart2>JoFwpBD.jpg</boxart2>
			<boxart3>XQ0QKjW.png</boxart3>
			<snapshot1>TPKiCVC.png</snapshot1>
			<snapshot2>mkYd3uo.png</snapshot2>
			<fanart1>xZwJmAX.jpg</fanart1>
		</game>
		<game name="AshGuine Story III - Fukushuu no Honoo (Japan)">
			<description>AshGuine Story III - Fukushuu no Honoo (Japan)</description>
			<rom name="No-Intro-Collection_2016-09-06/Microsoft-Msx2.zip/AshGuine%20Story%20III%20-%20Fukushuu%20no%20Honoo%20%28Japan%29.zip" size="124590" />
			<title_clean>AshGuine Story III - Fukushuu no Honoo</title_clean>
			<plot>Developed by Micro Cabin, AshGuine Story III is a top-view action-RPG with real-time battles. You navigate through the game world just like in an RPG and you have to get into houses to talk to people to gather information.</plot>
			<genre>Action; Role-Playing</genre>
			<studio>Micro Cabin</studio>
			<nplayers>1</nplayers>
			<ESRB>Not Rated</ESRB>
			<videoid>wNtEh8YvO5Y</videoid>
			<boxart1>98kKJ8k.png</boxart1>
			<snapshot1>03H8MdV.png</snapshot1>
			<snapshot2>Dc3jCv6.png</snapshot2>
		</game>
		<game name="Bubble Bobble (Japan)">
			<description>Bubble Bobble (Japan)</description>
			<rom name="No-Intro-Collection_2016-09-06/Microsoft-Msx2.zip/Bubble%20Bobble%20%28Japan%29.zip" size="67260" />
			<title_clean>Bubble Bobble</title_clean>
			<plot>Bubble Bobble is the story of two humans, Bub and Bob who wander into the mysterious cave of monsters and magically turn into dinosaurs. The only way to transform back is to reach the end of the cave...[CR]Bubble Bobble is a platform game, with each level being a single screen. The enemies must be cleared from a level to go to the next one. With one player controlling Bub and the other controlling Bob, the player can jump and collect items for points (such as fruit). The real power Bub and Bob have however is the ability to blow bubbles. These bubbles can be as platforms to leap on, or to trap enemies. Enemies trapped in a bubble must be popped by jumping into them, wherein they'll turn to fruit. Additionally, power-ups sometimes float by in bubbles. They include lightning, which flies out horizontally at enemies, and water, which drags the player and enemies straight down flowing over platforms. Taking too long to complete any level will summon Baron Von Blubba, who will float around the screen trying to destroy the player.</plot>
			<genre>Platform</genre>
			<studio>Taito</studio>
			<nplayers>1-2 Co-Op</nplayers>
			<ESRB>Not Rated</ESRB>
			<videoid>9byzIPKhKs8</videoid>
			<wiki_url>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bubble_Bobble</wiki_url>
			<boxart1>GJLfBqj.jpg</boxart1>
			<boxart2>gKpDFNx.jpg</boxart2>
			<boxart3>W8x16TW.png</boxart3>
			<snapshot1>wS0a3lw.png</snapshot1>
			<snapshot2>omiYaF0.png</snapshot2>
			<clearlogo1>8gvlpaN.png</clearlogo1>
		</game>
		<game name="Cheese 2 (Japan) (Program)">
			<description>Cheese 2 (Japan) (Program)</description>
			<rom name="No-Intro-Collection_2016-09-06/Microsoft-Msx2.zip/Cheese%202%20%28Japan%29%20%28Program%29.zip" size="18226" />
			<title_clean>Cheese 2</title_clean>
			<plot>20 years after the last fight with DIA51 an unidentified space fortress appeared and started an massive attack. Ray Waizen, the hero of the first Aleste game,  was a serving officer on board the first space ship that's been under attack and sadly got killed. His nineteen year old daughter, who is also a pilot, must save mankind and take revenge of her fathers dead...This second installment of the Aleste series is as its predecessor: a very fast vertical shooter with a massive and extensive arsenal of weaponry. Many different types of enemy spaceships that are constantly attacking you and the area bosses are again huge screen filling bunkers.</plot>
			<releasedate>1/1/1986</releasedate>
			<genre>Action</genre>
			<studio>&lt;cart2disk hack&gt;</studio>
			<nplayers>1</nplayers>
			<boxart1>3YicE60.jpg</boxart1>
			<boxart2>3QPqprm.jpg</boxart2>
			<boxart3>F40pYJz.jpg</boxart3>
			<snapshot1>7c7F2Dy.png</snapshot1>
			<snapshot2>87IuY8E.png</snapshot2>
			<snapshot3>6nMu2V5.png</snapshot3>
			<snapshot4>GaPIyHa.png</snapshot4>
			<snapshot5>5HkRy51.png</snapshot5>
		</game>
		<game name="Cockpit, The (Japan)">
			<description>Cockpit, The (Japan)</description>
			<rom name="No-Intro-Collection_2016-09-06/Microsoft-Msx2.zip/Cockpit%2C%20The%20%28Japan%29.zip" size="37410" />
			<title_clean>Cockpit, The</title_clean>
			<plot>The Cockpit is a Simulation game, developed and published by Nidecom, which was released in Japan in 1988.</plot>
			<genre>Flight Simulator</genre>
			<studio>Nidecom</studio>
			<nplayers>1</nplayers>
			<ESRB>Not Rated</ESRB>
			<boxart1>wl4rXtM.png</boxart1>
			<boxart2>EexwLes.jpg</boxart2>
			<boxart3>n052H89.jpg</boxart3>
			<snapshot1>d3TwmGw.png</snapshot1>
			<snapshot2>CLf9nzd.png</snapshot2>
			<fanart1>sogOgPe.jpg</fanart1>
		</game>
		<game name="Contra (Japan)">
			<description>Contra (Japan)</description>
			<rom name="No-Intro-Collection_2016-09-06/Microsoft-Msx2.zip/Contra%20%28Japan%29.zip" size="74303" />
			<title_clean>Contra</title_clean>
			<plot>The universe teeters on the brink of total annihilation at the hands of the vile alien warmonger, Red Falcon. Earth's only hope rests with you, a courageous member of the Special Forces elite commando squad. Your mission: Battle deep into the deadly Amazon jungle, where the Red Falcon and his galactic henchmen have transformed ancient Mayan temples into awesome monuments dedicated to mass destruction. A multitude of weapons, from rapid-fire machine guns to high-tech lasers are at your disposal as you sweat blood, fighting past 3-D mazes, underground security systems, and tropical forests surrounded by giant waterfalls and alien cannons. This is the ultimate test for the ultimate guerilla warrior. And if you survive, Earth survives!</plot>
			<releasedate>20/12/1989</releasedate>
			<year>1989</year>
			<genre>Shooter</genre>
			<studio>Konami</studio>
			<nplayers>2</nplayers>
			<rating>4.75</rating>
			<videoid>5Maej5IvbqA</videoid>
			<boxart1>vOrZs1f.jpg</boxart1>
			<snapshot1>fJl9ZMi.png</snapshot1>
			<snapshot2>xzU0rfO.png</snapshot2>
			<clearlogo1>Jrg1xBf.gif</clearlogo1>
			<clearlogo2>Y5WLmVF.png</clearlogo2>
		</game>
		<game name="Daisenryaku MSX2 (Japan)">
			<description>Daisenryaku MSX2 (Japan)</description>
			<rom name="No-Intro-Collection_2016-09-06/Microsoft-Msx2.zip/Daisenryaku%20MSX2%20%28Japan%29.zip" size="42660" />
			<title_clean>Daisenryaku MSX2</title_clean>
			<plot>Super Daisenryaku is one of the many titles in SystemSoft's long-running war strategy series. The game mechanics are based on Daisenryaku II, but many of the included maps are unique to this release, including several based on Phantasy Star in Sega's console version. There is no campaign mode, and any of the included maps can be played. Some maps are for two players, some for four, and any map can be played with any combination of human and computer players. The computer versions also feature an editor.The game is played on a large map made up of hexagonal spaces, each of which consists of one of the included  terrain types. Each player controls a number of units (bought with money), which each take up one space on the grid. The unit types are for the most part based on real-life military equipment from around the time the game was released, what is available to the player depends on the chosen faction. The choices range from single nations, such as China or the USA (the CD port by Microcabin in particular adds a lot of smaller ones, like Sweden and Libya),  to alliances and blocs, for example NATO, which uses a mixture of equipment of it's members. Different units have different strengths and weaknesses, which affect their performance in combat and their general role on the battlefield. The cheap infantry units for example are not very strong and mobile, but may capture facilities and cities, unlike battle tanks. Terrain also affects the outcome of battles. The goal of each game is to capture the other players' capitals.</plot>
			<releasedate>1/1/1987</releasedate>
			<genre>Strategy</genre>
			<studio>Micro Cabin</studio>
			<nplayers>1-4 Sim</nplayers>
			<boxart1>FrQXVNx.png</boxart1>
			<snapshot1>aV7ynO7.png</snapshot1>
			<snapshot2>Fi2y1WD.png</snapshot2>
		</game>
		<game name="Darwin 4078 (Japan)">
			<description>Darwin 4078 (Japan)</description>
			<rom name="No-Intro-Collection_2016-09-06/Microsoft-Msx2.zip/Darwin%204078%20%28Japan%29.zip" size="53059" />
			<title_clean>Darwin 4078</title_clean>
			<plot>The game takes place within a gigantic spaceship which has virtually infinite capacity because of its ability to manipulate time and space. The player must deal with enigmatic creatures called EVOL, which consist only of pure energy and need to keep themselves in capsules in order to maintain their existence in the world.[CR]All of the characters in the game are designed to resemble microscopic organisms, both in their appearance and their quick, tricky movements. The player's ship undergoes over 10 types of transformations throughout the game, each with offensive and defensive maneuvers specific to their design. The sound effects used are minimal, but different types of sounds are used according to the type of shots or their speed. A sound resembling a long scream results when the player's ship is hit and returns to its weakest evolutionary state. The game's designer, graphic designer, and music composer, Tomo Furukawa, would go on to become the vocalist of the band Guniw Tools.The game controls like a regular shoot-'em-up: A and C shoot bullets, B drops bombs; there is rapidfire. However, unlike regular shoot-'em-ups where weapons are upgraded through powerups, your ship "evolves" to survive situations and get past obstacles. Evolution occurs with the Evol (small faces with an E on them) and B-Evol (darker Evols). Each pickup adds a new evolution state to the list. After a particular amount of time, one evolution wears off and the next evolution is chosen. The DNA powerup does provide a more permanent weapon upgrade, but will merely just make the existing weapons stronger. You can hold up to nine DNA powerups.</plot>
			<releasedate>1/1/1987</releasedate>
			<year>1987</year>
			<genre>Shooter</genre>
			<studio>Hudson</studio>
			<nplayers>1</nplayers>
			<boxart1>lGg1i9d.png</boxart1>
			<snapshot1>5neyEsr.png</snapshot1>
			<snapshot2>1XNtDDf.png</snapshot2>
			<clearlogo1>VyLsLHK.png</clearlogo1>
		</game>
		<game name="Dires - Giger Loop (Japan)">
			<description>Dires - Giger Loop (Japan)</description>
			<rom name="No-Intro-Collection_2016-09-06/Microsoft-Msx2.zip/Dires%20-%20Giger%20Loop%20%28Japan%29.zip" size="38041" />
			<title_clean>Dires - Giger Loop</title_clean>
			<plot>Dires: Giger Loop is an Action game, developed and published by Bothtec, which was released in Japan in 1987.</plot>
			<releasedate>1/1/1987</releasedate>
			<year>1987</year>
			<genre>Action</genre>
			<studio>Bothtec</studio>
			<nplayers>1</nplayers>
			<boxart1>YRVmVAP.png</boxart1>
			<snapshot1>KXBo6GL.png</snapshot1>
			<snapshot2>rHuo6xN.png</snapshot2>
		</game>
		<game name="Dragon Buster (Japan)">
			<description>Dragon Buster (Japan)</description>
			<rom name="No-Intro-Collection_2016-09-06/Microsoft-Msx2.zip/Dragon%20Buster%20%28Japan%29.zip" size="53120" />
			<title_clean>Dragon Buster</title_clean>
			<plot>Originating in the arcades, Dragon Buster is an action platform game composed out of several large levels, each one containing various stages: a cave, a tower, a castle, etc. The player's goal in every level is to reach the final stage where the protagonist faces the level boss. There are often several ways to reach the final stages, and not all stages are necessary to visit. Equipped with a sword, the player character moves through platform stages, clearing them of diverse monsters, collecting power-ups and trying to stay in good health until the level boss, since it is impossible to heal between the stages. The hero's life meter (called "vitality" in the game) is the first introduction of such a feature to action games.</plot>
			<releasedate>1/1/1987</releasedate>
			<year>1987</year>
			<genre>Action; Platform</genre>
			<studio>Namco</studio>
			<nplayers>1</nplayers>
			<ESRB>Not Rated</ESRB>
			<videoid>8ZlSC5An3ys</videoid>
			<wiki_url>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dragon_Buster</wiki_url>
			<boxart1>EgXAMoG.png</boxart1>
			<boxart2>9bf8LI5.png</boxart2>
			<snapshot1>iyo3yGg.png</snapshot1>
			<snapshot2>g8FZ8TL.png</snapshot2>
			<clearlogo1>0tcd5wj.png</clearlogo1>
		</game>
		<game name="Dragon Quest (Japan)">
			<description>Dragon Quest (Japan)</description>
			<rom name="No-Intro-Collection_2016-09-06/Microsoft-Msx2.zip/Dragon%20Quest%20%28Japan%29.zip" size="57772" />
			<title_clean>Dragon Quest</title_clean>
			<plot>All is darkness. The Dragon-lord has captured the Princess and stolen Erdrick's powerful ball of light. You are Erdrick's heir. To you has fallen the most dangerous task - to rescue the King's daughter and recover the mystic ball of light. Search out the Dragon-lord's lair and face your destiny. In this role-playing adventure you are the Dragon Warrior!</plot>
			<releasedate>1/11/1986</releasedate>
			<year>1986</year>
			<genre>RPG</genre>
			<studio>Chunsoft</studio>
			<nplayers>1</nplayers>
			<rating>2</rating>
			<wiki_url>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dragon_Quest_(video_game)</wiki_url>
			<boxart1>aw5WgtL.png</boxart1>
			<snapshot1>StOdVIr.png</snapshot1>
			<snapshot2>3knwUr3.png</snapshot2>
			<fanart1>nnEFDDE.jpg</fanart1>
			<fanart2>ro8g9nr.jpg</fanart2>
			<clearlogo1>SNWcgcE.png</clearlogo1>
		</game>
		<game name="Dragon Slayer IV - Drasle Family (Japan)">
			<description>Dragon Slayer IV - Drasle Family (Japan)</description>
			<rom name="No-Intro-Collection_2016-09-06/Microsoft-Msx2.zip/Dragon%20Slayer%20IV%20-%20Drasle%20Family%20%28Japan%29.zip" size="111382" />
			<title_clean>Dragon Slayer IV - Drasle Family</title_clean>
			<plot>Long ago, an evil dragon named Keela was imprisoned inside a magical dungeon. However time has passed and the magic that sealed the dragon away is weakening. The Drasle family decides that it's time to destroy the dragon once and for all. However only one weapon is capable of doing this, the Dragon Slayer, which is itself sealed away by four magical crowns. The Drasle family decides to take on this quest, and will use every member of the family in order to accomplish it.[CR]The player chooses a character from among five different members of the Drasle family. The choices are: Xemm the father and woodcutter, Mayna the magic-using mother, Roas the brave warrior son, Lyll the athletic daughter and Pochi the domesticated monster-pet. Each character has unique abilities (including attack and jumping abilities) and can only use certain items from those collected. Players can travel back to the Drasle household at any point to change characters.[CR]The object of the game is to enter the large dungeon, itself divided into 5 areas, collecting a variety of items (which as mentioned, can only be used by particular characters) and use them to progress through the dungeon, defeating monsters. Power-ups dropped by monsters include gold, keys, health-restoring bread, magic-restoring potions and health-damaging poison. Gold can be spent on items and other power-ups that are available at various shops hidden inside the dungeon. The player must eventually defeat the four bosses guarding the crowns that seal the Dragon Slayer and then use that weapon to defeat the Kress.</plot>
			<releasedate>9/7/1987</releasedate>
			<year>1987</year>
			<genre>Driving, Racing</genre>
			<studio>Nihon Falcom</studio>
			<nplayers>1</nplayers>
			<boxart1>BL0DCV5.png</boxart1>
			<snapshot1>WR3FlT8.png</snapshot1>
			<snapshot2>Nka0bBT.png</snapshot2>
		</game>
		<game name="Druid (Japan)">
			<description>Druid (Japan)</description>
			<rom name="No-Intro-Collection_2016-09-06/Microsoft-Msx2.zip/Druid%20%28Japan%29.zip" size="59955" />
			<title_clean>Druid</title_clean>
			<plot>Druid is an action game inspired by the arcade hit Gauntlet. As the eponymous hero, your job is to destroy four magic skulls hidden over eight levels. [CR]The game is presented in a top-down view. The druid walks around the terrain seeking out the staircase that leads to the next level. On the way, he is harassed by hordes of monsters that come out of every direction and attack him, decreasing his health. To defend himself, the druid can use the spells of water, fire or electricity to toss projectiles. However, these magical weapons have limited ammo. [CR]The druid also has three other magical spells at his disposal - an invisibility spell which prevents the monsters from automatically approaching him, a golem spell which summons a helpful golem (which can be controlled by a second player), and a skull spell which destroys all on-screen enemies. The druid also carries around keys which open locked doors. But all these have very limited supplies. [CR]On his way, the druid finds many shops. Each such shop contains some keys or charges for the druid's spells, but the druid can only pick one item from each shop. [CR]The druid can also come across a pentagram on the ground which will restore his lost health.</plot>
			<genre>Action</genre>
			<studio>Nippon Dexter</studio>
			<nplayers>1</nplayers>
			<videoid>bqS38CvpbJs</videoid>
			<boxart1>SDIlnS9.png</boxart1>
			<snapshot1>yv8hoWd.png</snapshot1>
			<snapshot2>w6CaVGZ.png</snapshot2>
			<clearlogo1>hbXVzD9.png</clearlogo1>
		</game>
		<game name="Dynamite Bowl (Japan)">
			<description>Dynamite Bowl (Japan)</description>
			<rom name="No-Intro-Collection_2016-09-06/Microsoft-Msx2.zip/Dynamite%20Bowl%20%28Japan%29.zip" size="45488" />
			<title_clean>Dynamite Bowl</title_clean>
			<plot>Dynamite Bowl (&#12480;&#12452;&#12490;&#12510;&#12452;&#12488;&#12508;&#12454;&#12523;, Dainamaito B&#333;ru) is a 1987 multiplatform video game that simulates the traditional game of bowling. The MSX version was released for both the MSX-1 and the MSX-2 variations of the console.</plot>
			<releasedate>24/5/1987</releasedate>
			<year>1987</year>
			<genre>Sports</genre>
			<studio>Softvision</studio>
			<wiki_url>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dynamite_Bowl</wiki_url>
			<boxart1>FTXTyM6.jpg</boxart1>
			<snapshot1>5fUJItz.png</snapshot1>
			<snapshot2>plSI16W.png</snapshot2>
		</game>
		<game name="Eidolon, The (Europe)">
			<description>Eidolon, The (Europe)</description>
			<rom name="No-Intro-Collection_2016-09-06/Microsoft-Msx2.zip/Eidolon%2C%20The%20%28Europe%29.zip" size="59863" />
			<title_clean>Eidolon, The</title_clean>
			<plot>You control a mysterious 19th-century machine named "The Eidolon" through mysterious caves. Collect and create fireballs and encounter strange creatures like 'Greps', 'Biter Birds', 'Bottlenecks', 'Rotoflies', 'Puffer Birds' , and 'Guardian Dragons'. Each type of fireball you collect has different effects. For instance Blue fireballs freeze time, and green fireballs transform one monster into another type. A guardian dragon must be defeated at the end of each level.[CR]Eidolon is one of the progenitors of the first-person shooter genre, with full pseudo-3D panoramic graphics. This was achieved with the use of Lucasfilm Games 3D fractal technology, also used in Rescue on Fractalus! and Koronis Rift.</plot>
			<genre>Shooter</genre>
			<studio>P.A.W.</studio>
			<nplayers>1</nplayers>
			<ESRB>Not Rated</ESRB>
			<videoid>y7fMgYt-AD4</videoid>
			<wiki_url>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Eidolon</wiki_url>
			<boxart1>eYFijhi.png</boxart1>
			<snapshot1>l9HDtYa.png</snapshot1>
			<snapshot2>ojcVnj1.png</snapshot2>
			<clearlogo1>nIwJSwd.png</clearlogo1>
		</game>
		<game name="F-15 Strike Eagle (Japan)">
			<description>F-15 Strike Eagle (Japan)</description>
			<rom name="No-Intro-Collection_2016-09-06/Microsoft-Msx2.zip/F-15%20Strike%20Eagle%20%28Japan%29.zip" size="35855" />
			<title_clean>F-15 Strike Eagle</title_clean>
			<plot>The seven missions featured in this simulation of F-15 flight are all real-life missions the plane was originally used in. They take in the Middle East and Asia in the 1970s and early 1980s, and have air and ground targets to destroy. You have machine guns, guided missiles and bombs at your disposal. There is an arcade mode and 3 further difficulty levels. The game features 3 enemy aircraft and 3 types of enemy SAMs.</plot>
			<genre>Flight Simulator</genre>
			<studio>SystemSoft</studio>
			<nplayers>1</nplayers>
			<videoid>R2HqmeTnrh0</videoid>
			<boxart1>YOuZCvI.jpg</boxart1>
			<snapshot1>DTa9DRE.png</snapshot1>
			<snapshot2>pdeME0o.png</snapshot2>
			<clearlogo1>jUcVmXz.png</clearlogo1>
		</game>
		<game name="Famicle Parodic (Japan)">
			<description>Famicle Parodic (Japan)</description>
			<rom name="No-Intro-Collection_2016-09-06/Microsoft-Msx2.zip/Famicle%20Parodic%20%28Japan%29.zip" size="120804" />
			<title_clean>Famicle Parodic</title_clean>
			<plot>Shoot and bomb your way around in this Xevious-style shooter for the MSX2.</plot>
			<releasedate>1/1/1988</releasedate>
			<year>1988</year>
			<genre>Shooter</genre>
			<studio>Bit2</studio>
			<nplayers>1</nplayers>
			<videoid>zWbsIUlTqQk</videoid>
			<boxart1>Lo6jttW.jpg</boxart1>
			<boxart2>AX5GkVH.jpg</boxart2>
			<boxart3>o7nVatm.png</boxart3>
			<snapshot1>8QCnRmW.png</snapshot1>
			<snapshot2>IRHTPvF.png</snapshot2>
			<clearlogo1>O1Jf1Rj.png</clearlogo1>
		</game>
		<game name="Family Billiards (Japan)">
			<description>Family Billiards (Japan)</description>
			<rom name="No-Intro-Collection_2016-09-06/Microsoft-Msx2.zip/Family%20Billiards%20%28Japan%29.zip" size="27252" />
			<title_clean>Family Billiards</title_clean>
			<plot>Family Billiards is a Miscellaneous game, developed by Dual and published by Pack-In-Video, which was released in Japan in 1987.</plot>
			<genre>Sports</genre>
			<studio>Dual</studio>
			<nplayers>4</nplayers>
			<boxart1>ljiBCkL.png</boxart1>
			<snapshot1>HWzfqHy.png</snapshot1>
			<snapshot2>WbXUMcv.png</snapshot2>
			<clearlogo1>RNPKY4q.png</clearlogo1>
		</game>
		<game name="Family Boxing - MSX Title Match (Japan)">
			<description>Family Boxing - MSX Title Match (Japan)</description>
			<rom name="No-Intro-Collection_2016-09-06/Microsoft-Msx2.zip/Family%20Boxing%20-%20MSX%20Title%20Match%20%28Japan%29.zip" size="97092" />
			<title_clean>Family Boxing - MSX Title Match</title_clean>
			<plot>Ring King is a boxing game in which the action in the ring is viewed in a 3D top-down view and a full range of moves is provided, with the standard jabs complimented by body punches and the ability to dodge, duck or raise your guard.[CR]Each punch weakens your opponent's strength which can slightly recover during a round break. A rain of well placed blows can produce a quick knockout, but normally you must hit your opponent many times before he goes down.[CR]The game has three play modes. There is training mode to train your player before you enter a tournament. A ranking mode where you can select one of the three championships, Rookie, Japan and World. Each championship can be played at five difficulty levels. The third mode is the tournament mode. To reach the number one spot in the ranking or tournament mode you must train your boxer well.[CR]Before you start you must create your character and set his initial abilities, strength, speed and stamina. Each won bout increases these abilities slightly. The abilities of your opponent and you are visible in the status bar at the top of the screen during the game. Strength is represented with a boxing glove, speed with a shoe and stamina with a dumb bell.[CR]This game can be played by one player against the computer or by two players against each other. A password is given after each won bout and it enables you to continue with the next match in a tournament at a later time.</plot>
			<releasedate>1/1/1988</releasedate>
			<year>1988</year>
			<genre>Sports</genre>
			<studio>Wood Place</studio>
			<nplayers>2</nplayers>
			<videoid>akMW_JhNNbQ</videoid>
			<boxart1>oVd4hGD.png</boxart1>
			<snapshot1>m2WReMp.png</snapshot1>
			<snapshot2>1fPNdZ7.png</snapshot2>
			<clearlogo1>nvKdfSa.png</clearlogo1>
		</game>
		<game name="Fantasy Zone II - The Tears of Opa-Opa (Japan)">
			<description>Fantasy Zone II - The Tears of Opa-Opa (Japan)</description>
			<rom name="No-Intro-Collection_2016-09-06/Microsoft-Msx2.zip/Fantasy%20Zone%20II%20-%20The%20Tears%20of%20Opa-Opa%20%28Japan%29.zip" size="95557" />
			<title_clean>Fantasy Zone II - The Tears of Opa-Opa</title_clean>
			<plot>Opa-Opa is at it again in this zany return to his original homeland some ten years later. Welcome to Fantasy Zone II where perils are great and rewards even greater. During your visit you'll discover that peace is at stake once again and those who threaten it are more cunning and wicked than before. So beware, the evil Blackhearts are near and they're not alone. Scores of unusual and seemingly innocent creatures will enthusiastically approach you. But don't be fooled. They're not here to help. They're henchmen for the dark powers of the Blackhearts. And they'll sabotage every chance you've got to protect the warp gates from total ruin. So fight valiantly, because just when you think you've made it, the Blackhearts will be waiting.</plot>
			<genre>Shooter</genre>
			<studio>Atelier Double</studio>
			<nplayers>1</nplayers>
			<ESRB>Not Rated</ESRB>
			<boxart1>tNLVXGx.jpg</boxart1>
			<snapshot1>9nTR7eX.png</snapshot1>
			<snapshot2>8Aj6jpR.png</snapshot2>
		</game>
		<game name="Fire Ball (Japan)">
			<description>Fire Ball (Japan)</description>
			<rom name="No-Intro-Collection_2016-09-06/Microsoft-Msx2.zip/Fire%20Ball%20%28Japan%29.zip" size="52925" />
			<title_clean>Fire Ball</title_clean>
			<plot>Generic Pinball Game</plot>
			<genre>Action</genre>
			<studio>Hummingbird Soft</studio>
			<nplayers>1</nplayers>
			<ESRB>Not Rated</ESRB>
			<boxart1>XNPfsdz.png</boxart1>
			<snapshot1>xQzWIup.png</snapshot1>
			<snapshot2>LeIQt3L.png</snapshot2>
			<fanart1>xDW56mV.jpg</fanart1>
		</game>
		<game name="Fleet Commander II - Koukon no Kaiiki (Japan)">
			<description>Fleet Commander II - Koukon no Kaiiki (Japan)</description>
			<rom name="No-Intro-Collection_2016-09-06/Microsoft-Msx2.zip/Fleet%20Commander%20II%20-%20Koukon%20no%20Kaiiki%20%28Japan%29.zip" size="149360" />
			<title_clean>Fleet Commander II - Koukon no Kaiiki</title_clean>
			<plot>Fleet Commander II: Koukon no Kaiiki is a Strategy game, developed and published by ASCII, which was released in Japan in 1990.</plot>
			<genre>Strategy</genre>
			<studio>ASCII</studio>
			<nplayers>1</nplayers>
			<ESRB>Not Rated</ESRB>
			<boxart1>pTfcg3P.jpg</boxart1>
			<boxart2>84rAxbq.jpg</boxart2>
			<boxart3>fZRYDIQ.jpg</boxart3>
			<snapshot1>xgjj7FO.png</snapshot1>
			<snapshot2>9w2Cn4x.png</snapshot2>
		</game>
		<game name="Gakuen Monogatari - High School Story (Japan)">
			<description>Gakuen Monogatari - High School Story (Japan)</description>
			<rom name="No-Intro-Collection_2016-09-06/Microsoft-Msx2.zip/Gakuen%20Monogatari%20-%20High%20School%20Story%20%28Japan%29.zip" size="141087" />
			<title_clean>Gakuen Monogatari - High School Story</title_clean>
			<plot>Chan Ka-Kui is Hong Kong's supercop, and he is going after the evil underground gang to take them down once and for all.</plot>
			<releasedate>1/1/1988</releasedate>
			<genre>Action</genre>
			<studio>Great</studio>
			<nplayers>1</nplayers>
			<boxart1>8bHhPhf.jpg</boxart1>
			<snapshot1>Mx4bFcl.png</snapshot1>
			<snapshot2>j7EhUat.png</snapshot2>
			<snapshot3>6lI18rs.png</snapshot3>
			<snapshot4>Gs4KaQM.png</snapshot4>
			<snapshot5>INpjzJf.png</snapshot5>
			<snapshot6>P4MJxn0.png</snapshot6>
			<snapshot7>IaS6rt0.png</snapshot7>
			<snapshot8>OzCSIuQ.png</snapshot8>
			<snapshot9>SlOLSzL.png</snapshot9>
			<snapshot10>u1k4N7c.png</snapshot10>
		</game>
		<game name="Gambler Jiko Chuushinha 2 - Jishou! Kyougou Janshi Hen (Japan)">
			<description>Gambler Jiko Chuushinha 2 - Jishou! Kyougou Janshi Hen (Japan)</description>
			<rom name="No-Intro-Collection_2016-09-06/Microsoft-Msx2.zip/Gambler%20Jiko%20Chuushinha%202%20-%20Jishou%21%20Kyougou%20Janshi%20Hen%20%28Japan%29.zip" size="138212" />
			<title_clean>Gambler Jiko Chuushinha 2 - Jishou! Kyougou Janshi Hen</title_clean>
			<plot>Gambler Jiko Chuushinha 2: Jisou! Kyougou Janshi Hen is a Board game, developed and published by Game Arts, which was released in Japan in 1989.</plot>
			<genre>Strategy</genre>
			<studio>Game Arts</studio>
			<nplayers>1</nplayers>
			<ESRB>Not Rated</ESRB>
			<boxart1>AzEQQey.jpg</boxart1>
			<boxart2>Bzt5d9X.jpg</boxart2>
			<snapshot1>H4jbQDn.png</snapshot1>
			<snapshot2>3H4GuJP.png</snapshot2>
			<snapshot3>aaf1dqw.png</snapshot3>
		</game>
		<game name="Ganbare Goemon! - Karakuri Douchuu (Japan)">
			<description>Ganbare Goemon! - Karakuri Douchuu (Japan)</description>
			<rom name="No-Intro-Collection_2016-09-06/Microsoft-Msx2.zip/Ganbare%20Goemon%21%20-%20Karakuri%20Douchuu%20%28Japan%29.zip" size="88182" />
			<title_clean>Ganbare Goemon! - Karakuri Douchuu</title_clean>
			<plot>The second game in the Ganbare Goemon series (known in English as Mystical Ninja) and the first released on a video game console and home computer. It was initially released for the Family Computer July 30, 1986[1] and later released for the MSX one year later.[CR]The game revolves around the main character, Goemon, and his exploits. As the name suggests, his character was based on Ishikawa Goemon, the noble thief of Japanese Folklore. Unlike its sequels, this game still doesn't feature the comic situation and strange characters that define the series, and Goemon is portrayed as a noble thief rather than a plain hero.[2][CR]The game plays a top view action/adventure game (similar to The Legend of Zelda) though it is separated by stages. In each level Goemon must find three passes in order to advance. Some of these passes are found in boxes, secret passages or can be bought. After finishing all the stages, the game will present you with a new Japanese province (eight total), but all the levels will remain the same. The ending, however, will be different.[CR]Like the rest of the series, Goemon can be powered up if certain items are found and/or bought, which can be lost after a few hits.[CR]The MSX version has the option to be played in turns by two players, with the second player playing as a ninja named Nezumi Koz&#333;, which is the basis of Goemon's sidekick Ebisumaru. In addition, unlike the Family Computer version, the game has six more provinces with completely new levels after finishing the game once.</plot>
			<releasedate>25/2/1987</releasedate>
			<year>1987</year>
			<genre>Action; Adventure</genre>
			<studio>Konami</studio>
			<nplayers>2</nplayers>
			<boxart1>JjFrbq5.jpg</boxart1>
			<boxart2>WNmTFgt.jpg</boxart2>
			<boxart3>WMxj0BS.jpg</boxart3>
			<snapshot1>l0bklY2.png</snapshot1>
			<snapshot2>ERX8nCY.png</snapshot2>
			<snapshot3>S3FnMpd.png</snapshot3>
			<fanart1>d6mPxqX.jpg</fanart1>
			<clearlogo1>Xpv9bgB.jpg</clearlogo1>
		</game>
		<game name="Garakuta (Japan)">
			<description>Garakuta (Japan)</description>
			<rom name="No-Intro-Collection_2016-09-06/Microsoft-Msx2.zip/Garakuta%20%28Japan%29.zip" size="22124" />
			<title_clean>Garakuta</title_clean>
			<plot>Arkanoid-style Breakout clone, which unlike most other similar games has the bat on the side of the screen (there is a left/right option) instead of at the bottom.There are a number of types of special bricks, but unlike e.g. Arkanoid, they do not fall towards the bat. Instead, when you hit a special brick, it flips to show a letter. E.g. E (Extend bat), C (Catch ball), M (Missile), B (Bomb, explodes when hit by ball, clearing a number of bricks) and X (Extra life).The enemies/obstacles are more varied than in Arkanoid. Some make the bat freeze, some actually chew and eat your ball and spit out the core back at you!</plot>
			<releasedate>1/1/1988</releasedate>
			<genre>Action</genre>
			<studio>Wachi Software</studio>
			<nplayers>1</nplayers>
			<boxart1>C0ZaT7V.jpg</boxart1>
			<boxart2>wcxyQOS.jpg</boxart2>
			<boxart3>qdx6SH5.jpg</boxart3>
			<boxart4>LEn0MNx.jpg</boxart4>
			<boxart5>p9wMDZV.jpg</boxart5>
			<boxart6>5ujQB9g.jpg</boxart6>
			<snapshot1>JNfEtuL.png</snapshot1>
			<snapshot2>SMUdZEw.png</snapshot2>
			<snapshot3>RR1MVJr.png</snapshot3>
			<snapshot4>VvM6T8k.png</snapshot4>
			<snapshot5>kMp9bmH.png</snapshot5>
			<snapshot6>8Uq5yuj.png</snapshot6>
			<snapshot7>xSugikG.png</snapshot7>
			<snapshot8>kfh7Q2F.png</snapshot8>
			<snapshot9>1nIqyFM.png</snapshot9>
			<snapshot10>nmFmHe7.png</snapshot10>
		</game>
		<game name="Garyuu Ou (Japan)">
			<description>Garyuu Ou (Japan)</description>
			<rom name="No-Intro-Collection_2016-09-06/Microsoft-Msx2.zip/Garyuu%20Ou%20%28Japan%29.zip" size="96911" />
			<title_clean>Garyuu Ou</title_clean>
			<plot>Arkanoid-style Breakout clone, which unlike most other similar games has the bat on the side of the screen (there is a left/right option) instead of at the bottom.There are a number of types of special bricks, but unlike e.g. Arkanoid, they do not fall towards the bat. Instead, when you hit a special brick, it flips to show a letter. E.g. E (Extend bat), C (Catch ball), M (Missile), B (Bomb, explodes when hit by ball, clearing a number of bricks) and X (Extra life).The enemies/obstacles are more varied than in Arkanoid. Some make the bat freeze, some actually chew and eat your ball and spit out the core back at you!</plot>
			<releasedate>1/1/1986</releasedate>
			<genre>Action</genre>
			<studio>&lt;cart2disk hack&gt;</studio>
			<nplayers>1</nplayers>
			<boxart1>C0ZaT7V.jpg</boxart1>
			<boxart2>wcxyQOS.jpg</boxart2>
			<boxart3>qdx6SH5.jpg</boxart3>
			<boxart4>LEn0MNx.jpg</boxart4>
			<boxart5>p9wMDZV.jpg</boxart5>
			<boxart6>5ujQB9g.jpg</boxart6>
			<snapshot1>JNfEtuL.png</snapshot1>
			<snapshot2>SMUdZEw.png</snapshot2>
			<snapshot3>RR1MVJr.png</snapshot3>
			<snapshot4>VvM6T8k.png</snapshot4>
			<snapshot5>kMp9bmH.png</snapshot5>
			<snapshot6>8Uq5yuj.png</snapshot6>
			<snapshot7>xSugikG.png</snapshot7>
			<snapshot8>kfh7Q2F.png</snapshot8>
			<snapshot9>1nIqyFM.png</snapshot9>
			<snapshot10>nmFmHe7.png</snapshot10>
		</game>
		<game name="Gekitotsu Pennant Race - Pro Yakyuu, The (Japan)">
			<description>Gekitotsu Pennant Race - Pro Yakyuu, The (Japan)</description>
			<rom name="No-Intro-Collection_2016-09-06/Microsoft-Msx2.zip/Gekitotsu%20Pennant%20Race%20-%20Pro%20Yakyuu%2C%20The%20%28Japan%29.zip" size="81752" />
			<title_clean>Gekitotsu Pennant Race - Pro Yakyuu, The</title_clean>
			<plot>The excitement of baseball returns to the MSX with Gekitotsu! Pennant Race 2! More teams, more stadiums, more excitement, more action!</plot>
			<releasedate>1/1/1988</releasedate>
			<genre>Sports</genre>
			<studio>Konami</studio>
			<nplayers>2</nplayers>
			<boxart1>YhH0ezD.jpg</boxart1>
			<snapshot1>XyhMyu2.png</snapshot1>
			<snapshot2>t2sAMQl.png</snapshot2>
			<snapshot3>GS5XizQ.png</snapshot3>
			<snapshot4>JomTBGe.png</snapshot4>
			<snapshot5>zfmqORc.png</snapshot5>
			<snapshot6>cN4ksnf.png</snapshot6>
			<snapshot7>uxhqSXd.png</snapshot7>
			<snapshot8>3Cpwcp3.png</snapshot8>
			<snapshot9>z4oQEUP.png</snapshot9>
			<snapshot10>d2VP9U8.png</snapshot10>
		</game>
		<game name="Gekitotsu Pennant Race 2 (Japan)">
			<description>Gekitotsu Pennant Race 2 (Japan)</description>
			<rom name="No-Intro-Collection_2016-09-06/Microsoft-Msx2.zip/Gekitotsu%20Pennant%20Race%202%20%28Japan%29.zip" size="90261" />
			<title_clean>Gekitotsu Pennant Race 2</title_clean>
			<plot>The excitement of baseball returns to the MSX with Gekitotsu! Pennant Race 2! More teams, more stadiums, more excitement, more action!</plot>
			<genre>Sports</genre>
			<studio>Konami</studio>
			<nplayers>2</nplayers>
			<ESRB>Not Rated</ESRB>
			<videoid>v32WRzFJbrI</videoid>
			<boxart1>nqvCRvi.jpg</boxart1>
			<boxart2>z9RZkcH.jpg</boxart2>
			<boxart3>YoZvYlJ.jpg</boxart3>
			<boxart4>TYs0Okf.png</boxart4>
			<snapshot1>kNCedHB.png</snapshot1>
			<snapshot2>zPqhjzg.png</snapshot2>
			<snapshot3>W4IHG00.png</snapshot3>
			<clearlogo1>sQuRgRd.png</clearlogo1>
			<clearlogo2>FhQyywE.png</clearlogo2>
		</game>
		<game name="Gekitotsu Pennant Race 2 (Japan) (English Menu)">
			<description>Gekitotsu Pennant Race 2 (Japan) (English Menu)</description>
			<rom name="No-Intro-Collection_2016-09-06/Microsoft-Msx2.zip/Gekitotsu%20Pennant%20Race%202%20%28Japan%29%20%28English%20Menu%29.zip" size="89957" />
			<title_clean>Gekitotsu Pennant Race 2</title_clean>
			<plot>The excitement of baseball returns to the MSX with Gekitotsu! Pennant Race 2! More teams, more stadiums, more excitement, more action!</plot>
			<genre>Sports</genre>
			<studio>Konami</studio>
			<nplayers>2</nplayers>
			<ESRB>Not Rated</ESRB>
			<videoid>v32WRzFJbrI</videoid>
			<boxart1>nqvCRvi.jpg</boxart1>
			<boxart2>z9RZkcH.jpg</boxart2>
			<boxart3>YoZvYlJ.jpg</boxart3>
			<boxart4>TYs0Okf.png</boxart4>
			<snapshot1>kNCedHB.png</snapshot1>
			<snapshot2>zPqhjzg.png</snapshot2>
			<snapshot3>W4IHG00.png</snapshot3>
			<clearlogo1>sQuRgRd.png</clearlogo1>
			<clearlogo2>FhQyywE.png</clearlogo2>
		</game>
		<game name="Girly Block (Japan)">
			<description>Girly Block (Japan)</description>
			<rom name="No-Intro-Collection_2016-09-06/Microsoft-Msx2.zip/Girly%20Block%20%28Japan%29.zip" size="54158" />
			<title_clean>Girly Block</title_clean>
			<plot>A supercomputer called "Omega" has kidnapped a valious asset. At your hands the most powerful unit to stand a chance to rescue her.</plot>
			<genre>Action</genre>
			<studio>Compile</studio>
			<nplayers>1</nplayers>
			<ESRB>Not Rated</ESRB>
			<videoid>lDn3Qmsmvt4</videoid>
			<boxart1>aQa3mmi.jpg</boxart1>
			<boxart2>QxqjHmr.jpg</boxart2>
			<boxart3>w9OkRm0.png</boxart3>
			<snapshot1>w4ieHeY.png</snapshot1>
			<snapshot2>q6GgpIN.png</snapshot2>
			<snapshot3>UuCWoyL.png</snapshot3>
			<snapshot4>MbK0n4x.png</snapshot4>
			<clearlogo1>uMpXmir.png</clearlogo1>
		</game>
		<game name="Hacker (Japan)">
			<description>Hacker (Japan)</description>
			<rom name="No-Intro-Collection_2016-09-06/Microsoft-Msx2.zip/Hacker%20%28Japan%29.zip" size="63413" />
			<title_clean>Hacker</title_clean>
			<plot>Hacker is an adventure/trading game based on what was then a unique idea. You're starting into the adventure as a real hacker would do, lacking information of what is to come, only driven by your ambition. Consequently, the game opens with a plain text screen, prompting you for the login password. To break into the system is the first puzzle you've got to solve.</plot>
			<genre>Adventure; Strategy</genre>
			<studio>Pony Canyon</studio>
			<nplayers>1</nplayers>
			<ESRB>Not Rated</ESRB>
			<videoid>QhZietiXxtc</videoid>
			<wiki_url>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hacker_(video_game)</wiki_url>
			<boxart1>xwgI4Yz.png</boxart1>
			<snapshot1>gy6n0vD.png</snapshot1>
			<snapshot2>FtRYLlL.png</snapshot2>
			<snapshot3>ulSaWZI.png</snapshot3>
		</game>
		<game name="Hai no Majutsushi (Japan)">
			<description>Hai no Majutsushi (Japan)</description>
			<rom name="No-Intro-Collection_2016-09-06/Microsoft-Msx2.zip/Hai%20no%20Majutsushi%20%28Japan%29.zip" size="81265" />
			<title_clean>Hai no Majutsushi</title_clean>
			<plot>Hai no Majutsushi is an implementation of Mahjong tile game. The opponents in the game are characters from Konami's popular franchises: Simon Belmont from Castlevania series, Aphrodite and Poporon (Popolon) from Knightmare series, a snatcher from Snatcher, Dr. Venom from Gradius series, Goemon from Ganbare Goemon series, Penta the penguin from Antarctic Adventure series, and Moai from Gradius / Parodius series.</plot>
			<genre>Strategy</genre>
			<studio>Konami</studio>
			<nplayers>1</nplayers>
			<ESRB>Not Rated</ESRB>
			<videoid>41UqUz0O-ZM</videoid>
			<wiki_url>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_Konami_games#MSX2</wiki_url>
			<boxart1>jN5DtzH.jpg</boxart1>
			<boxart2>vfhYSpN.jpg</boxart2>
			<boxart3>xoUtmDm.jpg</boxart3>
			<snapshot1>cuRKia4.png</snapshot1>
			<snapshot2>2K19naL.png</snapshot2>
			<snapshot3>DYBktOY.png</snapshot3>
			<snapshot4>BPF3fGY.png</snapshot4>
		</game>
		<game name="Han Seimei Senki Andorogynus (Japan)">
			<description>Han Seimei Senki Andorogynus (Japan)</description>
			<rom name="No-Intro-Collection_2016-09-06/Microsoft-Msx2.zip/Han%20Seimei%20Senki%20Andorogynus%20%28Japan%29.zip" size="162984" />
			<title_clean>Han Seimei Senki Andorogynus</title_clean>
			<plot>In our universe matter and anti-matter co-exist with each other. However, prevalence of anti-matter may create chaos and eventually disrupt the normal flow of things. In a corner of a universe, a concentration of anti-matter led to the creation of an entire star, breeding forms of life threatening to destroy the world. Human beings, in an effort to save the universe, created the powerful Andorogynus - a life form capable of being male and female at once - and sent it on a mission to destroy the creation of anti-matter.Andorogynus (sic) is a top-down shoot-em-up. The player controls the titular hero(ine), shooting at constantly attacking enemies. Unlike in most games of the type, the screen scrolls down rather than up. The protagonist is equipped with a default single shot and has protective orbs revolving around that damage nearby enemies. The weapon can be enhanced (rapid fire, three-way fire, etc.) by collecting randomly descending power-ups. The player controls the male incarnation of the protagonist initially, but later switches to the female one.</plot>
			<releasedate>1/1/1986</releasedate>
			<genre>Action</genre>
			<studio>&lt;cart2disk hack&gt;</studio>
			<boxart1>RyPlw3F.png</boxart1>
			<snapshot1>QcjUYT5.png</snapshot1>
			<snapshot2>Cqc0aHw.png</snapshot2>
		</game>
		<game name="Hard Ball (Japan)">
			<description>Hard Ball (Japan)</description>
			<rom name="No-Intro-Collection_2016-09-06/Microsoft-Msx2.zip/Hard%20Ball%20%28Japan%29.zip" size="42716" />
			<title_clean>Hard Ball</title_clean>
			<plot>Hard Ball is a baseball game for one or two players. You can throw a variety of pitches from fast balls to curve balls, steal bases, select team members, and substitute players as the game is played.</plot>
			<genre>Sports</genre>
			<studio>Sony</studio>
			<nplayers>2</nplayers>
			<ESRB>Not Rated</ESRB>
			<videoid>UkUbnht08Nw</videoid>
			<wiki_url>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/HardBall!</wiki_url>
			<boxart1>1pCHeOr.jpg</boxart1>
			<boxart2>tPisTqJ.jpg</boxart2>
			<boxart3>u7kpioN.png</boxart3>
			<snapshot1>Ec4trX8.png</snapshot1>
			<snapshot2>yFug31a.png</snapshot2>
			<snapshot3>4AZCd7k.png</snapshot3>
			<snapshot4>1VCmJpP.png</snapshot4>
			<clearlogo1>798a8e2.png</clearlogo1>
		</game>
		<game name="Heroes of the Lance (Japan)">
			<description>Heroes of the Lance (Japan)</description>
			<rom name="No-Intro-Collection_2016-09-06/Microsoft-Msx2.zip/Heroes%20of%20the%20Lance%20%28Japan%29.zip" size="295514" />
			<title_clean>Heroes of the Lance</title_clean>
			<plot>Based on the later parts of the Dragonlance book Dragons of Autumn Twilight, the heroes descend into a ruined city in search of the disks of Mishakal.The gameplay consists of horizontal fighting with a maze like map using doors to change the view.  The party consists of the 8 Heroes of the Lance, using one at a time and the player can switch between them at any time.  Each character has different types of attacks and spells making them more suited to fighting different enemies as well as acting as lives.One of the AD&amp;D games that takes a break from the usual RPG style.</plot>
			<releasedate>1/1/1986</releasedate>
			<genre>Action</genre>
			<studio>&lt;cart2disk hack&gt;</studio>
			<boxart1>22Xn0uT.png</boxart1>
			<snapshot1>tRWscPQ.png</snapshot1>
			<snapshot2>Ws9JZxD.png</snapshot2>
			<snapshot3>VE3EN3y.png</snapshot3>
			<snapshot4>AmR4sT9.png</snapshot4>
			<snapshot5>j4ACXwZ.png</snapshot5>
			<snapshot6>HeMixkd.png</snapshot6>
			<snapshot7>ZfEzVV1.png</snapshot7>
			<snapshot8>OVXBsgI.png</snapshot8>
			<snapshot9>kRr13vP.png</snapshot9>
			<snapshot10>s35ebWN.png</snapshot10>
		</game>
		<game name="Higemaru Makai Shima - Nanatsu no Shima Daibouken (Japan)">
			<description>Higemaru Makai Shima - Nanatsu no Shima Daibouken (Japan)</description>
			<rom name="No-Intro-Collection_2016-09-06/Microsoft-Msx2.zip/Higemaru%20Makai%20Shima%20-%20Nanatsu%20no%20Shima%20Daibouken%20%28Japan%29.zip" size="82591" />
			<title_clean>Higemaru Makai Shima - Nanatsu no Shima Daibouken</title_clean>
			<plot>Taking the basic concept of Pirate Ship Higemaru, the Arcade game on which it is based, and expandings on it, is an adventure game as expansive and in-depth as the Legend of Zelda.[CR]The goal is to sail around until the player finds a pirate ship (the friendly green merchant ships will simply provide hints) and clear the boss. Doing so will allow the player to collect a port key which allows them to set anchor on one of the titular seven islands. The player must then remove the boss of that island and recover the treasure. At which point, the process must be repeated.</plot>
			<genre>Action</genre>
			<studio>Capcom</studio>
			<nplayers>1</nplayers>
			<ESRB>Not Rated</ESRB>
			<videoid>pugdmbNq2tA</videoid>
			<wiki_url>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Higemaru_Makaijima_-_Nanatsu_no_Shima_Daib%C5%8Dken</wiki_url>
			<boxart1>buB5zpL.jpg</boxart1>
			<boxart2>wYuzX9X.jpg</boxart2>
			<boxart3>wRDTLym.png</boxart3>
			<snapshot1>kxQtkZW.png</snapshot1>
			<snapshot2>dzsxSq3.png</snapshot2>
			<snapshot3>OpcatYz.png</snapshot3>
			<snapshot4>hmYan5y.png</snapshot4>
			<fanart1>hLbf26D.jpg</fanart1>
		</game>
		<game name="High School! Kimengumi (Japan)">
			<description>High School! Kimengumi (Japan)</description>
			<rom name="No-Intro-Collection_2016-09-06/Microsoft-Msx2.zip/High%20School%21%20Kimengumi%20%28Japan%29.zip" size="61213" />
			<title_clean>High School! Kimengumi</title_clean>
			<plot>Adventure game based on the manga by Motoei Shinzawa with the same name.</plot>
			<genre>Adventure</genre>
			<studio>Pony Canyon</studio>
			<nplayers>1</nplayers>
			<ESRB>Not Rated</ESRB>
			<videoid>yVTDM6C4RLc</videoid>
			<wiki_url>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/High_School!_Kimengumi#Games</wiki_url>
			<boxart1>THa4C2W.png</boxart1>
			<snapshot1>gmWBHHb.png</snapshot1>
			<snapshot2>Vk01Gqj.png</snapshot2>
			<snapshot3>jowJLfM.png</snapshot3>
			<snapshot4>G1DOwRO.png</snapshot4>
			<snapshot5>rru55on.jpg</snapshot5>
			<fanart1>EOR7m3X.jpg</fanart1>
		</game>
		<game name="Hinotori - Houou Hen (Japan)">
			<description>Hinotori - Houou Hen (Japan)</description>
			<rom name="No-Intro-Collection_2016-09-06/Microsoft-Msx2.zip/Hinotori%20-%20Houou%20Hen%20%28Japan%29.zip" size="91465" />
			<title_clean>Hinotori - Houou Hen</title_clean>
			<plot>Based on the "Ho-o" (or "Karma" volume) of Osamu Tezuka's famous manga Hi no tori (or "Phoenix"), "Hi no tori Hououhen" is a vertically-scrolling shooting game where Gaou's goal is to locate the mystical phoenix across 6 stages of labyrinths, enemies and various other obstacles. As the game progresses, Gaou can power up by obtaining phoenix plumes to activate special weapons and other items to help him gain abilities such as invulnerability and special shots. In order to reach the final boss and pay a visit to the phoenix, Gaou must obtain a series of keys scattered across the stages - and must even backtrack to find others. The game is over when all three lives are gone - or when Gaou has reached the phoenix's lair.</plot>
			<genre>Shooter</genre>
			<studio>Konami</studio>
			<nplayers>1</nplayers>
			<ESRB>Not Rated</ESRB>
			<videoid>Njs2rokFnIA</videoid>
			<wiki_url>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hi_no_Tori_Hououhen_(MSX)</wiki_url>
			<boxart1>tDQ8Rh6.jpg</boxart1>
			<boxart2>rdHwzl9.jpg</boxart2>
			<boxart3>BbGVF6G.jpg</boxart3>
			<snapshot1>HiGSmj5.png</snapshot1>
			<snapshot2>VJjz841.png</snapshot2>
			<snapshot3>a7s0cLB.png</snapshot3>
			<clearlogo1>tRsoZiV.png</clearlogo1>
		</game>
		<game name="Hole in One Special (Japan)">
			<description>Hole in One Special (Japan)</description>
			<rom name="No-Intro-Collection_2016-09-06/Microsoft-Msx2.zip/Hole%20in%20One%20Special%20%28Japan%29.zip" size="67449" />
			<title_clean>Hole in One Special</title_clean>
			<plot>After the huge success of the first two releases HAL Laboratory released a third golf simulation game. Again it is a standard 18-hole golf game, played from a top-down perspective. Hole In One Special can be played up to two players at three difficulty levels: average, expert and pro. You can compete in stroke play, match play and tournament play. The tournament play can be set at one to four days.[CR]During the game the following options can be changed: the direction of the ball, pick a club, set the curve of the ball and the stroke power.[CR]The main difference with the other two releases in the Hole In One series for MSX is that Hole In One Special makes full use of the MSX2 graphical capabilities and can only be played on MSX2 computers.</plot>
			<genre>Sports</genre>
			<studio>HAL Laboratory</studio>
			<nplayers>2</nplayers>
			<ESRB>Not Rated</ESRB>
			<videoid>-Hyj7VF2vt8</videoid>
			<boxart1>NflxJHV.jpg</boxart1>
			<boxart2>q8ETVdu.png</boxart2>
			<snapshot1>dT1w7iY.png</snapshot1>
			<snapshot2>pVU1AOE.png</snapshot2>
			<snapshot3>1b8vH5n.png</snapshot3>
			<clearlogo1>IhSXFpy.png</clearlogo1>
		</game>
		<game name="Hydlide 3 - The Space Memories (Japan)">
			<description>Hydlide 3 - The Space Memories (Japan)</description>
			<rom name="No-Intro-Collection_2016-09-06/Microsoft-Msx2.zip/Hydlide%203%20-%20The%20Space%20Memories%20%28Japan%29.zip" size="250078" />
			<title_clean>Hydlide 3 - The Space Memories</title_clean>
			<plot>The third entry in the Hydlide series, continuing its action RPG legacy. Character creation allows the player to choose one of the four character classes: Warrior, Thief, Priest, and Monk. In combat, the protagonist uses melee or long-ranged weapons or casts magic spells. Unlike the previous games in the series, the player is required to press the attack button during melee combat, instead of simply "bumping" into the enemies. There is an internal clock in the game, which makes it necessary for the protagonist to sleep periodically and regain his strength. The main character also has to eat from time to time, otherwise his hit points will gradually decrease. The morality system from the previous game returns: killing friendly creatures will reduce the player's morality level, which will eventually have an effect on one of the game's most decisive battles.</plot>
			<genre>Driving, Racing</genre>
			<studio>T&amp;E Soft</studio>
			<nplayers>1</nplayers>
			<ESRB>Not Rated</ESRB>
			<boxart1>gm4MECc.jpg</boxart1>
			<boxart2>rKe5KOg.png</boxart2>
			<snapshot1>n88BTg3.png</snapshot1>
			<snapshot2>BV3vJXp.png</snapshot2>
		</game>
		<game name="Ide Yousuke Meijin no Jissen Mahjong (Japan)">
			<description>Ide Yousuke Meijin no Jissen Mahjong (Japan)</description>
			<rom name="No-Intro-Collection_2016-09-06/Microsoft-Msx2.zip/Ide%20Yousuke%20Meijin%20no%20Jissen%20Mahjong%20%28Japan%29.zip" size="64166" />
			<title_clean>Ide Yousuke Meijin no Jissen Mahjong</title_clean>
			<plot>Originally released for Famicom in 1987, Ide Yousuke Meijin no Jissen Mahjong made its way to MSX2 one year later, thanks to the good folks at Pack-In-Video. The game is identical to its Famicom counterpart and features some solid 1v1 mahjong action.</plot>
			<genre>Strategy</genre>
			<studio>Capcom</studio>
			<nplayers>1</nplayers>
			<ESRB>Not Rated</ESRB>
			<boxart1>3luL3Ai.jpg</boxart1>
			<boxart2>AwDwrdw.jpg</boxart2>
			<boxart3>d8Q31mp.png</boxart3>
			<snapshot1>bSchuFZ.png</snapshot1>
			<snapshot2>3eYtwES.png</snapshot2>
		</game>
		<game name="Ikari (Japan)">
			<description>Ikari (Japan)</description>
			<rom name="No-Intro-Collection_2016-09-06/Microsoft-Msx2.zip/Ikari%20%28Japan%29.zip" size="71198" />
			<title_clean>Ikari</title_clean>
			<plot>Better known as Ikari Warriors in the west, Ikari is a vertically scrolling action game where one or two players fight their way through a variety of terrain, such as jungles, rivers, and ruins. Along the way different weapons can be found, including machine guns, grenades, and rocket launchers.</plot>
			<genre>Action; Shooter</genre>
			<studio>SNK</studio>
			<nplayers>1-2 Co-Op</nplayers>
			<ESRB>Not Rated</ESRB>
			<videoid>DLHCrrvVEw0</videoid>
			<wiki_url>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ikari_Warriors</wiki_url>
			<boxart1>KMAZ8Vj.jpg</boxart1>
			<boxart2>o4ddrE6.jpg</boxart2>
			<boxart3>SNbaSTn.jpg</boxart3>
			<snapshot1>m7zm45Z.png</snapshot1>
			<snapshot2>J4mM9B9.png</snapshot2>
			<clearlogo1>8MnbZEH.png</clearlogo1>
		</game>
		<game name="Inemuriryuu Asada Tetsuya no A-kyuu Mahjong (Japan)">
			<description>Inemuriryuu Asada Tetsuya no A-kyuu Mahjong (Japan)</description>
			<rom name="No-Intro-Collection_2016-09-06/Microsoft-Msx2.zip/Inemuriryuu%20Asada%20Tetsuya%20no%20A-kyuu%20Mahjong%20%28Japan%29.zip" size="63013" />
			<title_clean>Inemuriryuu Asada Tetsuya no A-kyuu Mahjong</title_clean>
			<plot>Inemuri Ryuu Adada Tetsuya no A-Kyuu Mahjong is a Board game, developed and published by Pony Canyon, which was released in Japan in 1988.</plot>
			<genre>Strategy</genre>
			<studio>Pony Canyon</studio>
			<nplayers>1</nplayers>
			<ESRB>Not Rated</ESRB>
			<boxart1>Nyx3FDD.png</boxart1>
			<boxart2>lV4AHlX.png</boxart2>
			<snapshot1>b8Sljxo.png</snapshot1>
			<snapshot2>apMG32m.png</snapshot2>
			<snapshot3>MBZ77BF.png</snapshot3>
		</game>
		<game name="Inindou - Datou Nobunaga (Japan)">
			<description>Inindou - Datou Nobunaga (Japan)</description>
			<rom name="No-Intro-Collection_2016-09-06/Microsoft-Msx2.zip/Inindou%20-%20Datou%20Nobunaga%20%28Japan%29.zip" size="497832" />
			<title_clean>Inindou - Datou Nobunaga</title_clean>
			<plot>1581, Japan. Fearing a rebellion and striving to conquer the entire country, the warlock Nobunaga orders to attack the Iga ninja clan. The ninjas bravely defend their village, but, being vastly outnumbered, are mercilessly slain by Nobunaga's men. Only one survived: you, the hero of the game. Shortly before the assault you were sent to a nearby village to warn the elder of Nobunaga's attack. However, the other village is also destroyed by Nobunaga's army. You swear to avenge his crime. But for now, you are just an inexperienced young men, and are "wanted" by Nobunaga's men and ruthless bounty hunters. Will you be able to unite Japan in the ultimate struggle against Nobunaga?[CR]Inindo: Way of the Ninja is a Japanese-style RPG with a touch of strategy. You navigate your hero on the world map, visit towns, and descend into dungeons. The battles are turn-based and are viewed from a third-person perspective, like in Final Fantasy games. You can move on the battle field and use melee or long-ranged attacks. You'll be able to recruit characters of various classes to your party, who will join you for profit or for other reasons. After you gain enough experience, you'll also be able to talk to daimyos (feudal rulers) of various castles and to convince them to work together against Nobunaga. You can also perform various tasks for the daimyos, such as spying.</plot>
			<genre>Role-Playing; Strategy</genre>
			<studio>Koei</studio>
			<nplayers>1</nplayers>
			<ESRB>Not Rated</ESRB>
			<boxart1>gFZSjWr.jpg</boxart1>
			<boxart2>rPpb3Ne.jpg</boxart2>
			<boxart3>Kt7YIG8.jpg</boxart3>
			<snapshot1>dFJWD5p.png</snapshot1>
			<snapshot2>VwDj5UG.png</snapshot2>
			<snapshot3>Ep7oZO6.png</snapshot3>
		</game>
		<game name="Ishin no Arashi (Japan)">
			<description>Ishin no Arashi (Japan)</description>
			<rom name="No-Intro-Collection_2016-09-06/Microsoft-Msx2.zip/Ishin%20no%20Arashi%20%28Japan%29.zip" size="282019" />
			<title_clean>Ishin no Arashi</title_clean>
			<plot>Ishin no Arashi is set during Bakumatsu period (around 1850 until the Meiji Restoration of 1867), the final stretch of the Japanese Edo period, which was a turbulent time, a time of great struggle between the supporters of the feudal shoguns, the rulers of the country, and the adherents of the Emperor, which eventually won and carried through the Meiji Restoration, turning Japan into a modern, powerful state. In Ishin no Arashi the player can choose one of the three major battles of Bakumastu period, and decide which leader will eventually propel Japan towards the Meiji era.[CR]This strategy game is somewhat similar to the better-known Romance of the Three Kingdoms series and other historical simulation games by the same company, but also differs from them by having much less complex diplomacy options and focusing the gameplay on navigation and individual encounters. Before beginning, the player chooses a general and customizes his parameters (stamina, attack power, charisma, knowledge). The player then controls the general with soldiers of his choice, navigating him on grids representing towns and countryside of Japan in turn-based fashion. The grids can be occupied by shops, schools (to train the general), friendly and hostile characters and groups. Battles, as well as negotiations and diplomatic procedures, are carried out automatically, and their outcome depends on the characters' statistics.</plot>
			<genre>Strategy</genre>
			<studio>Koei</studio>
			<nplayers>1</nplayers>
			<ESRB>Not Rated</ESRB>
			<boxart1>FHyxpKe.jpg</boxart1>
			<boxart2>H9e7Qnk.jpg</boxart2>
			<boxart3>anTwCLF.jpg</boxart3>
			<boxart4>lEuvfzR.jpg</boxart4>
			<snapshot1>dgJbpQg.png</snapshot1>
			<snapshot2>XkXnR6b.png</snapshot2>
		</game>
		<game name="Jansei (Japan)">
			<description>Jansei (Japan)</description>
			<rom name="No-Intro-Collection_2016-09-06/Microsoft-Msx2.zip/Jansei%20%28Japan%29.zip" size="53687" />
			<title_clean>Jansei</title_clean>
			<plot>Jansei is a Board game, developed and published by Sony, which was released in Japan in 1986.</plot>
			<genre>Strategy</genre>
			<studio>Sony</studio>
			<nplayers>1</nplayers>
			<ESRB>Not Rated</ESRB>
			<boxart1>gwuEc9l.jpg</boxart1>
			<boxart2>cAQS3k0.jpg</boxart2>
			<boxart3>bNPiOky.jpg</boxart3>
			<snapshot1>qgBJ4V7.png</snapshot1>
			<snapshot2>WvSlG7h.png</snapshot2>
		</game>
		<game name="Kempelen Chess (Japan)">
			<description>Kempelen Chess (Japan)</description>
			<rom name="No-Intro-Collection_2016-09-06/Microsoft-Msx2.zip/Kempelen%20Chess%20%28Japan%29.zip" size="69687" />
			<title_clean>Kempelen Chess</title_clean>
			<plot>Kempelen Chess is a computer chess game with a top-down view but with a 3D-feel. It includes various boards and play options. You can choose to play at one of the seven different difficulty levels. Chess can be played against the computer or a friend. All pieces are animated when moved.</plot>
			<genre>Strategy</genre>
			<studio>Andromeda Software</studio>
			<nplayers>2</nplayers>
			<ESRB>Not Rated</ESRB>
			<boxart1>2IE8qxL.jpg</boxart1>
			<snapshot1>M6R8u41.png</snapshot1>
			<snapshot2>dysrjy1.png</snapshot2>
			<snapshot3>35a13hd.png</snapshot3>
		</game>
		<game name="Kikikai-kai (Japan)">
			<description>Kikikai-kai (Japan)</description>
			<rom name="No-Intro-Collection_2016-09-06/Microsoft-Msx2.zip/Kikikai-kai%20%28Japan%29.zip" size="56380" />
			<title_clean>Kikikai-kai</title_clean>
			<plot>The youngest child of a mysteriously disappeared family didn't join the family on a journey to a far and unknown place to board an odd ark because she had to keep on cultivating their land. An humble peasant spread the word: a creature coming from the underworld took away the ark!The girl must have been touched by the hand of luck... and she alone is the only one who can save and take them safely back home.You can move around in eight directions, trying to defend yourself against the attacks of creatures coming from the underworld.You can defend yourself by means of scrolls with obscure magician runes, throwing cards and other weapons to be picked up en route.The magic cards and magic spells have a limited range or last only for a short period of time but can be powered up by collecting the runes found after destroying a formation of red flames-shaped enemies or waving an black and white flag.Several items (mostly pearls) will be found along the way and can be picked up and used to defeat the enemy creatures.A round consist of multiple scenes (areas) and each scene is completed when the Scene Guard has been defeated and when a round is completed one family member will be free and return safely home...</plot>
			<releasedate>1/1/1986</releasedate>
			<genre>Action</genre>
			<studio>Sony</studio>
			<nplayers>1</nplayers>
			<boxart1>HRvGtW5.jpg</boxart1>
			<snapshot1>keRhvPN.png</snapshot1>
			<snapshot2>0wedwy3.png</snapshot2>
			<snapshot3>a5KTuy0.png</snapshot3>
			<snapshot4>IJxfsDY.png</snapshot4>
			<snapshot5>3pvPuvo.png</snapshot5>
			<snapshot6>6VtHqGV.png</snapshot6>
			<snapshot7>leDb8Km.png</snapshot7>
			<snapshot8>P2qmxjz.png</snapshot8>
			<snapshot9>CV0ftZs.png</snapshot9>
			<snapshot10>rIskTBK.png</snapshot10>
		</game>
		<game name="King Kong 2 - Yomigaeru Densetsu (Japan)">
			<description>King Kong 2 - Yomigaeru Densetsu (Japan)</description>
			<rom name="No-Intro-Collection_2016-09-06/Microsoft-Msx2.zip/King%20Kong%202%20-%20Yomigaeru%20Densetsu%20%28Japan%29.zip" size="85013" />
			<title_clean>King Kong 2 - Yomigaeru Densetsu</title_clean>
			<plot>Based on King Kong Lives movie King Kong 2: Yomigaeru Densetsu is an action game with puzzle-solving and role-play elements, a more complex experience compared to Famicom version of King Kong 2.[CR]You play as Mitchel (Hank Mitchell from the movie) who travels to Golnebo Isle in search of Lady Kong, the only creature whose blood can save King Kong, seriously wounded in the end of the first movie. Exploring the island Mitchel will fight enemies with melee weapons and magic scrolls and gain experience points. With enough experience he levels up and gets increase in strength, speed, health and magic points. By entering certain buildings Mitchel can engage in conversations, buy weapons or healing items and rest. In conversations Mitchel will also get hints needed to solve some puzzles. The game has several endings depending on how long it took the player to beat it (game time is measured in days) and how many continues were used.</plot>
			<genre>RPG</genre>
			<studio>Konami</studio>
			<nplayers>1</nplayers>
			<ESRB>Not Rated</ESRB>
			<boxart1>Yh8Sp0l.jpg</boxart1>
			<boxart2>OQJeAQh.jpg</boxart2>
			<boxart3>C1x4Ri6.jpg</boxart3>
			<snapshot1>XpCwfua.png</snapshot1>
			<snapshot2>LxlDxHy.png</snapshot2>
			<snapshot3>oTUoyi5.png</snapshot3>
			<fanart1>LwAH9dY.jpg</fanart1>
			<clearlogo1>7XwPpSZ.png</clearlogo1>
			<clearlogo2>7tCPaFa.png</clearlogo2>
		</game>
		<game name="Kisei (Japan)">
			<description>Kisei (Japan)</description>
			<rom name="No-Intro-Collection_2016-09-06/Microsoft-Msx2.zip/Kisei%20%28Japan%29.zip" size="44065" />
			<title_clean>Kisei</title_clean>
			<plot>Kisei is a Board game, developed by Shogi Master and published by Sony, which was released in Japan in 1987.</plot>
			<genre>Strategy</genre>
			<studio>Shogi Master</studio>
			<nplayers>1</nplayers>
			<ESRB>Not Rated</ESRB>
			<boxart1>2JXJFfF.jpg</boxart1>
			<boxart2>mg0QHUb.jpg</boxart2>
			<boxart3>8lKgGBq.jpg</boxart3>
			<snapshot1>Y7KzmJv.png</snapshot1>
			<snapshot2>tw0RNmI.png</snapshot2>
		</game>
		<game name="Kitahei (Japan)">
			<description>Kitahei (Japan)</description>
			<rom name="No-Intro-Collection_2016-09-06/Microsoft-Msx2.zip/Kitahei%20%28Japan%29.zip" size="31846" />
			<title_clean>Kitahei</title_clean>
			<plot>Kitahei is a computer version of the ancient Japanese game shogi, which is a board game that plays much like chess. You can play it against the computer or another player. You can also save your progress to disk to come back to the game later.</plot>
			<genre>Strategy</genre>
			<studio>Micro Cabin</studio>
			<nplayers>2</nplayers>
			<ESRB>Not Rated</ESRB>
			<boxart1>vPk5rDh.jpg</boxart1>
			<boxart2>IVkWjCF.jpg</boxart2>
			<boxart3>cWnd6YA.jpg</boxart3>
			<boxart4>fMyl8Mw.jpg</boxart4>
			<snapshot1>gnn0GDR.png</snapshot1>
			<snapshot2>5d8zel5.png</snapshot2>
		</game>
		<game name="Koronis Rift (Europe)">
			<description>Koronis Rift (Europe)</description>
			<rom name="No-Intro-Collection_2016-09-06/Microsoft-Msx2.zip/Koronis%20Rift%20%28Europe%29.zip" size="76172" />
			<title_clean>Koronis Rift</title_clean>
			<plot>You play as a techno scavenger in the year 2049, exploring the Koronis Rift, the Ancients abandoned the planet, leaving behind many different artifacts and ships, which you can loot. Send your droid to retrieve modules and try to figure out what the ancient technology is for. It could be batteries, shields or even weapons, to help you fight the trigger-happy saucers that want you dead.[CR]The game uses fractal graphics, the terrain is vast and detailed, and the story behind it is quite complex, considering the type of game.</plot>
			<genre>Action; Strategy</genre>
			<studio>Mr. Micro</studio>
			<nplayers>1</nplayers>
			<ESRB>Not Rated</ESRB>
			<wiki_url>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Koronis_Rift</wiki_url>
			<boxart1>kd9X0LR.png</boxart1>
			<snapshot1>eL8fSDh.png</snapshot1>
			<snapshot2>pYR8OLG.png</snapshot2>
			<clearlogo1>X8NMl5B.png</clearlogo1>
		</game>
		<game name="Labyrinth (Japan)">
			<description>Labyrinth (Japan)</description>
			<rom name="No-Intro-Collection_2016-09-06/Microsoft-Msx2.zip/Labyrinth%20%28Japan%29.zip" size="120315" />
			<title_clean>Labyrinth</title_clean>
			<plot>The player starts this game off controlling the actions of an ordinary citizen on their way to a movie theater. In the south cinema, the player chats with two teenagers about the actual movie at which point a hush descends upon the room and the in-game film begins...where the player learns that they have been chosen to be the thrall of Jareth the Goblin King, who must be overcome to finish the game. A clock ticks down 13 meager hours to complete this task, lest the player's character end up lost in the labyrinth forever.</plot>
			<genre>Action; Adventure</genre>
			<studio>Pack-In-Video</studio>
			<nplayers>1</nplayers>
			<ESRB>Not Rated</ESRB>
			<videoid>kFYKwC3g4tw</videoid>
			<wiki_url>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Labyrinth:_The_Computer_Game</wiki_url>
			<boxart1>v1KaUNy.png</boxart1>
			<boxart2>AynZD2V.jpg</boxart2>
			<snapshot1>CbTH7ix.png</snapshot1>
			<snapshot2>8hS1RJw.png</snapshot2>
			<fanart1>uJNXcTe.jpg</fanart1>
		</game>
		<game name="Lupin Sansei - Babylon no Ougon Densetsu (Japan)">
			<description>Lupin Sansei - Babylon no Ougon Densetsu (Japan)</description>
			<rom name="No-Intro-Collection_2016-09-06/Microsoft-Msx2.zip/Lupin%20Sansei%20-%20Babylon%20no%20Ougon%20Densetsu%20%28Japan%29.zip" size="54526" />
			<title_clean>Lupin Sansei - Babylon no Ougon Densetsu</title_clean>
			<plot>A Lupin III adventure game inspired by the same title anime movie</plot>
			<genre>Adventure; Platform</genre>
			<studio>Toho</studio>
			<nplayers>1</nplayers>
			<ESRB>Not Rated</ESRB>
			<boxart1>8G5Xg7g.jpg</boxart1>
			<snapshot1>HdTkKLp.png</snapshot1>
			<snapshot2>wSd8w3e.png</snapshot2>
			<fanart1>DN3agBB.jpg</fanart1>
			<fanart2>Lkv3ujX.jpg</fanart2>
		</game>
		<game name="Lupin Sansei - Cagliostro no Shiro (Japan)">
			<description>Lupin Sansei - Cagliostro no Shiro (Japan)</description>
			<rom name="No-Intro-Collection_2016-09-06/Microsoft-Msx2.zip/Lupin%20Sansei%20-%20Cagliostro%20no%20Shiro%20%28Japan%29.zip" size="71269" />
			<title_clean>Lupin Sansei - Cagliostro no Shiro</title_clean>
			<plot>A video game adaption of Hayao Miyazaki's Lupin III anime film of the same name.</plot>
			<genre>Adventure; Platform</genre>
			<studio>Toho</studio>
			<nplayers>1</nplayers>
			<ESRB>Not Rated</ESRB>
			<boxart1>vSdwVj0.png</boxart1>
			<snapshot1>DCJfDct.png</snapshot1>
			<snapshot2>VlJR87N.png</snapshot2>
			<fanart1>0F8cB9d.jpg</fanart1>
		</game>
		<game name="Mad Rider (Japan)">
			<description>Mad Rider (Japan)</description>
			<rom name="No-Intro-Collection_2016-09-06/Microsoft-Msx2.zip/Mad%20Rider%20%28Japan%29.zip" size="57042" />
			<title_clean>Mad Rider</title_clean>
			<plot>Racing game against the clock. At the beginning you can select between six courses (Megacity, Plateau, Alps, Island, Egyptian and Canyon). You're driving a red sports car, and need to avoid other drivers and obstacles. You don't race other drivers. If you hit objects you tend to explode, apart from water, oil and Motor Cyclists where you spin out and can regain control.</plot>
			<genre>Driving, Racing</genre>
			<studio>Carry Lab</studio>
			<nplayers>1</nplayers>
			<ESRB>Not Rated</ESRB>
			<boxart1>dJqPg7x.jpg</boxart1>
			<boxart2>Q3n5t9d.jpg</boxart2>
			<boxart3>RyTgzcX.jpg</boxart3>
			<boxart4>QVwkCn7.jpg</boxart4>
			<snapshot1>Y4PzFnB.png</snapshot1>
			<snapshot2>nycavhC.png</snapshot2>
			<snapshot3>tH5HcQl.png</snapshot3>
			<snapshot4>PxJy3hC.png</snapshot4>
		</game>
		<game name="Maison Ikkoku - Kanketsu Hen - Sayonara, Soshite... (Japan)">
			<description>Maison Ikkoku - Kanketsu Hen - Sayonara, Soshite... (Japan)</description>
			<rom name="No-Intro-Collection_2016-09-06/Microsoft-Msx2.zip/Maison%20Ikkoku%20-%20Kanketsu%20Hen%20-%20Sayonara%2C%20Soshite...%20%28Japan%29.zip" size="424495" />
			<title_clean>Maison Ikkoku - Kanketsu Hen - Sayonara, Soshite...</title_clean>
			<plot>The game is based on the manga Maison Ikkoku by Rumiko Takahashi.[CR]Set in Tokyo of the 80's, the story can be described as a romantic tale with a touch of comedy. It centers on a boarding house which is managed by the young and lovely widow Kyoko Otonashi. The protagonist is a college student named Yusaki Godai, and his relationship with Kyoko is the main plot line. The game's story approximately corresponds to the middle volumes of the manga until the conclusion.[CR]The game is a "puzzle-less" adventure, the gameplay mostly focusing on simply depleting all the verb commands at every given screen and moving between locations. The commands include the usual "Look", "Talk", and Move" typical for Japanese adventures (no "Think" command), but also context-sensitive commands "Eat", "Drink", etc., as well as the possibility to use certain inventory items.</plot>
			<genre>Adventure</genre>
			<studio>Micro Cabin</studio>
			<nplayers>1</nplayers>
			<ESRB>Not Rated</ESRB>
			<boxart1>9u0sPOc.jpg</boxart1>
			<boxart2>67UsaAY.jpg</boxart2>
			<boxart3>d4mLb8j.jpg</boxart3>
			<snapshot1>e6wHPSV.png</snapshot1>
			<snapshot2>qwjJzCP.png</snapshot2>
		</game>
		<game name="Malaya no Hibou (Japan)">
			<description>Malaya no Hibou (Japan)</description>
			<rom name="No-Intro-Collection_2016-09-06/Microsoft-Msx2.zip/Malaya%20no%20Hibou%20%28Japan%29.zip" size="67797" />
			<title_clean>Malaya no Hibou</title_clean>
			<plot>Malaya no Hihou is an Action/Adventure game, developed and published by Pony Canyon, which was released in Japan in 1989.</plot>
			<genre>Action; Adventure</genre>
			<studio>Pony Canyon</studio>
			<nplayers>1</nplayers>
			<ESRB>Not Rated</ESRB>
			<videoid>kKQcwszS8Yg</videoid>
			<boxart1>jxea7Ow.jpg</boxart1>
			<boxart2>ra5IKMq.jpg</boxart2>
			<boxart3>j991Chs.jpg</boxart3>
			<snapshot1>7M6goad.png</snapshot1>
			<snapshot2>ZfntCEz.png</snapshot2>
		</game>
		<game name="Metal Gear (Europe)">
			<description>Metal Gear (Europe)</description>
			<rom name="No-Intro-Collection_2016-09-06/Microsoft-Msx2.zip/Metal%20Gear%20%28Europe%29.zip" size="87843" />
			<title_clean>Metal Gear</title_clean>
			<plot>Near the end of the 20th century, a small fortified nation named Outer Heaven (founded by a mysterious war hero whose name and identity are shrouded in secrecy) is threatening the nations of the "West" with the development of a new prototype weapon named Metal Gear, a walking tank which is capable of launching nuclear warheads from anywhere on the globe. As FOX-HOUND's (an elite black ops unit) newest recruit, going by the codename of Solid Snake, your mission is to infiltrate Outer Heaven and rescue your missing comrade, Grey Fox (who was captured after a failed infiltration), while gathering intelligence on Metal Gear. [CR]In order to fulfill this objective, the player must collect various weapons and equipments (including keycards for further access into the fortress), while avoiding visual contact with the enemy. The player must also confront bosses in the form of Outer Heaven's elite mercenary force and rescue hostages hidden within the fortress in order to increase player rank, which gives Snake an extended life bar and increased storage capacity for replenishable items and ammo. The player can use a wireless transceiver to come in touch with their commanding officer, Big Boss, to learn more about their current mission objectives or contact one of the local resistance members operating covertly within the fortress to gain useful tips and insights.</plot>
			<releasedate>13/7/1987</releasedate>
			<year>1987</year>
			<genre>Action; Stealth</genre>
			<studio>Konami</studio>
			<nplayers>1</nplayers>
			<rating>3</rating>
			<ESRB>Not Rated</ESRB>
			<videoid>GAzRsyYlyLA</videoid>
			<wiki_url>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Metal_Gear_(video_game)</wiki_url>
			<boxart1>1inbq0J.jpg</boxart1>
			<boxart2>vgW5dGG.jpg</boxart2>
			<snapshot1>4vqNPAQ.png</snapshot1>
			<snapshot2>lZi8qBT.png</snapshot2>
			<fanart1>Vot6dHa.jpg</fanart1>
			<fanart2>JiE7pPd.jpg</fanart2>
			<clearlogo1>7DEb8KX.png</clearlogo1>
		</game>
		<game name="Metal Gear 2 - Solid Snake (Japan)">
			<description>Metal Gear 2 - Solid Snake (Japan)</description>
			<rom name="No-Intro-Collection_2016-09-06/Microsoft-Msx2.zip/Metal%20Gear%202%20-%20Solid%20Snake%20%28Japan%29.zip" size="330323" />
			<title_clean>Metal Gear 2 - Solid Snake</title_clean>
			<plot>In 1999, a great scientist named Kio Marv invented "oilix", a special petroleum-purifying substance that was supposed to help in the upcoming oil crisis. Shortly after the invention became known in the world, Dr. Marv was abducted. An investigation showed that he was held captive in Zanzibar Land, an isolated state in Central Asia which was ruled by a group of mercenaries from all around the world. Having oilix in addition to nuclear weapons are bound to Zanzibar an invincible state that would sooner or later attempt to conquer the entire world. Roy Campbell, ex-commander of special unit FOXHOUND, sends Solid Snake, the man who has single-handedly brought down the military nation of Outer Heaven four years ago, on a mission to infiltrate Zanzibar and to bring back the scientist and his invention.[CR]Like its predecessor, Metal Gear 2: Solid Snake is a stealth game. The driving element of the gameplay is to stay unnoticed. If guards spot you, you don't have much chance in combat, unless you are armed with appropriate weapons, which aren't easily acquired. Snake can use a variety of weapons and gadgets to help him survive during his mission. He can also hide behind objects, punch guards, and crawl. From time to time he'll have to participate in boss battles, where stealth won't help any more.</plot>
			<releasedate>20/7/1990</releasedate>
			<year>1990</year>
			<genre>Action; Stealth</genre>
			<studio>Konami</studio>
			<nplayers>1</nplayers>
			<ESRB>Not Rated</ESRB>
			<videoid>yphNwuAGBr4</videoid>
			<wiki_url>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Metal_Gear_2:_Solid_Snake</wiki_url>
			<boxart1>vOCGiZt.jpg</boxart1>
			<boxart2>NGDAvy5.jpg</boxart2>
			<boxart3>lvi6nH4.jpg</boxart3>
			<snapshot1>kFHoyHJ.png</snapshot1>
			<snapshot2>zKoB8ee.png</snapshot2>
			<fanart1>lYiODYb.jpg</fanart1>
			<fanart2>tS23OYf.jpg</fanart2>
			<clearlogo1>80FghTI.png</clearlogo1>
		</game>
		<game name="Mirai (Japan)">
			<description>Mirai (Japan)</description>
			<rom name="No-Intro-Collection_2016-09-06/Microsoft-Msx2.zip/Mirai%20%28Japan%29.zip" size="78620" />
			<title_clean>Mirai</title_clean>
			<plot>The year is 720 of the Galactic Era. Humans have ventured into deep space and found they were not alone in the universe. Alien life forms populated the galaxy, both friendly and hostile. The Rainbow Nebula is home to that last kind, and the protagonist of the game is the only one who can fight them.[CR]Mirai is a sci-fi shooter with strong role-playing elements. The player controls the protagonist who uses a jetpack to fly through scrolling maze-like environments. Experience points and money are gained from defeating the numerous respawning enemies. Money can be used in the few friendly areas to purchase weapons and items. The player also has to keep an eye on the fuel gauge for the protagonist's jetpack.</plot>
			<genre>Role-Playing; Shooter</genre>
			<studio>XAIN Soft</studio>
			<nplayers>1</nplayers>
			<ESRB>Not Rated</ESRB>
			<videoid>1sdVxYZk-vM</videoid>
			<boxart1>qFwEDVZ.jpg</boxart1>
			<boxart2>CqN7zpT.jpg</boxart2>
			<boxart3>xXkls6x.jpg</boxart3>
			<snapshot1>kSF6lx5.png</snapshot1>
			<snapshot2>lzUwGmH.png</snapshot2>
			<snapshot3>B3h7ZB5.png</snapshot3>
		</game>
		<game name="Mississippi Satsujinjiken (Japan)">
			<description>Mississippi Satsujinjiken (Japan)</description>
			<rom name="No-Intro-Collection_2016-09-06/Microsoft-Msx2.zip/Mississippi%20Satsujinjiken%20%28Japan%29.zip" size="54815" />
			<title_clean>Mississippi Satsujinjiken</title_clean>
			<plot>Animal Land: Murder Case is an Adventure game, developed and published by Enix Corporation,  which was released in Japan in 1987.[CR] - CHEATS - [CR]Chapter Passwords[CR]At the password screen, enter the Hiragana characters equivalent to these pronunciations:[CR]</plot>
			<releasedate>1/1/1987</releasedate>
			<genre>Adventure</genre>
			<studio>Jaleco</studio>
			<nplayers>1</nplayers>
			<boxart1>tJztqiF.jpg</boxart1>
			<snapshot1>mnBAMiM.jpg</snapshot1>
			<snapshot2>kmY7u7j.jpg</snapshot2>
		</game>
		<game name="Moero!! Nettou Yakyuu '88 (Japan)">
			<description>Moero!! Nettou Yakyuu '88 (Japan)</description>
			<rom name="No-Intro-Collection_2016-09-06/Microsoft-Msx2.zip/Moero%21%21%20Nettou%20Yakyuu%20%2788%20%28Japan%29.zip" size="111131" />
			<title_clean>Moero!! Nettou Yakyuu '88</title_clean>
			<plot>Moero!! Nettou Yakyuu '88 is a Sports game, developed and published by Jaleco, which was released in Japan in 1988.</plot>
			<genre>Sports</genre>
			<studio>Jaleco</studio>
			<nplayers>2</nplayers>
			<ESRB>Not Rated</ESRB>
			<boxart1>nKX3Bso.jpg</boxart1>
			<boxart2>mEMzRLe.jpg</boxart2>
			<snapshot1>DA1jVwB.png</snapshot1>
			<snapshot2>gAapUcE.png</snapshot2>
			<snapshot3>iWgw2y8.png</snapshot3>
		</game>
		<game name="Nekketsu Juudou (Japan)">
			<description>Nekketsu Juudou (Japan)</description>
			<rom name="No-Intro-Collection_2016-09-06/Microsoft-Msx2.zip/Nekketsu%20Juudou%20%28Japan%29.zip" size="90651" />
			<title_clean>Nekketsu Juudou</title_clean>
			<plot>Sport competition of judo</plot>
			<genre>Fighting; Sports</genre>
			<studio>Opera House</studio>
			<nplayers>2</nplayers>
			<ESRB>Not Rated</ESRB>
			<boxart1>xIFV8kd.jpg</boxart1>
			<boxart2>ema6IRG.jpg</boxart2>
			<snapshot1>ful9NyB.png</snapshot1>
			<snapshot2>UT81df5.png</snapshot2>
			<snapshot3>BLfkcRp.png</snapshot3>
			<fanart1>FPI1h4m.jpg</fanart1>
		</game>
		<game name="Ninja-kun - Asura no Shou (Japan)">
			<description>Ninja-kun - Asura no Shou (Japan)</description>
			<rom name="No-Intro-Collection_2016-09-06/Microsoft-Msx2.zip/Ninja-kun%20-%20Asura%20no%20Shou%20%28Japan%29.zip" size="59017" />
			<title_clean>Ninja-kun - Asura no Shou</title_clean>
			<plot>The game tells another story in Ninja-kun series. This time it&#8217;s a platform game with some twists. There are two tasks alternating through levels: you are required either to kill every enemy in the level (as in the previous games) or simply to reach the exit. Running into enemies usually won&#8217;t kill you, however if you are hit by a single projectile, you&#8217;ll have to start from a checkpoint. Enemies vary from plain ninjas to giant skeletons or killer fish. Each level has a time limit, and when this limit is close to an end a fire wheel of death will appear on the screen, chasing Ninja-kun.[CR]Ninja-kun has some techniques for successful progression though the levels: many enemies can be temporarily stunned by jumping on them or hitting them from below; and ninja can obtain some power-ups including boomerang, bombs, a devastating fire attack or invincibility. Ninja-kun is capable of wall climbing and wall jumping, the latter requiring some practice from the player.[CR]The levels (called &#8220;scenes&#8221; in-game) are scattered through mountains, caves, beaches and underwater locations. You can choose which set of levels you&#8217;ll start in by playing a mini-game at the beginning.</plot>
			<genre>Platform</genre>
			<studio>Opera House</studio>
			<nplayers>1</nplayers>
			<ESRB>Not Rated</ESRB>
			<videoid>D0KjTOKHx7E</videoid>
			<boxart1>aCqLx5T.jpg</boxart1>
			<boxart2>t8f1Oha.jpg</boxart2>
			<boxart3>Umf37hf.jpg</boxart3>
			<snapshot1>rc7Klit.png</snapshot1>
			<snapshot2>Y3rQZjz.png</snapshot2>
			<snapshot3>N8KXQZF.png</snapshot3>
		</game>
		<game name="Nobunaga no Yabou - Bushou Fuuun Roku (Japan)">
			<description>Nobunaga no Yabou - Bushou Fuuun Roku (Japan)</description>
			<rom name="No-Intro-Collection_2016-09-06/Microsoft-Msx2.zip/Nobunaga%20no%20Yabou%20-%20Bushou%20Fuuun%20Roku%20%28Japan%29.zip" size="612521" />
			<title_clean>Nobunaga no Yabou - Bushou Fuuun Roku</title_clean>
			<plot>Nobunaga no Yabou: Bushou Fuuun Roku is the fourth game in the Nobunaga series. The story of Nobunaga takes place during the Japanese civil war of the 16th century. In this wartime strategy game, 15 different warlords are represented across several territories.[CR][B]Gameplay:[/B] is done in one of two scenarios; the beginning of the civil war in 1555 or Nobunaga surrounded by his enemies in 1571. Management of population, supplies and military are the gameplay and successful manipulation of these numbers in the right combination to attack and defend against hostile intentions is what will bring your forces to victory.</plot>
			<genre>Strategy</genre>
			<studio>Koei</studio>
			<nplayers>1</nplayers>
			<ESRB>Not Rated</ESRB>
			<videoid>E0BJ24lCKXM</videoid>
			<boxart1>zGO7KxM.jpg</boxart1>
			<boxart2>UMsSNHC.jpg</boxart2>
			<boxart3>jah0h5Y.jpg</boxart3>
			<snapshot1>J8BvcpX.png</snapshot1>
			<snapshot2>QrssK7E.png</snapshot2>
		</game>
		<game name="Nobunaga no Yabou - Sengoku Gunyuuden (Japan)">
			<description>Nobunaga no Yabou - Sengoku Gunyuuden (Japan)</description>
			<rom name="No-Intro-Collection_2016-09-06/Microsoft-Msx2.zip/Nobunaga%20no%20Yabou%20-%20Sengoku%20Gunyuuden%20%28Japan%29.zip" size="316374" />
			<title_clean>Nobunaga no Yabou - Sengoku Gunyuuden</title_clean>
			<plot>Nobunaga no Yabou: Sengoku Gunyuuden is the third game in the Nobunaga series. The setting is 16th century feudal Japan, a period when ruthless daimyo (feudal lords) contended with each other for dominance. Ultimately, the winner in this struggle will become Shogun and hold actual power over the islands, while being nominally subject to the Emperor.[CR]The game casts the player as one of the daimyo, allowing them freedom to decide the fate and future of feudal Japan, through diplomacy and ultimately war. The objective is to unify Japan under the player's rule. If the player fails through death on the battlefield, assassination at the hands of a ninja, or through natural causes, they can choose a successor and play on.</plot>
			<genre>Strategy</genre>
			<studio>Koei</studio>
			<nplayers>8</nplayers>
			<ESRB>Not Rated</ESRB>
			<videoid>Z_uL1PoWf64</videoid>
			<boxart1>b1rfEGn.jpg</boxart1>
			<boxart2>nQe3pSx.jpg</boxart2>
			<boxart3>riMJSDe.jpg</boxart3>
			<snapshot1>JxwC4ID.png</snapshot1>
			<snapshot2>l4Y2PHC.png</snapshot2>
		</game>
		<game name="Nobunaga no Yabou - Zenkoku Ban (Japan)">
			<description>Nobunaga no Yabou - Zenkoku Ban (Japan)</description>
			<rom name="No-Intro-Collection_2016-09-06/Microsoft-Msx2.zip/Nobunaga%20no%20Yabou%20-%20Zenkoku%20Ban%20%28Japan%29.zip" size="239257" />
			<title_clean>Nobunaga no Yabou - Zenkoku Ban</title_clean>
			<plot>Nobunaga no Yabou: Zenkokuban is the second game in the Nobunaga series. In the 16th century, Japan's Sengoku ("Warring States") period divided the nation into numerous feudal states, each ruled by a daimyo. These daimyos would often go to war with each other. Many dreamt of conquering the land, becoming the Shogun and ruling the entire country. One of those daimyos was the ambitious Nobunaga Oda, a merciless ruler and a renowned strategist. Players take on the role of Nobunaga Oda or one of many other daimyos to try to conquer Japan.[CR]Players begin by selecting either a 17 regions scenario or a larger 50 scenario. Then, the player must select a daimyo, each of which is rated attributes in several categories; Age, Health, Ambition, Luck, Charm and IQ. As the game progresses, these values change depending on events in the game. The age value represents a time limit of sorts, as an elderly daimyo becomes increasingly likely to die of old age or sickness.</plot>
			<genre>Strategy</genre>
			<studio>Koei</studio>
			<nplayers>8</nplayers>
			<ESRB>Not Rated</ESRB>
			<videoid>4q6AmYh-RgE</videoid>
			<boxart1>Ba2PItW.jpg</boxart1>
			<boxart2>Tn1ZrQH.jpg</boxart2>
			<boxart3>e62R819.jpg</boxart3>
			<snapshot1>5SMfF5m.png</snapshot1>
			<snapshot2>V3E2Eo0.png</snapshot2>
		</game>
		<game name="Ogre (Japan)">
			<description>Ogre (Japan)</description>
			<rom name="No-Intro-Collection_2016-09-06/Microsoft-Msx2.zip/Ogre%20%28Japan%29.zip" size="55636" />
			<title_clean>Ogre</title_clean>
			<plot>Ogre is a 2D turn-based strategy game, and a direct computer conversion of Steve Jackson's board game of supertanks going against conventional infantry with howitzers. It plays exactly like the board game - on a hex-based board one player controls ordinary military units (soldiers, tanks etc.), and defends against the second player, who controls a supertank named "Ogre" - Ogre is very powerful, and can easily destroy normal weaponry and ground forces.</plot>
			<genre>Strategy</genre>
			<studio>SystemSoft</studio>
			<nplayers>1</nplayers>
			<ESRB>Not Rated</ESRB>
			<videoid>aHd7OxBabVM</videoid>
			<boxart1>yQoVTz7.jpg</boxart1>
			<boxart2>7X4Tacv.jpg</boxart2>
			<snapshot1>TSNg4g4.png</snapshot1>
			<snapshot2>UscuYu6.png</snapshot2>
		</game>
		<game name="Ouke no Tani - El Giza no Fuuin (Japan)">
			<description>Ouke no Tani - El Giza no Fuuin (Japan)</description>
			<rom name="No-Intro-Collection_2016-09-06/Microsoft-Msx2.zip/Ouke%20no%20Tani%20-%20El%20Giza%20no%20Fuuin%20%28Japan%29.zip" size="79758" />
			<title_clean>Ouke no Tani - El Giza no Fuuin</title_clean>
			<plot>Far, far into the future, inter-planetary archaeologist Vick XIII, makes a choking discovery. The pyramids on earth are malfunctioning devices of alien origin with enough energy to destroy earth. And it's up to Vick to switch off the core functions of El Giza.[CR]The game consists of six pyramids each with its own wall engravings and color pattern; every pyramid contains 10 levels. The idea of the game is to collect crystals called soul stones in each level by solving the different puzzles and evading or killing the enemies using the many tools and weapons available to unlock the exit door that will take you to the next level.[CR]The game was released both for the MSX1 and MSX2 systems. The MSX2 version only saw a release in Japan. The MSX 2 version was the same game except minor changes like the music was remixed and some of the items and backgrounds recolored.</plot>
			<genre>Puzzle</genre>
			<studio>Konami</studio>
			<nplayers>1</nplayers>
			<ESRB>Not Rated</ESRB>
			<videoid>o8-3QXOGkf8</videoid>
			<wiki_url>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/King%27s_Valley_II</wiki_url>
			<boxart1>4vUcqhv.jpg</boxart1>
			<boxart2>xdwqPib.jpg</boxart2>
			<boxart3>crhJEdp.jpg</boxart3>
			<snapshot1>yLGYqHp.png</snapshot1>
			<snapshot2>zyzVdZw.png</snapshot2>
			<snapshot3>n06uDLY.png</snapshot3>
		</game>
		<game name="Out Run (Japan)">
			<description>Out Run (Japan)</description>
			<rom name="No-Intro-Collection_2016-09-06/Microsoft-Msx2.zip/Out%20Run%20%28Japan%29.zip" size="101683" />
			<title_clean>Out Run</title_clean>
			<plot>OutRun is a racing game that allows the player to race across varied terrain in a readily available Ferrari, complete with a female passenger, over a series of short tracks.[CR][B]Gameplay:[/B] is viewed from just above and behind the car. The roads are full of sharp bends and hazards, contact with which can cause the car to roll and lose the player's time. On each section of track there is a fork in the road, allowing the player to choose which direction he or she wishes to go in. The player has to to complete five track sections in total, out of the fifteen in the game.</plot>
			<genre>Driving, Racing</genre>
			<studio>Sega</studio>
			<nplayers>1</nplayers>
			<ESRB>Not Rated</ESRB>
			<videoid>J-UeZrKhsG0</videoid>
			<wiki_url>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Out_Run#Home_conversions</wiki_url>
			<boxart1>shkNR4J.jpg</boxart1>
			<boxart2>yX9Fom2.jpg</boxart2>
			<snapshot1>aWpwnJS.png</snapshot1>
			<snapshot2>54aPppK.png</snapshot2>
		</game>
		<game name="Pac-Mania (Japan)">
			<description>Pac-Mania (Japan)</description>
			<rom name="No-Intro-Collection_2016-09-06/Microsoft-Msx2.zip/Pac-Mania%20%28Japan%29.zip" size="48695" />
			<title_clean>Pac-Mania</title_clean>
			<plot>Pac-Mania is a variation on the game Pac-Man. You need to guide Pac-Man around a maze and eat all of the dots on the board in order to proceed on to the next round. Numerous, multi-colored ghosts also roam the maze trying to stop you. If you eat one of the power pellets in the maze, the ghosts will temporarily turn blue and run from you. Pac-Man can earn bonus points by eating the ghosts when they are in this state. The maze is now shown in isometric perspective and is larger than screen which will scroll to follow the action. To help get out of tight spots, Pac-Man now has the ability to jump. But be careful, because some of the ghosts have learned this trick as well and you could end up in a mid air collision!</plot>
			<genre>Action</genre>
			<studio>Namco</studio>
			<nplayers>1</nplayers>
			<ESRB>Not Rated</ESRB>
			<videoid>hxXlt930OVE</videoid>
			<wiki_url>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Pac-Mania</wiki_url>
			<boxart1>cSGWU55.jpg</boxart1>
			<boxart2>kAeiHrn.jpg</boxart2>
			<boxart3>cLBi4A9.jpg</boxart3>
			<snapshot1>tFLjAk0.png</snapshot1>
			<snapshot2>ZbfuTNW.png</snapshot2>
		</game>
		<game name="Pachi Pro Densetsu (Japan)">
			<description>Pachi Pro Densetsu (Japan)</description>
			<rom name="No-Intro-Collection_2016-09-06/Microsoft-Msx2.zip/Pachi%20Pro%20Densetsu%20%28Japan%29.zip" size="62434" />
			<title_clean>Pachi Pro Densetsu</title_clean>
			<plot>Pachipro Densetsu is a Pachinko game for one player.</plot>
			<genre>Card</genre>
			<studio>HAL Laboratory</studio>
			<nplayers>1</nplayers>
			<ESRB>Not Rated</ESRB>
			<boxart1>GQlOVdD.jpg</boxart1>
			<snapshot1>pyxuAJ6.png</snapshot1>
			<snapshot2>nok5sj4.png</snapshot2>
			<snapshot3>2686bIw.png</snapshot3>
		</game>
		<game name="Penguin-kun Wars 2 (Japan)">
			<description>Penguin-kun Wars 2 (Japan)</description>
			<rom name="No-Intro-Collection_2016-09-06/Microsoft-Msx2.zip/Penguin-kun%20Wars%202%20%28Japan%29.zip" size="104788" />
			<title_clean>Penguin-kun Wars 2</title_clean>
			<plot>Penguin-Kun and his friend Penpi-chan are playing a game, when suddenly Penpi-chani is kidnapped. Penguin-kun must challenge the world's finest in order to save her, but a greater evil lurks in the unknown.</plot>
			<genre>Sports</genre>
			<studio>ASCII</studio>
			<nplayers>2</nplayers>
			<ESRB>Not Rated</ESRB>
			<videoid>_iY0g5yVVB4</videoid>
			<boxart1>O0s7kTd.jpg</boxart1>
			<boxart2>poHgkny.jpg</boxart2>
			<snapshot1>IouClGW.png</snapshot1>
			<snapshot2>U9TZFyz.png</snapshot2>
			<snapshot3>werB90L.png</snapshot3>
			<snapshot4>Dl00H9R.png</snapshot4>
		</game>
		<game name="Predator (Japan)">
			<description>Predator (Japan)</description>
			<rom name="No-Intro-Collection_2016-09-06/Microsoft-Msx2.zip/Predator%20%28Japan%29.zip" size="72092" />
			<title_clean>Predator</title_clean>
			<plot>Predator is a 2D action platformer. The object of the game is to survive the dangers of the jungle while you shoot down guerillas and wildlife using variety of weapons including machine gun, landmines, and grenades. Killing an enemy usually gives you more ammo for one of the three weapons.</plot>
			<genre>Action; Platform</genre>
			<studio>Klon</studio>
			<nplayers>1</nplayers>
			<ESRB>Not Rated</ESRB>
			<videoid>7TUFhL-eMro</videoid>
			<boxart1>1tpFxKK.png</boxart1>
			<snapshot1>WDKW2MU.png</snapshot1>
			<snapshot2>x8Li0Uf.png</snapshot2>
			<clearlogo1>h2sEwP6.png</clearlogo1>
		</game>
		<game name="Pro Yakyuu Family Stadium - Pennant Race (Japan)">
			<description>Pro Yakyuu Family Stadium - Pennant Race (Japan)</description>
			<rom name="No-Intro-Collection_2016-09-06/Microsoft-Msx2.zip/Pro%20Yakyuu%20Family%20Stadium%20-%20Pennant%20Race%20%28Japan%29.zip" size="96925" />
			<title_clean>Pro Yakyuu Family Stadium - Pennant Race</title_clean>
			<plot>Baseball game for one or two players. You can choose one of the 18 teams to play an exhibition match against computer or a friend. Or how about battling it out against five other teams in Pennant Race mode, where you can save your progress with passwords. There is also an edit mode, where you can change the player names and modify their abilities.</plot>
			<genre>Sports</genre>
			<studio>Namco</studio>
			<nplayers>2</nplayers>
			<ESRB>Not Rated</ESRB>
			<videoid>A3ROBDaUClU</videoid>
			<boxart1>3raCoSw.jpg</boxart1>
			<boxart2>BVw7ShL.jpg</boxart2>
			<boxart3>QifDgfL.jpg</boxart3>
			<snapshot1>M4XSiBy.png</snapshot1>
			<snapshot2>Mp5huPs.png</snapshot2>
			<snapshot3>2ECYhwY.png</snapshot3>
		</game>
		<game name="Pro Yakyuu Fan - Telenet Stadium (Japan)">
			<description>Pro Yakyuu Fan - Telenet Stadium (Japan)</description>
			<rom name="No-Intro-Collection_2016-09-06/Microsoft-Msx2.zip/Pro%20Yakyuu%20Fan%20-%20Telenet%20Stadium%20%28Japan%29.zip" size="128289" />
			<title_clean>Pro Yakyuu Fan - Telenet Stadium</title_clean>
			<plot>Pro Yakyuu Fan Telenet Stadium is a Baseball game, developed and published by Telenet Japan, which was released in Japan in 1987.</plot>
			<genre>Sports</genre>
			<studio>Telenet Japan</studio>
			<nplayers>2</nplayers>
			<ESRB>Not Rated</ESRB>
			<videoid>Sjsis_sQykQ</videoid>
			<boxart1>22ni2B1.jpg</boxart1>
			<boxart2>g6iozTn.jpg</boxart2>
			<boxart3>bEZE2Qp.jpg</boxart3>
			<snapshot1>dR48hSx.png</snapshot1>
			<snapshot2>K4BpRuU.png</snapshot2>
			<snapshot3>zodxKF5.png</snapshot3>
		</game>
		<game name="Professional Mahjong Gokuu (Japan)">
			<description>Professional Mahjong Gokuu (Japan)</description>
			<rom name="No-Intro-Collection_2016-09-06/Microsoft-Msx2.zip/Professional%20Mahjong%20Gokuu%20%28Japan%29.zip" size="54179" />
			<title_clean>Professional Mahjong Gokuu</title_clean>
			<plot>Professional Mahjong Gokuu features several variations of the game of four-player mahjong. The main idea behind mahjong games is that players receive and discard tiles until they complete hands by forming groups and pairs. The game also features a plethora of options to customize the rules of the game to their liking.</plot>
			<genre>Strategy</genre>
			<studio>Chat Noir</studio>
			<nplayers>1</nplayers>
			<ESRB>Not Rated</ESRB>
			<boxart1>X1BRLSP.jpg</boxart1>
			<boxart2>tV0usC6.jpg</boxart2>
			<boxart3>52nhW5j.jpg</boxart3>
			<snapshot1>sC4CbNP.png</snapshot1>
			<snapshot2>Ly5PZxd.png</snapshot2>
		</game>
		<game name="Project A2 - Shijousaidai no Hyouteki (Japan)">
			<description>Project A2 - Shijousaidai no Hyouteki (Japan)</description>
			<rom name="No-Intro-Collection_2016-09-06/Microsoft-Msx2.zip/Project%20A2%20-%20Shijousaidai%20no%20Hyouteki%20%28Japan%29.zip" size="62749" />
			<title_clean>Project A2 - Shijousaidai no Hyouteki</title_clean>
			<plot>Project A2: Shijousaidai no Hyouteki is an action game based on Jackie Chan's Project A2. You fight your way through regular enemies by punching and kicking. Enter to different rooms and you might face a tough enemy, who challenges you to a 1v1 fight.</plot>
			<genre>Action; Fighting</genre>
			<studio>Pony Canyon</studio>
			<nplayers>1</nplayers>
			<ESRB>Not Rated</ESRB>
			<videoid>QDesrYujymA</videoid>
			<boxart1>MlN9Rr1.jpg</boxart1>
			<boxart2>m2bVWk6.jpg</boxart2>
			<boxart3>LzHULrZ.jpg</boxart3>
			<snapshot1>1C52MDJ.png</snapshot1>
			<snapshot2>sj0cDhb.png</snapshot2>
			<snapshot3>CRV7j1y.png</snapshot3>
			<snapshot4>OXLVTrY.png</snapshot4>
		</game>
		<game name="Quarth (Japan)">
			<description>Quarth (Japan)</description>
			<rom name="No-Intro-Collection_2016-09-06/Microsoft-Msx2.zip/Quarth%20%28Japan%29.zip" size="64134" />
			<title_clean>Quarth</title_clean>
			<plot>Quarth is a typical puzzle/arcade game. Quarth can be moved from right to left while the screen scrolls down. The playing field is filled with different blocks and your aim is to fill them in so they form complete rectangles or squares. Only when you succeed in this mission, the concerned blocks will disappear. New 'unformed' blocks appear while the playing field scrolls down making you play into full action at all times. As soon as a line of blocks reaches the bottom line, it is Game Over. Then you'll be granted 10 seconds to decide if you want continue the level. Each Level consists of 9 Areas and you progress to the next level once you've cleared the last area. The Battle mode is a dual player mode.</plot>
			<genre>Puzzle</genre>
			<studio>Konami</studio>
			<nplayers>2</nplayers>
			<ESRB>Not Rated</ESRB>
			<videoid>n6IMoaPKYms</videoid>
			<wiki_url>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Quarth</wiki_url>
			<boxart1>Nwre7XT.jpg</boxart1>
			<boxart2>0b6VWzU.jpg</boxart2>
			<boxart3>lIlXitm.jpg</boxart3>
			<boxart4>yGRe7Y1.jpg</boxart4>
			<snapshot1>SmXOjYu.png</snapshot1>
			<snapshot2>WHiO9Dp.png</snapshot2>
			<clearlogo1>HifNLUd.png</clearlogo1>
		</game>
		<game name="Quarth (Japan) (Demo)">
			<description>Quarth (Japan) (Demo)</description>
			<rom name="No-Intro-Collection_2016-09-06/Microsoft-Msx2.zip/Quarth%20%28Japan%29%20%28Demo%29.zip" size="56760" />
			<title_clean>Quarth</title_clean>
			<plot>Quarth is a typical puzzle/arcade game. Quarth can be moved from right to left while the screen scrolls down. The playing field is filled with different blocks and your aim is to fill them in so they form complete rectangles or squares. Only when you succeed in this mission, the concerned blocks will disappear. New 'unformed' blocks appear while the playing field scrolls down making you play into full action at all times. As soon as a line of blocks reaches the bottom line, it is Game Over. Then you'll be granted 10 seconds to decide if you want continue the level. Each Level consists of 9 Areas and you progress to the next level once you've cleared the last area. The Battle mode is a dual player mode.</plot>
			<genre>Puzzle</genre>
			<studio>Konami</studio>
			<nplayers>2</nplayers>
			<ESRB>Not Rated</ESRB>
			<videoid>n6IMoaPKYms</videoid>
			<wiki_url>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Quarth</wiki_url>
			<boxart1>Nwre7XT.jpg</boxart1>
			<boxart2>0b6VWzU.jpg</boxart2>
			<boxart3>lIlXitm.jpg</boxart3>
			<boxart4>yGRe7Y1.jpg</boxart4>
			<snapshot1>SmXOjYu.png</snapshot1>
			<snapshot2>Ln4bGHQ.png</snapshot2>
			<clearlogo1>HifNLUd.png</clearlogo1>
		</game>
		<game name="Rastan Saga (Japan)">
			<description>Rastan Saga (Japan)</description>
			<rom name="No-Intro-Collection_2016-09-06/Microsoft-Msx2.zip/Rastan%20Saga%20%28Japan%29.zip" size="109821" />
			<title_clean>Rastan Saga</title_clean>
			<plot>Rastan Saga features five levels of hacking and slashing gameplay with a boss at the end of each level. Numerous enemies assault you on your journey such as flying demons, chimeras, valkyries, piranhas, skeleton undead and more. Fight through to the end and save the land of Lograth from certain doom.[CR]The game features different weapons such as axes, maces and fire swords, each with its own attributes like extended range or attack power. Armour can also be picked up in the forms shields, cloaks and armour, reducing the damage from enemy attacks. Other items include rings (increase the speed of your weapon) and jewelery for bonus points.</plot>
			<genre>Action; Platform</genre>
			<studio>Taito</studio>
			<nplayers>1</nplayers>
			<ESRB>Not Rated</ESRB>
			<videoid>aH7q5ccu3WY</videoid>
			<wiki_url>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Rastan_(video_game)</wiki_url>
			<boxart1>3m9bf5Q.jpg</boxart1>
			<boxart2>TMJGA9e.jpg</boxart2>
			<boxart3>LRXGDJn.jpg</boxart3>
			<snapshot1>W58jag6.png</snapshot1>
			<snapshot2>N3IMlQP.png</snapshot2>
			<snapshot3>tYXcfE6.png</snapshot3>
		</game>
		<game name="Relics (Japan)">
			<description>Relics (Japan)</description>
			<rom name="No-Intro-Collection_2016-09-06/Microsoft-Msx2.zip/Relics%20%28Japan%29.zip" size="136073" />
			<title_clean>Relics</title_clean>
			<plot>Relics is an Action game, developed and published by Bothtec, which was released in Japan in 1986.</plot>
			<genre>Action</genre>
			<studio>Bothtec</studio>
			<nplayers>1</nplayers>
			<ESRB>Not Rated</ESRB>
			<boxart1>3r1Ilqy.jpg</boxart1>
			<boxart2>l5Xc8lK.jpg</boxart2>
			<snapshot1>aSnv3Eu.png</snapshot1>
			<snapshot2>sgStxOs.png</snapshot2>
		</game>
		<game name="Replicart (Japan)">
			<description>Replicart (Japan)</description>
			<rom name="No-Intro-Collection_2016-09-06/Microsoft-Msx2.zip/Replicart%20%28Japan%29.zip" size="59915" />
			<title_clean>Replicart</title_clean>
			<plot>It is the 22nd century. Earth is invaded by a aliens, led by a gigantic robotic snake. To repel the attack, Earth's scientists construct the Replicart machine, a deadly robot snake. The player takes the role of the pilot of the Replicart.[CR]Replicart is a single-player only Snake game variant. In each stage you have to collect a certain amount of a substance called 'Biteslime'. Once you fulfill your quota you can enter the next stage through an exit that opens on the left side of the screen. Collecting biteslime increases the length of your snake. If the head of your snake hits a wall, an enemy or part of its body you lose a life. Replicart enhances the basic Snake game formula by adding power ups like a Time Stop, which freezes enemies, speed increase/decrease or level warps.</plot>
			<genre>Action</genre>
			<studio>Klon</studio>
			<nplayers>1</nplayers>
			<ESRB>Not Rated</ESRB>
			<videoid>0hi7JrQeBtE</videoid>
			<boxart1>EAG9H0v.jpg</boxart1>
			<snapshot1>nnJndtQ.png</snapshot1>
			<snapshot2>y9XO16g.png</snapshot2>
			<snapshot3>OZBbCPN.png</snapshot3>
		</game>
		<game name="Return of Ishtar, The (Japan)">
			<description>Return of Ishtar, The (Japan)</description>
			<rom name="No-Intro-Collection_2016-09-06/Microsoft-Msx2.zip/Return%20of%20Ishtar%2C%20The%20%28Japan%29.zip" size="93337" />
			<title_clean>Return of Ishtar, The</title_clean>
			<plot>The Return of Ishtar is a sequel to The Tower of Druaga. It is an action game with light puzzle-solving elements that requires you to control two different characters. The characters are maiden Ki who fights with magic and the other one is Gilgamesh, the sword-wielding knight. Search for keys and special items. The tower has a few different ways to exit, and the aggregate total of levels is 128.[CR]Players are presented a password to allow them to continue from where they left off.</plot>
			<genre>Action; Puzzle</genre>
			<studio>Namco</studio>
			<nplayers>1</nplayers>
			<ESRB>Not Rated</ESRB>
			<videoid>mwmvcrS9WIo</videoid>
			<wiki_url>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Return_of_Ishtar</wiki_url>
			<boxart1>UD8zyy6.jpg</boxart1>
			<boxart2>06qNT2O.jpg</boxart2>
			<boxart3>hlrv1u4.jpg</boxart3>
			<snapshot1>0Xp7D91.png</snapshot1>
			<snapshot2>NS7Lhlp.png</snapshot2>
		</game>
		<game name="Return of Jelda (Japan)">
			<description>Return of Jelda (Japan)</description>
			<rom name="No-Intro-Collection_2016-09-06/Microsoft-Msx2.zip/Return%20of%20Jelda%20%28Japan%29.zip" size="37309" />
			<title_clean>Return of Jelda</title_clean>
			<plot>Return of Jelda is a Shooter game, developed and published by Carry Lab, which was released in Japan in 1987.</plot>
			<genre>Shooter</genre>
			<studio>Carry Lab</studio>
			<nplayers>1</nplayers>
			<ESRB>Not Rated</ESRB>
			<videoid>KdJVQaBcTU8</videoid>
			<boxart1>5vMsb3N.jpg</boxart1>
			<snapshot1>JVTjYKj.png</snapshot1>
			<snapshot2>ozNUC9h.png</snapshot2>
			<snapshot3>PInDD3z.png</snapshot3>
		</game>
		<game name="Rick to Mick no Daibouken (Japan)">
			<description>Rick to Mick no Daibouken (Japan)</description>
			<rom name="No-Intro-Collection_2016-09-06/Microsoft-Msx2.zip/Rick%20to%20Mick%20no%20Daibouken%20%28Japan%29.zip" size="35062" />
			<title_clean>Rick to Mick no Daibouken</title_clean>
			<plot>Rick to Mick no Daibouken is an Action game for one or two players (cooperative), developed and published by Humming Bird Soft in Japan in 1987.</plot>
			<genre>Action</genre>
			<studio>Humming Bird Soft</studio>
			<nplayers>1-2 Co-Op</nplayers>
			<ESRB>Not Rated</ESRB>
			<videoid>8pBibY7mNgg</videoid>
			<boxart1>6jswZjg.jpg</boxart1>
			<snapshot1>H5OG9q4.png</snapshot1>
			<snapshot2>xVglQwB.png</snapshot2>
		</game>
		<game name="Royal Blood (Japan)">
			<description>Royal Blood (Japan)</description>
			<rom name="No-Intro-Collection_2016-09-06/Microsoft-Msx2.zip/Royal%20Blood%20%28Japan%29.zip" size="526354" />
			<title_clean>Royal Blood</title_clean>
			<plot>Koei made an incursion into the fantasy worlds of magic with this game.[CR]Six magicians, each trapped inside a magical gem, are liberated from the crown by Princess Robyn, daughter of the tyrannical ruler of Ishmeria, King Eselred. Fleeing across the length and breadth of the island nation, they each choose a leader from the greatest noble houses as their champion to topple Eselred and bring peace to Ishmeria. [CR]Players select one of these noblemen and seek to unite all the provinces under their banner through a combination of warfare and diplomacy.</plot>
			<genre>Strategy</genre>
			<studio>Koei</studio>
			<nplayers>1</nplayers>
			<ESRB>Not Rated</ESRB>
			<wiki_url>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Gemfire</wiki_url>
			<boxart1>QnGleGn.jpg</boxart1>
			<boxart2>VN8w3RZ.jpg</boxart2>
			<boxart3>NLXtYaw.jpg</boxart3>
			<boxart4>UiV6KRm.jpg</boxart4>
			<snapshot1>oki6GhB.png</snapshot1>
			<snapshot2>1gpiUTx.png</snapshot2>
		</game>
		<game name="Sangokushi (Japan)">
			<description>Sangokushi (Japan)</description>
			<rom name="No-Intro-Collection_2016-09-06/Microsoft-Msx2.zip/Sangokushi%20%28Japan%29.zip" size="247547" />
			<title_clean>Sangokushi</title_clean>
			<plot>Based on the events of the Three Kingdoms era in China (3rd century), and on Luo Guanzhong's famous novel Sanguo Yanyi, the game casts the player in the role of one of the many warlords rivaling for control after the Yellow Turban Rebellion.[CR]This turn-based strategy game introduces hundreds of historical characters of the Three Kingdoms era. The game's main objective is to become the supreme ruler of the remnants of the falling Han Dynasty. To do this the player has to build a mighty empire by conquering provinces and recruiting generals worthy of command. Fight massive battles, triumph over natural disasters and capture enemy strongholds.</plot>
			<genre>Strategy</genre>
			<studio>Koei</studio>
			<nplayers>1</nplayers>
			<ESRB>Not Rated</ESRB>
			<wiki_url>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Romance_of_the_Three_Kingdoms_(video_game_series)</wiki_url>
			<boxart1>4YJhwZx.jpg</boxart1>
			<boxart2>4E3eKzS.jpg</boxart2>
			<boxart3>G6WDqm8.jpg</boxart3>
			<snapshot1>OpjWkYu.png</snapshot1>
			<snapshot2>S0a30yx.png</snapshot2>
		</game>
		<game name="Sangokushi II (Japan)">
			<description>Sangokushi II (Japan)</description>
			<rom name="No-Intro-Collection_2016-09-06/Microsoft-Msx2.zip/Sangokushi%20II%20%28Japan%29.zip" size="578378" />
			<title_clean>Sangokushi II</title_clean>
			<plot>The sequel to Sangokushi. The game concept is still the same, though they did improve a lot of features that one may consider 'disturbing' from RTK I (e.g. Generals dying easily due to disease, etc.). RTK can be said to be much more 'stable' where players no longer have to worry that much about time length in the game, as the game take a slower time rate to allow the players to build up their forces without much interference. The RTK II gameplay and interface is closely similar to Nobunaga's Ambition II.</plot>
			<genre>Strategy</genre>
			<studio>Koei</studio>
			<nplayers>1</nplayers>
			<ESRB>Not Rated</ESRB>
			<wiki_url>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Romance_of_the_Three_Kingdoms_(video_game_series)</wiki_url>
			<boxart1>2bTid7J.jpg</boxart1>
			<boxart2>Vrbxw9s.jpg</boxart2>
			<boxart3>j57ALvK.jpg</boxart3>
			<snapshot1>I3yE9Oo.png</snapshot1>
			<snapshot2>oQPL99Y.png</snapshot2>
			<snapshot3>zxF25hD.png</snapshot3>
			<snapshot4>wMLDegV.png</snapshot4>
		</game>
		<game name="Scramble Formation (Japan)">
			<description>Scramble Formation (Japan)</description>
			<rom name="No-Intro-Collection_2016-09-06/Microsoft-Msx2.zip/Scramble%20Formation%20%28Japan%29.zip" size="81478" />
			<title_clean>Scramble Formation</title_clean>
			<plot>Conversion of Taito's arcade classic, Scramble Formation is a vertical shoot'em up.  The player pilots a biplane over what is presumably the city of Tokyo. Power-ups include multiple biplanes. The option of using plane formations increases gameplay substantially.[CR]At the end of each level you 'll have to face the Big Enemy.</plot>
			<genre>Shooter</genre>
			<studio>Taito</studio>
			<nplayers>2</nplayers>
			<ESRB>Not Rated</ESRB>
			<videoid>oUR0nKuCFm8</videoid>
			<wiki_url>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Scramble_Formation</wiki_url>
			<boxart1>rGMVjOp.jpg</boxart1>
			<boxart2>s14ArPl.jpg</boxart2>
			<boxart3>wn1PCsr.jpg</boxart3>
			<snapshot1>v24GXpl.png</snapshot1>
			<snapshot2>qsiVTJl.png</snapshot2>
		</game>
		<game name="Seikima II Special - Akuma no Gyakushuu (Japan)">
			<description>Seikima II Special - Akuma no Gyakushuu (Japan)</description>
			<rom name="No-Intro-Collection_2016-09-06/Microsoft-Msx2.zip/Seikima%20II%20Special%20-%20Akuma%20no%20Gyakushuu%20%28Japan%29.zip" size="49699" />
			<title_clean>Seikima II Special - Akuma no Gyakushuu</title_clean>
			<plot>Players take control of Demon Kogure, a member of the real life Japanese heavy metal band Seikima-II. He is on a mission to rescue his fellow "demon" bandmates who have been captured and imprisoned by the God Zeus.[CR]The game is broken up into four zones that are composed of eight areas each. In each area players have to collect all the visible items laying around to complete that area. Once all the items are collected in the seven areas of a zone, players can then enter the eighth area where they will find one of their bandmates locked inside a cage. While collecting all the visible items, players will be continuously attacked by enemies that they can either try to jump and dodge or shoot their projectile weapon at them. Getting hit by an enemy will decrease the players life, which is already constantly draining.[CR]One of the items the player collects are moneybags. Collected moneybags earn the player money which can in turn be spent at the various shops found throughout the game. Shops sell life potions, stronger weapons, and also musical instruments for each band member.</plot>
			<genre>Platform</genre>
			<studio>ISCO</studio>
			<nplayers>1</nplayers>
			<ESRB>Not Rated</ESRB>
			<videoid>aJ3GF3grmTQ</videoid>
			<wiki_url>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Seikima_II_Akuma_no_Gyakushu!</wiki_url>
			<boxart1>xj8gSA2.jpg</boxart1>
			<boxart2>qqUVAFi.jpg</boxart2>
			<snapshot1>naOodPp.png</snapshot1>
			<snapshot2>ZCXwOdi.png</snapshot2>
		</game>
		<game name="Shanghai (Japan)">
			<description>Shanghai (Japan)</description>
			<rom name="No-Intro-Collection_2016-09-06/Microsoft-Msx2.zip/Shanghai%20%28Japan%29.zip" size="35565" />
			<title_clean>Shanghai</title_clean>
			<plot>Shanghai is one of the first video game adaptations of the tile-based game played with the Chinese mahjong stones - essentially a puzzle game that has little to do with real mahjong rules.[CR]The gameplay involves 144 tiles, each depicting different images, which have to be removed by matching them into pairs. The tiles are arranged in a gridded pattern, which is higher near the centre. A tile can only be removed if it has no tile next to it on at least one side.[CR]This computer implementation can generate a random board layout to take on and features five preset challenges, some of which have time limits of five or ten minutes, as well as a multiplayer mode.</plot>
			<genre>Puzzle</genre>
			<studio>SystemSoft</studio>
			<nplayers>2</nplayers>
			<ESRB>Not Rated</ESRB>
			<videoid>qFfIwdx6Rdc</videoid>
			<wiki_url>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Shanghai_(video_game)</wiki_url>
			<boxart1>U4u509Z.jpg</boxart1>
			<boxart2>ZvnLQuI.jpg</boxart2>
			<snapshot1>kiXVNaK.png</snapshot1>
			<snapshot2>f3IsEPY.png</snapshot2>
		</game>
		<game name="Shiryou Sensen - War of the Dead (Japan)">
			<description>Shiryou Sensen - War of the Dead (Japan)</description>
			<rom name="No-Intro-Collection_2016-09-06/Microsoft-Msx2.zip/Shiryou%20Sensen%20-%20War%20of%20the%20Dead%20%28Japan%29.zip" size="129230" />
			<title_clean>Shiryou Sensen - War of the Dead</title_clean>
			<plot>Due to mysterious circumstances, a flourishing city called Chinese Hill was cut off the rest of the world. Investigators found out that most of the buildings were destroyed, horrifying creatures are roaming the wilderness, and the few survivors have no means of escaping. The SSWAT (Supernatural Special Weapon Attack Team) sends an agent named Laila to the city. The young woman has powerful psychic abilities, which can enhance her firearms, helping her deal with the monsters. She must rescue the survivors and escort them to safety, at any cost...[CR]Shiryo Sensen - War of the Dead is an action game with slight RPG elements. The player navigates Laila over the top-down "world map": the ruined city has basically turned into large wilderness areas with a few buildings that are represented by icons on the map and can be explored. Enemies attack randomly. The battles take place on separate side-scrolling screens, and are fully action-based. Laila can jump, duck, and attack with melee or weapons or firearms (which require ammunition). Typically there are several enemies on the screen; Laila escapes the battle if she reaches the end of the short side-scrolling area. [CR]The goal of the game is to find and rescue the few survivors trapped in the buildings infested by enemies. Laila has to bring these survivors back to the church. Even though the map is almost completely open to the player (especially after Laila acquires a boat, which makes the world fully explorable), the rescuing must be completed in a linear fashion, by talking to characters in different buildings and receiving clues. The game has a day/night cycle; Laila can sleep at any time, which will restore a portion of her health.</plot>
			<genre>Action; Adventure</genre>
			<studio>Fun Project</studio>
			<nplayers>1</nplayers>
			<ESRB>Not Rated</ESRB>
			<videoid>CtaKjYvuueQ</videoid>
			<boxart1>4xWY244.jpg</boxart1>
			<boxart2>HkqPD1i.jpg</boxart2>
			<boxart3>K5kpZUB.jpg</boxart3>
			<boxart4>4ttUR5w.jpg</boxart4>
			<snapshot1>Xkt9yjw.png</snapshot1>
			<snapshot2>MdSbgzk.png</snapshot2>
			<snapshot3>JyAMrid.png</snapshot3>
			<snapshot4>ezJQJzh.png</snapshot4>
		</game>
		<game name="Space Manbow (Japan)">
			<description>Space Manbow (Japan)</description>
			<rom name="No-Intro-Collection_2016-09-06/Microsoft-Msx2.zip/Space%20Manbow%20%28Japan%29.zip" size="159643" />
			<title_clean>Space Manbow</title_clean>
			<plot>In the year 189 of the stellar calendar, humanity happened upon the ruins of an ancient (and, if the st. 7 decor is anything to go by, rather decadent and malicious) civilization, and sent an archaeological crew to explore them. However, the crew managed to activate the ruins' defense system.[CR]The system operated by identifying the Sol system as the intruders' origin, then launched the Sun-Fish ("Manbou" being Japanese for "Sunfish"), an ultimate weapon bio-mechanical starship capable of destroying an entire solar system and protected by an impregnable force-field bubble. The surviving members of the crew, however, find a chance to stop the Sun-Fish. By using an unearthed Manbou-J (i.e. Junior Sun-Fish) fighter and activating a teleportation system in the deepest part of the ruins, one pilot, Cleaver Mule, can actually get inside the force bubble and destroy the Sun-Fish from there.</plot>
			<genre>Shooter</genre>
			<studio>Konami</studio>
			<nplayers>1</nplayers>
			<ESRB>Not Rated</ESRB>
			<videoid>s5OBZcL01bg</videoid>
			<wiki_url>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Space_Manbow</wiki_url>
			<boxart1>LjEmzmO.jpg</boxart1>
			<boxart2>HaGhwoh.jpg</boxart2>
			<boxart3>Dljbvn3.jpg</boxart3>
			<snapshot1>9k0DsY7.png</snapshot1>
			<snapshot2>jDfbEqL.png</snapshot2>
			<snapshot3>dd8Vqsk.png</snapshot3>
			<snapshot4>FoAPKA2.png</snapshot4>
		</game>
		<game name="Star Virgin (Japan)">
			<description>Star Virgin (Japan)</description>
			<rom name="No-Intro-Collection_2016-09-06/Microsoft-Msx2.zip/Star%20Virgin%20%28Japan%29.zip" size="62565" />
			<title_clean>Star Virgin</title_clean>
			<plot>Star Virgins about as obscure as it comes, its a promotional hour long straight to video film from Japan. That was made to promote a little seen videogame of the same name distributed by Activision that only ever appeared on the long forgotten msx system.[CR]Plays out pretty much like a bonkers live action anime movie. Its a camp science fiction fantasy comedy about a girl whose secretly the lone fighter of justice Star Virgin, its her pursuit to stop the planet being attacked from robotic &amp; puppet monsters, giant spiders and whatever else would warrant as being an end of level boss in an 80s video game... at least I think thats the overall idea, because its obviously never been translated into English its hard to totally fathom out what the hells going on, but hey thats the beauty of the Japanese movies right.[CR]Star Virgin herself is every Japanorama fanboys wetdream, shes a cute pink power ranger with her own spacecraft &amp; powerbike and she kicks ass with a bazooka. The whole thing would have made an awesome music video for The Flaming Lips - Yoshimi Battles the Pink Robots (what I'm oddly playing while writing this). Sure its none essential throwaway stuff, but its a fun hour even without knowing what they're saying.[CR][Personal Reasons For Remembering][CR]Really loved the spacecraft scenes complete with their robotic butler drivers and its not every day I get to see a movie featuring a robotic Statue of Liberty and an evil genius who lives on a floating volcanic island.</plot>
			<genre>Action</genre>
			<studio>Marionette</studio>
			<nplayers>1</nplayers>
			<rating>5</rating>
			<ESRB>Not Rated</ESRB>
			<videoid>SuhzEiTkz7Q</videoid>
			<boxart1>Rq04XkD.png</boxart1>
			<snapshot1>9vGDixy.png</snapshot1>
			<snapshot2>tGicPHW.png</snapshot2>
			<snapshot3>pLb8ntl.png</snapshot3>
		</game>
		<game name="Strategic Mars (Japan)">
			<description>Strategic Mars (Japan)</description>
			<rom name="No-Intro-Collection_2016-09-06/Microsoft-Msx2.zip/Strategic%20Mars%20%28Japan%29.zip" size="55068" />
			<title_clean>Strategic Mars</title_clean>
			<plot>Strategic Mars is a shooter from dB-Soft. You start the game from player base, where you can buy upgrades when you get enough points from shooting enemies. At first you can upgrade your engine, repair the ship and get missiles which launch automatically against every enemy wave you face.[CR]You navigate and warp to fight enemies from the map screen, which tells you the difficulty of the enemies. Fuchsia dots have the easiest enemies and red icons the hardest. Once you clear all enemies from the map, you move to the next level. There are 12 levels in total, and you can even start from the last level if you so wish from the start screen, no passwords needed.</plot>
			<genre>Shooter</genre>
			<studio>dB-SOFT</studio>
			<nplayers>1</nplayers>
			<ESRB>Not Rated</ESRB>
			<videoid>CR9PXCZObbM</videoid>
			<boxart1>6Ei3jPF.jpg</boxart1>
			<boxart2>YgcBAo8.jpg</boxart2>
			<snapshot1>phNCTDC.png</snapshot1>
			<snapshot2>UfPRZRM.png</snapshot2>
			<snapshot3>Yy98SQg.png</snapshot3>
		</game>
		<game name="Suikoden - Tenmei no Chikai (Japan)">
			<description>Suikoden - Tenmei no Chikai (Japan)</description>
			<rom name="No-Intro-Collection_2016-09-06/Microsoft-Msx2.zip/Suikoden%20-%20Tenmei%20no%20Chikai%20%28Japan%29.zip" size="295217" />
			<title_clean>Suikoden - Tenmei no Chikai</title_clean>
			<plot>In the 12th century, the Emperor Hui Zhong is faced with an internal rebellion led by Imperial Minister Gao Qiu. The Song Dynasty comes to an end, and Gao Qiu became the new ruler. You take the role of an exiled ruler, and you must build your stats up to be able to challenge- and destroy- Gao Qiu and restore Hui Zhong to the throne.[CR]The game is a military strategy game, like most of Koei's games, but instead of conquering a country, the goal is to depose the despotic ruler of China. You start out lowly, and have to work your way up by conquering smaller prefectures, forming alliances, and fighting small battles. You have to earn the right to attack Gao Qiu's home prefecture, though- he is off limits until you are powerful.</plot>
			<genre>Strategy</genre>
			<studio>Koei</studio>
			<nplayers>1</nplayers>
			<ESRB>Not Rated</ESRB>
			<wiki_url>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bandit_Kings_of_Ancient_China</wiki_url>
			<boxart1>OmYwGSg.jpg</boxart1>
			<boxart2>m15nIZA.jpg</boxart2>
			<boxart3>Dzp2eYK.jpg</boxart3>
			<boxart4>OZwWOn0.jpg</boxart4>
			<boxart5>xLfucgu.jpg</boxart5>
			<boxart6>SeD9FPl.jpg</boxart6>
			<snapshot1>mjqz8Ot.png</snapshot1>
			<snapshot2>Kuk6GB5.png</snapshot2>
		</game>
		<game name="Super Daisenryaku (Japan)">
			<description>Super Daisenryaku (Japan)</description>
			<rom name="No-Intro-Collection_2016-09-06/Microsoft-Msx2.zip/Super%20Daisenryaku%20%28Japan%29.zip" size="112365" />
			<title_clean>Super Daisenryaku</title_clean>
			<plot>Super Daisenryaku is one of the many titles in SystemSoft's long-running war strategy series. The game mechanics are based on Daisenryaku II, but many of the included maps are unique to this release, including several based on Phantasy Star in Sega's console version. There is no campaign mode, and any of the included maps can be played. Some maps are for two players, some for four, and any map can be played with any combination of human and computer players. The computer versions also feature an editor.[CR]The game is played on a large map made up of hexagonal spaces, each of which consists of one of the included terrain types. Each player controls a number of units (bought with money), which each take up one space on the grid. The unit types are for the most part based on real-life military equipment from around the time the game was released, what is available to the player depends on the chosen faction. The choices range from single nations, such as China or the USA (the CD port by Microcabin in particular adds a lot of smaller ones, like Sweden and Libya), to alliances and blocs, for example NATO, which uses a mixture of equipment of it's members. [CR]Different units have different strengths and weaknesses, which affect their performance in combat and their general role on the battlefield. The cheap infantry units for example are not very strong and mobile, but may capture facilities and cities, unlike battle tanks. Terrain also affects the outcome of battles. The goal of each game is to capture the other players' capitals.</plot>
			<genre>Strategy</genre>
			<studio>SystemSoft</studio>
			<nplayers>4</nplayers>
			<ESRB>Not Rated</ESRB>
			<videoid>-nQvb81uXuc</videoid>
			<wiki_url>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Daisenryaku</wiki_url>
			<boxart1>G2rHoV6.jpg</boxart1>
			<boxart2>7qf9DyK.jpg</boxart2>
			<boxart3>2h8YNZ2.jpg</boxart3>
			<boxart4>0ILsk8d.jpg</boxart4>
			<boxart5>8XDFeMw.jpg</boxart5>
			<boxart6>FXUx6b4.jpg</boxart6>
			<snapshot1>rcV0lBO.png</snapshot1>
			<snapshot2>DerPwn4.png</snapshot2>
		</game>
		<game name="Super Load Runner (Japan)">
			<description>Super Load Runner (Japan)</description>
			<rom name="No-Intro-Collection_2016-09-06/Microsoft-Msx2.zip/Super%20Load%20Runner%20%28Japan%29.zip" size="66833" />
			<title_clean>Super Load Runner</title_clean>
			<plot>Between 1984 to 1986, Irem released four more different Lode Runner arcade games in Japan, following the original arcade games release. Stages were culled from these arcade games and were packaged into Super Lode Runner for the MSX. The game also kept the two-player mode from the arcade version.[CR]The game keeps the typical gameplay of the Lode Runner series. Players have to collect all the gold on the stage, while either avoiding or trapping the robotic guards who are constantly giving them chase. The game also features a level editor so players can create their own stages to play on.[CR](This game shouldn't be confused with the NES game of the same title - it contains an entirely different set of stages to play.)</plot>
			<genre>Action; Platform</genre>
			<studio>Irem</studio>
			<nplayers>1-2 Co-Op</nplayers>
			<ESRB>Not Rated</ESRB>
			<videoid>IeF-Szc7OQs</videoid>
			<wiki_url>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Lode_Runner</wiki_url>
			<boxart1>5KQzPiW.jpg</boxart1>
			<boxart2>MMcrCS4.jpg</boxart2>
			<snapshot1>GQOAMPl.png</snapshot1>
			<snapshot2>Fpr9lP6.png</snapshot2>
			<snapshot3>aQeqlvB.png</snapshot3>
			<snapshot4>vwsvZgI.png</snapshot4>
		</game>
		<game name="Super Rambo Special (Japan)">
			<description>Super Rambo Special (Japan)</description>
			<rom name="No-Intro-Collection_2016-09-06/Microsoft-Msx2.zip/Super%20Rambo%20Special%20%28Japan%29.zip" size="58970" />
			<title_clean>Super Rambo Special</title_clean>
			<plot>Super Rambo Special is an action game based on movie Rambo: First Blood Part 2. As in the movie you play the part of one-man-army John Rambo who is busted out of prison by his former CO to go deep into the Vietnamese jungle and rescue a group of P.O.W.s.[CR]You control Rambo from a top-down perspective as he explores the jungle looking for keys and avoiding enemy patrols, the keys allow you to unlock the many huts you will come across in the jungle and must be explored to release the P.O.W.s and gather weapons and munitions in order to raise some hell, as your trusty knife is not going to cut it against all those Vietnamese and Russian soldiers.</plot>
			<genre>Action</genre>
			<studio>Pack-In-Video</studio>
			<nplayers>1</nplayers>
			<ESRB>Not Rated</ESRB>
			<videoid>07pOobIof4E</videoid>
			<wiki_url>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Rambo_(film_series)#Other_media</wiki_url>
			<boxart1>jb83yhN.jpg</boxart1>
			<boxart2>K1kaACd.jpg</boxart2>
			<boxart3>Nlm4Ccl.jpg</boxart3>
			<snapshot1>1WiS0jG.png</snapshot1>
			<snapshot2>DgdTXWI.png</snapshot2>
		</game>
		<game name="Super Runner (Japan)">
			<description>Super Runner (Japan)</description>
			<rom name="No-Intro-Collection_2016-09-06/Microsoft-Msx2.zip/Super%20Runner%20%28Japan%29.zip" size="55456" />
			<title_clean>Super Runner</title_clean>
			<plot>Sports type running game with a twist. This game can be played with two players or against the computer. You need to pick up an object that resembles an American Football and be the first to cross the finish line. The other player needs to try to take the ball from you. For this you can hit and kick each other.[CR]On the first level it is just a straight run, there are no objects or enemies to stop you. But on subsequent levels you will need to avoid varies enemies and use your hitting and kicking to break blocks that are in your way. The blocks can fall on your head which stuns you for a few seconds, likewise if you get hit by an enemy. Get hit too often and you die.</plot>
			<genre>Sports</genre>
			<studio>Pony Canyon</studio>
			<nplayers>2</nplayers>
			<ESRB>Not Rated</ESRB>
			<videoid>jOVwtuV7fz0</videoid>
			<boxart1>ASbeGkx.jpg</boxart1>
			<boxart2>cwMDCU0.jpg</boxart2>
			<boxart3>VxdQwHS.jpg</boxart3>
			<snapshot1>L6kixzC.png</snapshot1>
			<snapshot2>OLadaMA.png</snapshot2>
		</game>
		<game name="Super Tritorn (Japan)">
			<description>Super Tritorn (Japan)</description>
			<rom name="No-Intro-Collection_2016-09-06/Microsoft-Msx2.zip/Super%20Tritorn%20%28Japan%29.zip" size="40195" />
			<title_clean>Super Tritorn</title_clean>
			<plot>The game is a big maze where you need to find objects, primary amongst them seem to be bottles of different colours. The game is laggy, in particular when wielding your weapon. Enemies in the first couple of screens don't seem to do you any real harm. You can kill them typically with a single hit, and you can even walk over them. Killing enemies gives you experience (EXP), and when your experience bar is full your life bar increases (H.P). After a few screens though the enemies suddenly get a lot tougher and can kill you almost immediately.</plot>
			<genre>RPG</genre>
			<studio>Sein Soft</studio>
			<nplayers>1</nplayers>
			<ESRB>Not Rated</ESRB>
			<videoid>vfeUnFW7tSw</videoid>
			<boxart1>6hTNq8V.jpg</boxart1>
			<boxart2>kOgVQG0.jpg</boxart2>
			<boxart3>QGMtkqJ.jpg</boxart3>
			<boxart4>hrvMusL.jpg</boxart4>
			<snapshot1>HOxPKrS.png</snapshot1>
			<snapshot2>BRpvcS3.png</snapshot2>
			<snapshot3>UupeB9k.png</snapshot3>
			<snapshot4>wtNcRuC.png</snapshot4>
			<snapshot5>gYnyxnf.png</snapshot5>
		</game>
		<game name="Taiyou no Shinden - Asteka II (Japan)">
			<description>Taiyou no Shinden - Asteka II (Japan)</description>
			<rom name="No-Intro-Collection_2016-09-06/Microsoft-Msx2.zip/Taiyou%20no%20Shinden%20-%20Asteka%20II%20%28Japan%29.zip" size="167054" />
			<title_clean>Taiyou no Shinden - Asteka II</title_clean>
			<plot>Despite its name (a misspelling of Azteca), the story of Taiyo no Shinden: Asteka II is dedicated to the Maya people, indigenous inhabitants of Southern Mexico and Central America, rather than the Aztecs. The player controls a nameless adventurer who searches for the Sun Key, a mysterious ancient artifact which can unlock the secrets of the Mayan civilization.[CR]Taiyo no Shinden: Asteka II is an adventure game which takes place in the ruins of the ancient city Chichen Itza on the Yucatan peninsula in Mexico. There is a top-down overworld on which the player can physically navigate the protagonist, entering temples and other locations. In such locations, the view switches to first-person perspective. The player interacts with the environment by selecting various verb commands ("Look", "Take", "Use", etc.), represented by icons, from a menu, and combining them with objects on the screen. In spite of its Japanese origins, the game features inventory item usage and puzzle-solving, which are more typical of Western-style adventures.</plot>
			<releasedate>10/12/1987</releasedate>
			<year>1987</year>
			<genre>Adventure</genre>
			<studio>Zap</studio>
			<nplayers>1</nplayers>
			<ESRB>Not Rated</ESRB>
			<videoid>WaqcUgAEw-4</videoid>
			<boxart1>nszWDBL.jpg</boxart1>
			<boxart2>pFZjkcB.jpg</boxart2>
			<boxart3>hqCYkJB.jpg</boxart3>
			<snapshot1>4OBvc3e.png</snapshot1>
			<snapshot2>BWO5pUJ.png</snapshot2>
			<snapshot3>As93k1B.png</snapshot3>
		</game>
		<game name="Teitoku no Ketsudan (Japan)">
			<description>Teitoku no Ketsudan (Japan)</description>
			<rom name="No-Intro-Collection_2016-09-06/Microsoft-Msx2.zip/Teitoku%20no%20Ketsudan%20%28Japan%29.zip" size="474306" />
			<title_clean>Teitoku no Ketsudan</title_clean>
			<plot>Teitoku no Ketsudan is another military sim from KOEI. In this game you can choose to be either Japan or the Allies. By managing your fleets and ordering new warships you can control many different sides of the conflict (Ship development, Base defense, Fleet arrangement, Direct battle control, Economic decisions). There are many different options of play in Teitoku no Ketsudan, you can choose to play from one of many different famous battles or you can play the campaign. You can control one side or both. There are also limited controls on victory conditions.</plot>
			<genre>Strategy</genre>
			<studio>Koei</studio>
			<nplayers>1</nplayers>
			<ESRB>Not Rated</ESRB>
			<videoid>nZplCDtuU3M</videoid>
			<wiki_url>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/P.T.O.</wiki_url>
			<boxart1>QQEdcn7.jpg</boxart1>
			<boxart2>UiLyIKW.jpg</boxart2>
			<boxart3>gFLTYhL.jpg</boxart3>
			<snapshot1>7BbwElS.png</snapshot1>
			<snapshot2>Mk0nFZg.png</snapshot2>
			<snapshot3>3iKzg2j.png</snapshot3>
		</game>
		<game name="Tengoku Yoitoko (Japan)">
			<description>Tengoku Yoitoko (Japan)</description>
			<rom name="No-Intro-Collection_2016-09-06/Microsoft-Msx2.zip/Tengoku%20Yoitoko%20%28Japan%29.zip" size="50664" />
			<title_clean>Tengoku Yoitoko</title_clean>
			<plot>Tengoku Yoitoko is a Role-Playing game, developed and published by Taito, which was released in Japan in 1987.</plot>
			<genre>RPG</genre>
			<studio>Taito</studio>
			<nplayers>1</nplayers>
			<ESRB>Not Rated</ESRB>
			<videoid>-rGNR_TgQC8</videoid>
			<boxart1>bqLaGrz.jpg</boxart1>
			<boxart2>JFziVch.jpg</boxart2>
			<boxart3>zqASLxm.jpg</boxart3>
			<snapshot1>8GoGSkA.png</snapshot1>
			<snapshot2>skBCfE5.png</snapshot2>
			<snapshot3>Q6T5xdo.png</snapshot3>
			<snapshot4>6RZxpoi.png</snapshot4>
		</game>
		<game name="Tetris (Japan)">
			<description>Tetris (Japan)</description>
			<rom name="No-Intro-Collection_2016-09-06/Microsoft-Msx2.zip/Tetris%20%28Japan%29.zip" size="64435" />
			<title_clean>Tetris</title_clean>
			<plot>This version of Tetris is one of many conversions of the famous block-stacking game. The goal is to place pieces made up of four tiles in a ten-by-twenty well, organizing them into complete rows, which then disappear. The goal of each round is to clear 25 lines, after which the player moves on to the next round. If the stack reaches the top of the field, the player loses a life, and if all three lives are lost, the game is over.[CR]The game lets the player choose the starting stage and round, as well as one of three background tunes. Difficulty is increased throughout the stages by an increase in speed and the addition of garbage blocks in the well.</plot>
			<genre>Puzzle</genre>
			<studio>Bullet-Proof Software</studio>
			<nplayers>1</nplayers>
			<ESRB>Not Rated</ESRB>
			<videoid>O6Bfi5wpNnQ</videoid>
			<wiki_url>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Tetris</wiki_url>
			<boxart1>ObXVNWs.jpg</boxart1>
			<boxart2>guKeHUw.jpg</boxart2>
			<boxart3>5r6gqOd.jpg</boxart3>
			<boxart4>eOlJjmp.jpg</boxart4>
			<boxart5>glcX35h.jpg</boxart5>
			<snapshot1>3SOvQZj.png</snapshot1>
			<snapshot2>nXChdrv.png</snapshot2>
			<snapshot3>kGvKlXJ.png</snapshot3>
			<snapshot4>wLi3Thw.png</snapshot4>
			<fanart1>Vdt27HW.jpg</fanart1>
		</game>
		<game name="Topple Zip (Japan)">
			<description>Topple Zip (Japan)</description>
			<rom name="No-Intro-Collection_2016-09-06/Microsoft-Msx2.zip/Topple%20Zip%20%28Japan%29.zip" size="58942" />
			<title_clean>Topple Zip</title_clean>
			<plot>Topple Zip is a vertically scrolling shooter that is marketed as a racing game. The basic premise is that you control an aircraft and fly in competition against several other, computer controlled crafts. In addition to shooting at your opponents, you may ram into them, and they into you. Doing so may dislodge a pill shaped power-up from them which you can then shoot and collect. [CR]Power-ups exist in various types, including defensive and offensive such as giving you better weapons. There are eight different levels, each of which contain a number of warps which link to other levels. How the levels connect is random each time you play the game. [CR]The goal of the game is to locate a key which is necessary to access the warp which leads to the eight and final level. Collect it from whichever level it is hidden inside of, and access the eighth level before any of your competitors.</plot>
			<genre>Shooter</genre>
			<studio>Bothtec</studio>
			<nplayers>1</nplayers>
			<ESRB>Not Rated</ESRB>
			<videoid>5n_wB89DC9s</videoid>
			<boxart1>uiCkgRS.jpg</boxart1>
			<boxart2>LqIcSFB.jpg</boxart2>
			<snapshot1>hQVBzUy.png</snapshot1>
			<snapshot2>Yw7u1g6.png</snapshot2>
		</game>
		<game name="Treasure of Usas, The (Japan, Europe)">
			<description>Treasure of Usas, The (Japan, Europe)</description>
			<rom name="No-Intro-Collection_2016-09-06/Microsoft-Msx2.zip/Treasure%20of%20Usas%2C%20The%20%28Japan%2C%20Europe%29.zip" size="96006" />
			<title_clean>Treasure of Usas, The</title_clean>
			<plot>The Treasure Of Usas is a platform game. Centuries ago, the War God Induras banished Usas, the supreme Mother God, and threw the four pieces of her jewel in the winds. Wit and Cles are attempting to find the broken jewel to try and achieve one of the greatest discoveries of the academic world. Their adventures, controlled by you, will lead them to many strange places to fight many unusual enemies. There are five stages in the game.[CR]There are emotion icons in the game and by touching these icons your player will change emotion. At the top of the screen you can see which emotion you have. This is important because you 'll have to have the same emotion of the demon of the level to fight him.</plot>
			<genre>Platform</genre>
			<studio>Konami</studio>
			<nplayers>1</nplayers>
			<rating>4</rating>
			<ESRB>Not Rated</ESRB>
			<videoid>5Q3DFQzhvwk</videoid>
			<boxart1>ZgpOzQr.jpg</boxart1>
			<boxart2>88lccQi.jpg</boxart2>
			<snapshot1>YOOTqZk.png</snapshot1>
			<snapshot2>BYuktc0.png</snapshot2>
			<fanart1>DGG8CAZ.jpg</fanart1>
			<clearlogo1>AowJW6F.png</clearlogo1>
		</game>
		<game name="Tsurikichi Sanpei - Blue Marine Hen (Japan)">
			<description>Tsurikichi Sanpei - Blue Marine Hen (Japan)</description>
			<rom name="No-Intro-Collection_2016-09-06/Microsoft-Msx2.zip/Tsurikichi%20Sanpei%20-%20Blue%20Marine%20Hen%20%28Japan%29.zip" size="44880" />
			<title_clean>Tsurikichi Sanpei - Blue Marine Hen</title_clean>
			<plot>Tsurikichi Sanpei: Blue Marine Hen is a Sports game, developed and published by Victor Musical Industries, which was released in Japan in 1988.</plot>
			<genre>Sports</genre>
			<studio>Victor Musical Industries</studio>
			<nplayers>1</nplayers>
			<ESRB>Not Rated</ESRB>
			<videoid>U47AXHh-ZgQ</videoid>
			<boxart1>hT3POs4.jpg</boxart1>
			<snapshot1>voVcWkt.png</snapshot1>
			<snapshot2>Bb7XmAf.png</snapshot2>
			<snapshot3>BUtQHVo.png</snapshot3>
		</game>
		<game name="Ultima Exodus (Japan)">
			<description>Ultima Exodus (Japan)</description>
			<rom name="No-Intro-Collection_2016-09-06/Microsoft-Msx2.zip/Ultima%20Exodus%20%28Japan%29.zip" size="97668" />
			<title_clean>Ultima Exodus</title_clean>
			<plot>After the defeat of the evil wizard Mondain and his mistress Minax in the previous two Ultimas, peace has returned to the land of Sorsaria. Times passes and eventually geological disruptions and a resurgence of the monster populace occur, and it is soon learned that Mondain and Minax had conceived a child named Exodus before their death. Now that child has become an adult with the power to avenge the death of his parents. Obviously, it falls upon the hero from Earth to find and stop him.[CR]The third title in the Ultima series was the first to feature a party of adventurers instead of a single player character. The party is created at the beginning of the game by assigning various class combinations and determining the characters' attributes. The game has larger and more detailed towns, populated by NPCs the protagonist can converse with to obtain clues. Like in earlier Ultima games, exploration is divided between top-down overworld locations and first-person 3D dungeons. This installment introduces separate combat screens where player-controlled party fights multiple monsters in a turn-based tile-based system.</plot>
			<genre>RPG</genre>
			<studio>Origin</studio>
			<nplayers>1</nplayers>
			<ESRB>Not Rated</ESRB>
			<videoid>l1B867WP9KQ</videoid>
			<wiki_url>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ultima_III:_Exodus</wiki_url>
			<boxart1>TtQXG8P.jpg</boxart1>
			<boxart2>ZeHBuqh.jpg</boxart2>
			<boxart3>hdyqZ69.jpg</boxart3>
			<boxart4>OkGukSr.jpg</boxart4>
			<boxart5>Qui6GbC.jpg</boxart5>
			<snapshot1>ZwXWq53.png</snapshot1>
			<snapshot2>q6q6RPr.png</snapshot2>
			<snapshot3>2S7di2j.png</snapshot3>
		</game>
		<game name="Urusei Yatsura - Koi no Survival Birthday (Japan)">
			<description>Urusei Yatsura - Koi no Survival Birthday (Japan)</description>
			<rom name="No-Intro-Collection_2016-09-06/Microsoft-Msx2.zip/Urusei%20Yatsura%20-%20Koi%20no%20Survival%20Birthday%20%28Japan%29.zip" size="341216" />
			<title_clean>Urusei Yatsura - Koi no Survival Birthday</title_clean>
			<plot>Urusei Yatsura: Koi no Survival Birthday is an Adventure game, developed and published by Micro Cabin, which was released in Japan in 1987.</plot>
			<genre>Adventure</genre>
			<studio>Micro Cabin</studio>
			<nplayers>1</nplayers>
			<ESRB>Not Rated</ESRB>
			<wiki_url>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Urusei_Yatsura#Other_media</wiki_url>
			<boxart1>lhC8r5I.jpg</boxart1>
			<boxart2>h5m0F2p.jpg</boxart2>
			<boxart3>MjOVafm.jpg</boxart3>
			<snapshot1>51DFbYo.png</snapshot1>
			<snapshot2>9tZBqEg.png</snapshot2>
		</game>
		<game name="Vampire Killer (Japan, Europe)">
			<description>Vampire Killer (Japan, Europe)</description>
			<rom name="No-Intro-Collection_2016-09-06/Microsoft-Msx2.zip/Vampire%20Killer%20%28Japan%2C%20Europe%29.zip" size="77910" />
			<title_clean>Vampire Killer</title_clean>
			<plot>You are young Simon, who has just entered Dracula's Satanic Castle. The world of Dransylvania is in trouble, and you are the one to set it right. You have to fight your way through 18 stages of demons to where Dracula is hiding. Once you have destroyed Dracula, the evil force behind all the trouble will show up, attempting to destroy you! Destroy this menace, and Dransylvania will return to it's happy days after a wait of hundreds of years.[CR]Vampire Killer follows the same plot as Castlevania, but with a different gameplay. At each stage, Simon has to find a white key to open the exit door which leads to the next stage. The keys are usually hidden in the castle's walls, in which he will also find useful items. Items can also be found by whipping candles and other sources of light inside the castle.</plot>
			<releasedate>30/10/1986</releasedate>
			<year>1986</year>
			<genre>Action; Adventure; Platform</genre>
			<studio>Konami</studio>
			<nplayers>1</nplayers>
			<rating>4</rating>
			<ESRB>Not Rated</ESRB>
			<videoid>6</videoid>
			<wiki_url>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Vampire_Killer</wiki_url>
			<boxart1>EKweHp8.jpg</boxart1>
			<boxart2>5x7hJjD.jpg</boxart2>
			<boxart3>zDdEZRe.jpg</boxart3>
			<snapshot1>bzEIjWI.png</snapshot1>
			<snapshot2>VGx9tvL.png</snapshot2>
			<fanart1>IPKgB14.jpg</fanart1>
			<clearlogo1>VPzJWLy.png</clearlogo1>
		</game>
		<game name="Victorious Nine II - Koukou Yakyuu Hen (Japan)">
			<description>Victorious Nine II - Koukou Yakyuu Hen (Japan)</description>
			<rom name="No-Intro-Collection_2016-09-06/Microsoft-Msx2.zip/Victorious%20Nine%20II%20-%20Koukou%20Yakyuu%20Hen%20%28Japan%29.zip" size="46134" />
			<title_clean>Victorious Nine II - Koukou Yakyuu Hen</title_clean>
			<plot>Victorious Nine II is a baseball game where you can pitch, hit, field, and run just like in a real baseball game. You can choose your own team and players line up, the stadium you want to play. In the 1-player mode, you play against the computer. The 2-player mode consist of 2 game play choices: opponent mode (you against a friend) or computer mode (the two of you against the computer).</plot>
			<genre>Sports</genre>
			<studio>Taito</studio>
			<nplayers>1-2 Co-Op</nplayers>
			<ESRB>Not Rated</ESRB>
			<videoid>iySt_hDQvgA</videoid>
			<boxart1>6SvrAyQ.jpg</boxart1>
			<snapshot1>i3hIlb0.png</snapshot1>
			<snapshot2>dCSAbnc.png</snapshot2>
			<snapshot3>M93jEp6.png</snapshot3>
			<snapshot4>asZ50Lt.png</snapshot4>
		</game>
		<game name="Woody Poco (Japan)">
			<description>Woody Poco (Japan)</description>
			<rom name="No-Intro-Collection_2016-09-06/Microsoft-Msx2.zip/Woody%20Poco%20%28Japan%29.zip" size="80735" />
			<title_clean>Woody Poco</title_clean>
			<plot>Woody Poco is a side-scrolling action role-playing game similar to Mystical Ninja.[CR]The player controls an old wooden figure named "Poco." He is a hero who has lived in harmony with humans for many years. For Poco, the journey is to find the fairy who teaches people to get back to being friendly with wooden dolls. Enemies encountered through the game are strange creatures and bothersome old men. The player attacks by using his fists at them. Players can steal the items in the store. But after stealing, the player's appearance is changed to resemble that of a thief. Hotels and pawn shops can no longer admit the player for the remainder of the game after a theft has taken place.[CR]The player can equip one hand with a weapon, and the other with a passive tool, such as a lamp for dark areas. The player can buy gear, sleep at hotels, gamble, steal, and bribe non-player characters. The player needs to eat to prevent hunger, with recharging health based on food level. It features an in-game clock, with day/night cycles and four seasons; the color changes to reflect the time of day and the season.</plot>
			<genre>Action; Role-Playing</genre>
			<studio>dB-SOFT</studio>
			<nplayers>1</nplayers>
			<ESRB>Not Rated</ESRB>
			<videoid>-D564OrUxmg</videoid>
			<wiki_url>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Woody_Poco</wiki_url>
			<boxart1>cf9x03I.jpg</boxart1>
			<snapshot1>czqDgrM.png</snapshot1>
			<snapshot2>lhHq72W.png</snapshot2>
			<snapshot3>hMe1hTK.png</snapshot3>
		</game>
		<game name="Xevious - Fardraut Saga (Japan)">
			<description>Xevious - Fardraut Saga (Japan)</description>
			<rom name="No-Intro-Collection_2016-09-06/Microsoft-Msx2.zip/Xevious%20-%20Fardraut%20Saga%20%28Japan%29.zip" size="84787" />
			<title_clean>Xevious - Fardraut Saga</title_clean>
			<plot>Xevious: Fardraut Saga is a vertically-scrolling shooter that contains two modes: Recon and Scramble. The Recon mode is a port of the arcade game Xevious; the Scramble mode can be considered its sequel, adding sixteen new stages, enemies, and boss battles, as the brave fighter pilots continue to defend the Earth against its former inhabitants, who migrated to the planet Xevious thousands of years ago and are now determined to re-capture their ancestral homeland.[CR]The game's Scramble mode allows the player to control three other aircrafts in addition to the seris' trademark Solvalou, each possessing unique weapons. These aircrafts include Solgrado (armed with spread shot), Zeodalley (twin back fire), and Gampmission, a large ship that is also a combination of the previous three, with massive firepower and enhanced lock-on abilities. A specific aircraft can be assigned to each of the player's "lives". The amount of points needed to gather an extra life increases if the player selects more powerful ships. Also, enemies become progressively harder as the controlled aircraft collects power-ups.</plot>
			<releasedate>23/12/1988</releasedate>
			<year>1988</year>
			<genre>Shooter</genre>
			<studio>Compile</studio>
			<nplayers>1</nplayers>
			<ESRB>Not Rated</ESRB>
			<videoid>rZKCjky9dp4</videoid>
			<wiki_url>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Xevious:_Fardraut_Saga</wiki_url>
			<boxart1>5f6tDpq.jpg</boxart1>
			<boxart2>YFeu4ND.jpg</boxart2>
			<boxart3>dDCave5.jpg</boxart3>
			<boxart4>kvm1ZHD.jpg</boxart4>
			<snapshot1>MQwYyWD.png</snapshot1>
			<snapshot2>UyHGR38.png</snapshot2>
			<snapshot3>c9TWBR7.png</snapshot3>
		</game>
		<game name="Yaksa (Japan)">
			<description>Yaksa (Japan)</description>
			<rom name="No-Intro-Collection_2016-09-06/Microsoft-Msx2.zip/Yaksa%20%28Japan%29.zip" size="137442" />
			<title_clean>Yaksa</title_clean>
			<plot>Yaksa is an Action Role-Playing game, developed and published by Wolf Team, which was released in Japan in 1987.</plot>
			<genre>Action; Role-Playing</genre>
			<studio>Wolf Team</studio>
			<nplayers>1</nplayers>
			<ESRB>Not Rated</ESRB>
			<videoid>d2r5_9q8ucw</videoid>
			<boxart1>AGS58JT.jpg</boxart1>
			<boxart2>YOMleRt.jpg</boxart2>
			<snapshot1>AItph7Q.png</snapshot1>
			<snapshot2>5Ma4OTz.png</snapshot2>
			<snapshot3>oThjyfD.png</snapshot3>
		</game>
		<game name="Yuurei-kun (Japan)">
			<description>Yuurei-kun (Japan)</description>
			<rom name="No-Intro-Collection_2016-09-06/Microsoft-Msx2.zip/Yuurei-kun%20%28Japan%29.zip" size="72893" />
			<title_clean>Yuurei-kun</title_clean>
			<plot>Yuurei-kun is an Action game, developed and published by System Sacom, which was released in Japan in 1988.</plot>
			<genre>Action</genre>
			<studio>System Sacom</studio>
			<nplayers>1</nplayers>
			<ESRB>Not Rated</ESRB>
			<videoid>pLTVAsW4qR4</videoid>
			<boxart1>E4M75CO.jpg</boxart1>
			<boxart2>BXwG90j.jpg</boxart2>
			<snapshot1>fryeT1B.png</snapshot1>
			<snapshot2>UXgOwPJ.png</snapshot2>
			<snapshot3>viYqL0C.png</snapshot3>
		</game>
		<game name="Zanac Ex (Japan)">
			<description>Zanac Ex (Japan)</description>
			<rom name="No-Intro-Collection_2016-09-06/Microsoft-Msx2.zip/Zanac%20Ex%20%28Japan%29.zip" size="53769" />
			<title_clean>Zanac Ex</title_clean>
			<plot>Zanax EX is an enhanced version of the vertically scrolling shooter Zanac A.I.. While preserving the locations and the gameplay system of the original version, this release builds upon the graphical enhancements of the Famicom/NES version of Zanac A.I..[CR]The backgrounds are noticeably more detailed than in the original version; also, some locations have different graphical design. The scrolling is also smoother than in the previous releases, effectively altering the feeling of control and gameplay speed. The status bar, which has occupied the right side of the screen in the original release, has been moved to the top of the screen, occupying significantly less space.</plot>
			<genre>Shooter</genre>
			<studio>Compile</studio>
			<nplayers>1</nplayers>
			<ESRB>Not Rated</ESRB>
			<videoid>neBHzceGUbI</videoid>
			<wiki_url>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Zanac</wiki_url>
			<boxart1>rdR8ZVH.jpg</boxart1>
			<boxart2>tYtdBMz.jpg</boxart2>
			<boxart3>fsc9boc.jpg</boxart3>
			<snapshot1>DXJVhzl.png</snapshot1>
			<snapshot2>Tif7f09.png</snapshot2>
			<snapshot3>aGWU8ol.png</snapshot3>
			<clearlogo1>CRwPR8O.png</clearlogo1>
		</game>
		<game name="Zoids - Chuuou Tairiku no Tatakai (Japan)">
			<description>Zoids - Chuuou Tairiku no Tatakai (Japan)</description>
			<rom name="No-Intro-Collection_2016-09-06/Microsoft-Msx2.zip/Zoids%20-%20Chuuou%20Tairiku%20no%20Tatakai%20%28Japan%29.zip" size="69164" />
			<title_clean>Zoids - Chuuou Tairiku no Tatakai</title_clean>
			<plot>Zoids: Chuuou Tairiku no Tatakai is a Role-Playing game, developed by Micronics and published by Toshiba EMI, which was released in Japan in 1988.</plot>
			<genre>RPG</genre>
			<studio>Micronics</studio>
			<nplayers>1</nplayers>
			<ESRB>Not Rated</ESRB>
			<videoid>VJNULraHoSU</videoid>
			<boxart1>wmiOxPd.jpg</boxart1>
			<boxart2>IBxJ47W.jpg</boxart2>
			<boxart3>SlfCp9Q.jpg</boxart3>
			<snapshot1>Mqbybjp.png</snapshot1>
			<snapshot2>PKRCuVK.png</snapshot2>
			<snapshot3>Yv2sfO1.png</snapshot3>
			<snapshot4>xKlDZAr.png</snapshot4>
		</game>
		<game name="Zombie Hunter (Japan)">
			<description>Zombie Hunter (Japan)</description>
			<rom name="No-Intro-Collection_2016-09-06/Microsoft-Msx2.zip/Zombie%20Hunter%20%28Japan%29.zip" size="57047" />
			<title_clean>Zombie Hunter</title_clean>
			<plot>The city of Palma has always been protected by the spirits of the four elements. However, Dolgo, the spirit of the earth, revolts and makes off with the Life Seeker, the controller of the world's life energies, to his underground lair. In doing so, the people of Palma begin to lose their very souls. The spirit of the air has ordered that a champion needs to be found, to retrieve the Life Seeker from the clutches of Dolgo. You are that champion.[CR]Zombie Hunter is an action role-playing game, somewhat similar to Zelda II with its side-scrolling battles. You receive experience from defeating your enemies and you have an inventory complete with armor and weapons.</plot>
			<genre>Action; Role-Playing</genre>
			<studio>Hi-Score Software</studio>
			<nplayers>1</nplayers>
			<ESRB>Not Rated</ESRB>
			<videoid>zdyifJ-EDbA</videoid>
			<boxart1>Pwuf9xY.jpg</boxart1>
			<snapshot1>sr3pJWJ.png</snapshot1>
			<snapshot2>EDdhdAf.png</snapshot2>
		</game>
		<game name="Zukkoke Yajikita Onmitsu Douchuu (Japan)">
			<description>Zukkoke Yajikita Onmitsu Douchuu (Japan)</description>
			<rom name="No-Intro-Collection_2016-09-06/Microsoft-Msx2.zip/Zukkoke%20Yajikita%20Onmitsu%20Douchuu%20%28Japan%29.zip" size="53315" />
			<title_clean>Zukkoke Yajikita Onmitsu Douchuu</title_clean>
			<plot>Zukkoke Yajikita Onmitsu Douchuu is an Action game, developed and published by HAL Laboratory, which was released in Japan in 1987.</plot>
			<genre>Action</genre>
			<studio>HAL Laboratory</studio>
			<nplayers>1</nplayers>
			<ESRB>Not Rated</ESRB>
			<videoid>UBqSB4IbttY</videoid>
			<boxart1>mK5Ttwz.jpg</boxart1>
			<boxart2>mtZHvKQ.jpg</boxart2>
			<snapshot1>NR2DaFE.png</snapshot1>
			<snapshot2>arTIgrD.png</snapshot2>
			<snapshot3>vdO6SaN.png</snapshot3>
		</game>
</datafile>