<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<datafile>
	<header>
		<emu_name>Naomi</emu_name>
		<emu_description>Arcade</emu_description>
		<emu_category>Arcade</emu_category>
		<emu_version>032021</emu_version>
		<emu_date>02/02/2020</emu_date>
		<emu_author>Zach Morris</emu_author>
		<emu_visibility>visible</emu_visibility>
		<emu_homepage>http://archive.org</emu_homepage>
		<emu_baseurl>https://archive.org/download/</emu_baseurl>
		<emu_launcher>retroplayer</emu_launcher>
		<emu_default_addon>none</emu_default_addon>
		<emu_ext_launch_cmd>none</emu_ext_launch_cmd>
		<emu_downloadpath>default</emu_downloadpath>
		<emu_postdlaction>unzip_and_launch_file</emu_postdlaction>
		<emu_comment>The NAOMI (New Arcade Operation Machine Idea) is the successor to the Sega Model 3. Sega first demonstrated NAOMI publicly at the 1998 Amusement Machine Show (an annual trade show hosted in Tokyo by the Japan Amusement Machinery Manufacturers Association). After the show, Sega released the first NAOMI title to the Japanese market: The House of the Dead 2.[CR]NAOMI uses some of the same electronic components as the Dreamcast home game console.  However, NAOMI has twice as much system memory, twice as much video memory, and four times as much sound memory.[CR]Some NAOMI titles read game data from a GD-ROM optical disc, which is also the Dreamcast software medium. Game data can also be stored in a 168-megabyte bank of solid-state ROM. GD-ROM support requires a specialized DIMM board in addition to the GD-ROM drive.[CR]A modified version of the NAOMI was used for the Sammy Atomiswave.</emu_comment>
		<emu_thumb>vrR0RcE.jpg</emu_thumb>
		<emu_banner>Nwz95k4.jpg</emu_banner>
		<emu_fanart>tLbaXoN.jpg</emu_fanart>
		<emu_logo>x7CFqy3.png</emu_logo>
		<emu_trailer>l5Q4wogpMjQ</emu_trailer>
	</header>
	<game name="18 Wheeler (deluxe, Rev A)">
		<description>18 Wheeler (deluxe, Rev A)</description>
		<rom name="naomi_non_merged/18wheelr_folder.zip" size="110458375"/>
		<emu_command>18wheelr/18wheelr.zip</emu_command>
		<plot>18 Wheeler: American Pro Trucker (also known as just 18 Wheeler) is an arcade game developed by Sega AM2 and distributed by Sega. The game was first released in arcades in 2000, then ported to the Dreamcast in 2001. It was later released for the PlayStation 2 in 2001 and Nintendo GameCube in 2002 by Acclaim Entertainment. Sega followed up on the success of 18 Wheeler with a sequel, The King of Route 66, which was released in the arcades around 2002 and ported to the PlayStation 2. This was one of the final arcade video games ports to be on the Dreamcast after its discontinuation before Sega became a third party developer.</plot>
		<releasedate>26/07/2000</releasedate>
		<year>2000</year>
		<studio>Sega AM2</studio>
		<nplayers>1</nplayers>
		<ESRB>AAMA - Green (Suitable For All Ages)</ESRB>
		<boxart1>6etjyTN.jpg</boxart1>
		<boxart2>W1NlbuM.png</boxart2>
		<clearlogo1>Zxuzt01.png</clearlogo1>
		<genre>Driving</genre>
	</game>
	<game name="Alien Front (Rev T)">
		<description>Alien Front (Rev T)</description>
		<rom name="naomi_non_merged/alienfnt_folder.zip" size="48096725"/>
		<emu_command>alienfnt/alienfnt.zip</emu_command>
		<plot>Alien Front is a video game released for Sega NAOMI arcade hardware in 2001. It is a team-based vehicluar combat game. In its original form, Alien Front was not brought to home consoles, however it was retooled and given an online focus in the form of Alien Front Online for the Sega Dreamcast. It is suspected both games are largely identical, with this arcade version merely relying on local multiplayer as opposed to battles played over the internet.</plot>
		<year>2001</year>
		<studio>WOW Entertainment</studio>
		<nplayers>2</nplayers>
		<ESRB>AAMA - Yellow (Animated Violence Mild)</ESRB>
		<boxart1>ayfbatb.jpg</boxart1>
		<boxart2>cCRZ6OJ.png</boxart2>
		<boxart3>BIzbWVr.jpg</boxart3>
		<snapshot1>UEK5HKE.png</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>h3viUua.png</snapshot2>
		<banner1>ylgcr90.png</banner1>
		<genre>Action,Shooter</genre>
	</game>
	<game name="Airline Pilots (World, Rev B)">
		<description>Airline Pilots (World, Rev B)</description>
		<rom name="naomi_non_merged/alpilot_folder.zip" size="43289716"/>
		<emu_command>alpilot/alpilot.zip</emu_command>
		<plot>Airline Pilots is a flight simulator released for Sega NAOMI arcade hardware in 1999. The game simulates flying a Boeing 777 aircraft, and was developed with the input of engineers and pilots from Japan Airlines. Two different cabinet models were manufactured. The default type is a typical sit down cabinet with one monitor, while the "DX type" cabinet features three side-by-side 29" monitors, which surround the player to create a "cockpit".[CR]The extreme difficulty of "Airline Pilots", combined with a lack of interest in realistic flight simulators, led Sega to manufacture a conversion kit which allowed owners to convert the units into the more popular Sega Strike Fighter. As a result, Airline Pilots cabinets are relatively rare.</plot>
		<releasedate>01/01/1999</releasedate>
		<year>1999</year>
		<studio>Sega</studio>
		<nplayers>1</nplayers>
		<ESRB>Not Rated</ESRB>
		<boxart1>eMNaGZJ.jpg</boxart1>
		<boxart2>dCiwfx1.png</boxart2>
		<boxart3>1uI7hLr.png</boxart3>
		<snapshot1>ljqcM9k.png</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>ojtsMbV.png</snapshot2>
		<banner1>uiMhcg5.png</banner1>
		<genre>Flight Simulator,Flying</genre>
	</game>
	<game name="Asian Dynamite / Dynamite Deka EX">
		<description>Asian Dynamite / Dynamite Deka EX</description>
		<rom name="naomi_non_merged/asndynmt_folder.zip" size="155152815"/>
		<emu_command>asndynmt/asndynmt.zip</emu_command>
		<plot>Asian Dynamite is a Sega NAOMI arcade beat-'em-up game. It is known as Dynamite Deka EX in Japan, and is a direct sequel to Dynamite Deka, meaning in its localised form, Asian Dynamite is a direct sequel to Die Hard Arcade, with the references to the movie franchise removed.[CR]The game has not been ported to home platforms, nor has it even seen a US release. It is extremely similar to Dynamite Cop in design, simply sporting an updated Asian aesthetic and replacing Jean Ivy and Eddie Brown with Caroline Powell and Jennifer Genuine, respectively. Caroline is the president's daughter from the first game grown up.</plot>
		<releasedate>30/07/2007</releasedate>
		<year>2007</year>
		<studio>Sega</studio>
		<nplayers>1-2 Co-Op</nplayers>
		<ESRB>T - Teen</ESRB>
		<videoid>gL3uyK70FEs</videoid>
		<boxart1>k6PU0WN.png</boxart1>
		<boxart2>5Z2DW3s.jpg</boxart2>
		<boxart3>u8GHsPs.png</boxart3>
		<snapshot1>G46gvyJ.png</snapshot1>
		<clearlogo1>Gat3wXZ.png</clearlogo1>
		<fanart1>dL1fJNV.jpg</fanart1>
		<genre>Action,Beat Em Up,Fighter</genre>
	</game>
	<game name="Akatsuki Blitzkampf Ausf. Achse (Japan)">
		<description>Akatsuki Blitzkampf Ausf. Achse (Japan)</description>
		<rom name="naomi_non_merged/ausfache_folder.zip" size="79038773"/>
		<emu_command>ausfache/ausfache.zip</emu_command>
		<plot>Akatsuki Blitzkampf Ausf Achse is based upon the original Akatsuki Blitzkampf Japanese PC dojin 2D fighting game from SUBTLE STYLE which was originally released on the 30th April 2007. The original PC game got a lot of attention in Japan for its high-resolution sprites and older style gameplay similar to that of the older Samurai Showdown in the way that you can parry. This Naomi arcade release features improved graphics as well as an extra character going under the name of Perfect.</plot>
		<releasedate>20/02/2008</releasedate>
		<year>2008</year>
		<studio>Subtle Style</studio>
		<nplayers>2</nplayers>
		<ESRB>E - Everyone</ESRB>
		<boxart1>xCvWjWq.jpg</boxart1>
		<boxart2>miT9Mrt.jpg</boxart2>
		<boxart3>Ih7ssn6.jpg</boxart3>
		<snapshot1>F5VeVLJ.png</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>ng3DXBT.jpg</snapshot2>
		<banner1>UExda7A.png</banner1>
		<genre>Fighter</genre>
		<groups>Akatsuki Blitzkampf series</groups>
	</game>
	<game name="Azumanga Daioh Puzzle Bobble (GDL-0018)">
		<description>Azumanga Daioh Puzzle Bobble (GDL-0018)</description>
		<rom name="naomi_non_merged/azumanga_folder.zip" size="88996498"/>
		<emu_command>azumanga/azumanga.zip</emu_command>
		<plot>Azumanga Daioh Puzzle Bobble is a game based on the Azumanga Daioh anime and manga which was released by Taito Corporation as an arcade-only Puzzle Bobble spin-off on June 1, 2002. It was developed by MOSS for the Sega NAOMI GD-ROM arcade and distributed in Japan exclusively. It also has a two-player mode and the original voice actors from the Azumanga Daioh anime reprise their roles. It is controlled using one joystick and two buttons</plot>
		<releasedate>01/01/2002</releasedate>
		<year>2002</year>
		<studio>MOSS (Taito license)</studio>
		<nplayers>2</nplayers>
		<ESRB>E - Everyone</ESRB>
		<boxart1>4XUToJ2.png</boxart1>
		<boxart2>2f5DvKT.jpg</boxart2>
		<boxart3>yzar7Hj.jpg</boxart3>
		<snapshot1>Rr3elxt.png</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>lUxtEiI.png</snapshot2>
		<banner1>RFPhaIa.png</banner1>
		<clearlogo1>uylXEmR.png</clearlogo1>
		<genre>Puzzle</genre>
		<groups>Bust-A-Move / Puzzle Bobble variants</groups>
	</game>
	<game name="Border Down (Rev A) (GDL-0023A)">
		<description>Border Down (Rev A) (GDL-0023A)</description>
		<rom name="naomi_non_merged/bdrdown_folder.zip" size="211449120"/>
		<emu_command>bdrdown/bdrdown.zip</emu_command>
		<plot>Border Down is a horizontally scrolling shoot 'em up video game developed by G.rev and released in Japanese arcades in 2003. It is a spiritual sequel to Metal Black, a favorite game of creator Hiroyuki Maruyama. As with most other Sega NAOMI titles, the game was later released on the Dreamcast in September 2003 in two incarnations: a normal edition, and a limited edition that came bundled with a music CD and alternative cover art. Border Down was G.rev's second independent game (though they did subcontracted work on other titles, most notably Ikaruga and Gradius V), released after Sega's official discontinuation of the Dreamcast console.</plot>
		<releasedate>20/09/2003</releasedate>
		<year>2004</year>
		<studio>G.Rev</studio>
		<nplayers>1</nplayers>
		<ESRB>AAMA - Green (Suitable For All Ages)</ESRB>
		<boxart1>TvPYFWU.jpg</boxart1>
		<boxart2>DRRZ4Rf.png</boxart2>
		<boxart3>Z2iilMp.jpg</boxart3>
		<snapshot1>BBF0mFz.png</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>oNouYRy.png</snapshot2>
		<banner1>t5ETIpC.png</banner1>
		<clearlogo1>vrtzME7.png</clearlogo1>
		<genre>Shooter</genre>
	</game>
	<game name="Capcom Vs. SNK Millennium Fight 2000 (Rev C)">
		<description>Capcom Vs. SNK Millennium Fight 2000 (Rev C)</description>
		<rom name="naomi_non_merged/capsnk_folder.zip" size="100195690"/>
		<emu_command>capsnk/capsnk.zip</emu_command>
		<plot>Capcom vs. SNK: Millennium Fight 2000 (カプコン バーサス エス・エヌ・ケイ ミレニアムファイト 2000, Kapukon Bāsasu Es-Enu-Kei Mireniamu Faito Nisen), also known as simply Capcom vs. SNK in international releases, is a 2000 head-to-head fighting game produced by Capcom originally released as a coin-operated arcade game for Sega's NAOMI hardware and later ported to the Dreamcast. It is the second game in the SNK vs. Capcom series and the first game in the series to be released for the arcades.</plot>
		<releasedate>13/08/2000</releasedate>
		<year>2000</year>
		<studio>Capcom</studio>
		<nplayers>2</nplayers>
		<ESRB>Not Rated</ESRB>
		<videoid>YW_sP-DX_3g</videoid>
		<boxart1>CDzBvTB.jpg</boxart1>
		<boxart2>tm3Uhgf.jpg</boxart2>
		<boxart3>D4iQ2Mm.jpg</boxart3>
		<genre>Fighter</genre>
		<groups>Capcom vs. SNK series,Franchise crossovers</groups>
	</game>
	<game name="Chaos Field (Japan) (GDL-0025)">
		<description>Chaos Field (Japan) (GDL-0025)</description>
		<rom name="naomi_non_merged/cfield_folder.zip" size="148042694"/>
		<emu_command>cfield/cfield.zip</emu_command>
		<plot>The technological advancements of mankind discover a dimension of absolute chaos that its discoverers soon called the Chaos Field. Upon its discovery, the overly destructive inhabitants of the Chaos Field, known as the Abo, invaded Earth which is considered the Orderfield. The war raged so long that special pilots were selected to fly the best star fighters equipped with trans-dimensional technology to combat the Abo and save the Orderfield.</plot>
		<releasedate>01/06/2004</releasedate>
		<year>2004</year>
		<studio>Able Corporation</studio>
		<nplayers>1</nplayers>
		<ESRB>E - Everyone</ESRB>
		<boxart1>pCLj4TF.jpg</boxart1>
		<boxart2>ezIAGlS.jpg</boxart2>
		<boxart3>6vEDD0T.png</boxart3>
		<snapshot1>DqORd6F.png</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>g0fbmil.png</snapshot2>
		<clearlogo1>t4aHa2H.png</clearlogo1>
		<genre>Driving,Shooter</genre>
	</game>
	<game name="Musapey's Choco Marker (Rev A) (GDL-0014A)">
		<description>Musapey's Choco Marker (Rev A) (GDL-0014A)</description>
		<rom name="naomi_non_merged/chocomk_folder.zip" size="69939405"/>
		<emu_command>chocomk/chocomk.zip</emu_command>
		<plot>Musapey's Choco Marker is a Puzzle game, developed and published by Ecole, which was released in Japan in 2002.</plot>
		<year>2002</year>
		<studio>Ecole</studio>
		<nplayers>2</nplayers>
		<ESRB>Not Rated</ESRB>
		<boxart1>hJOpE7L.png</boxart1>
		<boxart2>1rL5oWA.png</boxart2>
		<boxart3>DIPuoFu.png</boxart3>
		<snapshot1>dYwSq9t.png</snapshot1>
		<banner1>FmU1fMc.png</banner1>
		<clearlogo1>NwZZGRs.png</clearlogo1>
		<genre>Puzzle</genre>
	</game>
	<game name="Cleopatra Fortune Plus (GDL-0012)">
		<description>Cleopatra Fortune Plus (GDL-0012)</description>
		<rom name="naomi_non_merged/cleoftp_folder.zip" size="67196147"/>
		<emu_command>cleoftp/cleoftp.zip</emu_command>
		<plot>Cleopatra Fortune Plus (クレオパトラフォーチュン プラス) is a puzzle game developed by Altron and published by Taito for the Sega NAOMI arcade system. It is the sequel to Taito's 1997 game Cleopatra Fortune.[CR]The gameplay is similar to Tetris, but here the player has to direct blocks of stone and treasure to create closures, which then eliminates the treasure and adds to the player's score. Also, if a full line of stone blocks is formed, they will disappear in a similar fashion to Tetris, and also add to the player's score. The game's name comes from its mascot, which is a super deformed version of the ancient Egyptian queen Cleopatra. Additionally, the game utilizes an Egyptian theme. [CR]Cleopatra Fortune Plus was released 2002, on the Sega NAOMI system.</plot>
		<releasedate>01/01/1996</releasedate>
		<year>1996</year>
		<studio>Altron</studio>
		<nplayers>2</nplayers>
		<ESRB>Not Rated</ESRB>
		<boxart1>Q9UhUC5.jpg</boxart1>
		<boxart2>F6m3hWE.jpg</boxart2>
		<boxart3>5W1bkg0.png</boxart3>
		<snapshot1>c5hx39j.png</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>UeodVZt.png</snapshot2>
		<genre>Puzzle</genre>
	</game>
	<game name="Confidential Mission (GDS-0001)">
		<description>Confidential Mission (GDS-0001)</description>
		<rom name="naomi_non_merged/confmiss_folder.zip" size="130812513"/>
		<emu_command>confmiss/confmiss.zip</emu_command>
		<plot>Confidential Mission is a light gun game published by Sega, first available as an arcade game, then ported to the Dreamcast. The game is in the same style as the Virtua Cop series or The House of the Dead series, with support for one or two players. The game was developed by Sega's Hitmaker development team and first released in 2000. Its plot is of the same vein as James Bond and Mission: Impossible. Despite it also having an arcade release, it never enjoyed the popularity of the Virtua Cop nor The House of the Dead series, which were also produced by Sega.</plot>
		<releasedate>01/11/2000</releasedate>
		<year>2000</year>
		<studio>Hitmaker</studio>
		<nplayers>2</nplayers>
		<ESRB>Not Rated</ESRB>
		<videoid>gXj2n7isfNg</videoid>
		<boxart1>cNLhuSl.png</boxart1>
		<boxart2>0Tl9kkQ.jpg</boxart2>
		<boxart3>6VscHav.jpg</boxart3>
		<snapshot1>mefwotJ.png</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>lUssa4f.png</snapshot2>
		<banner1>1nqwnsD.png</banner1>
		<genre>Shooter</genre>
		<groups>Games referenced in movies</groups>
	</game>
	<game name="Crackin' DJ">
		<description>Crackin' DJ</description>
		<rom name="naomi_non_merged/crackndj_folder.zip" size="113260608"/>
		<emu_command>crackndj/crackndj.zip</emu_command>
		<plot>Crackin' DJ</plot>
		<year>2000</year>
		<studio>Sega</studio>
		<nplayers>1</nplayers>
		<ESRB>Not Rated</ESRB>
		<genre>Music,Rhythm</genre>
	</game>
	<game name="Crackin' DJ Part 2 (Japan)">
		<description>Crackin' DJ Part 2 (Japan)</description>
		<rom name="naomi_non_merged/crakndj2_folder.zip" size="110578632"/>
		<emu_command>crakndj2/crakndj2.zip</emu_command>
		<studio>Sega</studio>
		<ESRB>Not Rated</ESRB>
		<genre>Music</genre>
	</game>
	<game name="Crazy Taxi">
		<description>Crazy Taxi</description>
		<rom name="naomi_non_merged/crzytaxi_folder.zip" size="65321196"/>
		<emu_command>crzytaxi/crzytaxi.zip</emu_command>
		<plot>Crazy Taxi is a series of score attack racing video games that was developed by Hitmaker and published by Sega. The first game appeared in arcades in 1999 and was very successful, prompting Sega to port the arcade version to their Dreamcast console in 2000. It is the third best-selling Dreamcast game in the United States, selling over a million copies. The game was later ported to the PlayStation 2, Nintendo GameCube, and PC with sequels also appearing on the Xbox, Game Boy Advance, and PlayStation Portable systems.</plot>
		<releasedate>01/02/1999</releasedate>
		<year>1999</year>
		<nplayers>1</nplayers>
		<ESRB>E10+ - Everyone 10+</ESRB>
		<videoid>qjIGkv0_dEM</videoid>
		<boxart1>JkTnABk.jpg</boxart1>
		<boxart2>bnF8bSf.jpg</boxart2>
		<boxart3>jmqcXeZ.png</boxart3>
		<snapshot1>7tc9BcW.png</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>QcMCkgd.png</snapshot2>
		<banner1>btgiZVJ.png</banner1>
		<genre>Driving,Racing</genre>
		<groups>Crazy Taxi series,Genre: Open world driving,Middleware: CRI,Nintendo Player's Choice releases,PlayStation 2 Greatest Hits releases,PlayStation 2 Platinum Range releases,SEGA Forever series,Taxi games</groups>
	</game>
	<game name="Cosmic Smash (Rev A)">
		<description>Cosmic Smash (Rev A)</description>
		<rom name="naomi_non_merged/csmash_folder.zip" size="44847330"/>
		<emu_command>csmash/csmash.zip</emu_command>
		<plot>Cosmic Smash is an arcade game that was later ported to the Dreamcast console. It is a futuristic combination of squash and Breakout, and is a single player game.</plot>
		<releasedate>20/10/2000</releasedate>
		<year>2001</year>
		<studio>Sega Rosso</studio>
		<nplayers>1</nplayers>
		<ESRB>AAMA - Green (Suitable For All Ages)</ESRB>
		<boxart1>rrKV9n3.png</boxart1>
		<boxart2>AVRU2t8.png</boxart2>
		<boxart3>eKl2zD5.jpg</boxart3>
		<snapshot1>jpJzMKQ.png</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>BdWrzUB.png</snapshot2>
		<banner1>0PmzWhY.png</banner1>
		<genre>Sports,Sports,Tennis</genre>
	</game>
	<game name="Cannon Spike / Gun Spike">
		<description>Cannon Spike / Gun Spike</description>
		<rom name="naomi_non_merged/cspike_folder.zip" size="66668795"/>
		<emu_command>cspike/cspike.zip</emu_command>
		<plot>Cannon Spike (Gunspike in Japan) is an overhead-camera shooting game in the vein of Smash TV and another Capcom creation, the Commando series. Released for the arcades, and later for the Sega Dreamcast, it uses Capcom-designed characters and runs on Sega's Naomi Hardware.[CR]Cannon Spike is a linear game, heavily focused towards boss encounters. A main feature of the game is the ability to play as a number of familiar Capcom characters from other franchises. The international name of Cannon Spike is the name of a trademark attack performed by Cammy, a character from the Street Fighter series of video games and one of the protagonists of this title.</plot>
		<releasedate>01/01/2000</releasedate>
		<year>2000</year>
		<studio>Capcom</studio>
		<nplayers>2</nplayers>
		<ESRB>Not Rated</ESRB>
		<videoid>pbGIIVK9pDc</videoid>
		<boxart1>md9um2N.jpg</boxart1>
		<boxart2>9fNuuH7.jpg</boxart2>
		<boxart3>wYCmcs0.png</boxart3>
		<snapshot1>5vgSUcB.png</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>zNNlsK2.jpg</snapshot2>
		<banner1>4PLx6vN.png</banner1>
		<clearlogo1>lKemle1.png</clearlogo1>
		<fanart1>MmamS24.jpg</fanart1>
		<genre>Action,Beat Em Up,Shooter</genre>
		<groups>Franchise crossovers</groups>
	</game>
	<game name="Capcom Vs. SNK 2 Mark Of The Millennium 2001 (USA) (GDL-0008)">
		<description>Capcom Vs. SNK 2 Mark Of The Millennium 2001 (USA) (GDL-0008)</description>
		<rom name="naomi_non_merged/cvs2_folder.zip" size="163296388"/>
		<emu_command>cvs2/cvs2.zip</emu_command>
		<plot>Capcom vs. SNK 2 combines characters and gameplay elements from various Capcom and SNK fighting games, mainly the Street Fighter and The King of Fighters series. Other elements, most noticeably different fighting styles, incorporated elements from other games as well, such as Street Fighter III, Garou: Mark of the Wolves, and the Samurai Shodown series.[CR]This game runs on the Sga NAOMI Arcade system which is based on Sega Dreamcast's hardware.</plot>
		<releasedate>01/08/2001</releasedate>
		<year>2001</year>
		<studio>Capcom</studio>
		<nplayers>2</nplayers>
		<ESRB>Not Rated</ESRB>
		<videoid>IZmouManskU</videoid>
		<boxart1>VtMEVks.jpg</boxart1>
		<boxart2>xWfvdS4.jpg</boxart2>
		<boxart3>pRZSjW2.jpg</boxart3>
		<snapshot1>nTxwfWb.png</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>oTA041x.jpg</snapshot2>
		<banner1>VHQNYUR.png</banner1>
		<clearlogo1>dRDJ4dh.png</clearlogo1>
		<genre>Fighter</genre>
		<groups>Capcom vs. SNK series,Franchise crossovers,Middleware: CRI</groups>
	</game>
	<game name="Capcom Vs. SNK 2 Millionaire Fighting 2001 (Japan, Rev A) (GDL-0007A)">
		<description>Capcom Vs. SNK 2 Millionaire Fighting 2001 (Japan, Rev A) (GDL-0007A)</description>
		<rom name="naomi_non_merged/cvs2mf_folder.zip" size="163292832"/>
		<emu_command>cvs2mf/cvs2mf.zip</emu_command>
		<plot>Capcom vs. SNK 2 combines characters and gameplay elements from various Capcom and SNK fighting games, mainly the Street Fighter and The King of Fighters series. Other elements, most noticeably different fighting styles, incorporated elements from other games as well, such as Street Fighter III, Garou: Mark of the Wolves, and the Samurai Shodown series.[CR]This game runs on the Sga NAOMI Arcade system which is based on Sega Dreamcast's hardware.</plot>
		<releasedate>01/08/2001</releasedate>
		<year>2001</year>
		<studio>Capcom</studio>
		<nplayers>2</nplayers>
		<ESRB>Not Rated</ESRB>
		<videoid>IZmouManskU</videoid>
		<boxart1>VtMEVks.jpg</boxart1>
		<boxart2>xWfvdS4.jpg</boxart2>
		<boxart3>pRZSjW2.jpg</boxart3>
		<snapshot1>nTxwfWb.png</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>oTA041x.jpg</snapshot2>
		<banner1>VHQNYUR.png</banner1>
		<clearlogo1>dRDJ4dh.png</clearlogo1>
		<genre>Fighter</genre>
	</game>
	<game name="Capcom Vs. SNK Millennium Fight 2000 Pro (Japan) (GDL-0004)">
		<description>Capcom Vs. SNK Millennium Fight 2000 Pro (Japan) (GDL-0004)</description>
		<rom name="naomi_non_merged/cvsgd_folder.zip" size="8310549"/>
		<emu_command>cvsgd/cvsgd.zip</emu_command>
		<plot>Two of the worlds greatest arcade fighter developers, Capcom and SNK, join forces to finally answer the question asked by many for years: Who is the dominant fighter?[CR]A range of fighters from both worlds are available to choose from, with two different fighting styles (Capcom and SNK, of course) meaning that players of both worlds can fit into the game easily, while new gamers can try Ryu using the SNK format.</plot>
		<releasedate>01/01/2000</releasedate>
		<year>2000</year>
		<studio>Capcom</studio>
		<nplayers>2</nplayers>
		<ESRB>Not Rated</ESRB>
		<boxart1>CDzBvTB.jpg</boxart1>
		<boxart2>tm3Uhgf.jpg</boxart2>
		<boxart3>D4iQ2Mm.jpg</boxart3>
		<genre>Fighter</genre>
		<groups>Capcom vs. SNK series,Franchise crossovers</groups>
	</game>
	<game name="Death Crimson OX (Rev A)">
		<description>Death Crimson OX (Rev A)</description>
		<rom name="naomi_non_merged/deathcox_folder.zip" size="65526195"/>
		<emu_command>deathcox/deathcox.zip</emu_command>
		<plot>Death Crimson OX is a light gun shooting game developed by Ecole. It was released in arcades in 2000 then ported to the Dreamcast console in 2001 (published by Sammy Entertainment), several months after Sega had dropped support for the console. It is the third game in the Death Crimson series, and the only one to be released outside Japan.</plot>
		<releasedate>10/05/2001</releasedate>
		<year>2001</year>
		<nplayers>2</nplayers>
		<ESRB>Not Rated</ESRB>
		<boxart1>9BNSpPx.jpg</boxart1>
		<boxart2>P7aE9RM.png</boxart2>
		<boxart3>9MLHXX3.jpg</boxart3>
		<snapshot1>4v7L3A7.jpg</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>JC32Edj.jpg</snapshot2>
		<clearlogo1>8ii2hfW.png</clearlogo1>
		<genre>Shooter</genre>
	</game>
	<game name="Derby Owners Club 2000 Ver.2 (Japan, Rev A)">
		<description>Derby Owners Club 2000 Ver.2 (Japan, Rev A)</description>
		<rom name="naomi_non_merged/derbyo2k_folder.zip" size="63682533"/>
		<emu_command>derbyo2k/derbyo2k.zip</emu_command>
		<plot>Derby Owners Club 2000</plot>
		<year>2000</year>
		<studio>Sega</studio>
		<ESRB>Not Rated</ESRB>
		<genre>Sports,Sports,Horse Racing</genre>
	</game>
	<game name="Derby Owners Club (Japan, Rev B)">
		<description>Derby Owners Club (Japan, Rev B)</description>
		<rom name="naomi_non_merged/derbyoc_folder.zip" size="55084397"/>
		<emu_command>derbyoc/derbyoc.zip</emu_command>
		<plot>Derby Owners Club (JPN, USA, EXP, KOR, AUS) (Rev B)</plot>
		<year>1999</year>
		<studio>Sega</studio>
		<ESRB>Not Rated</ESRB>
		<genre>Sports,Horse Racing</genre>
	</game>
	<game name="Derby Owners Club II Ver.2.1 (Japan, Rev B)">
		<description>Derby Owners Club II Ver.2.1 (Japan, Rev B)</description>
		<rom name="naomi_non_merged/derbyoc2_folder.zip" size="124626319"/>
		<emu_command>derbyoc2/derbyoc2.zip</emu_command>
		<plot>Derby Owners Club II (JPN, USA, EXP, KOR, AUS)</plot>
		<year>2001</year>
		<studio>Sega</studio>
		<ESRB>Not Rated</ESRB>
		<genre>Sports,Sports,Horse Racing</genre>
	</game>
	<game name="Derby Owners Club World Edition EX (Rev D)">
		<description>Derby Owners Club World Edition EX (Rev D)</description>
		<rom name="naomi_non_merged/derbyocw_folder.zip" size="48959531"/>
		<emu_command>derbyocw/derbyocw.zip</emu_command>
		<plot>Derby Owners Club World Edition (JPN, USA, EXP, KOR, AUS) (Rev D)</plot>
		<year>2001</year>
		<studio>Sega</studio>
		<nplayers>1</nplayers>
		<ESRB>Not Rated</ESRB>
		<genre>Sports,Sports,Horse Racing</genre>
	</game>
	<game name="Dead or Alive 2">
		<description>Dead or Alive 2</description>
		<rom name="naomi_non_merged/doa2_folder.zip" size="119212790"/>
		<emu_command>doa2/doa2.zip</emu_command>
		<plot>Dead or Alive 2 is a fighting game in the Dead or Alive series, developed by Team Ninja and published by Tecmo. It debuted in arcades in 1999 and was later ported for the Dreamcast and the PlayStation 2 in 2000. Several enhanced editions of the game were released, including the updates Dead or Alive 2 Hardcore and Dead or Alive 2 Hard*Core.</plot>
		<releasedate>16/10/1999</releasedate>
		<year>1999</year>
		<studio>Team Ninja</studio>
		<nplayers>2</nplayers>
		<ESRB>T - Teen</ESRB>
		<boxart1>JpDA6LM.jpg</boxart1>
		<boxart2>Yc1DBFc.jpg</boxart2>
		<boxart3>3u9S8K6.jpg</boxart3>
		<snapshot1>J5jnql3.png</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>vwkWU5j.png</snapshot2>
		<banner1>zcnwJCW.png</banner1>
		<genre>Fighter</genre>
		<groups>Dead or Alive series,Launch title: PlayStation 2 (North America),PlayStation 2 Platinum Range releases</groups>
	</game>
	<game name="Dead or Alive 2 Millennium">
		<description>Dead or Alive 2 Millennium</description>
		<rom name="naomi_non_merged/doa2m_folder.zip" size="119272745"/>
		<emu_command>doa2m/doa2m.zip</emu_command>
		<plot>Dead or Alive 2 Millennium is an updated version of Dead or Alive 2, which includes features from the Dreamcast version that were not present in the arcade. The game was only released on the Sega NAOMI platform in arcades.</plot>
		<releasedate>01/01/2000</releasedate>
		<year>2000</year>
		<studio>Team Ninja</studio>
		<nplayers>2</nplayers>
		<ESRB>Not Rated</ESRB>
		<videoid>Te2SmH4kWHk</videoid>
		<boxart1>JpDA6LM.jpg</boxart1>
		<boxart2>Yc1DBFc.jpg</boxart2>
		<boxart3>3u9S8K6.jpg</boxart3>
		<snapshot1>J5jnql3.png</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>vwkWU5j.png</snapshot2>
		<banner1>zcnwJCW.png</banner1>
		<genre>Fighter</genre>
		<groups>Dead or Alive series,Launch title: PlayStation 2 (North America),PlayStation 2 Platinum Range releases</groups>
	</game>
	<game name="Dynamite Baseball '99 (Japan, Rev B)">
		<description>Dynamite Baseball '99 (Japan, Rev B)</description>
		<rom name="naomi_non_merged/dybb99_folder.zip" size="111542745"/>
		<emu_command>dybb99/dybb99.zip</emu_command>
		<plot>A baseball game from SEGA for the Naomi arcade hardware.</plot>
		<year>1998</year>
		<studio>Sega</studio>
		<nplayers>2</nplayers>
		<ESRB>Not Rated</ESRB>
		<genre>Sports,Sports,Baseball</genre>
	</game>
	<game name="Dynamite Baseball NAOMI (Japan)">
		<description>Dynamite Baseball NAOMI (Japan)</description>
		<rom name="naomi_non_merged/dybbnao_folder.zip" size="120358281"/>
		<emu_command>dybbnao/dybbnao.zip</emu_command>
		<plot>Dynamite Baseball NAOMI (JPN)</plot>
		<year>1998</year>
		<studio>Sega</studio>
		<nplayers>2</nplayers>
		<ESRB>Not Rated</ESRB>
		<genre>Sports,Sports,Baseball</genre>
	</game>
	<game name="Virtua Golf / Dynamic Golf (Rev A) (GDS-0009A)">
		<description>Virtua Golf / Dynamic Golf (Rev A) (GDS-0009A)</description>
		<rom name="naomi_non_merged/dygolf_folder.zip" size="72112868"/>
		<emu_command>dygolf/dygolf.zip</emu_command>
		<plot>Dynamic Golf is a Sports game, developed by Wow Entertainment and published by Sega, which was released in 2001</plot>
		<year>2001</year>
		<studio>Sega</studio>
		<nplayers>1</nplayers>
		<ESRB>AAMA - Green (Suitable For All Ages)</ESRB>
		<boxart1>f9Y1rN9.jpg</boxart1>
		<boxart2>3ZRQW1b.jpg</boxart2>
		<boxart3>KkdeZpo.jpg</boxart3>
		<banner1>46ArJpY.jpg</banner1>
		<genre>Sports,Golf</genre>
	</game>
	<game name="Ferrari F355 Challenge (deluxe, no link)">
		<description>Ferrari F355 Challenge (deluxe, no link)</description>
		<rom name="naomi_non_merged/f355_folder.zip" size="103138829"/>
		<emu_command>f355/f355.zip</emu_command>
		<plot>Get behind the wheel of one of the most world's most prestigious cars - the F355 Ferrari. [CR]F355 features a number of game modes: the Arcade mode which is the same as the checkpoint arcade version; Championship mode where you race a total of 6 races for the combined highest score; Single play which is the same as Arcade mode but with no time limit; Versus play with a two player split screen; and Network Race where you can connect to the Internet and race a time attack against other players ghost cars.[CR]The courses that are available to race on are Motegi, short and long versions of Suzuka, Monza, Sugo, Long Beach, Atlanta Motor Speedway, Nurburgring (GP track), Laguna Seca, Sepang, and Fiorano (Ferrari's test track). [CR]The game features 3 levels of difficulty. There are also four Assist functions - Stability Control for cornering, Traction Control from the engine to the tires, Anti Lock Brake System to keep the tires from locking during braking and Intelligent Brake System for braking before corners so beginners can concentrate on steering.[CR]You can also connect to the Internet and register your driver data.</plot>
		<releasedate>20/07/1999</releasedate>
		<year>1999</year>
		<studio>Sega</studio>
		<nplayers>1</nplayers>
		<ESRB>Not Rated</ESRB>
		<boxart1>nHVvbzU.jpg</boxart1>
		<genre>Driving,Racing</genre>
		<groups>Automobile: Ferrari F355,Ferrari licensees</groups>
	</game>
	<game name="Ferrari F355 Challenge 2 - International Course Edition (twin/deluxe)">
		<description>Ferrari F355 Challenge 2 - International Course Edition (twin/deluxe)</description>
		<rom name="naomi_non_merged/f355twn2_folder.zip" size="109811924"/>
		<emu_command>f355twn2/f355twn2.zip</emu_command>
	</game>
	<game name="Giant Gram: All Japan Pro Wrestling 2 (Japan)">
		<description>Giant Gram: All Japan Pro Wrestling 2 (Japan)</description>
		<rom name="naomi_non_merged/ggram2_folder.zip" size="59805236"/>
		<emu_command>ggram2/ggram2.zip</emu_command>
		<plot>Giant Gram is the sequel to the ST-V/Saturn "puroresu" title "All Japan Pro Wrestling Featuring Virtua". Both titles feature AJPW superstars, as well as Virtua Fighter characters. Japanese "puroresu" is all about fighting spirit and appeal. Gimmicks and soap opera theatrics do not get you "over" the way they do in the US of A. It's all about ability, athleticism, and sportsmanship.</plot>
		<releasedate>24/06/1999</releasedate>
		<year>1999</year>
		<studio>Scarab</studio>
		<nplayers>2</nplayers>
		<ESRB>Not Rated</ESRB>
		<boxart1>sfE303h.jpg</boxart1>
		<boxart2>0kc6FtI.jpg</boxart2>
		<clearlogo1>EZcWDPC.png</clearlogo1>
		<genre>Sports</genre>
	</game>
	<game name="Guilty Gear X">
		<description>Guilty Gear X</description>
		<rom name="naomi_non_merged/ggx_folder.zip" size="93382981"/>
		<emu_command>ggx/ggx.zip</emu_command>
		<plot>When the humans created artificial beings named "gears" in 22th century, they didn't expect that their creation will eventually turn against them. Because gears had no will of their own and could only obey humans. Only one gear, named Justice, was able to transfer his will onto other gears and to rebel against the humans. In year 2180, Justice was killed as a result of a bloody tournament organized by the Sacred Order of Holy Knights. Yet recently, a new gear was discovered. He showed no signs of hostility, yet he had no master and was roaming about free. It was impossible to capture or to kill him because he was immensely strong. Fearing a new Justice will grow out of this gear, the Order organized yet another tournament, this time with a solid prize: five hundred thousand world dollars for the winner.[CR]Guilty Gear X is a follow up to Guilty Gear, and is also a 2D fighting game. There are now 16 characters available for you to choose. The battle system became more complicated, thanks to the variety of moves you can perform. Beside special attacks which you can execute if you build up your Tension Gauge by attacking or advancing towards your opponent, there is also a variety of defensing moves to perform. The instant kill moves are back from the previous game.</plot>
		<releasedate>01/07/2000</releasedate>
		<year>2000</year>
		<studio>Arc System Works</studio>
		<nplayers>2</nplayers>
		<ESRB>T - Teen</ESRB>
		<videoid>3X2Xdm0NPQg</videoid>
		<boxart1>CvBWptd.jpg</boxart1>
		<boxart2>6Mjh9qx.jpg</boxart2>
		<boxart3>xnX0UeH.png</boxart3>
		<snapshot1>SSSIkv2.png</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>B9Rux12.png</snapshot2>
		<banner1>dYMHlpZ.png</banner1>
		<clearlogo1>C5Z6DAr.png</clearlogo1>
		<genre>Fighter</genre>
		<groups>Guilty Gear series</groups>
	</game>
	<game name="Guilty Gear XX (GDL-0011)">
		<description>Guilty Gear XX (GDL-0011)</description>
		<rom name="naomi_non_merged/ggxx_folder.zip" size="260764718"/>
		<emu_command>ggxx/ggxx.zip</emu_command>
		<plot>The third main installment (5th overall) of the Guilty Gear series, Guilty Gear X2 furthered the plot of the series, as well as introduced new characters and gameplay mechanics. Adds a new feature to the series: a burst gauge, which is fulfilled as the player causes or receives damage.[2] By pressing buttons in combination, the player character jump and unleash a blast of energy - a Psyche Burst. It allows the player to break combinations and super moves in the middle of the opponent's offensive. Also, if the blast hit the adversary, the tension gauge is filled to its maximum capacity immediately.[CR]The game picks up the story approximately two weeks after the events of Guilty Gear X. A new organization called Post-War Administration Bureau is looking for and destroying Gears, descendants of Japanese, and those who are able to use qi energy in combat. To achieve their goals the organization has created several copies of Ky Kiske, the Robo-Kys. In addition, I-No sparks conflict as she wants to destroy all she perceived threats to her master, "That Man", the creator of the Gears. Each character provides a different ending.</plot>
		<releasedate>23/05/2002</releasedate>
		<year>2002</year>
		<studio>Arc System Works</studio>
		<nplayers>2</nplayers>
		<ESRB>E - Everyone</ESRB>
		<videoid>x52NZxQbDqA</videoid>
		<boxart1>yfUHCnz.jpg</boxart1>
		<boxart2>bVQmyO5.jpg</boxart2>
		<boxart3>da7iHiQ.png</boxart3>
		<snapshot1>F1RDlak.png</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>XkEFZSb.png</snapshot2>
		<banner1>085ilpS.png</banner1>
		<clearlogo1>mUgXtq6.png</clearlogo1>
		<genre>Fighter</genre>
		<groups>Guilty Gear series</groups>
	</game>
	<game name="Guilty Gear XX Accent Core (Japan) (GDL-0041)">
		<description>Guilty Gear XX Accent Core (Japan) (GDL-0041)</description>
		<rom name="naomi_non_merged/ggxxac_folder.zip" size="265929615"/>
		<emu_command>ggxxac/ggxxac.zip</emu_command>
		<plot>Guilty Gear XX Accent Core is an enhanced version of GGX and the 13th installment of the Guilty Gear series. No changes to the battle system have been made, but new features were added. These include the return of Kliff and Justice, with appropriate changes and additions made for the game, the return of Mission mode, a new Survival mode with level-up features, a new Gallery mode with new illustrations, and bug fixes, rebalances, and tune ups from the previous version.</plot>
		<releasedate>20/12/2006</releasedate>
		<year>2006</year>
		<nplayers>2</nplayers>
		<ESRB>Not Rated</ESRB>
		<videoid>RkVzeaohN-w</videoid>
		<boxart1>qSuU4Yh.jpg</boxart1>
		<boxart2>B4C0ymO.jpg</boxart2>
		<boxart3>y1NDXfy.png</boxart3>
		<snapshot1>VfzdfV7.png</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>R1yNv4o.png</snapshot2>
		<clearlogo1>E0xUGME.png</clearlogo1>
		<genre>Fighter</genre>
	</game>
	<game name="Guilty Gear XX #Reload (Japan, Rev A) (GDL-0019A)">
		<description>Guilty Gear XX #Reload (Japan, Rev A) (GDL-0019A)</description>
		<rom name="naomi_non_merged/ggxxrl_folder.zip" size="265593661"/>
		<emu_command>ggxxrl/ggxxrl.zip</emu_command>
		<plot>Guilty Gear XX Reload is the first update to Guilty Gear XX and the 7th installment of the Guilty Gear series. It features balancing changes along with giving the character Robo-Ky its own moveset, with it being merely a palette-swap of Ky in the original game. The console version adds a fully voiced story mode dictating the events that took place after X as seen through each character's view. It also added Kliff and Justice back in as secret characters.</plot>
		<releasedate>26/03/2003</releasedate>
		<year>2003</year>
		<nplayers>2</nplayers>
		<ESRB>Not Rated</ESRB>
		<videoid>aEKI-YHThQY</videoid>
		<boxart1>GeS72ov.jpg</boxart1>
		<boxart2>A3mD1sa.jpg</boxart2>
		<boxart3>CZsiRE3.png</boxart3>
		<snapshot1>yCXoM1T.png</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>WrhHbrj.png</snapshot2>
		<banner1>KRwmT0q.png</banner1>
		<clearlogo1>AOdOe4N.png</clearlogo1>
		<genre>Fighter</genre>
		<groups>Guilty Gear series</groups>
	</game>
	<game name="Guilty Gear XX #Reload (Japan) (GDL-0019)">
		<description>Guilty Gear XX #Reload (Japan) (GDL-0019)</description>
		<rom name="naomi_non_merged/ggxxrlo_folder.zip" size="265597518"/>
		<emu_command>ggxxrlo/ggxxrlo.zip</emu_command>
		<plot>Guilty Gear XX Reload is the first update to Guilty Gear XX and the 7th installment of the Guilty Gear series. It features balancing changes along with giving the character Robo-Ky its own moveset, with it being merely a palette-swap of Ky in the original game. The console version adds a fully voiced story mode dictating the events that took place after X as seen through each character's view. It also added Kliff and Justice back in as secret characters.</plot>
		<releasedate>26/03/2003</releasedate>
		<year>2003</year>
		<nplayers>2</nplayers>
		<ESRB>Not Rated</ESRB>
		<videoid>aEKI-YHThQY</videoid>
		<boxart1>GeS72ov.jpg</boxart1>
		<boxart2>A3mD1sa.jpg</boxart2>
		<boxart3>CZsiRE3.png</boxart3>
		<snapshot1>yCXoM1T.png</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>WrhHbrj.png</snapshot2>
		<banner1>KRwmT0q.png</banner1>
		<clearlogo1>AOdOe4N.png</clearlogo1>
		<genre>Fighter</genre>
		<groups>Guilty Gear series</groups>
	</game>
	<game name="Guilty Gear XX Slash (Japan, Rev A) (GDL-0033A)">
		<description>Guilty Gear XX Slash (Japan, Rev A) (GDL-0033A)</description>
		<rom name="naomi_non_merged/ggxxsla_folder.zip" size="260150360"/>
		<emu_command>ggxxsla/ggxxsla.zip</emu_command>
		<plot>Slash is the second update to Guilty Gear XX, after Reload. It again features a wide range of balance tweaks and other adjustments, along with two new characters: A.B.A (originally introduced in Isuka) and Order Sol, and a new canceling system called Force Roman Cancel.</plot>
		<releasedate>28/09/2005</releasedate>
		<year>2005</year>
		<studio>Arc System Works</studio>
		<nplayers>2</nplayers>
		<ESRB>Not Rated</ESRB>
		<boxart1>UPxeN9D.png</boxart1>
		<boxart2>T6AKH9R.jpg</boxart2>
		<boxart3>zBtUE5b.jpg</boxart3>
		<snapshot1>PgThhTI.png</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>JKTiBlf.png</snapshot2>
		<banner1>TezeD1O.png</banner1>
		<clearlogo1>rlQj9o2.png</clearlogo1>
		<genre>Fighter</genre>
		<groups>Guilty Gear series</groups>
	</game>
	<game name="Giant Gram 2000">
		<description>Giant Gram 2000</description>
		<rom name="naomi_non_merged/gram2000_folder.zip" size="120365138"/>
		<emu_command>gram2000/gram2000.zip</emu_command>
		<plot>Giant Gram is the sequel to the ST-V/Saturn "puroresu" title "All Japan Pro Wrestling Featuring Virtua". Both titles feature AJPW superstars, as well as Virtua Fighter characters. Japanese "puroresu" is all about fighting spirit and appeal. Gimmicks and soap opera theatrics do not get you "over" the way they do in the US of A. It's all about ability, athleticism, and sportsmanship.</plot>
		<releasedate>24/06/1999</releasedate>
		<year>1999</year>
		<studio>Scarab</studio>
		<nplayers>2</nplayers>
		<ESRB>Not Rated</ESRB>
		<boxart1>sfE303h.jpg</boxart1>
		<boxart2>0kc6FtI.jpg</boxart2>
		<clearlogo1>EZcWDPC.png</clearlogo1>
		<genre>Sports</genre>
	</game>
	<game name="Mobile Suit Gundam: Federation Vs. Zeon (GDL-0001)">
		<description>Mobile Suit Gundam: Federation Vs. Zeon (GDL-0001)</description>
		<rom name="naomi_non_merged/gundmgd_folder.zip" size="147461712"/>
		<emu_command>gundmgd/gundmgd.zip</emu_command>
		<plot>Mobile Suit Gundam: Federation vs. Zeon is a 2001 arcade video game based on the anime television series Mobile Suit Gundam. An upgraded edition of the game, Federation vs. Zeon DX (DX stands for "Deluxe"), includes 360-degree, zero-G space battlefields. Both versions were later ported to the Dreamcast and PlayStation 2 game consoles.</plot>
		<releasedate>06/12/2001</releasedate>
		<year>2001</year>
		<studio>Capcom</studio>
		<nplayers>1</nplayers>
		<ESRB>AAMA - Yellow (Animated Violence Mild)</ESRB>
		<boxart1>5ZFWmu0.png</boxart1>
		<boxart2>sg82NVH.png</boxart2>
		<boxart3>XOk38Vn.png</boxart3>
		<snapshot1>jMzoN69.png</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>9Arx7Cd.png</snapshot2>
		<banner1>9ifTi2T.png</banner1>
		<clearlogo1>OzhQwYy.png</clearlogo1>
		<genre>Action,Driving,Shooter</genre>
		<groups>Gundam VS. series,Gundam licensees,Sunrise Robot licensees</groups>
	</game>
	<game name="Mobile Suit Gundam: Federation Vs. Zeon DX (USA, Japan) (GDL-0006)">
		<description>Mobile Suit Gundam: Federation Vs. Zeon DX (USA, Japan) (GDL-0006)</description>
		<rom name="naomi_non_merged/gundmxgd_folder.zip" size="179612230"/>
		<emu_command>gundmxgd/gundmxgd.zip</emu_command>
		<plot>Mobile Suit Gundam: Federation vs. Zeon is a 2001 arcade video game based on the anime television series Mobile Suit Gundam. An upgraded edition of the game, Federation vs. Zeon DX (DX stands for "Deluxe"), includes 360-degree, zero-G space battlefields. Both versions were later ported to the Dreamcast and PlayStation 2 game consoles.</plot>
		<releasedate>06/12/2001</releasedate>
		<year>2001</year>
		<studio>Capcom</studio>
		<nplayers>1</nplayers>
		<ESRB>AAMA - Yellow (Animated Violence Mild)</ESRB>
		<boxart1>5ZFWmu0.png</boxart1>
		<boxart2>sg82NVH.png</boxart2>
		<boxart3>XOk38Vn.png</boxart3>
		<snapshot1>jMzoN69.png</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>9Arx7Cd.png</snapshot2>
		<banner1>9ifTi2T.png</banner1>
		<clearlogo1>OzhQwYy.png</clearlogo1>
		<genre>Action,Driving,Shooter</genre>
		<groups>Gundam VS. series,Gundam licensees,Sunrise Robot licensees</groups>
	</game>
	<game name="Gun Survivor 2 Biohazard Code: Veronica (World, BHF2 Ver.E)">
		<description>Gun Survivor 2 Biohazard Code: Veronica (World, BHF2 Ver.E)</description>
		<rom name="naomi_non_merged/gunsur2_folder.zip" size="184259099"/>
		<emu_command>gunsur2/gunsur2.zip</emu_command>
		<plot>Gun Survivor 2 – Biohazard – Code: Veronica is a light gun shooter video game developed and published by Capcom and the 7th installment of the Resident Evil series. The arcade version was developed in conjunction with Namco for the arcade machines. The game is the second installment in the Gun Survivor series and sequel to Resident Evil Survivor. The game is adapted from Resident Evil Code: Veronica and features enemies and characters from that game, and enemies from Resident Evil 2 and Resident Evil 3: Nemesis</plot>
		<studio>Namco</studio>
		<nplayers>2</nplayers>
		<ESRB>Not Rated</ESRB>
		<videoid>Vrbdae73PP8</videoid>
		<boxart1>B9MJGaY.jpg</boxart1>
		<boxart2>Iu8cpRx.jpg</boxart2>
		<boxart3>yH8Mscq.png</boxart3>
		<snapshot1>GNrypVR.png</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>ejQbfJQ.png</snapshot2>
		<banner1>T7wL3jw.png</banner1>
		<clearlogo1>lWyUHGh.png</clearlogo1>
		<genre>Shooter</genre>
	</game>
	<game name="Giga Wing 2">
		<description>Giga Wing 2</description>
		<rom name="naomi_non_merged/gwing2_folder.zip" size="60399670"/>
		<emu_command>gwing2/gwing2.zip</emu_command>
		<plot>Giga Wing 2 is a 2000 vertical scrolling shooter arcade game developed by Takumi and published by Capcom on Sega's NAOMI arcade system board and later ported in 2001 to the Dreamcast console. The arcade version is notable both for its excessive scores (scores in the quintillions are not unheard of), and for using a horizontally aligned monitor (much like Treasure Co. Ltd's Radiant Silvergun), something that is considered rare for a vertical shooter.</plot>
		<releasedate>01/01/2000</releasedate>
		<year>2000</year>
		<studio>Takumi Corporation</studio>
		<nplayers>2</nplayers>
		<ESRB>E - Everyone</ESRB>
		<videoid>WrDlFfW7FWE</videoid>
		<boxart1>mduBJe5.jpg</boxart1>
		<boxart2>sYEUfG1.jpg</boxart2>
		<boxart3>VJwfadV.png</boxart3>
		<snapshot1>5xuJPuK.png</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>OC530qq.png</snapshot2>
		<genre>Shooter</genre>
		<groups>Giga Wing series</groups>
	</game>
	<game name="Heavy Metal Geomatrix (Rev B)">
		<description>Heavy Metal Geomatrix (Rev B)</description>
		<rom name="naomi_non_merged/hmgeo_folder.zip" size="78001408"/>
		<emu_command>hmgeo/hmgeo.zip</emu_command>
		<plot>Heavy Metal: Geomatrix is a fully 3D arena fighting video game released in 2001 by both Sega and Capcom for the Sega NAOMI and Dreamcast, based upon the Heavy Metal license.</plot>
		<releasedate>01/01/1985</releasedate>
		<year>1985</year>
		<studio>Capcom</studio>
		<nplayers>2</nplayers>
		<ESRB>AAMA - Yellow (Animated Violence Mild)</ESRB>
		<videoid>PuLjOn6IlYI</videoid>
		<boxart1>bIRH6mP.jpg</boxart1>
		<boxart2>6pgoVX1.jpg</boxart2>
		<boxart3>54m684t.png</boxart3>
		<snapshot1>kyBubJ0.png</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>wK90Jte.png</snapshot2>
		<banner1>R5IJYv9.png</banner1>
		<clearlogo1>QNM6G0l.png</clearlogo1>
		<genre>Action,Fighter,Shooter</genre>
		<groups>Heavy Metal games,Inspiration: Comics</groups>
	</game>
	<game name="The House of the Dead 2 (USA)">
		<description>The House of the Dead 2 (USA)</description>
		<rom name="naomi_non_merged/hotd2_folder.zip" size="105032940"/>
		<emu_command>hotd2/hotd2.zip</emu_command>
		<plot>The House of the Dead 2 is a rail shooter light gun game. It incorporates a branching path system that allows players to take a variety of different routes leading to the same point in the game's story.</plot>
		<releasedate>01/11/1998</releasedate>
		<year>1998</year>
		<studio>Sega</studio>
		<nplayers>2</nplayers>
		<ESRB>Not Rated</ESRB>
		<videoid>rr8r_x5LPBc</videoid>
		<boxart1>bIRH6mP.jpg</boxart1>
		<boxart2>6pgoVX1.jpg</boxart2>
		<boxart3>54m684t.png</boxart3>
		<snapshot1>kyBubJ0.png</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>wK90Jte.png</snapshot2>
		<banner1>R5IJYv9.png</banner1>
		<clearlogo1>QNM6G0l.png</clearlogo1>
		<genre>Shooter</genre>
		<groups>Genre: Light Gun Shooter,Launch title: Dreamcast (North America),The House of the Dead series,Theme: Zombies</groups>
	</game>
	<game name="Ikaruga (GDL-0010)">
		<description>Ikaruga (GDL-0010)</description>
		<rom name="naomi_non_merged/ikaruga_folder.zip" size="40525938"/>
		<emu_command>ikaruga/ikaruga.zip</emu_command>
		<plot>Ikaruga is a shoot 'em up developed by Treasure. It is the spiritual sequel to Radiant Silvergun (1998) and was originally released in Japanese arcades in December 2001. The game's story follows a rebel pilot named Shinra as he battles an enemy nation using a specially designed fighter called the Ikaruga which can flip between two polarities, black and white. This polarity mechanism is the game's key feature and the foundation for its stage and enemy design. All enemies and bullets in the game are either black or white. Bullets which are the same color as the player are absorbed while the others will kill the player. The game features both single-player and cooperative modes.</plot>
		<releasedate>20/12/2001</releasedate>
		<year>2001</year>
		<studio>Treasure</studio>
		<nplayers>2</nplayers>
		<ESRB>AAMA - Green (Suitable For All Ages)</ESRB>
		<boxart1>8VhcMid.jpg</boxart1>
		<boxart2>SMyYaNC.jpg</boxart2>
		<boxart3>46eJROz.jpg</boxart3>
		<snapshot1>Fj9R3jU.png</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>pCOdPlP.png</snapshot2>
		<banner1>p1IEadP.png</banner1>
		<clearlogo1>ZAWOCRj.png</clearlogo1>
		<genre>Shooter</genre>
		<groups>Genre: Bullet hell / Danmaku,Genre: Scrolling shoot 'em up,Steam Greenlight games</groups>
	</game>
	<game name="Illvelo (Illmatic Envelope) (Japan)">
		<description>Illvelo (Illmatic Envelope) (Japan)</description>
		<rom name="naomi_non_merged/illvelo_folder.zip" size="92708136"/>
		<emu_command>illvelo/illvelo.zip</emu_command>
		<plot>Illmatic Envelope, commonly abbreviated Illvelo, is a 2008 shoot-em-up for the Sega NAOMI arcade platform by Milestone. They ported it to the Nintendo Wii later that year as Illvelo Wii, with Sega partnering in its release.</plot>
		<releasedate>20/06/2008</releasedate>
		<year>2008</year>
		<studio>Milestone</studio>
		<ESRB>Not Rated</ESRB>
		<videoid>ueg8o8QPE7E</videoid>
		<boxart1>7MZ6Vzz.jpg</boxart1>
		<boxart2>TEH0nqm.jpg</boxart2>
		<boxart3>d54JypQ.png</boxart3>
		<clearlogo1>8pG6qs3.png</clearlogo1>
		<genre>Shoot Em Up,Shooter</genre>
		<groups>Genre: Bullet hell / Danmaku,Illvelo series</groups>
	</game>
	<game name="Inu no Osanpo / Dog Walking (Japan, Export, Rev A)">
		<description>Inu no Osanpo / Dog Walking (Japan, Export, Rev A)</description>
		<rom name="naomi_non_merged/inunoos_folder.zip" size="83525590"/>
		<emu_command>inunoos/inunoos.zip</emu_command>
		<plot>Inu no Osanpo (犬のおさんぽ), (lit. "Walk the Dog") is a dog-walking simulation game developed by Wow Entertainment and published by Sega for the Sega NAOMI arcade system in 2001. Players "walk" a virtual dog by walking on a treadmill and control the pet with a leash attached to a plastic dog in front of the player. The game was only released in Japan.[CR]Inu no Osanpo simulates the experience of walking a dog. Players first choose one of six breeds of dog to walk: Poodle, Pug, Pembroke Welsh Corgi, Shiba Inu, Labrador Retriever, or Siberian Husky. The difficulty of the game changes depending on the breed of dog chosen. After selecting a dog, the player selects one of three possible walking routes, each with a unique scenario.[CR]The goal of Inu no Osanpo is to maintain the dog's happiness long enough to complete the entire route.</plot>
		<year>2001</year>
		<studio>Sega</studio>
		<nplayers>1</nplayers>
		<ESRB>Not Rated</ESRB>
		<genre>Miscellaneous,Virtual Life,Simulation</genre>
	</game>
	<game name="Jambo! Safari (Rev A)">
		<description>Jambo! Safari (Rev A)</description>
		<rom name="naomi_non_merged/jambo_folder.zip" size="33187862"/>
		<emu_command>jambo/jambo.zip</emu_command>
		<plot>Jambo! Safari is a video game first released by Sega in 1999. The original arcade version of the game used the Naomi board, arcade hardware which was based on Sega's Dreamcast video game console. Despite the fact that other Naomi-based arcade games were released for the Dreamcast, Jambo! Safari was never ported to the Sega console. The UK version of the Official Dreamcast Magazine reported that the game was to be released in a 3-in-1 compilation along with other games in Sega's "Real Life Career Series", Brave Firefighters and Emergency Call Ambulance, but such a game was never released and neither of the other two games were ported either. Sega released versions of the game for the Wii and Nintendo DS, under the title Jambo! Safari: Animal Rescue on November 17, 2009.</plot>
		<releasedate>01/01/1999</releasedate>
		<year>1999</year>
		<studio>AM2, TOSE</studio>
		<nplayers>1</nplayers>
		<ESRB>Not Rated</ESRB>
		<videoid>ceKmwBp_rxI</videoid>
		<boxart1>M67lQP1.jpg</boxart1>
		<boxart2>cmi6V59.png</boxart2>
		<boxart3>E58AA3J.jpg</boxart3>
		<snapshot1>4acyaks.png</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>PImJf30.png</snapshot2>
		<banner1>88fqkOP.png</banner1>
		<clearlogo1>dXgefrd.png</clearlogo1>
		<genre>Adventure,Racing</genre>
	</game>
	<game name="Jingi Storm - The Arcade (Japan) (GDL-0037)">
		<description>Jingi Storm - The Arcade (Japan) (GDL-0037)</description>
		<rom name="naomi_non_merged/jingystm_folder.zip" size="146490822"/>
		<emu_command>jingystm/jingystm.zip</emu_command>
		<plot>Jingi Storm is a 3D versus fighting game were each of the nine male fighters is paired up with a female, whose only purpose is to deliver the winning/losing lines at the end of each match.</plot>
		<releasedate>20/09/2006</releasedate>
		<year>2006</year>
		<studio>Atrativa Japan</studio>
		<nplayers>2</nplayers>
		<ESRB>Not Rated</ESRB>
		<videoid>JOlfmdOqwCM</videoid>
		<boxart1>etifTfS.jpg</boxart1>
		<boxart2>G91ydf8.jpg</boxart2>
		<boxart3>QfM8vpA.png</boxart3>
		<snapshot1>58UteDR.png</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>4rgSUC5.png</snapshot2>
		<banner1>fj0JMdV.png</banner1>
		<clearlogo1>TfRM2Oe.png</clearlogo1>
		<genre>Fighter</genre>
	</game>
	<game name="Karous (Japan) (GDL-0040)">
		<description>Karous (Japan) (GDL-0040)</description>
		<rom name="naomi_non_merged/karous_folder.zip" size="130840720"/>
		<emu_command>karous/karous.zip</emu_command>
		<plot>Karous is a vertical-scrolling shooter video game developed by Milestone Inc. for the Sega NAOMI platform, and released in Japanese arcades on November 15, 2006. The game was later ported to the Sega Dreamcast, becoming the system's last officially licensed title when it was released in Japan on March 8, 2007.</plot>
		<releasedate>15/11/2006</releasedate>
		<year>2006</year>
		<studio>MileStone Inc.</studio>
		<nplayers>1</nplayers>
		<ESRB>AAMA - Green (Suitable For All Ages)</ESRB>
		<boxart1>Dvh44u2.jpg</boxart1>
		<boxart2>KaXgSpS.png</boxart2>
		<boxart3>lX4noxd.png</boxart3>
		<snapshot1>iYG4auf.png</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>EEpasfA.png</snapshot2>
		<clearlogo1>RBVWTMs.png</clearlogo1>
		<genre>Shooter</genre>
		<groups>Karous series</groups>
	</game>
	<game name="La Keyboard (GDS-0017)">
		<description>La Keyboard (GDS-0017)</description>
		<rom name="naomi_non_merged/keyboard_folder.zip" size="33325374"/>
		<emu_command>keyboard/keyboard.zip</emu_command>
		<plot>La Keyboardxyu (GDS-0017)</plot>
		<year>2001</year>
		<studio>Sega Rosso</studio>
		<nplayers>2</nplayers>
		<ESRB>Not Rated</ESRB>
		<boxart1>2V8hyVU.png</boxart1>
		<boxart2>KwLaPJl.png</boxart2>
		<boxart3>HjowcR8.png</boxart3>
		<snapshot1>9CqnBIL.png</snapshot1>
		<banner1>wM65kpi.png</banner1>
		<clearlogo1>2IaXeLL.png</clearlogo1>
		<genre>Quiz</genre>
	</game>
	<game name="Kick '4' Cash (Export)">
		<description>Kick '4' Cash (Export)</description>
		<rom name="naomi_non_merged/kick4csh_folder.zip" size="44706447"/>
		<emu_command>kick4csh/kick4csh.zip</emu_command>
		<plot>Kick '4' Cash</plot>
		<year>2004</year>
		<studio>Sega</studio>
		<ESRB>Not Rated</ESRB>
		<genre>Sports,Sports,Soccer</genre>
	</game>
	<game name="Kurukuru Chameleon (Japan) (GDL-0034)">
		<description>Kurukuru Chameleon (Japan) (GDL-0034)</description>
		<rom name="naomi_non_merged/kurucham_folder.zip" size="41756612"/>
		<emu_command>kurucham/kurucham.zip</emu_command>
		<plot>Kuru Kuru Chameleon is a 2006 puzzle game by Starfish for the Sega NAOMI GD-ROM arcade platform. It is thought to have been released exclusively in Japan.[CR]Two players take opposite corners of a rectangular playing field consisting of hexagonal tiles of various colors. Each player is in control of one set of tiles which all have the same color and all touch on at least one side. On each turn, the player chooses one of the remaining colors, which turns their current set of tiles into that color and adds all adjacent tiles of that color to their set. The first player to have a majority of the fields tiles in their control wins.</plot>
		<year>2006</year>
		<studio>Starfish</studio>
		<nplayers>2</nplayers>
		<ESRB>Not Rated</ESRB>
		<boxart1>dKQt3st.png</boxart1>
		<boxart2>70I8Hgk.jpg</boxart2>
		<boxart3>ctkKnQc.png</boxart3>
		<snapshot1>gRlDhsB.png</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>AvLcOdO.png</snapshot2>
		<banner1>WtnIges.png</banner1>
		<clearlogo1>fXidRuC.png</clearlogo1>
		<genre>Puzzle</genre>
	</game>
	<game name="Lupin The Third - The Shooting (Rev A) (GDS-0018A)">
		<description>Lupin The Third - The Shooting (Rev A) (GDS-0018A)</description>
		<rom name="naomi_non_merged/lupinsho_folder.zip" size="199082262"/>
		<emu_command>lupinsho/lupinsho.zip</emu_command>
		<plot>Players take the role of Lupin III as they shoot through fifteen of The Wolf's wackiest endeavors. Driving scenarios where the player has to shoot left or right in order to control their vehicle appear as special levels. The game also offers a co-op mode where a second player can take up the role of Jigen and assist Lupin throughout the adventure.</plot>
		<releasedate>01/01/2001</releasedate>
		<year>2001</year>
		<studio>WOW Entertainment</studio>
		<nplayers>2</nplayers>
		<ESRB>Not Rated</ESRB>
		<boxart1>VPQ93hv.png</boxart1>
		<boxart2>Q54G44I.jpg</boxart2>
		<genre>Shooter</genre>
	</game>
	<game name="Lupin The Third - The Shooting (GDS-0018)">
		<description>Lupin The Third - The Shooting (GDS-0018)</description>
		<rom name="naomi_non_merged/lupinshoo_folder.zip" size="216057174"/>
		<emu_command>lupinshoo/lupinshoo.zip</emu_command>
		<plot>Players take the role of Lupin III as they shoot through fifteen of The Wolf's wackiest endeavors. Driving scenarios where the player has to shoot left or right in order to control their vehicle appear as special levels. The game also offers a co-op mode where a second player can take up the role of Jigen and assist Lupin throughout the adventure.</plot>
		<releasedate>01/01/2001</releasedate>
		<year>2001</year>
		<studio>WOW Entertainment</studio>
		<nplayers>2</nplayers>
		<ESRB>Not Rated</ESRB>
		<boxart1>VPQ93hv.png</boxart1>
		<boxart2>Q54G44I.jpg</boxart2>
		<genre>Shooter</genre>
	</game>
	<game name="Lupin The Third - The Typing (Rev A) (GDS-0021A)">
		<description>Lupin The Third - The Typing (Rev A) (GDS-0021A)</description>
		<rom name="naomi_non_merged/luptype_folder.zip" size="159608965"/>
		<emu_command>luptype/luptype.zip</emu_command>
		<plot>Lupin the 3rd: The Typing is a keyboard game developed by Wow Entertainment and published by Sega for the Sega NAOMI arcade system. Similar to Typing of the Dead, it is based on the Lupin the 3rd: The Shooting game released in the previous year, but reworked for typing in words to perform shots rather than using a light gun.</plot>
		<year>2002</year>
		<studio>Sega</studio>
		<nplayers>2</nplayers>
		<ESRB>Not Rated</ESRB>
		<boxart1>eMfhfNo.jpg</boxart1>
		<boxart2>3s64UsO.png</boxart2>
		<boxart3>F9HpVRl.png</boxart3>
		<banner1>zX6p549.png</banner1>
		<clearlogo1>OGbE1Gh.png</clearlogo1>
		<genre>Miscellaneous,Shooter</genre>
	</game>
	<game name="Mamoru-kun wa Norowarete Shimatta! (Japan)">
		<description>Mamoru-kun wa Norowarete Shimatta! (Japan)</description>
		<rom name="naomi_non_merged/mamonoro_folder.zip" size="153164166"/>
		<emu_command>mamonoro/mamonoro.zip</emu_command>
		<plot>Mamorukun Curse is a shoot 'em up arcade game developed by G.rev and Gulti. The game was released for arcade in Japan on July 30, 2008.[CR]The game puts the player in control of Mamoru in an overhead shooter. Different from most shooters, the scrolling is not forced. The player is able to move about as they please, although most movements end up being up and down.[CR]The "curse" part of the title comes from a special "curse bomb" attack which uses a separate button from the standard shot. These bombs can be used both to destroy the enemies' bullets, and to "curse" them, making them more powerful but opening up chances for a higher score.</plot>
		<releasedate>30/07/2008</releasedate>
		<year>2008</year>
		<nplayers>1</nplayers>
		<ESRB>Not Rated</ESRB>
		<boxart1>iDgo5hV.jpg</boxart1>
		<boxart2>RYZTuKe.jpg</boxart2>
		<boxart3>ByKMTag.png</boxart3>
		<banner1>K5VBQrW.png</banner1>
		<clearlogo1>jXsdQ1C.png</clearlogo1>
		<genre>Shooter</genre>
	</game>
	<game name="Mars TV (Japan)">
		<description>Mars TV (Japan)</description>
		<rom name="naomi_non_merged/marstv_folder.zip" size="60610408"/>
		<emu_command>marstv/marstv.zip</emu_command>
		<plot>This game involves groups of three players who compete in a series of TV quiz shows held on Mars. In order to become the most famous contestant, you must win the various mini-games on offer.</plot>
		<ESRB>Not Rated</ESRB>
		<genre>Quiz</genre>
	</game>
	<game name="Mazan: Flash of the Blade (World, MAZ2 Ver.A)">
		<description>Mazan: Flash of the Blade (World, MAZ2 Ver.A)</description>
		<rom name="naomi_non_merged/mazan_folder.zip" size="77272818"/>
		<emu_command>mazan/mazan.zip</emu_command>
		<plot>[I]Mazan: Flash of The Blade[/I] is first-person perspective sword fighting game in which the player uses a motion sensor controlled replica katana to guide the movement of the sword on screen. The game runs on the Sega NAOMI hardware.[CR]The story revolves around two ancient swords: Soulstealer an evil blade forged in hell and as cold as ice witch over time will corrupt and transform the wielder into a monster. The other being Lightbringer a sword imbued with holy light. Soulstealers wielders have spread and corrupted the land spreading disease and filling it with abominations. The player takes control of the man wielding Lightbringer to rid the land of evil.[CR]You fight various beheaded enemies, skeletal samurai and monsters. The game offers a total of three stages each with a boss at the end. Hidden routes as well as items can be found by slashing objects.</plot>
		<releasedate>20/03/2002</releasedate>
		<studio>Namco</studio>
		<nplayers>1</nplayers>
		<ESRB>Not Rated</ESRB>
		<genre>Fighter</genre>
	</game>
	<game name="Melty Blood Actress Again Version A (Japan, Rev A)">
		<description>Melty Blood Actress Again Version A (Japan, Rev A)</description>
		<rom name="naomi_non_merged/mbaa_folder.zip" size="245243643"/>
		<emu_command>mbaa/mbaa.zip</emu_command>
		<plot>Melty Blood: Actress Again, is the third game in the Melty Blood fighting game series. It was released in the 4Q 2008 on Sega Naomi hardware. Compared to Act Cadenza, the game features three entirely new playable characters, as well as several new alternate versions of existing characters in the PS2 version. All characters now feature selection between three different fighting styles, known as Full Moon Style, Crescent Moon Style (most similar to Act Cadenza) and Half Moon Style, which changes not only the way in which life and Magic Circuit meters function, but also each characters' basic and special attacks.</plot>
		<releasedate>19/09/2008</releasedate>
		<year>2008</year>
		<studio>Ecole</studio>
		<nplayers>2</nplayers>
		<ESRB>Not Rated</ESRB>
		<boxart1>7weSskS.jpg</boxart1>
		<boxart2>TpuCLKy.jpg</boxart2>
		<boxart3>SywnT04.png</boxart3>
		<clearlogo1>rGmGqol.png</clearlogo1>
		<fanart1>W3dNNtN.jpg</fanart1>
		<genre>Fighter</genre>
		<groups>Tsukihime / Melty Blood games</groups>
	</game>
	<game name="Melty Blood Act Cadenza Version B2 (Japan) (GDL-0039A)">
		<description>Melty Blood Act Cadenza Version B2 (Japan) (GDL-0039A)</description>
		<rom name="naomi_non_merged/meltyb_folder.zip" size="211120531"/>
		<emu_command>meltyb/meltyb.zip</emu_command>
		<plot>Melty Blood follows one year after Tsukihime and some days after of Kagetsu Tohya. In the beginning of August 2001, Shiki Tohno hears of a new series of murders in Misaki Town, similar to the ones that took place Tsukihime, in the last weeks of October 1999. Whilst searching for the murderer he meets Sion Eltnam Atlasia who initiates a fight with him, attempting to capture him. After the fight she reveals that her reason for trying to capture him is to get in contact with the "True Ancestor" (referring to Arcueid) so that she may acquire information on the "cure for vampirism". Shiki then decides to help her with this task.</plot>
		<releasedate>27/07/2007</releasedate>
		<year>2007</year>
		<studio>Ecole Software</studio>
		<nplayers>2</nplayers>
		<ESRB>AAMA - Yellow (Animated Violence Mild)</ESRB>
		<videoid>AnwLYXEC3-Y</videoid>
		<boxart1>lteTx0m.png</boxart1>
		<boxart2>5oJM8Vj.jpg</boxart2>
		<boxart3>LcO70fs.jpg</boxart3>
		<snapshot1>DF8GTtO.png</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>VdgbTxO.png</snapshot2>
		<genre>Fighter</genre>
		<groups>Tsukihime / Melty Blood games</groups>
	</game>
	<game name="Melty Blood Act Cadenza Ver. A (Japan) (GDL-0028C)">
		<description>Melty Blood Act Cadenza Ver. A (Japan) (GDL-0028C)</description>
		<rom name="naomi_non_merged/meltybld_folder.zip" size="223749440"/>
		<emu_command>meltybld/meltybld.zip</emu_command>
		<plot>Melty Blood follows one year after Tsukihime and some days after of Kagetsu Tohya. In the beginning of August 2001, Shiki Tohno hears of a new series of murders in Misaki Town, similar to the ones that took place Tsukihime, in the last weeks of October 1999. Whilst searching for the murderer he meets Sion Eltnam Atlasia who initiates a fight with him, attempting to capture him. After the fight she reveals that her reason for trying to capture him is to get in contact with the "True Ancestor" (referring to Arcueid) so that she may acquire information on the "cure for vampirism". Shiki then decides to help her with this task.</plot>
		<releasedate>15/03/2005</releasedate>
		<year>2005</year>
		<studio>Ecole Software</studio>
		<nplayers>2</nplayers>
		<ESRB>AAMA - Yellow (Animated Violence Mild)</ESRB>
		<videoid>AnwLYXEC3-Y</videoid>
		<boxart1>lteTx0m.png</boxart1>
		<boxart2>5oJM8Vj.jpg</boxart2>
		<boxart3>LcO70fs.jpg</boxart3>
		<snapshot1>DF8GTtO.png</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>VdgbTxO.png</snapshot2>
		<genre>Fighter</genre>
		<groups>Tsukihime / Melty Blood games</groups>
	</game>
	<game name="Melty Blood Act Cadenza (Japan) (GDL-0028)">
		<description>Melty Blood Act Cadenza (Japan) (GDL-0028)</description>
		<rom name="naomi_non_merged/meltyblo_folder.zip" size="223838905"/>
		<emu_command>meltyblo/meltyblo.zip</emu_command>
		<plot>Melty Blood follows one year after Tsukihime and some days after of Kagetsu Tohya. In the beginning of August 2001, Shiki Tohno hears of a new series of murders in Misaki Town, similar to the ones that took place Tsukihime, in the last weeks of October 1999. Whilst searching for the murderer he meets Sion Eltnam Atlasia who initiates a fight with him, attempting to capture him. After the fight she reveals that her reason for trying to capture him is to get in contact with the "True Ancestor" (referring to Arcueid) so that she may acquire information on the "cure for vampirism". Shiki then decides to help her with this task.</plot>
		<releasedate>15/03/2005</releasedate>
		<year>2005</year>
		<studio>Ecole Software</studio>
		<nplayers>2</nplayers>
		<ESRB>Not Rated</ESRB>
		<videoid>onArSwQ-z0Q</videoid>
		<boxart1>lteTx0m.png</boxart1>
		<boxart2>5oJM8Vj.jpg</boxart2>
		<boxart3>LcO70fs.jpg</boxart3>
		<snapshot1>DF8GTtO.png</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>VdgbTxO.png</snapshot2>
		<genre>Fighter</genre>
		<groups>Tsukihime / Melty Blood games</groups>
	</game>
	<game name="Melty Blood Act Cadenza Version B (Japan) (GDL-0039)">
		<description>Melty Blood Act Cadenza Version B (Japan) (GDL-0039)</description>
		<rom name="naomi_non_merged/meltybo_folder.zip" size="205358983"/>
		<emu_command>meltybo/meltybo.zip</emu_command>
		<plot>Melty Blood follows one year after Tsukihime and some days after of Kagetsu Tohya. In the beginning of August 2001, Shiki Tohno hears of a new series of murders in Misaki Town, similar to the ones that took place Tsukihime, in the last weeks of October 1999. Whilst searching for the murderer he meets Sion Eltnam Atlasia who initiates a fight with him, attempting to capture him. After the fight she reveals that her reason for trying to capture him is to get in contact with the "True Ancestor" (referring to Arcueid) so that she may acquire information on the "cure for vampirism". Shiki then decides to help her with this task.</plot>
		<releasedate>27/07/2007</releasedate>
		<year>2007</year>
		<studio>Ecole Software</studio>
		<nplayers>2</nplayers>
		<ESRB>AAMA - Yellow (Animated Violence Mild)</ESRB>
		<videoid>AnwLYXEC3-Y</videoid>
		<boxart1>lteTx0m.png</boxart1>
		<boxart2>5oJM8Vj.jpg</boxart2>
		<boxart3>LcO70fs.jpg</boxart3>
		<snapshot1>DF8GTtO.png</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>VdgbTxO.png</snapshot2>
		<genre>Fighter</genre>
		<groups>Tsukihime / Melty Blood games</groups>
	</game>
	<game name="Moeru Casinyo (Japan) (GDL-0013)">
		<description>Moeru Casinyo (Japan) (GDL-0013)</description>
		<rom name="naomi_non_merged/moeru_folder.zip" size="8310695"/>
		<emu_command>moeru/moeru.zip</emu_command>
		<plot>Moeru Casinyo (JPN) / Burning Casino (GDL-0013)</plot>
		<year>2002</year>
		<studio>Altron</studio>
		<nplayers>1</nplayers>
		<ESRB>Not Rated</ESRB>
		<genre>Casino</genre>
	</game>
	<game name="The Maze of the Kings (GDS-0022)">
		<description>The Maze of the Kings (GDS-0022)</description>
		<rom name="naomi_non_merged/mok_folder.zip" size="145015458"/>
		<emu_command>mok/mok.zip</emu_command>
		<plot>A 1 to 2 player shooting game where each player assumes the role of an archaeological treasure hunter armed with a magical cane who travels across rivers and deserts and explores the insides of pyramids searching for lost treasure while killing mummies and other evil creatures. Each player gets a choice of what kind of firepwoer to use for his or her character's magical cane: Light, Spark, or Fire.</plot>
		<releasedate>06/03/2002</releasedate>
		<year>2002</year>
		<studio>Sega</studio>
		<nplayers>2</nplayers>
		<ESRB>E - Everyone</ESRB>
		<boxart1>VrLrtYR.jpg</boxart1>
		<boxart2>VwP4B2H.jpg</boxart2>
		<boxart3>k2WO3mp.png</boxart3>
		<snapshot1>Zd4JOFJ.png</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>U18QINd.png</snapshot2>
		<banner1>B8QD6gv.png</banner1>
		<clearlogo1>U37bx2r.png</clearlogo1>
		<genre>Shooter</genre>
		<groups>Protagonist: Treasure hunter</groups>
	</game>
	<game name="Monkey Ball (GDS-0008)">
		<description>Monkey Ball (GDS-0008)</description>
		<rom name="naomi_non_merged/monkeyba_folder.zip" size="84544558"/>
		<emu_command>monkeyba/monkeyba.zip</emu_command>
		<plot>Monkey Ball is a Sega NAOMI arcade game, originally released in 2001. It is the first game in the Super Monkey Ball series.[CR]The arcade cabinet of Monkey Ball is unique for its banana-shaped joystick. All the bananas in the game are sponsored by Dole, a practise that would carry through to its successor, Super Monkey Ball and Super Monkey Ball 2. There are three characters, AiAi, MeeMee and Baby, three difficulty levels and numerous puzzles to complete.[CR]Monkey Ball was somewhat unique at the time of release. Though marble/ball rolling games had been done in the past, such as Marble Madness, these types of games are fairly rare, and none had ever been presented in 3D.[CR]Monkey Ball itself was not ported to consoles. Instead, an upgraded version titled Super Monkey Ball was released for the GameCube a few years later. It contains all the levels seen in Monkey Ball, plus enhanced graphics and extra features.</plot>
		<releasedate>01/01/2001</releasedate>
		<year>2001</year>
		<nplayers>1-4</nplayers>
		<ESRB>Not Rated</ESRB>
		<boxart1>3bC9rX8.jpg</boxart1>
		<boxart2>14Bfs2x.png</boxart2>
		<boxart3>6wKp9aU.png</boxart3>
		<banner1>WbeIrF6.png</banner1>
		<clearlogo1>vzlJdKN.png</clearlogo1>
		<genre>Platform,Puzzle</genre>
		<groups>Animals: Primates (monkeys or apes),Genre: Rolling ball,Launch title: GameCube (Japan),Nintendo Player's Choice releases,Super Monkey Ball series</groups>
	</game>
	<game name="Mushiking The King Of Beetles - Mushiking II / III / III+ (Ver. 2.001) (World)">
		<description>Mushiking The King Of Beetles - Mushiking II / III / III+ (Ver. 2.001) (World)</description>
		<rom name="naomi_non_merged/mushik2e_folder.zip" size="76338588"/>
		<emu_command>mushik2e/mushik2e.zip</emu_command>
		<plot>Mushiking: The King of Beetles 2k4 also called Mushiking: Battle of the Beetles 2004, is a combination arcade game and collectible card game developed by Sega and released in Japan and other Asian countries such as the Philippines. The game involves battles between cards describing various beetle species. The cards can be scanned in by a Mushiking arcade machine, which will both carry out battles and dispense new cards.[CR]The rock-paper-scissors-style battle game can be played by one player against CPU-controlled beetles, or with two or more players against each other in Tournament mode or Tag Battle mode. The game is played with cards representing beetles and skill cards related to three move types - Hitting, Pinching and Throwing. At the start of a match, players may scan one beetle card and up to three different skill cards with the card scanner in the middle of the machine before choosing one of the three move types to execute within a given time limit. The first player whose beetle reaches 0 stamina points loses.</plot>
		<year>2004</year>
		<studio>Sega</studio>
		<nplayers>2</nplayers>
		<ESRB>Not Rated</ESRB>
		<snapshot1>QObcFlX.jpg</snapshot1>
		<genre>Card Battle</genre>
	</game>
	<game name="Marvel Vs. Capcom 2 New Age of Heroes (Export, Korea, Rev A)">
		<description>Marvel Vs. Capcom 2 New Age of Heroes (Export, Korea, Rev A)</description>
		<rom name="naomi_non_merged/mvsc2_folder.zip" size="91743110"/>
		<emu_command>mvsc2/mvsc2.zip</emu_command>
		<plot>Marvel vs. Capcom 2: New Age of Heroes is a crossover fighting game developed and published by Capcom. It is the fourth installment in both the Marvel vs. Capcom series and Capcom's Vs. series respectively, which features characters from both Capcom's video game franchises and comic book series published by Marvel Comics. Originally released in Japanese arcades in 2000, the game received ports to the Dreamcast, PlayStation 2, PlayStation 3, Xbox, Xbox 360, and iOS devices over the span of twelve years.</plot>
		<releasedate>01/11/2000</releasedate>
		<year>2000</year>
		<studio>Capcom</studio>
		<nplayers>2</nplayers>
		<ESRB>Not Rated</ESRB>
		<videoid>KQjlbjdEZfo</videoid>
		<boxart1>KdM8Jyk.jpg</boxart1>
		<boxart2>z5YhA8s.png</boxart2>
		<boxart3>xi7NCNQ.jpg</boxart3>
		<banner1>V1iTFra.png</banner1>
		<clearlogo1>eMGFlMh.png</clearlogo1>
		<fanart1>dps5fbi.jpg</fanart1>
		<genre>Fighter</genre>
		<groups>Franchise crossovers,Marvel licensees,Marvel vs. Capcom series,Middleware: CRI</groups>
	</game>
	<game name="Ninja Assault (World, NJA2 Ver.A)">
		<description>Ninja Assault (World, NJA2 Ver.A)</description>
		<rom name="naomi_non_merged/ninjaslt_folder.zip" size="85096845"/>
		<emu_command>ninjaslt/ninjaslt.zip</emu_command>
		<plot>Ruling with an army of demonic soldiers, Shogun Kigai has conquered the innocent nation of Tenshin and kidnapped its beautiful Princess Koto. As violence and carnage tear apart the land, three great Ninjas rise to end the bloodshed and rescue the Princess. Armed with sacred weapons, the three Ninjas embark on a journey to destroy the evil Shogun and defeat his menacing army of demons..</plot>
		<releasedate>18/11/2000</releasedate>
		<year>2000</year>
		<studio>Namco</studio>
		<nplayers>2</nplayers>
		<ESRB>Not Rated</ESRB>
		<videoid>wKDSTLLPMZo</videoid>
		<boxart1>https://imgur.com/i0ANipO.p</boxart1>
		<boxart2>LajtRWD.jpg</boxart2>
		<boxart3>eJhucOr.png</boxart3>
		<banner1>rQMLyOS.png</banner1>
		<clearlogo1>aJqS2X7.png</clearlogo1>
		<genre>Shooter</genre>
	</game>
	<game name="Oinori-daimyoujin Matsuri">
		<description>Oinori-daimyoujin Matsuri</description>
		<rom name="naomi_non_merged/oinori_folder.zip" size="38160192"/>
		<emu_command>oinori/oinori.zip</emu_command>
		<plot>Oinori-daimyoujin Matsuri (Rev.A)</plot>
		<year>2003</year>
		<studio>Sega</studio>
		<ESRB>Not Rated</ESRB>
		<genre>Casino,Miscellaneous</genre>
	</game>
	<game name="OutTrigger">
		<description>OutTrigger</description>
		<rom name="naomi_non_merged/otrigger_folder.zip" size="86116742"/>
		<emu_command>otrigger/otrigger.zip</emu_command>
		<plot>Outtrigger is a first/third person shoot-em-up game originally released for Sega NAOMI arcade hardware before being ported to the Sega Dreamcast. It is compatible with the Dreamcast Mouse, and in Japan, came bundled with one.[CR]Developed by Sega AM2 and produced by Yu Suzuki, the game featured four unique characters, each with their own class and abilities. This makes it the first hero shooter.</plot>
		<releasedate>01/11/1999</releasedate>
		<year>1999</year>
		<studio>Sega</studio>
		<nplayers>1</nplayers>
		<ESRB>Not Rated</ESRB>
		<boxart1>bmMpZtR.png</boxart1>
		<boxart2>kTHifCN.png</boxart2>
		<boxart3>ViHVP9s.jpg</boxart3>
		<snapshot1>FCwbDeS.png</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>uAH1tvJ.png</snapshot2>
		<banner1>hwsLcgk.png</banner1>
		<clearlogo1>Q8NyTQA.png</clearlogo1>
		<genre>Shooter</genre>
	</game>
	<game name="Project Justice / Moero! Justice Gakuen (Rev A)">
		<description>Project Justice / Moero! Justice Gakuen (Rev A)</description>
		<rom name="naomi_non_merged/pjustic_folder.zip" size="132267177"/>
		<emu_command>pjustic/pjustic.zip</emu_command>
		<plot>A group of long time friends now unite in the pursuit of honor and excellence. Setting all past rivalries aside, they band together to uncover the mystery behind an unusual series of events. Join over 20 playable characters, each with their own unique skills and custom attacks, as they compete in 3-on-3 battles in beautifully rendered 3-D worlds. Assemble your team and perform incredible fighting combos all for one united goal...Project Justice!</plot>
		<releasedate>16/05/2001</releasedate>
		<year>2001</year>
		<studio>Capcom</studio>
		<nplayers>2</nplayers>
		<ESRB>Not Rated</ESRB>
		<videoid>ZjfFw4NwqmQ</videoid>
		<boxart1>IX444i7.png</boxart1>
		<boxart2>mvBnN5B.jpg</boxart2>
		<boxart3>h849rP0.jpg</boxart3>
		<snapshot1>3ufsBsN.png</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>NPjPqC0.jpg</snapshot2>
		<clearlogo1>5tIk2sw.png</clearlogo1>
		<fanart1>Y7i0OsM.jpg</fanart1>
		<fanart2>iRIePPc.jpg</fanart2>
		<genre>Fighter</genre>
	</game>
	<game name="Pokasuka Ghost! (Japan)">
		<description>Pokasuka Ghost! (Japan)</description>
		<rom name="naomi_non_merged/pokasuka_folder.zip" size="149252998"/>
		<emu_command>pokasuka/pokasuka.zip</emu_command>
		<plot>Pokasuka Ghost</plot>
		<year>2007</year>
		<studio>Sega</studio>
		<nplayers>2</nplayers>
		<ESRB>Not Rated</ESRB>
		<genre>Action,Shooter</genre>
	</game>
	<game name="Power Stone">
		<description>Power Stone</description>
		<rom name="naomi_non_merged/pstone_folder.zip" size="45757655"/>
		<emu_command>pstone/pstone.zip</emu_command>
		<plot>Power Stone is a fully 3D arena fighting game made by Capcom. Power Stone was initially released on the Sega NAOMI hardware and later ported to the Dreamcast. In 2006, Capcom ported the game and its sequel to the PlayStation Portable as Power Stone Collection. An anime TV series based on the game ran in 1999 from April 3 to September 25.</plot>
		<releasedate>13/02/1999</releasedate>
		<year>1999</year>
		<studio>Capcom</studio>
		<nplayers>2</nplayers>
		<boxart1>eAvGPmN.jpg</boxart1>
		<boxart2>uwANqDr.jpg</boxart2>
		<boxart3>QMKLTU9.jpg</boxart3>
		<snapshot1>Wjnh70P.png</snapshot1>
		<banner1>sf3rNsu.png</banner1>
		<clearlogo1>xek7Acm.png</clearlogo1>
		<genre>Fighter,Platform</genre>
		<groups>Games made into TV series,Launch title: Dreamcast (North America),Power Stone games</groups>
	</game>
	<game name="Power Stone 2">
		<description>Power Stone 2</description>
		<rom name="naomi_non_merged/pstone2_folder.zip" size="59407866"/>
		<emu_command>pstone2/pstone2.zip</emu_command>
		<plot>Power Stone 2 is a multiplayer fighting game that built on the innovative gameplay introduced by its predecessor, Power Stone. Power Stone 2 allows up to four players to choose from multiple characters and utilize items such as tables, chairs, and rocks in battle.</plot>
		<releasedate>01/04/2000</releasedate>
		<year>2000</year>
		<studio>Capcom</studio>
		<nplayers>1-4</nplayers>
		<boxart1>40Ww90a.jpg</boxart1>
		<boxart2>1Q0SAta.jpg</boxart2>
		<boxart3>OAcvNMx.jpg</boxart3>
		<banner1>RaHPsIo.png</banner1>
		<clearlogo1>F3TIYVz.png</clearlogo1>
		<genre>Fighter,Platform</genre>
		<groups>Power Stone games</groups>
	</game>
	<game name="Psyvariar 2 - The Will To Fabricate (Japan) (GDL-0024)">
		<description>Psyvariar 2 - The Will To Fabricate (Japan) (GDL-0024)</description>
		<rom name="naomi_non_merged/psyvar2_folder.zip" size="141565965"/>
		<emu_command>psyvar2/psyvar2.zip</emu_command>
		<plot>Psyvariar 2: The Will to Fabricate is a vertically scrolling shoot em up developed by SKONEC Entertainment and distributed by Success. It is the sequel to the 2000 title, Psyvariar.[CR]The game was initially developed for the Sega NAOMI arcade platform, and was released in Japanese arcades in November 2003.</plot>
		<year>2003</year>
		<studio>G-Rev</studio>
		<nplayers>1</nplayers>
		<ESRB>Not Rated</ESRB>
		<boxart1>98wGHaI.png</boxart1>
		<boxart2>hrdqOTG.jpg</boxart2>
		<boxart3>cigzPkv.png</boxart3>
		<banner1>1A9zAGm.png</banner1>
		<clearlogo1>9GCaOV7.png</clearlogo1>
		<genre>Shooter</genre>
	</game>
	<game name="Puyo Puyo Da! (Japan)">
		<description>Puyo Puyo Da! (Japan)</description>
		<rom name="naomi_non_merged/puyoda_folder.zip" size="116433843"/>
		<emu_command>puyoda/puyoda.zip</emu_command>
		<plot>Puyo Puyo DA! featuring Ellena System is a Puyo Puyo dancing game created in 1999 for Arcade and Dreamcast. The game was released only in Japan.[CR]Arle Nadja and her friends take some time off from Puyo fighting and challenge players to dance with them. The game features several dance stages similar to those of Dance Dance Revolution. It also introduces a new ELLENA system used to render the game as well as a new exclusive character featuring the same name (Ellena Stevens, the protagonist of the original Broadway Legend Ellena). One or two players can dance to a variety of J-pop tunes by using the controller buttons to copy their opponents moves. Based on how well a player copies the moves, Nuisance Puyos are sent to their opponent. The player not having Nuisance Puyos on their side of the screen when the song is over wins the stage.</plot>
		<releasedate>20/10/1994</releasedate>
		<year>1999</year>
		<studio>Compile</studio>
		<ESRB>Not Rated</ESRB>
		<boxart1>4Eecw6Z.jpg</boxart1>
		<genre>Music,Rhythm</genre>
		<groups>Puyo Puyo games,Puyo Puyo variants,Puyo-Puyo / Madō Monogatari universe,Satakore (SegaSaturn Collection) releases</groups>
	</game>
	<game name="Puyo Pop Fever (World) (GDS-0034)">
		<description>Puyo Pop Fever (World) (GDS-0034)</description>
		<rom name="naomi_non_merged/puyofev_folder.zip" size="155888865"/>
		<emu_command>puyofev/puyofev.zip</emu_command>
		<plot>Accord, teacher of the local magic school, has lost her magic flying cane. There is word of an award so the students are busy searching high and low for it. Naturally, our heroes Amitie and her school nemesis Raffine make their way toward the distant dark castle, challenging - and being challenged by - everyone you come across in a game of Puyo Pop.[CR]Puyo Pop Fever is a puzzle game of the falling-block variety, the goal of which is to clear your blocks (Puyos) by combining four or more of the same color, which will then vanish. This will produce Nuisance Puyos. These colorless Puyos will fall onto your opponents screen, thus blocking chains and combos they could create. These pesky Puyos can only be exterminated by removing neighboring Puyos.[CR]When an opponent sends Nuisance Puyos to your screen you can try to "offset" by clearing your own Puyos and limiting the number that would fall on your screen. This will also increase your Fever Meter. When this meter fills you will be given a set of prearranged Puyos with which you can wrack up giant combos and send tons of Nuisance Puyos to your opponent. When any player's field becomes so full that they can no longer drop Puyos they lose the game.[CR]The game features a two-player mode. Some versions allow for more people such as the DS version which allows up to eight players to compete in free-for-all or team modes.</plot>
		<releasedate>04/02/2004</releasedate>
		<year>2004</year>
		<studio>Sonic Team</studio>
		<nplayers>2</nplayers>
		<ESRB>Not Rated</ESRB>
		<videoid>Gfe34ve-VBQ</videoid>
		<boxart1>Qb0kEGW.jpg</boxart1>
		<boxart2>W4Ounnv.jpg</boxart2>
		<clearlogo1>OAOQKx8.png</clearlogo1>
		<genre>Puzzle</genre>
		<groups>Graphics Engine: RenderWare,Middleware: CRI,Puyo Puyo games,Puyo Puyo variants,Puyo-Puyo / Madō Monogatari universe</groups>
	</game>
	<game name="Puyo Puyo Fever (Japan) (GDS-0031)">
		<description>Puyo Puyo Fever (Japan) (GDS-0031)</description>
		<rom name="naomi_non_merged/puyofevj_folder.zip" size="154512197"/>
		<emu_command>puyofevj/puyofevj.zip</emu_command>
		<plot>Accord, teacher of the local magic school, has lost her magic flying cane. There is word of an award so the students are busy searching high and low for it. Naturally, our heroes Amitie and her school nemesis Raffine make their way toward the distant dark castle, challenging - and being challenged by - everyone you come across in a game of Puyo Pop.[CR]Puyo Pop Fever is a puzzle game of the falling-block variety, the goal of which is to clear your blocks (Puyos) by combining four or more of the same color, which will then vanish. This will produce Nuisance Puyos. These colorless Puyos will fall onto your opponents screen, thus blocking chains and combos they could create. These pesky Puyos can only be exterminated by removing neighboring Puyos.[CR]When an opponent sends Nuisance Puyos to your screen you can try to "offset" by clearing your own Puyos and limiting the number that would fall on your screen. This will also increase your Fever Meter. When this meter fills you will be given a set of prearranged Puyos with which you can wrack up giant combos and send tons of Nuisance Puyos to your opponent. When any player's field becomes so full that they can no longer drop Puyos they lose the game.[CR]The game features a two-player mode. Some versions allow for more people such as the DS version which allows up to eight players to compete in free-for-all or team modes.</plot>
		<releasedate>04/02/2004</releasedate>
		<year>2004</year>
		<studio>Sonic Team</studio>
		<nplayers>2</nplayers>
		<ESRB>Not Rated</ESRB>
		<videoid>Gfe34ve-VBQ</videoid>
		<boxart1>Qb0kEGW.jpg</boxart1>
		<boxart2>W4Ounnv.jpg</boxart2>
		<clearlogo1>OAOQKx8.png</clearlogo1>
		<genre>Puzzle</genre>
		<groups>Graphics Engine: RenderWare,Middleware: CRI,Puyo Puyo games,Puyo Puyo variants,Puyo-Puyo / Madō Monogatari universe</groups>
	</game>
	<game name="Quiz Ah Megamisama">
		<description>Quiz Ah Megamisama</description>
		<rom name="naomi_non_merged/qmegamis_folder.zip" size="62957396"/>
		<emu_command>qmegamis/qmegamis.zip</emu_command>
		<ESRB>Not Rated</ESRB>
		<genre>Quiz</genre>
	</game>
	<game name="Radirgy (Japan, Rev A) (GDL-0032A)">
		<description>Radirgy (Japan, Rev A) (GDL-0032A)</description>
		<rom name="naomi_non_merged/radirgy_folder.zip" size="137021795"/>
		<emu_command>radirgy/radirgy.zip</emu_command>
		<plot>Radirgy is a vertical-screen top-down bullet-hell shooter originally developed by Milestone for Naomi arcade system and later released on console systems. The game features bright, cartoony, cel-shaded graphics. At the beginning, the player is given choice among three different mecha-ships: one with a spread-gun, a weak homing laser, or a slow but powerful bubble gun. Additionally, each ship can use a sword for anything that gets too close, or specific enemies which can't be killed otherwise, a shield, which appears at the front of the ship once the player lets go of the fire button, and a smart-bomb-like field that can be extended around the player in a small circle, damaging enemies, absorbing their shots and turning them into points.</plot>
		<releasedate>13/10/2005</releasedate>
		<year>2005</year>
		<studio>Milestone</studio>
		<ESRB>Not Rated</ESRB>
		<boxart1>1mBogBg.jpg</boxart1>
		<genre>Shooter</genre>
		<groups>Radirgy series</groups>
	</game>
	<game name="Radirgy Noa (Japan)">
		<description>Radirgy Noa (Japan)</description>
		<rom name="naomi_non_merged/radirgyn_folder.zip" size="112664294"/>
		<emu_command>radirgyn/radirgyn.zip</emu_command>
		<plot>Radirgy Noa (also written as Radirgynoa) is a vertically scrolling shoot em up that was released in June 2009 for the Sega Naomi arcade platform by Milestone Inc. and the sequel to Radirgy.[CR]Radirgy Noa features a cel-shaded graphical style very similar to that of its predecessor and 2-player co-op. Screen orientation is horizontal. Ruki Mishima, a reddemed villain of the first game, joins the cast as a player character.</plot>
		<releasedate>20/06/2009</releasedate>
		<year>2009</year>
		<studio>MileStone Inc.</studio>
		<nplayers>1-2 Co-Op</nplayers>
		<ESRB>Not Rated</ESRB>
		<videoid>amWgB5nepbQ</videoid>
		<boxart1>NrJ9PAz.jpg</boxart1>
		<boxart2>lh3RzLl.jpg</boxart2>
		<snapshot1>7v3kW5U.jpg</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>W4r1u9U.jpg</snapshot2>
		<clearlogo1>XkBt5Pq.png</clearlogo1>
		<genre>Shooter</genre>
		<groups>Radirgy series</groups>
	</game>
	<game name="Radirgy (Japan) (GDL-0032)">
		<description>Radirgy (Japan) (GDL-0032)</description>
		<rom name="naomi_non_merged/radirgyo_folder.zip" size="136896276"/>
		<emu_command>radirgyo/radirgyo.zip</emu_command>
		<plot>Radirgy is a vertical-screen top-down bullet-hell shooter originally developed by Milestone for Naomi arcade system and later released on console systems. The game features bright, cartoony, cel-shaded graphics. At the beginning, the player is given choice among three different mecha-ships: one with a spread-gun, a weak homing laser, or a slow but powerful bubble gun. Additionally, each ship can use a sword for anything that gets too close, or specific enemies which can't be killed otherwise, a shield, which appears at the front of the ship once the player lets go of the fire button, and a smart-bomb-like field that can be extended around the player in a small circle, damaging enemies, absorbing their shots and turning them into points.</plot>
		<releasedate>13/10/2005</releasedate>
		<year>2005</year>
		<studio>Milestone</studio>
		<ESRB>Not Rated</ESRB>
		<boxart1>1mBogBg.jpg</boxart1>
		<genre>Shooter</genre>
		<groups>Radirgy series</groups>
	</game>
	<game name="Rhythm Tengoku (Japan)">
		<description>Rhythm Tengoku (Japan)</description>
		<rom name="naomi_non_merged/rhytngk_folder.zip" size="125751761"/>
		<emu_command>rhytngk/rhytngk.zip</emu_command>
		<plot>Rhythm Tengoku is a rhythm game developed by Nintendo SPD and published by Nintendo. It was released on August 3, 2006, and was the last game developed by Nintendo for the Game Boy Advance. An arcade version of the game was reprogrammed and published by Sega on September 20, 2007. Both versions were released in Japan exclusively. The game has spawned three sequels; Rhythm Heaven, Rhythm Heaven Fever, and Rhythm Heaven Megamix. It began as an idea created by its composer and supervisor Tsunku who proposed it to Nintendo due to his belief that they could do a better job with it than he could.[CR]Rhythm Tengokus gameplay focuses on audio cues rather than visual cues to convey information to players. It features a number of unique stages which have their own type of rhythm and gameplay. Players follow the rhythm (in some rhythm games as a character) until the end where they are given a score based on their performance. The gameplay and music were both well received by critics and consumers. Parallels have been drawn between it and the developer's previous work on the WarioWare series.</plot>
		<ESRB>Not Rated</ESRB>
		<boxart1>ZOF4mTZ.jpg</boxart1>
		<genre>Music</genre>
	</game>
	<game name="Ring Out 4x4 (Rev A)">
		<description>Ring Out 4x4 (Rev A)</description>
		<rom name="naomi_non_merged/ringout_folder.zip" size="40933256"/>
		<emu_command>ringout/ringout.zip</emu_command>
		<plot>A top-down 3D vehicular-combat arcade game where players attempt to knock each-other off the arena.</plot>
		<year>1999</year>
		<ESRB>Not Rated</ESRB>
		<snapshot1>LnfC0bB.png</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>uMDm3hd.jpg</snapshot2>
		<genre>Racing</genre>
	</game>
	<game name="Samba de Amigo ver. 2000 (Japan)">
		<description>Samba de Amigo ver. 2000 (Japan)</description>
		<rom name="naomi_non_merged/samba2k_folder.zip" size="167232766"/>
		<emu_command>samba2k/samba2k.zip</emu_command>
		<plot>Samba de Amigo is a rhythm game developed by Sonic Team and published by Sega. The game was released in arcades in December 1999, and for the Dreamcast video game console in 2000.[CR]In Samba de Amigo, the player uses controllers shaped like maracas with the goal of matching a series of patterns displayed on-screen. The music in Samba de Amigo is made of primarily popular Latin music songs rather than common or traditional samba. The game also features non-Latin pop songs.</plot>
		<releasedate>20/03/2000</releasedate>
		<year>1999</year>
		<studio>Sonic Team</studio>
		<nplayers>2</nplayers>
		<ESRB>Not Rated</ESRB>
		<boxart1>RX0qrgu.jpg</boxart1>
		<genre>Music,Rhythm</genre>
		<groups>Samba De Amigo series</groups>
	</game>
	<game name="Senko no Ronde (Japan, Rev A) (GDL-0030A)">
		<description>Senko no Ronde (Japan, Rev A) (GDL-0030A)</description>
		<rom name="naomi_non_merged/senko_folder.zip" size="8310718"/>
		<emu_command>senko/senko.zip</emu_command>
		<plot>Due to a past catastrophe on Earth, humanity was forced to live amongst the stars for several centuries, resulting in the creation of the S.D. calendar and the birth of the Aria Federation, an empire whose influence extends from Earth to Saturn. In S.D. 1478, an embassy located within the empires capital on Earths moon was seized by terrorists, and forces deployed by Aria's Special Space Service ended in disaster as the terrorists triggered a self-detonation device, killing themselves and several civilians in the process.[CR]The game begins six years after this event, with the player assuming the role of one of eight characters who will become involved in a mastermind's scheme to take control of the Aria Federation's superweapon and use it for his own purposes.[CR]Toward the Terra, a science fiction series created by Keiko Takemiya, has played a major influence for both Senko no Ronde's story and art style.</plot>
		<releasedate>20/04/2005</releasedate>
		<year>2005</year>
		<studio>G.Rev</studio>
		<nplayers>2</nplayers>
		<ESRB>Not Rated</ESRB>
		<boxart1>e5cPlv2.jpg</boxart1>
		<boxart2>Db2EtS7.jpg</boxart2>
		<boxart3>dCykeYo.png</boxart3>
		<snapshot1>sSfQzNp.png</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>z2Wf5fO.png</snapshot2>
		<banner1>Nt5t2Sg.png</banner1>
		<clearlogo1>Rj66IcM.png</clearlogo1>
		<genre>Driving,Shooter</genre>
		<groups>Senko no Ronde series</groups>
	</game>
	<game name="Senko no Ronde Special (Export, Japan) (GDL-0038)">
		<description>Senko no Ronde Special (Export, Japan) (GDL-0038)</description>
		<rom name="naomi_non_merged/senkosp_folder.zip" size="247607722"/>
		<emu_command>senkosp/senkosp.zip</emu_command>
		<plot>Senko no Ronde SP is a fighting game developed by G.Rev and published by Sega for the Sega NAOMI arcade system. It is the sequel to Senko no Ronde, and includes many features backported from the game Senko no Ronde Rev X.</plot>
		<year>2005</year>
		<studio>G.Rev</studio>
		<nplayers>2</nplayers>
		<ESRB>Not Rated</ESRB>
		<boxart1>e5cPlv2.jpg</boxart1>
		<boxart2>Db2EtS7.jpg</boxart2>
		<boxart3>dCykeYo.png</boxart3>
		<snapshot1>sSfQzNp.png</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>z2Wf5fO.png</snapshot2>
		<banner1>Nt5t2Sg.png</banner1>
		<clearlogo1>Rj66IcM.png</clearlogo1>
		<genre>Shooter</genre>
	</game>
	<game name="Street Fighter Zero 3 Upper (Japan) (GDL-0002)">
		<description>Street Fighter Zero 3 Upper (Japan) (GDL-0002)</description>
		<rom name="naomi_non_merged/sfz3ugd_folder.zip" size="115786682"/>
		<emu_command>sfz3ugd/sfz3ugd.zip</emu_command>
		<plot>Street Fighter Zero 3 is the third game in the Street Fighter Alpha series, following Street Fighter Alpha: Warriors' Dreams and Street Fighter Alpha 2. The gameplay system from the previous Alpha games was given a complete overhaul with the addition of three selectable fighting styles based on Street Fighter Alpha: Warriors' Dreams (A-ism), Street Fighter Alpha 2 (V-ism), and Super Street Fighter II Turbo (X-ism), new stages, over 7 new and returning characters, and a new and exclusive soundtrack for the game.[CR]The game illustrations, select screens, soundtrack, sound effects, etc, all have a similar style to the Final Fight series, unlike the previous games.[CR]Street Fighter Zero 3 Upper discards the Manual and Auto modes from the previous Alpha games by offering the player three different playing styles known as "isms." The standard playing style, A-ism (or Z-ism in Japan), is based on the previous games, in which the player has a three-level Super Combo gauge with access to several Super Combo moves. X-ism is a simple style based on Super Street Fighter II Turbo, in which the player has a single-level Super Combo gauge and access to a single, but powerful, Super Combo move. The third style, V-ism (or variable style), a unique style that allows the player to perform Custom Combos similar to the ones in Street Fighter Alpha 2. In X-ism, players cannot air-block nor use Alpha Counters. The game also introduces a Guard Power gauge which depletes each time the player blocks - everytime the gauge is completely depleted, the player suffers a "guard crush" (in which the gauge itself decreases in size, thus causing the player to gradatively lose ability to block attacks as the guard gauge keeps decreasing) which leaves him/her temporarily vulnerable for an attack.</plot>
		<releasedate>01/01/2001</releasedate>
		<year>2001</year>
		<studio>Capcom</studio>
		<nplayers>2</nplayers>
		<ESRB>Not Rated</ESRB>
		<videoid>8yj64Ar4PwA</videoid>
		<boxart1>fFmxSTs.jpg</boxart1>
		<boxart2>BpojB8W.jpg</boxart2>
		<boxart3>ZRRbTT7.jpg</boxart3>
		<snapshot1>fbfDaSf.png</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>95z9fSk.png</snapshot2>
		<banner1>GmXrR2O.jpg</banner1>
		<clearlogo1>DdN7ksb.png</clearlogo1>
		<genre>Fighter</genre>
		<groups>Street Fighter series</groups>
	</game>
	<game name="Sega Tetris">
		<description>Sega Tetris</description>
		<rom name="naomi_non_merged/sgtetris_folder.zip" size="35374578"/>
		<emu_command>sgtetris/sgtetris.zip</emu_command>
		<plot>Ready to take a step into the surreal? Then welcome to Sega Tetris. Originally created by Sega AM1 as a NAOMI arcade game, the subsequently created Wow Entertainment ported Sega Tetris to the Dreamcast in 2000. A Japanese exclusive, Sega Tetris is a pretty interesting and original take on the original game, not least because of the bizarre imagery and settings it uses. The game naturally playes in a familiar manner with the usual gameplay mechanics in place, but it's the extra details that make Sega Tetris such a fun title. The addiction of bizarre cartoon characters that dance and gyrate by the play board as you move the Tetriminos around is interesting, and the way they hit the blocks to destroy any lines you make can be amusing.</plot>
		<releasedate>20/03/1999</releasedate>
		<year>1999</year>
		<studio>Sega</studio>
		<nplayers>2</nplayers>
		<ESRB>Not Rated</ESRB>
		<videoid>d7ANcuLMFqU</videoid>
		<boxart1>XaHeCiG.jpg</boxart1>
		<boxart2>rSduCmO.jpg</boxart2>
		<boxart3>eFt4ol0.jpg</boxart3>
		<snapshot1>R9HUaNX.jpg</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>uQf8cmn.png</snapshot2>
		<clearlogo1>koiTYjJ.png</clearlogo1>
		<genre>Puzzle</genre>
		<groups>Tetris licensees</groups>
	</game>
	<game name="Shakatto Tambourine Cho Powerup Chu (2K1 AUT) (GDS-0016)">
		<description>Shakatto Tambourine Cho Powerup Chu (2K1 AUT) (GDS-0016)</description>
		<rom name="naomi_non_merged/shaktamb_folder.zip" size="187264050"/>
		<emu_command>shaktamb/shaktamb.zip</emu_command>
		<plot>Shakatto Tambourine Cho Powerup Chu (GDS-0016)</plot>
		<year>2001</year>
		<studio>Sega</studio>
		<ESRB>Not Rated</ESRB>
		<genre>Music,Rhythm</genre>
	</game>
	<game name="Dengen Tenshi Taisen Janshi Shangri-la">
		<description>Dengen Tenshi Taisen Janshi Shangri-la</description>
		<rom name="naomi_non_merged/shangril_folder.zip" size="103342404"/>
		<emu_command>shangril/shangril.zip</emu_command>
		<plot>Dengen Tenshi Taisen Janshi Shangri-la (JPN, USA, EXP, KOR, AUS)</plot>
		<year>1999</year>
		<studio>Marvelous Ent.</studio>
		<nplayers>1</nplayers>
		<ESRB>Not Rated</ESRB>
		<genre>Mahjong</genre>
	</game>
	<game name="Shikigami no Shiro II / The Castle of Shikigami II (GDL-0021)">
		<description>Shikigami no Shiro II / The Castle of Shikigami II (GDL-0021)</description>
		<rom name="naomi_non_merged/shikgam2_folder.zip" size="114746154"/>
		<emu_command>shikgam2/shikgam2.zip</emu_command>
		<plot>In the recent past, a band of champions gathered to engage this threat. Using weapons forged by the great magicians and masters of arcane sciences, the heroes managed to banished the demons, quelling their thirst for conquest! The time: 2006, the distant future. The Demon Gods and their mystical castle have reappeared above the skies of Tokyo City with the goal of continuing the domination and conquest of humanity. Can the heroes of recent legend return to defeat the nemesis of all mankind? The tools for defeating the gods are trapped within the very castle in which the demons reside. The hope of the world lies on the shoulders of these heroes; they must succeed in this vertical shooter.</plot>
		<releasedate>24/03/2004</releasedate>
		<year>2004</year>
		<studio>Alfa System</studio>
		<nplayers>2</nplayers>
		<ESRB>Not Rated</ESRB>
		<videoid>XDr3T4_91Co</videoid>
		<boxart1>Cr6KAXG.jpg</boxart1>
		<genre>Shooter</genre>
	</game>
	<game name="Shootout Pool">
		<description>Shootout Pool</description>
		<rom name="naomi_non_merged/shootopl_folder.zip" size="17431270"/>
		<emu_command>shootopl/shootopl.zip</emu_command>
		<plot>Shootout Pool is an arcade billiards game released for Sega NAOMI arcade hardware</plot>
		<year>2001</year>
		<studio>Sega</studio>
		<nplayers>2</nplayers>
		<ESRB>Not Rated</ESRB>
		<boxart1>XHq4Nqg.jpg</boxart1>
		<boxart2>PWRyHvw.jpg</boxart2>
		<boxart3>JWcRSsW.jpg</boxart3>
		<snapshot1>mEtQW72.png</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>z4rexqU.png</snapshot2>
		<clearlogo1>yeUTBEc.png</clearlogo1>
		<genre>Sports,Sports,Billiards</genre>
	</game>
	<game name="Shooting Love 2007 (Japan)">
		<description>Shooting Love 2007 (Japan)</description>
		<rom name="naomi_non_merged/sl2007_folder.zip" size="114619142"/>
		<emu_command>sl2007/sl2007.zip</emu_command>
		<plot>Shooting Love 2007 is a Sega NAOMI arcade shoot-'em-up game developed by Triangle Service. It contains two games; Exzeal, which is a sequel to Trizeal and Shmups Skills Test</plot>
		<releasedate>27/07/2007</releasedate>
		<year>2007</year>
		<studio>Triangle Service</studio>
		<nplayers>2</nplayers>
		<ESRB>Not Rated</ESRB>
		<videoid>hvLwOwODDTc</videoid>
		<boxart1>6SRzz1m.png</boxart1>
		<boxart2>Pp3M58o.png</boxart2>
		<boxart3>rXWGjY2.png</boxart3>
		<clearlogo1>k3o0Euq.png</clearlogo1>
		<genre>Shooter</genre>
		<groups>Triangle Service Love series</groups>
	</game>
	<game name="Slashout (GDS-0004)">
		<description>Slashout (GDS-0004)</description>
		<rom name="naomi_non_merged/slashout_folder.zip" size="142303119"/>
		<emu_command>slashout/slashout.zip</emu_command>
		<plot>Slashout is the third installment to the Spikeout series, released for Sega NAOMI hardware in 2000. Unlike other games in the series, Slashout has a completely different setting, based in a fantasy world with different characters-gameplay remains similar, however.</plot>
		<releasedate>01/01/2000</releasedate>
		<year>2000</year>
		<studio>Sega</studio>
		<nplayers>1</nplayers>
		<ESRB>AAMA - Yellow (Animated Violence Mild)</ESRB>
		<boxart1>Pf6jndO.jpg</boxart1>
		<boxart2>uBVz8uD.jpg</boxart2>
		<boxart3>sd5f4O6.jpg</boxart3>
		<snapshot1>4VCW81p.png</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>gvZCAwc.png</snapshot2>
		<banner1>uTAxfFT.png</banner1>
		<clearlogo1>gkqJnbP.png</clearlogo1>
		<genre>Action,Beat Em Up,Fighter</genre>
		<groups>Spikeout series</groups>
	</game>
	<game name="Sega Marine Fishing">
		<description>Sega Marine Fishing</description>
		<rom name="naomi_non_merged/smarinef_folder.zip" size="37337434"/>
		<emu_command>smarinef/smarinef.zip</emu_command>
		<plot>Sega Marine Fishing is a fishing video game in which the player attempts to catch various marine sport fish. The gameplay's emphasis was on enticing fish to bite onto the lure and then successfully fighting the fish and reeling it to the boat.</plot>
		<releasedate>20/10/2000</releasedate>
		<year>2000</year>
		<studio>WOW Entertainment</studio>
		<nplayers>1</nplayers>
		<ESRB>AAMA - Green (Suitable For All Ages)</ESRB>
		<boxart1>zlt4SLQ.jpg</boxart1>
		<boxart2>ik5SvlM.jpg</boxart2>
		<boxart3>y7RdVGD.png</boxart3>
		<snapshot1>xQasQRC.png</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>KokWj4i.png</snapshot2>
		<banner1>BCwlZZq.png</banner1>
		<clearlogo1>mhsKnme.png</clearlogo1>
		<genre>Sports,Sports,Fishing</genre>
		<groups>SEGA Bass Fishing series</groups>
	</game>
	<game name="World Series 99 / Super Major League 99">
		<description>World Series 99 / Super Major League 99</description>
		<rom name="naomi_non_merged/smlg99_folder.zip" size="115005565"/>
		<emu_command>smlg99/smlg99.zip</emu_command>
		<plot>World Series 99, known as Super Major League 99 (スーパーメジャーリーグ99) in Japan, is an arcade baseball game released for Sega NAOMI hardware in 1999.</plot>
		<year>2001</year>
		<studio>Sega</studio>
		<nplayers>2</nplayers>
		<ESRB>Not Rated</ESRB>
		<videoid>bCtZxHUYrPs</videoid>
		<genre>Sports,Sports,Baseball</genre>
	</game>
	<game name="Spawn In the Demon's Hand (Rev B)">
		<description>Spawn In the Demon's Hand (Rev B)</description>
		<rom name="naomi_non_merged/spawn_folder.zip" size="61378717"/>
		<emu_command>spawn/spawn.zip</emu_command>
		<plot>Spawn: In the Demon's Hand is a video game developed and published by Capcom for the Dreamcast and arcade. It is based on the comic book character Spawn created by Todd McFarlane and produced by Image Comics. A port was planned for the PlayStation 2 as a launch title but it was later canceled.</plot>
		<releasedate>20/01/2000</releasedate>
		<year>1999</year>
		<studio>Capcom</studio>
		<nplayers>1</nplayers>
		<ESRB>AAMA - Yellow (Animated Violence Mild)</ESRB>
		<boxart1>ztHbRRR.jpg</boxart1>
		<boxart2>zMCQoEx.jpg</boxart2>
		<boxart3>u07a8V3.png</boxart3>
		<snapshot1>giiYM22.png</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>rIbiZBR.png</snapshot2>
		<banner1>zPIMb2i.png</banner1>
		<clearlogo1>3Lbd3cl.png</clearlogo1>
		<genre>Action,Beat Em Up</genre>
		<groups>Inspiration: Comics,Protagonist: Black,Spawn licensees</groups>
	</game>
	<game name="Spikers Battle (GDS-0005)">
		<description>Spikers Battle (GDS-0005)</description>
		<rom name="naomi_non_merged/spkrbtl_folder.zip" size="152723904"/>
		<emu_command>spkrbtl/spkrbtl.zip</emu_command>
		<plot>Spikers Battle is a cross between a 3D beat 'em-up and versus fighting game. The game takes place in a urban setting and offers a total of eight playable streetfighter characters. Returning characters from the earlier 1998 arcade game Spikeout are Spike, Linda, Tenshin and White. The new fighters are Albelto, Hikaru, Fengli and Gorn.[CR]In the game you fight in several different arenas against three playable and/or non-playable characters in a best out of three round match. Aside from the kick and punch attacks weapons like a baseball bat, hammer and flame thrower can be picked up and used on the opponents. Beaten enemies sometimes drop boxes that replenish life.</plot>
		<releasedate>01/07/2001</releasedate>
		<year>2001</year>
		<studio>Sega</studio>
		<nplayers>1</nplayers>
		<ESRB>E - Everyone</ESRB>
		<videoid>Jn6r0rjRAv4</videoid>
		<boxart1>gs3v1G7.jpg</boxart1>
		<boxart2>i3nHaWL.jpg</boxart2>
		<boxart3>qaL1TPw.jpg</boxart3>
		<snapshot1>1rD7jrt.png</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>VosygOF.png</snapshot2>
		<banner1>a443Kmy.png</banner1>
		<clearlogo1>gJw7VJ5.png</clearlogo1>
		<genre>Beat Em Up,Fighter</genre>
		<groups>Spikeout series</groups>
	</game>
	<game name="Sports Jam (GDS-0003)">
		<description>Sports Jam (GDS-0003)</description>
		<rom name="naomi_non_merged/sprtjam_folder.zip" size="128612778"/>
		<emu_command>sprtjam/sprtjam.zip</emu_command>
		<plot>Sports Jam contains many sports games that can be played by a single player or as multi-player games. Players can select from a great range of sporting games.[CR]Sports include 3 point shoot out, a basketball game in which the player needs both speed and accuracy to sink as many 3 point shots as possible in the time allowed, and Touch down derby, an American football game where the player attempts to return a kickdown all the way for a touchdown.</plot>
		<releasedate>20/12/2000</releasedate>
		<year>2000</year>
		<studio>Sega</studio>
		<nplayers>2</nplayers>
		<ESRB>Not Rated</ESRB>
		<videoid>tf9Ee4Ffwb4</videoid>
		<boxart1>KiXzy0w.jpg</boxart1>
		<boxart2>j3vDw8w.png</boxart2>
		<boxart3>kn7nmcJ.png</boxart3>
		<snapshot1>Wu8HgBf.png</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>g5meWUH.png</snapshot2>
		<banner1>SlM4n9m.png</banner1>
		<clearlogo1>qeDbVtx.png</clearlogo1>
		<fanart1>chirrEl.jpg</fanart1>
		<genre>Sports</genre>
	</game>
	<game name="Super Shanghai 2005 (Japan, Rev A) (GDL-0031A)">
		<description>Super Shanghai 2005 (Japan, Rev A) (GDL-0031A)</description>
		<rom name="naomi_non_merged/ss2005_folder.zip" size="64262754"/>
		<emu_command>ss2005/ss2005.zip</emu_command>
		<plot>Super Shanghai 2005 (Rev A) (GDL-0031A)</plot>
		<year>2005</year>
		<studio>Starfish</studio>
		<nplayers>2</nplayers>
		<ESRB>Not Rated</ESRB>
		<boxart1>bvcYqHs.jpg</boxart1>
		<boxart2>g3Coyor.jpg</boxart2>
		<boxart3>ZtckRVv.png</boxart3>
		<banner1>d9dGugK.png</banner1>
		<clearlogo1>mq0T0cr.png</clearlogo1>
		<genre>Puzzle</genre>
	</game>
	<game name="Super Shanghai 2005 (Japan) (GDL-0031)">
		<description>Super Shanghai 2005 (Japan) (GDL-0031)</description>
		<rom name="naomi_non_merged/ss2005o_folder.zip" size="63285716"/>
		<emu_command>ss2005o/ss2005o.zip</emu_command>
		<plot>Super Shanghai 2005 (GDL-0031)</plot>
		<year>2005</year>
		<studio>Starfish</studio>
		<nplayers>2</nplayers>
		<ESRB>Not Rated</ESRB>
		<boxart1>bvcYqHs.jpg</boxart1>
		<boxart2>g3Coyor.jpg</boxart2>
		<boxart3>ZtckRVv.png</boxart3>
		<banner1>d9dGugK.png</banner1>
		<clearlogo1>mq0T0cr.png</clearlogo1>
		<genre>Puzzle</genre>
	</game>
	<game name="Sega Strike Fighter (Rev A)">
		<description>Sega Strike Fighter (Rev A)</description>
		<rom name="naomi_non_merged/sstrkfgt_folder.zip" size="79542937"/>
		<emu_command>sstrkfgt/sstrkfgt.zip</emu_command>
		<plot>As the pilot of an F/A-18 Hornet, a player embarks on a multitude of hair raising missions. These missions range from basic training to full fledged air-to-air and air-to-ground engagements.[CR]This game was released in two cabinet styles Deluxe and Standard. Both models have rudder pedals, throttle with a button for air brake, and flight stick with trigger guns and thumb button missles. However, the Deluxe model is slightly larger and is styled much like the cockpit of a fighter. It has three monitors one for forward headsupdisplay view and two that act as window views for left and right. The Standard model just has a seat and one monitor for forward headsupdisplay view.</plot>
		<releasedate>01/07/1991</releasedate>
		<year>1991</year>
		<studio>Sega</studio>
		<nplayers>1</nplayers>
		<ESRB>Not Rated</ESRB>
		<videoid>PXDaGTVzQmM</videoid>
		<boxart1>YXaryA6.jpg</boxart1>
		<boxart2>v8APJNp.jpg</boxart2>
		<boxart3>DNFhwyJ.jpg</boxart3>
		<snapshot1>daXATtq.png</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>5zbpfHG.png</snapshot2>
		<banner1>kIaGlVW.png</banner1>
		<clearlogo1>nZ40gVv.png</clearlogo1>
		<fanart1>kA3I4VD.jpg</fanart1>
		<genre>Action,Flying,Shooter</genre>
	</game>
	<game name="Doki Doki Idol Star Seeker (GDL-0005)">
		<description>Doki Doki Idol Star Seeker (GDL-0005)</description>
		<rom name="naomi_non_merged/starseek_folder.zip" size="37057597"/>
		<emu_command>starseek/starseek.zip</emu_command>
		<plot>Doki Doki Idol Star Seeker is an arcade puzzle game for Sega NAOMI hardware.</plot>
		<year>2001</year>
		<studio>G-Rev</studio>
		<nplayers>2</nplayers>
		<ESRB>Not Rated</ESRB>
		<boxart1>LjUymG5.jpg</boxart1>
		<boxart2>9PQ7tCP.png</boxart2>
		<boxart3>8jATOvR.png</boxart3>
		<snapshot1>2urNv1U.png</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>hMEVq2W.png</snapshot2>
		<clearlogo1>1JXVous.png</clearlogo1>
		<genre>Puzzle</genre>
	</game>
	<game name="Idol Janshi Suchie-Pai 3 (Japan)">
		<description>Idol Janshi Suchie-Pai 3 (Japan)</description>
		<rom name="naomi_non_merged/suchie3_folder.zip" size="107266323"/>
		<emu_command>suchie3/suchie3.zip</emu_command>
		<plot>The third arcade entry in the [I]Suchie-Pai[/I] series, [I]Idol Janshi Suchie-Pai III[/I] brings more strip mahjong with Misaki Kyoko, better known as Suchie-Pai. But things get strange when a second Suchie-Pai appears. [CR]This game features some returning opponents and some new opponents. Graphics are vastly improved over those of its predecessors, released several years earlier.</plot>
		<releasedate>20/03/1999</releasedate>
		<year>1999</year>
		<studio>Jaleco</studio>
		<nplayers>1</nplayers>
		<ESRB>Not Rated</ESRB>
		<genre>Mahjong</genre>
		<groups>Suchie-Pai series</groups>
	</game>
	<game name="Noukone Puzzle Takoron (Japan) (GDL-0042)">
		<description>Noukone Puzzle Takoron (Japan) (GDL-0042)</description>
		<rom name="naomi_non_merged/takoron_folder.zip" size="53181350"/>
		<emu_command>takoron/takoron.zip</emu_command>
		<plot>Noumiso Konekone Puzzle Takoron is a puzzle game by Compile Heart.[CR]The player controls a 2x2 cursor over a field of colored octopuses. Pressing a button causes the octopuses under the cursor to rotate counter-clockwise. Numbered nets are scattered around the playing field. If the player arranges a number of same-colored octopuses under the net, the octopuses under the net, as well as any other octopuses of the same color which are connected orthogonally, are removed.[CR]By removing octopuses in this way, the player can send sea urchins to their opponents playing field. Sea urchins can not be removed using nets, but are removed if they are orthogonal to other octopuses being removed, similar to ojama puyos in Puyo Puyo. If the players field fills up for 3 seconds, they lose.</plot>
		<year>2006</year>
		<studio>Compile</studio>
		<nplayers>2</nplayers>
		<ESRB>Not Rated</ESRB>
		<boxart1>HEIWwT0.jpg</boxart1>
		<boxart2>LajtRWD.jpg</boxart2>
		<boxart3>eJhucOr.png</boxart3>
		<banner1>rQMLyOS.png</banner1>
		<clearlogo1>aJqS2X7.png</clearlogo1>
		<genre>Puzzle</genre>
	</game>
	<game name="Touch de Uno! 2 (Japan)">
		<description>Touch de Uno! 2 (Japan)</description>
		<rom name="naomi_non_merged/tduno2_folder.zip" size="52354858"/>
		<emu_command>tduno2/tduno2.zip</emu_command>
		<plot>Touch de Uno! 2</plot>
		<year>2000</year>
		<studio>Sega</studio>
		<nplayers>2</nplayers>
		<ESRB>Not Rated</ESRB>
		<genre>Tabletop</genre>
	</game>
	<game name="Tetris Kiwamemichi (Japan) (GDL-0020)">
		<description>Tetris Kiwamemichi (Japan) (GDL-0020)</description>
		<rom name="naomi_non_merged/tetkiwam_folder.zip" size="63376656"/>
		<emu_command>tetkiwam/tetkiwam.zip</emu_command>
		<plot>Tetris Kiwamemichi looks very similar to Tetris DS, as well as Tetris Advance. The game includes a two player co-op and versus mode. Infinity is included, but can be disabled. Like the gameboy tetris versions, this game features a post entry delay, that lets you move and rotate a piece before it starts to drop. This significantly decreases the difficulty of 20G play.</plot>
		<year>2004</year>
		<studio>Success</studio>
		<nplayers>2</nplayers>
		<ESRB>Not Rated</ESRB>
		<videoid>77Ozemy_zFU</videoid>
		<boxart1>AlVJX2b.jpg</boxart1>
		<boxart2>qqOP7PQ.png</boxart2>
		<boxart3>rUZbFGT.png</boxart3>
		<clearlogo1>4nTYgB4.png</clearlogo1>
		<genre>Puzzle</genre>
	</game>
	<game name="Tokyo Bus Guide (Japan, Rev A)">
		<description>Tokyo Bus Guide (Japan, Rev A)</description>
		<rom name="naomi_non_merged/tokyobus_folder.zip" size="85759219"/>
		<emu_command>tokyobus/tokyobus.zip</emu_command>
		<plot>Tokyo Bus Tour is a driving game where the player assumes the role of a bus driver who gives passengers a tour of Tokyo, Japan.</plot>
		<studio>Fortyfive</studio>
		<ESRB>Not Rated</ESRB>
		<boxart1>bFIQP7t.jpg</boxart1>
		<boxart2>E0aaCUc.jpg</boxart2>
		<boxart3>Nx9aZUH.jpg</boxart3>
		<snapshot1>OKyIU9N.jpg</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>8L2II3k.jpg</snapshot2>
		<clearlogo1>GKvEvi1.png</clearlogo1>
	</game>
	<game name="The Typing of the Dead (Rev A)">
		<description>The Typing of the Dead (Rev A)</description>
		<rom name="naomi_non_merged/totd_folder.zip" size="93716419"/>
		<emu_command>totd/totd.zip</emu_command>
		<plot>The Typing of the Dead is an arcade game that was developed by WOW Entertainment and published by Sega for the NAOMI hardware. The game was released in Japanese arcades in 1999 and was ported to the Sega Dreamcast in 2001 by Smilebit.[CR]The Typing of the Dead is a modification of Sega's 1998 light gun arcade game The House of the Dead 2 in which the gun is replaced by a computer keyboard. The player takes the role of a secret agent in a zombie-infested Venice and must quickly type letters, words and phrases in order to kill fast-advancing enemies.[CR]Despite falling under the criteria of 'edutainment', the game was lauded by mainstream game critics for its humor, difficulty and originality.</plot>
		<releasedate>20/03/1999</releasedate>
		<year>2000</year>
		<studio>Sega</studio>
		<nplayers>2</nplayers>
		<ESRB>Not Rated</ESRB>
		<boxart1>L9jmdYG.jpg</boxart1>
		<boxart2>Iy8qfi5.jpg</boxart2>
		<boxart3>yW9XtHq.png</boxart3>
		<snapshot1>f12Y1vG.png</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>ZKwKtXm.png</snapshot2>
		<clearlogo1>zP2LWOU.png</clearlogo1>
		<genre>Educational,Miscellaneous,Shooter</genre>
		<groups>The House of the Dead series,The Typing of the Dead series,Theme: Zombies</groups>
	</game>
	<game name="Shin Nihon Pro Wrestling Toukon Retsuden 4 Arcade Edition (Japan, TRF1 Ver.A)">
		<description>Shin Nihon Pro Wrestling Toukon Retsuden 4 Arcade Edition (Japan, TRF1 Ver.A)</description>
		<rom name="naomi_non_merged/toukon4_folder.zip" size="227507202"/>
		<emu_command>toukon4/toukon4.zip</emu_command>
		<plot>Toukon Retsuden 4 was developed by Yukes, and is mainly focused on providing a realistic representation of professional wrestling. Toukon Retsuden's presentation is similar to real life broadcasts, including crowd noise and extravagant introductions. The gameplay found in Toukon Retsuden is vastly different from traditional American/Japanese wrestling games</plot>
		<releasedate>02/09/1999</releasedate>
		<year>1999</year>
		<studio>Yuke's</studio>
		<nplayers>2</nplayers>
		<ESRB>Not Rated</ESRB>
		<boxart1>3tNsxbJ.jpg</boxart1>
		<genre>Sports,Sports,Wrestling</genre>
	</game>
	<game name="Toy Fighter">
		<description>Toy Fighter</description>
		<rom name="naomi_non_merged/toyfight_folder.zip" size="48261922"/>
		<emu_command>toyfight/toyfight.zip</emu_command>
		<plot>Toy Fighter is a Sega NAOMI versus fighting game released in 1999. Plans were supposedly put in place to release this game on the Sega Dreamcast, though were shelved for unknown reasons</plot>
		<releasedate>01/01/1999</releasedate>
		<year>1999</year>
		<nplayers>2</nplayers>
		<ESRB>Not Rated</ESRB>
		<boxart1>BCsf9bP.jpg</boxart1>
		<boxart2>tOc4iLo.jpg</boxart2>
		<boxart3>lWVe6Dq.png</boxart3>
		<snapshot1>CCASWRf.png</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>UZ7oP09.png</snapshot2>
		<banner1>swReteB.png</banner1>
		<clearlogo1>WMMIPeP.png</clearlogo1>
		<genre>Fighter</genre>
	</game>
	<game name="Trigger Heart Exelica Ver.A (Japan) (GDL-0036A)">
		<description>Trigger Heart Exelica Ver.A (Japan) (GDL-0036A)</description>
		<rom name="naomi_non_merged/trgheart_folder.zip" size="94230144"/>
		<emu_command>trgheart/trgheart.zip</emu_command>
		<plot>Triggerheart Exelica is a vertically scrolling shoot 'em up developed by Warashi for the Sega NAOMI platform. The game was first released in Japanese arcades in May 2006, and was later ported to the Sega Dreamcast, becoming the system's penultimate licensed title when it was released in Japan on February 22, 2007-only two weeks prior to Karous.</plot>
		<releasedate>20/05/2006</releasedate>
		<year>2005</year>
		<studio>Warashi</studio>
		<nplayers>2</nplayers>
		<ESRB>AAMA - Green (Suitable For All Ages)</ESRB>
		<boxart1>RmChbzp.jpg</boxart1>
		<boxart2>uCwdV1q.jpg</boxart2>
		<boxart3>NJW9hev.png</boxart3>
		<snapshot1>sRMmW2A.png</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>GKdUGfZ.png</snapshot2>
		<clearlogo1>U3ubXdw.png</clearlogo1>
		<genre>Shooter</genre>
	</game>
	<game name="Trigger Heart Exelica (Japan) (GDL-0036)">
		<description>Trigger Heart Exelica (Japan) (GDL-0036)</description>
		<rom name="naomi_non_merged/trghearto_folder.zip" size="90458169"/>
		<emu_command>trghearto/trghearto.zip</emu_command>
		<plot>Triggerheart Exelica is a vertically scrolling shoot 'em up developed by Warashi for the Sega NAOMI platform. The game was first released in Japanese arcades in May 2006, and was later ported to the Sega Dreamcast, becoming the system's penultimate licensed title when it was released in Japan on February 22, 2007-only two weeks prior to Karous.</plot>
		<releasedate>20/05/2006</releasedate>
		<year>2005</year>
		<studio>Warashi</studio>
		<nplayers>2</nplayers>
		<ESRB>AAMA - Green (Suitable For All Ages)</ESRB>
		<boxart1>RmChbzp.jpg</boxart1>
		<boxart2>uCwdV1q.jpg</boxart2>
		<boxart3>NJW9hev.png</boxart3>
		<snapshot1>sRMmW2A.png</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>GKdUGfZ.png</snapshot2>
		<clearlogo1>U3ubXdw.png</clearlogo1>
		<genre>Shooter</genre>
	</game>
	<game name="Trizeal (Japan) (GDL-0026)">
		<description>Trizeal (Japan) (GDL-0026)</description>
		<rom name="naomi_non_merged/trizeal_folder.zip" size="133952078"/>
		<emu_command>trizeal/trizeal.zip</emu_command>
		<plot>Trizeal is a Japanese shoot 'em up arcade game developed by Triangle Service.[CR]Players control and can transform a spaceship into three forms (which alternates weapon attacks), working through multiple levels and boss sequences. The game can be played in four different screen modes, with one mode mimicking the narrow arcade version. A ship from Triangle Service's previous release, XII Stag, is hidden in the game and can be unlocked by holding the X button before selecting a stage in Stage Attack mode. The power-ups can be used to upgrade each separate weapon respectively.[CR]There are 6 levels in the game, they get progressively harder until the last stage which consists of only two bosses. Two unlockable modes become available when the game is completed, they are Omake mode and Lifting mode. Omake mode is a short level which has denser bullet patterns than the normal game, lifting mode is where you have to juggle a stone on your ship to score points</plot>
		<releasedate>20/09/2004</releasedate>
		<year>2004</year>
		<studio>Taito</studio>
		<nplayers>1</nplayers>
		<ESRB>Not Rated</ESRB>
		<boxart1>Bjl9wzh.png</boxart1>
		<boxart2>x9Q3AwJ.jpg</boxart2>
		<boxart3>CcnNAbP.png</boxart3>
		<clearlogo1>db2MkFX.png</clearlogo1>
		<genre>Shooter</genre>
		<groups>Zeal series</groups>
	</game>
	<game name="Under Defeat (Japan) (GDL-0035)">
		<description>Under Defeat (Japan) (GDL-0035)</description>
		<rom name="naomi_non_merged/undefeat_folder.zip" size="156530389"/>
		<emu_command>undefeat/undefeat.zip</emu_command>
		<plot>Under Defeat is a shoot 'em up arcade game by G.rev. It was released for the Sega Dreamcast in March 2006. The game takes place in an alternate reality based on World War II, and, in a controversial twist, players control German-speaking characters (under the banner of "the Empire"), fighting against enemies ("the Union") that speak English and possess weapons patterned after those of both real-life Allied and Axis powers (for example, naval units in Level 2 bear heavy resemblance toward the Imperial Japanese warships). The game was released very late in the life of the Dreamcast, but sold much better than expected, probably because there were no other home ports planned in the foreseeable future.</plot>
		<year>2005</year>
		<studio>G.Rev</studio>
		<nplayers>2</nplayers>
		<ESRB>AAMA - Green (Suitable For All Ages)</ESRB>
		<boxart1>ED47zg5.png</boxart1>
		<boxart2>gukcfsG.png</boxart2>
		<boxart3>rWWAyRB.jpg</boxart3>
		<clearlogo1>ZuNMkH1.png</clearlogo1>
		<genre>Shooter</genre>
	</game>
	<game name="Usagi - Yamashiro Mahjong Hen (Japan) (GDL-0022)">
		<description>Usagi - Yamashiro Mahjong Hen (Japan) (GDL-0022)</description>
		<rom name="naomi_non_merged/usagiym_folder.zip" size="114046401"/>
		<emu_command>usagiym/usagiym.zip</emu_command>
		<plot>Usagi: Yasei no Touhai: Yamashiro Mahjong Hen is a mahjong game developed by Warashi and published by Taito for the Sega NAOMI arcade system. It is based on the manga Usagi Yasei no Tohai by Makoto Ito.</plot>
		<year>2003</year>
		<studio>Warashi, Taito</studio>
		<nplayers>1</nplayers>
		<ESRB>Not Rated</ESRB>
		<boxart1>hVZbWTb.jpg</boxart1>
		<boxart2>OVpqx4u.jpg</boxart2>
		<boxart3>mLYdZyq.png</boxart3>
		<snapshot1>S8iZVwj.png</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>yI9bVLd.png</snapshot2>
		<clearlogo1>cyJNniv.png</clearlogo1>
		<genre>Board Game,Mahjong</genre>
	</game>
	<game name="Virtua Athletics / Virtua Athlete (GDS-0019)">
		<description>Virtua Athletics / Virtua Athlete (GDS-0019)</description>
		<rom name="naomi_non_merged/vathlete_folder.zip" size="88713698"/>
		<emu_command>vathlete/vathlete.zip</emu_command>
		<plot>Virtua Athlete is a sports game developed by Hitmaker and published by Sega for the Sega NAOMI arcade system. It is based on the Dreamcast game Virtua Athlete 2K, released a year earlier.</plot>
		<year>2002</year>
		<studio>Sega</studio>
		<nplayers>2</nplayers>
		<ESRB>AAMA - Green (Suitable For All Ages)</ESRB>
		<boxart1>Jy1UqSO.jpg</boxart1>
		<boxart2>3De8eBy.jpg</boxart2>
		<boxart3>Yvxi10v.png</boxart3>
		<snapshot1>OxcRoo4.png</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>t4BWekC.png</snapshot2>
		<banner1>xeNwHem.png</banner1>
		<clearlogo1>KLfWqhV.png</clearlogo1>
		<genre>Sports,Track and Field</genre>
	</game>
	<game name="Virtua NBA (USA)">
		<description>Virtua NBA (USA)</description>
		<rom name="naomi_non_merged/virnba_folder.zip" size="105029543"/>
		<emu_command>virnba/virnba.zip</emu_command>
		<plot>Virtua NBA is a basketball game released for Sega NAOMI arcade hardware in 2000.</plot>
		<releasedate>01/01/2000</releasedate>
		<year>2000</year>
		<studio>Sega</studio>
		<nplayers>2</nplayers>
		<ESRB>Not Rated</ESRB>
		<videoid>aLDUwFlNkjQ</videoid>
		<boxart1>kXvrYpH.jpg</boxart1>
		<boxart2>CWkPkFr.jpg</boxart2>
		<boxart3>8F6EVkm.png</boxart3>
		<snapshot1>mc9LUnT.png</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>AP2sVbX.png</snapshot2>
		<banner1>eETSuQf.png</banner1>
		<clearlogo1>DyDCCmP.png</clearlogo1>
		<genre>Sports</genre>
	</game>
	<game name="Virtual On Oratorio Tangram M.S.B.S. ver5.66 2000 Edition">
		<description>Virtual On Oratorio Tangram M.S.B.S. ver5.66 2000 Edition</description>
		<rom name="naomi_non_merged/vonot_folder.zip" size="96011622"/>
		<emu_command>vonot/vonot.zip</emu_command>
		<plot>Virtual-On Oratorio Tangram is an arcade game for the Sega NAOMI. Oratorio Tangram is a 3D fighting game where the player assumes control of a giant humanoid robot. It is a sequel to the 1995 video game Virtual On: Cyber Troopers.</plot>
		<year>2000</year>
		<studio>Sega</studio>
		<ESRB>Not Rated</ESRB>
		<boxart1>oTbIeu3.jpg</boxart1>
		<boxart2>u04d1t7.jpg</boxart2>
		<boxart3>ZYAY1v4.png</boxart3>
		<snapshot1>hw9sqXV.png</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>RWu5gRo.png</snapshot2>
		<banner1>tcs9SUz.png</banner1>
		<clearlogo1>gXVReag.png</clearlogo1>
		<genre>Shooter</genre>
	</game>
	<game name="Virtua Striker 2 Ver. 2000 (Rev C)">
		<description>Virtua Striker 2 Ver. 2000 (Rev C)</description>
		<rom name="naomi_non_merged/vs2_2k_folder.zip" size="63865702"/>
		<emu_command>vs2_2k/vs2_2k.zip</emu_command>
		<plot>The Virtua Striker 2 is an arcade-style football/soccer sports games by Sega.[CR]A critic for Next Generation applauded the original Virtua Striker 2 as both excellent to play and watch. He cited the smooth and accurate control, realistic player moves, camera which consistently zooms in or out to the perfect frame at every moment of play, gorgeous texture-mapped players and backgrounds, and realistically strong defense.</plot>
		<releasedate>01/01/1997</releasedate>
		<year>1997</year>
		<studio>Sega</studio>
		<nplayers>2</nplayers>
		<ESRB>Not Rated</ESRB>
		<videoid>Uon06EejKeM</videoid>
		<boxart1>Bbdm68a.jpg</boxart1>
		<boxart2>xU3sTsz.png</boxart2>
		<boxart3>5YKDOVo.jpg</boxart3>
		<snapshot1>TDO1mra.png</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>6n2FXTO.png</snapshot2>
		<banner1>pEwpQde.png</banner1>
		<clearlogo1>eT8LWsu.png</clearlogo1>
		<genre>Sports,Sports,Soccer</genre>
		<groups>SEGA Sports games,Virtua Striker series</groups>
	</game>
	<game name="Virtua Tennis 2 / Power Smash 2 (Rev A) (GDS-0015A)">
		<description>Virtua Tennis 2 / Power Smash 2 (Rev A) (GDS-0015A)</description>
		<rom name="naomi_non_merged/vtennis2_folder.zip" size="125674251"/>
		<emu_command>vtennis2/vtennis2.zip</emu_command>
		<plot>Virtua Tennis (Power Smash in Japan) is a 1999 tennis arcade game created by Sega-AM3. The player competes through tennis tournaments in an arcade mode. For the home console market the game was expanded with the introduction of the campaign mode. It was later ported to Dreamcast in 2000, and for Microsoft Windows in 2002. A Game Boy Advance version was also released in 2002.</plot>
		<year>2001</year>
		<studio>Sega AM-3</studio>
		<nplayers>2</nplayers>
		<ESRB>AAMA - Green (Suitable For All Ages)</ESRB>
		<boxart1>xRNCZ7z.jpg</boxart1>
		<boxart2>AOcKIlF.png</boxart2>
		<boxart3>cySJTOW.jpg</boxart3>
		<snapshot1>Ez8IeAM.png</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>okqKWc8.png</snapshot2>
		<banner1>kAotzLj.png</banner1>
		<clearlogo1>ni4QXET.png</clearlogo1>
		<genre>Sports,Tennis</genre>
	</game>
	<game name="Virtua Tennis / Power Smash (GDS-0011)">
		<description>Virtua Tennis / Power Smash (GDS-0011)</description>
		<rom name="naomi_non_merged/vtennisg_folder.zip" size="53145720"/>
		<emu_command>vtennisg/vtennisg.zip</emu_command>
		<plot>Virtua Tennis (Power Smash in Japan) is a 1999 tennis arcade game created by Sega-AM3. The player competes through tennis tournaments in an arcade mode. For the home console market the game was expanded with the introduction of the campaign mode. It was later ported to Dreamcast in 2000, and for Microsoft Windows in 2002. A Game Boy Advance version was also released in 2002.</plot>
		<releasedate>20/03/1999</releasedate>
		<year>1999</year>
		<studio>Sega AM-3</studio>
		<nplayers>2</nplayers>
		<ESRB>Not Rated</ESRB>
		<boxart1>xRNCZ7z.jpg</boxart1>
		<boxart2>AOcKIlF.png</boxart2>
		<boxart3>cySJTOW.jpg</boxart3>
		<snapshot1>Ez8IeAM.png</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>okqKWc8.png</snapshot2>
		<banner1>kAotzLj.png</banner1>
		<clearlogo1>ni4QXET.png</clearlogo1>
		<genre>Sports,Sports,Tennis</genre>
		<groups>SEGA Sports games,Virtua Tennis series</groups>
	</game>
	<game name="World Kicks (World, WK2 Ver.A)">
		<description>World Kicks (World, WK2 Ver.A)</description>
		<rom name="naomi_non_merged/wldkicks_folder.zip" size="77912410"/>
		<emu_command>wldkicks/wldkicks.zip</emu_command>
		<plot>World Kicks was produced by Namco in 2000.[CR]A soccer simulation game from Namco.[CR]What sets this soccer game apart from all other sports games is its innovative control scheme. You use the joystick to control your player's movement. Kicking the ball is not done with buttons instead, a kick pad, located on the bottom of the cabinet and in the shape of a soccer ball, is used to determine the ball's movement and speed, depending on how hard you kick the pad</plot>
		<studio>Namco</studio>
		<ESRB>Not Rated</ESRB>
		<genre>Sports</genre>
	</game>
	<game name="Wave Runner GP">
		<description>Wave Runner GP</description>
		<rom name="naomi_non_merged/wrungp_folder.zip" size="50454349"/>
		<emu_command>wrungp/wrungp.zip</emu_command>
		<plot>Wave Runner GP is a jet ski racing game by Sega and AM1 [CR]This is a racing game which does something different from other arcade racers, but does lack in areas and originality. You actually get to ride a replica of a Yamaha WaveRunner on water, while you race against other 7 other opponents. The game plays like Sega Rally Championship around some veins, but does something different which makes the game fresh, such as riding on a jet ski instead of cars. The game also relies on doing tricks on ramps which somewhat affects your scoring. There are three courses in game, ranging from Novice (beginner course), Intermediate (advanced course), and the Expert course.</plot>
		<releasedate>01/01/1996</releasedate>
		<year>1996</year>
		<studio>Sega</studio>
		<nplayers>1</nplayers>
		<ESRB>Not Rated</ESRB>
		<videoid>1vnqlNnq-qo</videoid>
		<boxart1>yw6ctlC.jpg</boxart1>
		<boxart2>791Uif0.jpg</boxart2>
		<boxart3>M8c5N38.png</boxart3>
		<snapshot1>fCuC1fV.png</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>1ccNaAH.png</snapshot2>
		<clearlogo1>QAo2F7J.png</clearlogo1>
		<genre>Racing,Water</genre>
	</game>
	<game name="World Series Baseball / Super Major League (GDS-0010)">
		<description>World Series Baseball / Super Major League (GDS-0010)</description>
		<rom name="naomi_non_merged/wsbbgd_folder.zip" size="163711606"/>
		<emu_command>wsbbgd/wsbbgd.zip</emu_command>
		<plot>World Series BaseBall is a baseball game released for Sega NAOMI arcade hardware in 2001.</plot>
		<year>2001</year>
		<studio>Sega</studio>
		<nplayers>2</nplayers>
		<ESRB>Not Rated</ESRB>
		<boxart1>iUaF79b.jpg</boxart1>
		<boxart2>QJfsjHY.png</boxart2>
		<boxart3>molpDbh.jpg</boxart3>
		<snapshot1>4JN41MC.png</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>51cXMMm.png</snapshot2>
		<banner1>jhrRDBq.png</banner1>
		<clearlogo1>vXBrZ1f.png</clearlogo1>
		<genre>Sports,Sports,Baseball</genre>
	</game>
	<game name="WWF Royal Rumble">
		<description>WWF Royal Rumble</description>
		<rom name="naomi_non_merged/wwfroyal_folder.zip" size="109634727"/>
		<emu_command>wwfroyal/wwfroyal.zip</emu_command>
		<plot>WWF Royal Rumble is a professional wrestling video game released by LJN in 1993 for the Super NES and Sega Genesis. Like its predecessor, WWF Super WrestleMania it is based on the World Wrestling Federation (WWF). It features a variety of match types, including the newly added Royal Rumble match. The game's roster consists of wrestlers who were top stars in the WWF at the time, and each version of the game has five exclusive playable characters.</plot>
		<releasedate>01/08/2000</releasedate>
		<year>2000</year>
		<studio>Sculptured Software</studio>
		<nplayers>2</nplayers>
		<videoid>xLIVoYtRf04</videoid>
		<boxart1>eCnq798.jpg</boxart1>
		<boxart2>qo0bqHB.jpg</boxart2>
		<boxart3>TNZ5dxF.png</boxart3>
		<snapshot1>M2Wqevi.png</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>jDboXkF.png</snapshot2>
		<banner1>8aA43Mf.png</banner1>
		<clearlogo1>yTIoZ5Y.png</clearlogo1>
		<genre>Fighter,Sports</genre>
		<groups>WWE / WWF wrestling games</groups>
	</game>
	<game name="Extreme Hunting 2">
		<description>Extreme Hunting 2</description>
		<releasedate>01/08/2006</releasedate>
		<year>2006</year>
		<studio>Sega</studio>
		<genre>Hunting,Shooting,Sports</genre>
		<nplayers>1-2 Co-Op</nplayers>
		<videoid>fMr0_bI7VYo</videoid>
		<boxart1>NUjyRUe.jpg</boxart1>
		<rom name="naomi_non_merged/xtrmhnt2_folder.zip" size="122148602"/>
		<emu_command>xtrmhnt2/xtrmhnt2.zip</emu_command>

	</game>
	<game name="Extreme Hunting">
		<description>Extreme Hunting</description>
		<releasedate>01/08/2004</releasedate>
		<year>2004</year>
		<studio>Sega</studio>
		<genre>Hunting,Shooting,Sports</genre>
		<nplayers>1-2 Co-Op</nplayers>
		<videoid>EnZ5kbwB4e8</videoid>
		<boxart1>304Tp9v.jpg</boxart1>
		<rom name="naomi_non_merged/xtrmhunt_folder.zip" size="104257983"/>
		<emu_command>xtrmhunt/xtrmhunt.zip</emu_command>
	</game>
	<game name="Zero Gunner 2">
		<description>Zero Gunner 2</description>
		<rom name="naomi_non_merged/zerogu2_folder.zip" size="48893114"/>
		<emu_command>zerogu2/zerogu2.zip</emu_command>
		<plot>Zero Gunner 2 is a 3D multidirectional shooter developed by Psikyo as a sequel to Zero Gunner, the original arcade game. It was released for the Dreamcast in Japan in 2001.</plot>
		<releasedate>20/05/2001</releasedate>
		<year>2001</year>
		<studio>Psikyo</studio>
		<nplayers>2</nplayers>
		<ESRB>AAMA - Green (Suitable For All Ages)</ESRB>
		<boxart1>J45vrZn.png</boxart1>
		<boxart2>3gBsO6G.png</boxart2>
		<boxart3>KtJiuBh.jpg</boxart3>
		<snapshot1>AHKrB4D.png</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>jcfRRKE.png</snapshot2>
		<banner1>vIdgdJm.png</banner1>
		<clearlogo1>oBKKYAF.png</clearlogo1>
		<genre>Driving,Shooter</genre>
		<groups>Genre: Scrolling shoot 'em up,Zero Gunner series</groups>
	</game>
	<game name="Zombie Revenge (Rev A)">
		<description>Zombie Revenge (Rev A)</description>
		<rom name="naomi_non_merged/zombrvn_folder.zip" size="101891644"/>
		<emu_command>zombrvn/zombrvn.zip</emu_command>
		<plot>Zombie Revenge is an arcade and Sega Dreamcast video game released in 1999, a Beat Em Up game. Armed with their fists, feet, and whatever weapons they should find along the way, players are tasked with ridding an unnamed city of zombies. Originally titled Blood Bullet: The House of the Dead Side Story, the game was later renamed Zombies Nightmare before Sega decided on the name Zombie Revenge.</plot>
		<releasedate>01/02/1999</releasedate>
		<year>1999</year>
		<studio>Sega</studio>
		<nplayers>2</nplayers>
		<boxart1>msvkYgn.jpg</boxart1>
		<boxart2>ItuhVaZ.jpg</boxart2>
		<boxart3>Y9qlOlJ.png</boxart3>
		<snapshot1>xXoIKgO.png</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>8hviryW.png</snapshot2>
		<banner1>JuSvZsu.png</banner1>
		<clearlogo1>LMikZGL.png</clearlogo1>
		<genre>Beat Em Up,Fighter</genre>
		<groups>Theme: Zombies</groups>
	</game>
	<game name="Touch De Zunou (Japan, Rev A)">
		<description>Touch De Zunou (Japan, Rev A)</description>
		<rom name="naomi_non_merged/zunou_folder.zip" size="64914288"/>
		<emu_command>zunou/zunou.zip</emu_command>
		<plot>Touch de Zunou</plot>
		<year>2006</year>
		<studio>Sega</studio>
		<ESRB>Not Rated</ESRB>
		<genre>Puzzle</genre>
	</game>
</datafile>