<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<datafile>
    <header>
        <emu_name>PlayStation Portable Minis</emu_name>
        <emu_description>Playstation Portable Minis</emu_description>
        <emu_category>Sony, 2000s, Handheld</emu_category>
        <emu_version>10212019</emu_version>
        <emu_date>08/08/2021</emu_date>
        <emu_author>Zach Morris</emu_author>
        <emu_visibility>visible</emu_visibility>
        <emu_homepage>http://www.redump.org/</emu_homepage>
        <emu_baseurl>https://archive.org/download/</emu_baseurl>
        <emu_launcher>retroplayer</emu_launcher>
        <emu_default_addon>none</emu_default_addon>
        <emu_ext_launch_cmd>none</emu_ext_launch_cmd>
        <emu_downloadpath>default</emu_downloadpath>        
        <emu_postdlaction>none</emu_postdlaction>
        <emu_comment>PlayStation Portable Minis, also known simply as PSP minis, is a line of small, casual games available to download from the PlayStation Store.[CR]The series was launched on October 1, 2009[1] for the PlayStation Portable, specifically for the launch of the digital-only model PSP go.[CR]Compatibility with the PlayStation 3 was added on December 17, 2009 and the PlayStation Vita at the handhelds launch.[CR]By July 14, 2010, over 1 million minis had been downloaded worldwide.[CR]Developer: Sony[CR]Media Medium: Digital[CR]CPU: MIPS R4000-based[CR]Memory: 32MB[CR]Graphics: Sony CXD187[CR]Sound: Embedded Virtual Mobile Engine (VME) Sound Core[CR]Display: 480 x 272</emu_comment>
        <emu_thumb>RKPY2DQ.jpg</emu_thumb>
        <emu_banner>7onIMsc.jpg</emu_banner>
        <emu_fanart>fdmFqu2.jpg</emu_fanart>
        <emu_logo>9TzLM4s.png</emu_logo>
        <emu_trailer>OUiqlK9Pt5Q</emu_trailer>
    </header>
  <game name="1000 Tiny Claws (USA, PSP Mini)">
    <description>1000 Tiny Claws (USA, PSP Mini)</description>
	<groups>PSP Mini</groups>
    <rom name="pspminis/1000%20Tiny%20Claws%20%28USA%29.cso" size="90234428"/>
    <rating>3.00</rating>
    <studio>Mediatonic</studio>
    <releasedate>04/10/2011</releasedate>
    <plot>Your legendary sky-pirate crew may have been responsible for unleashing an apocalyptic curse of giant insects upon the world -- and now there's only 24 hours to save their necks from the hangman's noose... Despite protestations that 'dangerously cursed islands' should REALLY be more clearly sign-posted, First Mate Rana sets out to smash her way through the relentless scuttling horde in a sword-swinging arcade battler set against an epic backdrop of sky-islands and piracy![CR]Can YOU survive against overwhelming odds? Deploy combo attacks and running swipes, blocks and dodges, then use DEVASTATING special moves to turn the tables on the SWARM and send the bugs spiraling into the clouds. Just make sure you keep solid ground beneath your own feet at the same time...[CR]Join Rana, Captain Bluebell and Mr Yoho as they deal outsky-pirate justice! Make barely coherent plans! Enjoy celebratory fruit cocktails ... and BREAK the curse of 1000 TINY CLAWS!</plot>
    <genre>Action</genre>
    <boxart1>RY7LwZe.jpg</boxart1>
  </game>
  <game name="20Q (Europe, PSP Mini)">
    <description>20Q (Europe, PSP Mini)</description>
	<groups>PSP Mini</groups>
    <rom name="pspminis/20Q%20%28Europe%29.cso" size="10966131"/>
    <plot>20Q is a Miscellaneous game, developed by I-Play and published by 20Q.net Inc., which was released in Europe in 2011.</plot>
    <genre>Education</genre>
    <year>2017</year>
  </game>
  <game name="2D Adventures of Rotating Octopus Character, The (USA, PSP Mini)">
    <description>2D Adventures of Rotating Octopus Character, The (USA, PSP Mini)</description>
	<groups>PSP Mini</groups>
    <rom name="pspminis/2D%20Adventures%20of%20Rotating%20Octopus%20Character%2C%20The%20%28USA%29.cso" size="23889384"/>
    <studio>Dakko Dakko</studio>
    <releasedate>14/06/2011</releasedate>
    <plot>The 2D Adventures of Rotating Octopus Character is a twitchy, fast paced platform game playable with the simple use of just two buttons. Rotating Octopus Character can't stop spinning, and he sticks to everything, but he can change direction, and he can jump. So, armed with those two moves - Reverse, and Jump - you're tasked with helping ROC to collect all the baby octopi who have been so unfortunately scattered all over the world. The videogame world is full of hazards for a spinning octopus, too, so it's not just a case of jump-and-grab. Timing is everything to avoid sending ROC hurtling to his doom.</plot>
    <boxart1>ezObAVb.jpg</boxart1>
    <boxart2>JjhHimC.png</boxart2>
  </game>
  <game name="3 2 1 - Supercrash! (USA, PSP Mini)">
    <description>3 2 1 - Supercrash! (USA, PSP Mini)</description>
	<groups>PSP Mini</groups>
    <rom name="pspminis/3%202%201%20-%20Supercrash%21%20%28USA%29.cso" size="22974282"/>
  </game>
  <game name="3D Twist &amp; Match (USA, PSP Mini)">
    <description>3D Twist &amp; Match (USA, PSP Mini)</description>
	<groups>PSP Mini</groups>
    <rom name="pspminis/3D%20Twist%20%26%20Match%20%28USA%29.cso" size="25444127"/>
    <rating>2.00</rating>
    <studio>Sanuk Games</studio>
    <releasedate>12/04/2011</releasedate>
    <plot>How quickly can you rotate 3D objects to match their silhouettes? Challenge your spatial visualization skills and make optimal moves to build combos. With its intuitive controls, 3D Twist and Match is easy to pick up, yet its intense, frantic game play will have you coming back again and again. The game features 10 themes: Beach, Halloween, Christmas, Jungle, Food, Vehicles, Tools, Music, Sports and Electronics. Game modes include Classic, Rush and Practice. There are three levels of difficulty, 200 objects to match and oodles of trophies to unlock.</plot>
    <genre>Puzzle</genre>
    <boxart1>mdPL7zN.jpg</boxart1>
    <clearlogo1>kQHRuWj.png</clearlogo1>
    <boxart2>F5kbM6t.png</boxart2>
  </game>
  <game name="4x4 Jam (USA, PSP Mini)">
    <description>4x4 Jam (USA, PSP Mini)</description>
	<groups>PSP Mini</groups>
    <rom name="pspminis/4x4%20Jam%20%28USA%29.cso" size="59111212"/>
    <rating>2.50</rating>
    <studio>Invictus</studio>
    <releasedate>06/07/2010</releasedate>
    <plot>Find yourself behind the wheels of off-road vehicles in 4x4 JAM. Jump over your opponent or roll down a steep hill. No rules, no boundaries, racing is sheer fun.</plot>
    <boxart1>87G0q01.jpg</boxart1>
    <boxart2>UyWSDrs.png</boxart2>
  </game>
  <game name="5-in-1 Arcade Hits (USA, PSP Mini)">
    <description>5-in-1 Arcade Hits (USA, PSP Mini)</description>
	<groups>PSP Mini</groups>
    <rom name="pspminis/5-in-1%20Arcade%20Hits%20%28USA%29.cso" size="17967229"/>
    <studio>Grip Digital</studio>
    <releasedate>06/07/2010</releasedate>
    <plot>5-in-1 Arcade Hits is a "PlayStation Minis" bundle of five separate games in a single downloadable package. Despite the title, most of the games have little or nothing to do with any traditional arcade-style games.[CR]The five included games are:[CR]Pairs A simple memory game where players must match sixteen pairs of cards. There are three skill levels to choose from. At the easiest level, the cards show pictures of simple objects. At the medium level, the cards show numbers. At the highest difficulty level, the cards show complex symbols. Players are also timed and high scores are awarded for uncovering multiple pairs in a row.[CR]15Puzzle The classic 4x4 "sliding tile" puzzle. There are three levels of difficulty. Choosing the easiest setting assigns a number to each sliding tile and requires players to correctly organize the numbers. The medium and high settings require players to properly arrange a picture. Each session is timed, and the players' best times are saved on a high score table.[CR]Pool An eight-ball pool game for one or two players. Bonus points are awarded for sinking multiple balls in one shot and for "chains" (pocketing at least one ball in consecutive turns).[CR]Solitaire A standard Klondike Solitaire game with two modes of difficulty. The "easy" variant allows players to draw one card from the pile each turn while the "hard" variant requires players to draw three cards from the pile each turn. Additional points are awarded if the player is able to complete the game in a specified time limit.[CR]Tetroid Of all the games included in the compilation, this is the one that most resembles something one might find in an arcade. Tetroid plays like Arkanoid flipped on its side. However, along with having to break the bricks, the play field slowly and continuously shifts toward the paddle as the game progresses. The game ends when a row containing one or more bricks meets the paddle.[CR]All games have their own high score tables. If desired, a unique string can be generated for the player that will allow them to import their high scores onto a global leaderboard when entered on the developers' website.</plot>
    <genre>Puzzle, Sports</genre>
    <boxart1>M1O20eC.jpg</boxart1>
    <boxart2>NQUPPJZ.png</boxart2>
  </game>
  <game name="5-in-1 Solitaire (USA, PSP Mini)">
    <description>5-in-1 Solitaire (USA, PSP Mini)</description>
	<groups>PSP Mini</groups>
    <rom name="pspminis/5-in-1%20Solitaire%20%28USA%29.cso" size="6477000"/>
  </game>
  <game name="Ace Armstrong vs. the Alien Scumbags! (USA, PSP Mini)">
    <description>Ace Armstrong vs. the Alien Scumbags! (USA, PSP Mini)</description>
	<groups>PSP Mini</groups>
    <rom name="pspminis/Ace%20Armstrong%20vs.%20the%20Alien%20Scumbags%21%20%28USA%29.cso" size="44674678"/>
  </game>
  <game name="Actual Crimes - Jack the Ripper (USA, PSP Mini)">
    <description>Actual Crimes - Jack the Ripper (USA, PSP Mini)</description>
	<groups>PSP Mini</groups>
    <rom name="pspminis/Actual%20Crimes%20-%20Jack%20the%20Ripper%20%28USA%29.cso" size="88550831"/>
    <studio>Sanuk Games</studio>
    <releasedate>05/10/2010</releasedate>
    <plot>In 19th century Victorian England, an unknown serial killer brutally murdered five prostitutes between August 31st and November 9th of 1888 and was never caught by the police. He received the nickname of "Jack The Ripper" after the signature from a letter, that was supposedly written and sent by the gloating assassin to the Scotland Yard and printed in the newspapers of the time. Chief Constable Melville Macnaghten investigated the case and wrote a final report naming five suspects.[CR]Real Crimes: Jack the Ripper is the second entry in a series of a hidden object games based on actual murder cases. As Macnaghten and the notorious forensic scientist Francis Galton, the player must search and click on all the items listed at left side of the screen, on locations related to the case and filled with assorted objects. Some of the items are clues about the murders, bringing up a window at the center of the screen with details about the object and its relation to the case. The hint button is a police badge below the list, that shows the position of one of the required items when activated. Police badges can be found and collected from the scenery for extra hints.[CR]A few mini-games appear between locations, where the player has to complete a jigsaw puzzle with pieces of a shredded letter, a tile-sliding picture puzzle, a spot-the-differences game with two similar images, a memory game with matching tarot cards and other similar challenges. There are two modes: Detective Mode with a time limit of 10 minutes per scene, and a Rookie Mode without any time constraints. Extra seconds can be added to the timer by collecting the fingerprints pressed over the scenery.</plot>
    <genre>Horror, Puzzle</genre>
    <boxart1>bzruUnI.jpg</boxart1>
  </game>
  <game name="Aero Racer (USA, PSP Mini)">
    <description>Aero Racer (USA, PSP Mini)</description>
	<groups>PSP Mini</groups>
    <rom name="pspminis/Aero%20Racer%20%28USA%29.cso" size="33339125"/>
    <studio>Halfbrick</studio>
    <releasedate>11/03/2010</releasedate>
    <plot>Formerly known as Rocket Racing, Aero Racer is a single-player top-down arcade-like futuristic speed racer entailing a competition between colored neon rocket ships.[CR]The defining challenge of the game lies in controlling the momentum of the racing craft by using rear jet-boosters to grind and thrust off track boundaries, resulting in increased acceleration. Unlike other contemporary racing games, there are no weapons or damage meters; players must maintain a single minded effort to beat opponents to the finishing line.[CR]Players can enjoy the following four different game modes:[CR]Campaign: success in races, challenges, and trials enables players to progress through increasingly difficult tiers.[CR]Grand Prix: a set of interconnected races.[CR]Quick Race: instant pick-up and play mode.[CR]Party Mode: players take turns to compete in single-player challenges.</plot>
    <genre>Racing</genre>
    <boxart1>yViajIx.jpg</boxart1>
    <boxart2>eeFVfld.png</boxart2>
  </game>
  <game name="Age of Hammer Wars (USA, PSP Mini)">
    <description>Age of Hammer Wars (USA, PSP Mini)</description>
	<groups>PSP Mini</groups>
    <rom name="pspminis/Age%20of%20Hammer%20Wars%20%28USA%29.cso" size="42061488"/>
    <rating>4.00</rating>
    <nplayers>1</nplayers>
    <plot>This game is a unique mixture of action, RPG and simulator. Player finds himself in the world, where the air is ruled by hovering vehicles - one of which he takes under control. According to a plot, player have to fight his way through the numerous combats with monsters and accomplish different missions. During the headway to the the heart of the fairy kingdom , player's hovering vehicle gets new weapon, armor and other useful power-ups.</plot>
    <year>2010</year>
    <videoid>yw2eLaExRDo</videoid>
    <boxart1>lQp6dW9.jpg</boxart1>
    <snapshot1>8X7QOer.png</snapshot1>
    <snapshot2>DGcYJZ5.png</snapshot2>
    <snapshot3>hQLv0Ar.png</snapshot3>
  </game>
  <game name="Age of Zombies (USA, PSP Mini)">
    <description>Age of Zombies (USA, PSP Mini)</description>
	<groups>PSP Mini</groups>
    <rom name="pspminis/Age%20of%20Zombies%20%28USA%29.cso" size="22165929"/>
    <studio>Halfbrick</studio>
    <releasedate>25/02/2010</releasedate>
    <plot>The evil Professor Brains has sent hordes of zombies back to various periods in history to destroy mankind. It's up to time traveling protagonist Barry Steakfries to foil this evil scheme.[CR]Age of Zombies is a top-down shooter that will take the player to the prehistory, thirties Chicago, ancient Egypt, medieval Japan and the future. To defend himself against large waves of zombies, Barry can use his standard gun, for which he receives no points, or various other weapons like SMGs, flamethrowers, shotguns, miniguns and explosives which can be found around the map.</plot>
    <genre>Horror, Shooter</genre>
    <boxart1>Gic1BVp.jpg</boxart1>
  </game>
  <game name="Alien Havoc (USA, PSP Mini)">
    <description>Alien Havoc (USA, PSP Mini)</description>
	<groups>PSP Mini</groups>
    <rom name="pspminis/Alien%20Havoc%20%28USA%29.cso" size="9175271"/>
    <studio>Creat Studios</studio>
    <releasedate>01/10/2009</releasedate>
    <plot>Relive the fun and challenge of classic gaming with Alien Havoc! [CR]As an alien you must travel to a distant planet to coral the local cows into you space ship. The farmers, however, value their livestock and will do whatever they can to prevent pesky aliens from snatching away the cows. Cows too will get angry when they are picked up be sure to feed them on a regular basis. [CR]-  Customize your alien's head and body[CR]-   Adventure through 20 challenging farms that wrap vertically and horizontally[CR]-   Succeed by using the terrain and objects to aid you when dealing with farmers[CR]-  Get the highest score you can by being quick and by keeping your cows happy</plot>
    <genre>Action</genre>
    <boxart1>EwEYX6B.jpg</boxart1>
  </game>
  <game name="Alien Zombie Death (USA, PSP Mini)">
    <description>Alien Zombie Death (USA, PSP Mini)</description>
	<groups>PSP Mini</groups>
    <rom name="pspminis/Alien%20Zombie%20Death%20%28USA%29.cso" size="9440056"/>
    <studio>PomPom Software</studio>
    <releasedate>25/03/2010</releasedate>
    <plot>In Alien Zombie Death, players take on the role of the Spaceman who is working all alone on mining platforms, and who is constantly under siege by Alien Zombies..[CR]The game consists of fourteen levels (seven planets each with their own moon). Each level consists of multiple platforms that can be jumped up to or dropped down on. The player moves between these platforms while dodging environmental hazards and firing on the various aliens that constantly spawn in the level. Each level has several medals that can be earned for completing various tasks such as collecting a set number of coins or shooting a specific number of a certain type of alien. These medals are used to open up the later levels which are locked at the start.[CR]Players can also find temporary weapon upgrades for the standard laser gun such as the 3-Way beam and Laser Missile scattered around the levels. Also, the Spaceman can only take three hits before the game ends, however a health item will occasionally appear which restores a hit when collected. Being that the enemies never stop coming till the Spaceman dies, other than collecting medals, the other goal of the game is to get as high of a score as possible for each level.</plot>
    <genre>Action, Platform, Shooter</genre>
    <boxart1>gnds2jo.jpg</boxart1>
  </game>
  <game name="Alpha Mission (USA, PSP Mini)">
    <description>Alpha Mission (USA, PSP Mini)</description>
	<groups>PSP Mini</groups>
    <rom name="pspminis/Alpha%20Mission%20%28USA%29.cso" size="7605778"/>
    <plot>Out beyond, in the galaxy of Tetrenova, a war has been fought that has exhausted resources and even worlds. The survivors band together and look for a new place to rebuild. They choose a seemingly undeveloped planet, Earth.[CR]Using your defense ship 'Syd,' you must destroy the invading forces and ground targets with bombs. Obtain power-ups to gain energy for ship upgrades that allow you to transform to a more powerful machine. The game itself is a vertical shooter, moving continuously up towards the top of the screen.</plot>
    <boxart1>pIqqVQm.png</boxart1>
    <clearlogo1>wAapeCK.png</clearlogo1>
    <boxart2>VFHMT3Z.png</boxart2>
  </game>
  <game name="Ambassador Kane (Europe, PSP Mini)">
    <description>Ambassador Kane (Europe, PSP Mini)</description>
	<groups>PSP Mini</groups>
    <rom name="pspminis/Ambassador%20Kane%20%28Europe%29.cso" size="28403335"/>
    <rating>4.00</rating>
    <studio>PlaygroundSquad</studio>
    <releasedate>14/12/2011</releasedate>
    <plot>Ambassador Kane is a platform/puzzle game in a 2.5D view. It is your job as chief of security to make sure the ambassador survives his perilous journey through the galaxy![CR]Create a safe path for the ambassador so that he can reach and hack terminals to open the exit door on each level. Use the two different construction robots - the stair robot and the teleporter robot - to build a path. But be aware of enemies and laser fences that will have a fatal impact on Kane and your construction units if you don't pay attention. Pull out your sniper rifle which you can use to eliminate threats.[CR]Improve your high score by collecting stars and documents - you'll earn stars by completing each level under a given time and you'll find documents throughout the levels. Collect them all to unlock the 20 insanely difficult bonus levels, a special surprise, and an alternate ending!</plot>
    <genre>Platform, Puzzle</genre>
    <boxart1>6iPeCHt.jpg</boxart1>
    <clearlogo1>G3RG7x3.png</clearlogo1>
    <boxart2>oQr6Z7K.png</boxart2>
  </game>
  <game name="Ancient Game Treasures Mill (USA, PSP Mini)">
    <description>Ancient Game Treasures Mill (USA, PSP Mini)</description>
	<groups>PSP Mini</groups>
    <rom name="pspminis/Ancient%20Game%20Treasures%20Mill%20%28USA%29.cso" size="10866397"/>
    <studio>G1M2</studio>
    <releasedate>15/03/2011</releasedate>
    <plot>G1M2 is known for classic gaming, but Ancient Game Treasures: Mill takes retro gaming to a new level of "Old School" - all the way back to Ancient Egypt. Ancient Game Treasures: Mill includes three varieties of games from the Mill family including Three Men's Morris, Six Men's Morris, and Nine Men's Morris. Align three of your game pieces in a straight line to form a "Mill" with the reward of removing one of your opponent's pieces from the board. The game starts with players taking turns strategically placing game pieces on the board. After all of the pieces have been placed, players take turns sliding game pieces to open spots on the board next to their existing pieces. When a player has only three game pieces left, their pieces can "jump" around the board to any open space. The first player to remove all but two of their opponent's pieces or trap all of their opponent's pieces so they cannot move wins the game.</plot>
    <genre>Strategy, Board Game</genre>
    <boxart1>Qs4Jjzj.jpg</boxart1>
    <clearlogo1>aWWVBMh.png</clearlogo1>
    <boxart2>kLcqwys.png</boxart2>
  </game>
  <game name="Angry Birds (USA, PSP Mini)">
    <description>Angry Birds (USA, PSP Mini)</description>
	<groups>PSP Mini</groups>
    <rom name="pspminis/Angry%20Birds%20%28USA%29.cso" size="18576011"/>
    <studio>Chillingo</studio>
    <releasedate>04/01/2011</releasedate>
    <plot>The survival of the Angry Birds is at stake. Dish out revenge on the green pigs who stole the Birds' eggs. Use the unique destructive powers of the Angry Birds to lay waste to the pigs' fortified castles. Angry Birds features hours of gameplay, challenging physics-based castle demolition, and lots of replay value. Each of the 63 levels requires logic, skill, and brute force to crush the enemy.</plot>
    <boxart1>z1HFQYD.jpg</boxart1>
    <clearlogo1>zlkkZAP.png</clearlogo1>
    <fanart1>08ZnLqI.jpg</fanart1>
    <boxart2>2VXTPNR.png</boxart2>
  </game>
  <game name="Apache Overkill (USA, PSP Mini)">
    <description>Apache Overkill (USA, PSP Mini)</description>
	<groups>PSP Mini</groups>
    <rom name="pspminis/Apache%20Overkill%20%28USA%29.cso" size="5352789"/>
    <rating>1.00</rating>
    <studio>Playerthree</studio>
    <releasedate>05/10/2010</releasedate>
    <plot>Apache Overkill is a side-scrolling pixel/retro style shooter that originated as a Flash game on the web and was upgraded and enhanced for the iOS and PSN versions. The player controls an Apache attack helicopter through four different levels but the objectives remain the same, simply destroy everything in the helicopter's path in the air and on the ground and pick up all the health, weapons and ammo that drop down from the top of the screen.</plot>
    <genre>Action, Shooter</genre>
    <boxart1>XlT9OmU.jpg</boxart1>
  </game>
  <game name="Aquattack! (USA, PSP Mini)">
    <description>Aquattack! (USA, PSP Mini)</description>
	<groups>PSP Mini</groups>
    <rom name="pspminis/Aquattack%21%20%28USA%29.cso" size="8734340"/>
    <studio>Valcon Games</studio>
    <releasedate>07/12/2010</releasedate>
    <plot>Aquattack is a colour-matching game in the vein of Bejeweled. Players are presented with a grid (presented as a fisherman's net) of different coloured fish, which they must match together in groups of three or more to allow them to escape. A row or a column can be shifted along as many times as they like until a matching set is created. A fish that goes off the end of the grid is simply wrapped around to the front. Each game has a clock that counts down from one minute, each time the player creates a matching set, some time is added to the clock.[CR]As the game progresses, additional obstacles are added, like more types of fish, to make finding matching sets harder and immovable blocks, that can only be destroyed through the use of bombs (which are generated by creating a set of 4). There is also a challenge mode that involves the giving the player specific goals to accomplish, rather than simply aiming for as high a score as possible.</plot>
    <genre>Puzzle</genre>
    <boxart1>L71d7s2.jpg</boxart1>
    <clearlogo1>wGW8Zxr.png</clearlogo1>
    <boxart2>6bmXo4e.png</boxart2>
  </game>
  <game name="Arcade Air Hockey &amp; Bowling (USA, PSP Mini)">
    <description>Arcade Air Hockey &amp; Bowling (USA, PSP Mini)</description>
	<groups>PSP Mini</groups>
    <rom name="pspminis/Arcade%20Air%20Hockey%20%26%20Bowling%20%28USA%29.cso" size="26378634"/>
    <rating>2.50</rating>
    <studio>Icon Games</studio>
    <releasedate>24/08/2010</releasedate>
    <plot>Arcade Air Hockey and Bowling(tm) offers fully featured 3D versions of Air Hockey and Bowling, with smooth analogue control and realistic gameplay. Win trophies and unlock new equipment in the World Tour career mode, or challenge a friend to play. [CR]- 2-player multiplayer - play with friends and family in versus play modes [CR]- Varied game modes - including Practice, Versus, Custom Tournament and Season [CR]- Season mode - become the World Ranked No.1 player; winning extra player rewards including new equipment and special trophies [CR]- Sophisticated AI - opponent AI designed to play a realistic 'human' game, from amateur level through to top ranking</plot>
    <genre>Sports</genre>
    <boxart1>wEPZuFF.jpg</boxart1>
    <boxart2>ySNgrh9.png</boxart2>
  </game>
  <game name="Arcade Darts (USA, PSP Mini)">
    <description>Arcade Darts (USA, PSP Mini)</description>
	<groups>PSP Mini</groups>
    <rom name="pspminis/Arcade%20Darts%20%28USA%29.cso" size="24105825"/>
    <studio>Icon Games</studio>
    <plot>With authentic darts playing feel, prepare for fun as you control your throws precisely and easily with. Challenge over 20 different computer opponents with a range of playing skills or play against a friend.</plot>
    <genre>Sports</genre>
    <boxart1>Fh0OyYA.jpg</boxart1>
    <clearlogo1>7uuzLzd.png</clearlogo1>
    <snapshot1>no208bW.png</snapshot1>
    <boxart2>mHGS3jR.png</boxart2>
    <snapshot2>s8KKA0Z.png</snapshot2>
    <snapshot3>Pt5LUXW.png</snapshot3>
  </game>
  <game name="Arcade Essentials (USA, PSP Mini)">
    <description>Arcade Essentials (USA, PSP Mini)</description>
	<groups>PSP Mini</groups>
    <rom name="pspminis/Arcade%20Essentials%20%28USA%29.cso" size="16071414"/>
  </game>
  <game name="Arcade Essentials Evolution (USA, PSP Mini)">
    <description>Arcade Essentials Evolution (USA, PSP Mini)</description>
	<groups>PSP Mini</groups>
    <rom name="pspminis/Arcade%20Essentials%20Evolution%20%28USA%29.cso" size="11795281"/>
    <studio>Nordcurrent</studio>
    <releasedate>13/09/2011</releasedate>
    <plot>Arcade Essentials Evolution is a new collection of five great games inspired by classic arcade titles. The five games are Lunar Parking, Smashout, Vulcanoids, Toader and Scolopendra. Arcade Essentials Evolution gives new life to time-tested classics. You will get to play the games you have always enjoyed, but now with cutting-edge visuals. [CR]- 5 Classic Arcade Games in one pack[CR]- Tons of levels to unlock, high score tables and other cool stuff to keep you entertained[CR]- Stylish, cutting-edge graphics and sound effects- Mysterious monochrome world to immerse</plot>
    <genre>Action, Shooter</genre>
    <boxart1>3hlROmh.jpg</boxart1>
    <clearlogo1>VMy9bpt.png</clearlogo1>
    <boxart2>BY7IY8D.png</boxart2>
  </game>
  <game name="Arcade Pool (USA, PSP Mini)">
    <description>Arcade Pool (USA, PSP Mini)</description>
	<groups>PSP Mini</groups>
    <rom name="pspminis/Arcade%20Pool%20%28USA%29.cso" size="55783721"/>
    <boxart1>jqhPITG.jpg</boxart1>
    <clearlogo1>j8MBYEV.png</clearlogo1>
    <boxart2>nNbcux9.png</boxart2>
  </game>
  <game name="Archibald's Adventures (USA, PSP Mini)">
    <description>Archibald's Adventures (USA, PSP Mini)</description>
	<groups>PSP Mini</groups>
    <rom name="pspminis/Archibald%27s%20Adventures%20%28USA%29.cso" size="23864461"/>
    <boxart1>mN2KUlb.jpg</boxart1>
  </game>
  <game name="Arctic Adventures - Polar's Puzzles (USA, PSP Mini)">
    <description>Arctic Adventures - Polar's Puzzles (USA, PSP Mini)</description>
	<groups>PSP Mini</groups>
    <rom name="pspminis/Arctic%20Adventures%20-%20Polar%27s%20Puzzles%20%28USA%29.cso" size="24231643"/>
  </game>
  <game name="Athena (USA, PSP Mini)">
    <description>Athena (USA, PSP Mini)</description>
	<groups>PSP Mini</groups>
    <rom name="pspminis/Athena%20%28USA%29.cso" size="15420316"/>
    <studio>SNK Playmore</studio>
    <plot>Join Athena, Princess of the Kingdom of Victory as she opens the "Forbidden Door" and descends into a world of fantasy in this classic platform arcade game originally released in 1986.</plot>
    <boxart1>7xi2OeP.jpg</boxart1>
    <boxart2>eor2aFZ.png</boxart2>
  </game>
  <game name="BABEL - The King of the Blocks (USA, PSP Mini)">
    <description>BABEL - The King of the Blocks (USA, PSP Mini)</description>
	<groups>PSP Mini</groups>
    <rom name="pspminis/BABEL%20-%20The%20King%20of%20the%20Blocks%20%28USA%29.cso" size="24066887"/>
    <studio>StormBasic Games</studio>
    <releasedate>14/06/2011</releasedate>
    <plot>Build your empire and become the King.[CR]- Put your building skills to the test and create your own kingdom made out of blocks.[CR]- Place falling pieces in the right position at the right time to create amazing buildings.[CR]- Challenge yourself to over 50 levels in three exciting game modes and become King of the Blocks</plot>
    <genre>Puzzle</genre>
    <boxart1>tilegKA.jpg</boxart1>
  </game>
  <game name="Basha Baloot (Europe, PSP Mini)">
    <description>Basha Baloot (Europe, PSP Mini)</description>
	<groups>PSP Mini</groups>
    <rom name="pspminis/Basha%20Baloot%20%28Europe%29.cso" size="11727352"/>
    <studio>Quirkat</studio>
    <releasedate>02/03/2011</releasedate>
    <plot>Basha Baloot brings the popular trick-taking card game to the minis platform. Partner up with the game AI and play against the rival team in this game of wit and strategy. The game puts the player in an atmosphere of playing with old friends, with rich arabesque visuals that stem from traditional game boards and tables from the Arabian region. The realistic gameplay is further enhanced by a relaxing soundtrack, and all in all provides for hours of endless fun!</plot>
    <genre>Strategy</genre>
    <boxart1>2OBQIW5.jpg</boxart1>
    <clearlogo1>CeE4dBG.png</clearlogo1>
    <boxart2>nUv3vpg.png</boxart2>
  </game>
  <game name="Basha Card Game Collection (Europe, PSP Mini)">
    <description>Basha Card Game Collection (Europe, PSP Mini)</description>
	<groups>PSP Mini</groups>
    <rom name="pspminis/Basha%20Card%20Game%20Collection%20%28Europe%29.cso" size="11723702"/>
    <nplayers>1</nplayers>
    <studio>Quirkat</studio>
    <releasedate>19/01/2011</releasedate>
    <plot>Try your hand at three of the Middle East's most loved card games, Tarneeb, Baloot and Trix.[CR]Win sets with your partner in Tarneeb, play through four kingdoms in Trix or earn the most points in Baloot.[CR]Enjoy the rich visuals that stem from traditional board games, coupled with a relaxing soundtrack.</plot>
    <genre>Strategy</genre>
    <boxart1>P5BO8Pd.jpg</boxart1>
    <clearlogo1>CtIkOPt.png</clearlogo1>
    <boxart2>A4tKQiv.png</boxart2>
  </game>
  <game name="Basha Tarneeb (Europe, PSP Mini)">
    <description>Basha Tarneeb (Europe, PSP Mini)</description>
	<groups>PSP Mini</groups>
    <rom name="pspminis/Basha%20Tarneeb%20%28Europe%29.cso" size="11727502"/>
    <studio>Quirkat</studio>
    <releasedate>19/01/2011</releasedate>
    <plot>Basha Tarneeb brings the popular 4-player trick-taking card game to the minis platform. Partner up with the game AI and play against the rival team in this game of wit and strategy. The game puts the player in an atmosphere of playing with old friends, with rich arabesque visuals that stem from traditional game boards and tables from the Arabian region. The realistic gameplay is further enhanced by a relaxing soundtrack, and all in all provides for hours of endless fun!</plot>
    <genre>Strategy</genre>
    <boxart1>GfBWOjk.jpg</boxart1>
  </game>
  <game name="Basha Trix (Europe, PSP Mini)">
    <description>Basha Trix (Europe, PSP Mini)</description>
	<groups>PSP Mini</groups>
    <rom name="pspminis/Basha%20Trix%20%28Europe%29.cso" size="11726136"/>
    <studio>Quirkat</studio>
    <releasedate>11/01/2011</releasedate>
    <plot>Play through four exciting kingdoms of trix on the minis platform. This 4-player game puts the player in an atmosphere of playing with old friends, with rich arabesque visuals that stem from traditional game boards and tables from the Arabian region. The realistic gameplay is further enhanced by a relaxing soundtrack, and all in all provides for hours of endless fun!</plot>
    <genre>Strategy</genre>
    <boxart1>mo3jlzX.jpg</boxart1>
  </game>
  <game name="Bashi Blocks (USA, PSP Mini)">
    <description>Bashi Blocks (USA, PSP Mini)</description>
	<groups>PSP Mini</groups>
    <rom name="pspminis/Bashi%20Blocks%20%28USA%29.cso" size="40955159"/>
  </game>
  <game name="Battle Poker (USA, PSP Mini)">
    <description>Battle Poker (USA, PSP Mini)</description>
	<groups>PSP Mini</groups>
    <rom name="pspminis/Battle%20Poker%20%28USA%29.cso" size="12168468"/>
    <studio>Left Field Productions</studio>
    <releasedate>10/12/2009</releasedate>
    <plot>Battle Poker is a puzzle game in which you battling against the CPU and clock to make the best arrangement of five-card hands possible. [CR]There are two modes: Shuffle Up 'N Deal With It, in which you arrange the five-by-five grid of cards to make ten of the best possible poker hands, and Chain Reaction, where you simply have to make as many five-card poker hands within the time limit by selecting individual adjacent cards with X and then pressing X again to capture the hand.[CR]Battles are played across multiple rounds with points scored for each round based on the quality of the hands.</plot>
    <genre>Puzzle</genre>
    <boxart1>M2shwoC.jpg</boxart1>
    <clearlogo1>pkVRkZ5.png</clearlogo1>
    <snapshot1>Lb8jfdP.png</snapshot1>
    <boxart2>scT82Di.png</boxart2>
  </game>
  <game name="Beach Buzzin' Chopper (Europe, PSP Mini)">
    <description>Beach Buzzin' Chopper (Europe, PSP Mini)</description>
	<groups>PSP Mini</groups>
    <rom name="pspminis/Beach%20Buzzin%27%20Chopper%20%28Europe%29.cso" size="21479143"/>
    <rating>2.00</rating>
    <studio>Asylum Entertainment</studio>
    <releasedate>29/09/2010</releasedate>
    <plot>You control a beach-sports chopper that is buzzin' private beaches for bikini babes and handsome hunks. Some of the babes and hunks are already taken but others are happy to climb on board! Avoid the angered beach bodies whose squeezes you've stolen as they pursue you in jet packs and beach buggies armed with rubber bullets trying to get their favourite honey or dude back. If you're successful, you get to party with the most beautiful girls or hunky guys on the beach!</plot>
    <genre>Shooter</genre>
    <boxart1>8rOb5kw.jpg</boxart1>
    <clearlogo1>7SrTdV6.png</clearlogo1>
    <boxart2>rRzw3Di.png</boxart2>
  </game>
  <game name="Beam 'em Up (USA, PSP Mini)">
    <description>Beam 'em Up (USA, PSP Mini)</description>
	<groups>PSP Mini</groups>
    <rom name="pspminis/Beam%20%27em%20Up%20%28USA%29.cso" size="16762431"/>
    <studio>Immersive Games</studio>
    <releasedate>15/06/2010</releasedate>
    <plot>Beam'em Up is a downloadable action/puzzle game for PSP in which the player is cast in the role of a space scientist, piloting a spaceship with the goal of acquiring and collecting alien specimens from various planets and environments. Thanks to lush environments styled in 1950s sci-fi visuals, an accurate 2D physics system, addictive puzzle gameplay, and collection mechanics, Beat'em Up is homage to the classic era of videogames, revisited with contemporary look and feel.</plot>
    <boxart1>0apmFlY.jpg</boxart1>
  </game>
  <game name="Bee Wars (Europe, PSP Mini)">
    <description>Bee Wars (Europe, PSP Mini)</description>
	<groups>PSP Mini</groups>
    <rom name="pspminis/Bee%20Wars%20%28Europe%29.cso" size="8113673"/>
    <studio>GameShastra</studio>
    <releasedate>11/10/2011</releasedate>
    <plot>Bee Wars is a hybrid of turn based strategy and resource management. Your objective is to control a group of bees having different skills and collect more honey than the enemies in a given level, but beware! Opponent bees will attack your workers and thief bees will steal honey from your hive. You must either opt to eliminate all of them or outmatch them by collecting more honey till all the moves run out.[CR]Strategize, by securing your worker bees from the opponent ninja bees and collected honey from the opponent thief bees. At the same time you can also counter with your own thief and ninja bees to cripple their collection and gain advantage.[CR]Highlights:[CR]* 80 unlock-able levels with progressive difficulty[CR]* 4 controllable species of bees, each possessing different skills and abilities[CR]* Player promotion feature: For achieving certain conditions players are awarded with medals of honor and are promoted to higher levels</plot>
    <genre>Strategy</genre>
    <boxart1>Fxe09ls.jpg</boxart1>
    <clearlogo1>7Raie6c.png</clearlogo1>
    <boxart2>tp4GFOH.png</boxart2>
  </game>
  <game name="Bermuda Triangle (USA, PSP Mini)">
    <description>Bermuda Triangle (USA, PSP Mini)</description>
	<groups>PSP Mini</groups>
    <rom name="pspminis/Bermuda%20Triangle%20%28USA%29.cso" size="11367494"/>
    <studio>SNK Playmore</studio>
    <releasedate>24/01/2012</releasedate>
    <plot>Bermuda Triangle is a scrolling shooter designed by the same team as Ikari Warriors. The player must survive each of the 9 levels, which automatically scroll both up and down, long enough to reach and destroy the boss. The ZIG, being a much larger ship than most scrolling shooter ships, can sustain several hits before being destroyed, and has both a straight ahead shot and a rotating turret that can fire in 8 directions. SYD ships can be picked up in levels and will fly near the ZIG in four different formations. They can block enemy shots but will be destroyed if hit by enemy ships. Energy can be picked up as well, which will either restore lost health or, at full health, power up the attack of the ZIG and SYDs.</plot>
    <genre>Action, Shooter</genre>
    <boxart1>YowRoVd.jpg</boxart1>
  </game>
  <game name="Best of Solitaire (USA, PSP Mini)">
    <description>Best of Solitaire (USA, PSP Mini)</description>
	<groups>PSP Mini</groups>
    <rom name="pspminis/Best%20of%20Solitaire%20%28USA%29.cso" size="23488645"/>
    <studio>Cosmigo</studio>
    <releasedate>17/05/2011</releasedate>
    <plot>Best of Solitaire" features 101 variations of the most well-known and best-loved single-player card games including Klondike, Freecell, Spider, Pyramid and Yukon. Most games have custom gameplay options so you can enjoy the game with your favorite rules. [CR]On-screen instructions allow learning of new Solitaire variations. [CR]Statistics are available for players who love to track their wins. Save the game status any time for later. The game's style and interface has been designed for easy intuitive operation.</plot>
    <genre>Puzzle</genre>
    <boxart1>QYTUm8K.jpg</boxart1>
  </game>
  <game name="Blast Off (USA, PSP Mini)">
    <description>Blast Off (USA, PSP Mini)</description>
	<groups>PSP Mini</groups>
    <rom name="pspminis/Blast%20Off%20%28USA%29.cso" size="23625683"/>
    <plot>Blast Off is an interstellar arcade game featuring gravity fields, lost astronauts and bizarre planetary systems. Use your rocket ship to rescue astronauts and carry them through the warpgate to safety. But be careful! The ever-present force of gravity can help you on your journey, but can also bring you crashing down. [CR]- 45 missions across four difficulty settings[CR]- Planets and Asteroids gravity attract the ship, allowing players to float around the level[CR]- Black Holes attract the ship with even more ferocity[CR]- White Holes have a reverse gravity field, pushing the ship away[CR]- Mission success is ranked on remaining fuel and air, astronauts collected[CR]- Awarded Silver, Gold or Brick medals based on final mission outcome [CR]Good luck, and Blast Off!</plot>
    <boxart1>JNdfiUZ.jpg</boxart1>
    <clearlogo1>ro33QPS.jpg</clearlogo1>
  </game>
  <game name="Blimp - The Flying Adventures (USA, PSP Mini)">
    <description>Blimp - The Flying Adventures (USA, PSP Mini)</description>
	<groups>PSP Mini</groups>
    <rom name="pspminis/Blimp%20-%20The%20Flying%20Adventures%20%28USA%29.cso" size="42170361"/>
    <studio>Grip Digital</studio>
    <releasedate>07/12/2010</releasedate>
    <plot>You are an elite pilot of a small blimp who will have the future of an entire planet on his shoulders. Blimp: The Flying Adventures is larger-than-life journey that will take you across a savage planet. [CR]Lush jungles, snowy mountains, scorched deserts and dusty rocks in twenty beautiful, hand-drawn, danger-filled levels will test your skills; flying a blimp is an experience like nothing you have played before! [CR]Defend strategic targets, transport soldiers, collect supplies and decimate the enemy fleet. The future of your homeworld is yours to write! And when you are done with the main campaign, try the more challenging difficulty levels, find all the hidden treasures and upload your high score to global Leaderboards to see if you are the best blimp pilot in the known universe! [CR]The adventure is taking off! Are you brave enough to join?</plot>
    <genre>Action, Shooter</genre>
    <boxart1>4q6WkYg.jpg</boxart1>
    <clearlogo1>7l2cGlz.png</clearlogo1>
    <boxart2>0RcBIu2.png</boxart2>
  </game>
  <game name="Block Cascade Fusion (USA, PSP Mini)">
    <description>Block Cascade Fusion (USA, PSP Mini)</description>
	<groups>PSP Mini</groups>
    <rom name="pspminis/Block%20Cascade%20Fusion%20%28USA%29.cso" size="11863956"/>
    <studio>Gamelion Studios</studio>
    <releasedate>17/05/2011</releasedate>
    <plot>Block Cascade Fusion is a very addictive puzzle game which lets you enter compelling worlds full of different falling blocks. You can rotate and move them as you wish, but remember - five in the line is your goal! Once the timer stops, the fusion will start and all converted blocks will be swept away, awarding you with massive amount of points. Score high enough, and you're in for a treat!</plot>
    <genre>Puzzle</genre>
    <boxart1>hqhzdjI.jpg</boxart1>
    <clearlogo1>Gbk7o5F.png</clearlogo1>
    <boxart2>E7kMF4m.png</boxart2>
  </game>
  <game name="Bloons (USA, PSP Mini)">
    <description>Bloons (USA, PSP Mini)</description>
	<groups>PSP Mini</groups>
    <rom name="pspminis/Bloons%20%28USA%29.cso" size="9574608"/>
    <studio>Digital Goldfish</studio>
    <releasedate>22/02/2011</releasedate>
    <plot>Achieve total Bloon popping satisfaction with Bloons(r) TD. This really is classic TD at its best. With a multitude of towers and weapons at your disposal can you pop all of the bloons before they escape? Battle your way through 50 challenging levels and 8 exciting tracks as your army of monkeys defend the never ending wave of bloons. Upgrade towers and traps to defeat the enemy and earn the gold medals to become the TD master!</plot>
    <genre>Strategy</genre>
    <boxart1>xGIEGeB.jpg</boxart1>
    <clearlogo1>9zWFb3l.png</clearlogo1>
    <snapshot1>KlI64pg.png</snapshot1>
    <boxart2>5l7wW4O.png</boxart2>
    <snapshot2>jiRnnC1.png</snapshot2>
    <snapshot3>AsJyXUp.png</snapshot3>
  </game>
  <game name="Bloons TD (USA, PSP Mini)">
    <description>Bloons TD (USA, PSP Mini)</description>
	<groups>PSP Mini</groups>
    <rom name="pspminis/Bloons%20TD%20%28USA%29.cso" size="8873847"/>
    <studio>Digital Goldfish</studio>
    <releasedate>22/02/2011</releasedate>
    <plot>Achieve total Bloon popping satisfaction with Bloons(r) TD. This really is classic TD at its best. With a multitude of towers and weapons at your disposal can you pop all of the bloons before they escape? Battle your way through 50 challenging levels and 8 exciting tracks as your army of monkeys defend the never ending wave of bloons. Upgrade towers and traps to defeat the enemy and earn the gold medals to become the TD master!</plot>
    <genre>Strategy</genre>
    <boxart1>doaCZp4.png</boxart1>
  </game>
  <game name="Boom Beats (USA, PSP Mini)">
    <description>Boom Beats (USA, PSP Mini)</description>
	<groups>PSP Mini</groups>
    <rom name="pspminis/Boom%20Beats%20%28USA%29.cso" size="24719712"/>
    <boxart1>zfNAuaC.png</boxart1>
  </game>
  <game name="BounceBack (Europe, PSP Mini)">
    <description>BounceBack (Europe, PSP Mini)</description>
	<groups>PSP Mini</groups>
    <rom name="pspminis/BounceBack%20%28Europe%29.cso" size="26816882"/>
    <studio>Sheffield Hallam University Enterprises Limited</studio>
    <releasedate>12/09/2012</releasedate>
    <plot>BounceBack is an exciting 2D Platform/Puzzle game about a bouncy ball called Lanos who over time has lost his bounce! Control Lanos on a quest to get his bounce back, solving puzzles and overcoming obstacles in 28 thought-provoking levels. Journey higher and higher through several progressively challenging areas to get Lanos back to his home world on the moon! Collect the magical Bounceables in order to fill up your BounceBar and get some serious air! Along the way befriend a host of memorable support characters to aid in puzzle solving, each with unique special abilities at your disposal. Do you have what it takes to bounce all the way to the stars? Don your thinking cap and download this puzzle-fuelled title now!</plot>
    <genre>Action, Platform, Puzzle</genre>
    <boxart1>WRDitxK.jpg</boxart1>
    <clearlogo1>XdaiSMf.png</clearlogo1>
    <boxart2>Z78I5qj.png</boxart2>
  </game>
  <game name="Bowling 3D (USA, PSP Mini)">
    <description>Bowling 3D (USA, PSP Mini)</description>
	<groups>PSP Mini</groups>
    <rom name="pspminis/Bowling%203D%20%28USA%29.cso" size="22379510"/>
    <boxart1>sO0wiGH.jpg</boxart1>
  </game>
  <game name="Brainpipe (USA, PSP Mini)">
    <description>Brainpipe (USA, PSP Mini)</description>
	<groups>PSP Mini</groups>
    <rom name="pspminis/Brainpipe%20%28USA%29.cso" size="24985209"/>
  </game>
  <game name="BreakQuest (USA, PSP Mini)">
    <description>BreakQuest (USA, PSP Mini)</description>
	<groups>PSP Mini</groups>
    <rom name="pspminis/BreakQuest%20%28USA%29.cso" size="66525302"/>
    <rating>3.50</rating>
    <nplayers>1</nplayers>
    <releasedate>18/03/2010</releasedate>
    <plot>A huge corporation rules the world by making thousands of TV channels and shows for people to watch. Everyone becomes addicted, starting the destruction of human intelligence. The player has to put up a transmitter to stop the satellite signals and end the corporation's rule.</plot>
    <genre>Puzzle</genre>
    <boxart1>vhdIUw7.jpg</boxart1>
  </game>
  <game name="BreakQuest - Extra Evolution (USA, PSP Mini)">
    <description>BreakQuest - Extra Evolution (USA, PSP Mini)</description>
	<groups>PSP Mini</groups>
    <rom name="pspminis/BreakQuest%20-%20Extra%20Evolution%20%28USA%29.cso" size="57134524"/>
    <studio>Beatshapers</studio>
    <releasedate>16/10/2012</releasedate>
    <plot>BreakQuest is back and is twice the fun! Stunning visuals and shapes, energizing physics and exciting sounds! Enjoy 100 sompletely redesigned action-packed levels, each featuring own colorful design, elements behavior and visual effects. An advanced physics and collision system gives a never-seen-before experience for your pleasure. And don't forget about weapons and power-up bonuses as well as the amazing Gravitor which attracts the ball to you. Breaking bricks has never been so fun!</plot>
    <genre>Action</genre>
    <boxart1>j7Asxxi.jpg</boxart1>
    <clearlogo1>Y1Hklpj.png</clearlogo1>
    <boxart2>yJT4Rxy.png</boxart2>
  </game>
  <game name="Brick Breaker (USA, PSP Mini)">
    <description>Brick Breaker (USA, PSP Mini)</description>
	<groups>PSP Mini</groups>
    <rom name="pspminis/Brick%20Breaker%20%28USA%29.cso" size="10023990"/>
    <boxart1>xyv7rY1.jpg</boxart1>
    <clearlogo1>TewCseH.png</clearlogo1>
    <boxart2>QE1GKce.png</boxart2>
  </game>
  <game name="Bubble Trubble (USA, PSP Mini)">
    <description>Bubble Trubble (USA, PSP Mini)</description>
	<groups>PSP Mini</groups>
    <rom name="pspminis/Bubble%20Trubble%20%28USA%29.cso" size="19859425"/>
    <nplayers>1</nplayers>
    <studio>Creat Studios</studio>
    <releasedate>12/11/2009</releasedate>
    <plot>Bubble Trubble is a dynamic new twist to falling puzzle games that lets players rotate and drop clusters of colored bubbles, matching colors to fuse them together and grow them until they burst. Be sure to combine matched colored bubbles together before running out of room. To avoid any trubble, you've gotta burst your Bubble! Three zany cartoon animal guides react to players performances as they present each level and its unique environment's challenge. Be sure to watch out for the Power Bubbles that may enhance or impede your performance.</plot>
    <genre>Puzzle</genre>
    <boxart1>aZ2mLqw.jpg</boxart1>
  </game>
  <game name="Bunny Dodge (USA, PSP Mini)">
    <description>Bunny Dodge (USA, PSP Mini)</description>
	<groups>PSP Mini</groups>
    <rom name="pspminis/Bunny%20Dodge%20%28USA%29.cso" size="21594590"/>
    <boxart1>3Fv9r0V.jpg</boxart1>
    <clearlogo1>BE1y7n3.png</clearlogo1>
    <boxart2>S2aSmQG.png</boxart2>
  </game>
  <game name="Burnin' Rubber (USA, PSP Mini)">
    <description>Burnin' Rubber (USA, PSP Mini)</description>
	<groups>PSP Mini</groups>
    <rom name="pspminis/Burnin%27%20Rubber%20%28USA%29.cso" size="3303617"/>
    <studio>G1M2</studio>
    <genre>Racing</genre>
    <boxart1>BgFyxlv.png</boxart1>
  </game>
  <game name="Busy Sweets Factory (USA, PSP Mini)">
    <description>Busy Sweets Factory (USA, PSP Mini)</description>
	<groups>PSP Mini</groups>
    <rom name="pspminis/Busy%20Sweets%20Factory%20%28USA%29.cso" size="6496733"/>
    <studio>Sony Computer Entertainment</studio>
    <releasedate>11/05/2010</releasedate>
    <plot>Make the sweets as fast as you can in this simple little puzzler. You are in charge of preparing desserts for customers as they roll off a Sweets Factory assembly line, so apply the frosting, whipped cream and decorations as fast as you can to make those tasty treats ready for customers.</plot>
    <genre>Puzzle</genre>
    <boxart1>84535mX.jpg</boxart1>
  </game>
  <game name="Canabalt (USA, PSP Mini)">
    <description>Canabalt (USA, PSP Mini)</description>
	<groups>PSP Mini</groups>
    <rom name="pspminis/Canabalt%20%28USA%29.cso" size="11465997"/>
    <rating>3.00</rating>
    <boxart1>gHgJIa3.jpg</boxart1>
    <clearlogo1>KRjGZws.png</clearlogo1>
    <boxart2>naicxQC.png</boxart2>
  </game>
  <game name="Car Jack Streets (USA, PSP Mini)">
    <description>Car Jack Streets (USA, PSP Mini)</description>
	<groups>PSP Mini</groups>
    <rom name="pspminis/Car%20Jack%20Streets%20%28USA%29.cso" size="88795383"/>
  </game>
  <game name="Card Shark (USA, PSP Mini)">
    <description>Card Shark (USA, PSP Mini)</description>
	<groups>PSP Mini</groups>
    <rom name="pspminis/Card%20Shark%20%28USA%29.cso" size="15201095"/>
    <boxart1>txolYhy.jpg</boxart1>
    <clearlogo1>VAxyD3s.png</clearlogo1>
    <boxart2>2MOYsbS.png</boxart2>
  </game>
  <game name="Carnivores - Dinosaur Hunter (USA, PSP Mini)">
    <description>Carnivores - Dinosaur Hunter (USA, PSP Mini)</description>
	<groups>PSP Mini</groups>
    <rom name="pspminis/Carnivores%20-%20Dinosaur%20Hunter%20%28USA%29.cso" size="37182152"/>
    <studio>Beatshapers</studio>
    <releasedate>17/08/2010</releasedate>
    <plot>Carnivores: Dinosaur Hunter lets players explore huge non-linear locations as they attempt to track down a variety of dinosaurs that are armed with some ferociously advanced AI. As a result, these are no "pea-brained" dinosaurs -- these are dangerous creatures that are able to see, hear and sense the hunter. If you're not careful, it's very easy for the hunter to become the hunted.[CR]With a series of different dinosaurs across varied, distinct environments (including pine forests, muddy marshes and rolling hills,) how you approach your target is important. Wind direction, scent and the use of a special dinosaur call are all key elements in tracking your prey.</plot>
    <genre>Shooter</genre>
    <boxart1>Nri0KRz.jpg</boxart1>
  </game>
  <game name="Carnivores - Ice Age (USA, PSP Mini)">
    <description>Carnivores - Ice Age (USA, PSP Mini)</description>
	<groups>PSP Mini</groups>
    <rom name="pspminis/Carnivores%20-%20Ice%20Age%20%28USA%29.cso" size="35717262"/>
    <studio>Beatshapers</studio>
    <plot>Carnivores: Ice Age is third game in the hunting series. This version is set on the Arctic regions of planet FMM UV-32. Scientists of DinoHunt Corp. discovered that animals from the Ice Age still live there and they establish a hunting program. There are no missions in the game. The player selects what to hunt  and then roams the planet using a mini-map, a compass and an assortment of guns to hunt down the animals. [CR]In the PS3/PSP mini version the killing animations are toned down and corpses disappear instead of being picked up by a dropship.</plot>
    <genre>Shooter</genre>
    <boxart1>NQLe1yw.jpg</boxart1>
    <clearlogo1>Ow3al5R.png</clearlogo1>
    <boxart2>1cR3XXy.png</boxart2>
  </game>
  <game name="Caterpillar (USA, PSP Mini)">
    <description>Caterpillar (USA, PSP Mini)</description>
	<groups>PSP Mini</groups>
    <rom name="pspminis/Caterpillar%20%28USA%29.cso" size="10869655"/>
    <studio>Tikgames</studio>
    <releasedate>14/09/2010</releasedate>
    <plot>Caterpillar is a fast-paced, arcade game that pits you against relentless caterpillars. Take a stand against an army of pests in Caterpillar! Click and eliminate groups of matching tiles to prevent the tricky insects from reaching the finish line. Dissolve enough tiles while keeping the bugs at bay and you'll advance to the next level. You can double the challenge in Pairs mode and stop two pests from zigzagging away in opposite directions. Race mode and Conundrum mode will present players with a whole new set of twists and challenges for hours of additional gameplay. With four different game modes to choose from and hundreds of levels to play, Caterpillar will keep reflexes sharp and give players a mental boost.</plot>
    <genre>Puzzle</genre>
    <boxart1>7E7Vfkf.jpg</boxart1>
  </game>
  <game name="Championship Manager 2010 Express (Europe, PSP Mini)">
    <description>Championship Manager 2010 Express (Europe, PSP Mini)</description>
	<groups>PSP Mini</groups>
    <rom name="pspminis/Championship%20Manager%202010%20Express%20%28Europe%29.cso" size="11565150"/>
    <studio>Square Enix</studio>
    <plot>Championship Manager 2010 Express gives players total control on the move as you manage your favourite teams from around the UK, France and Italy anytime, anywhere. Packed with all the player data, club information and more from the 2009/10 season.[CR]Pick from across multiple UK, French and Italian leagues and begin the journey to managerial success.[CR]* Individual Player Training -Hone player skills and prepare them ahead of the big games. [CR]* 2D Match Engine - See how your team is dealing with the opposition and be ready to tweak your tactics on the fly, or make key substitutions if things aren't going your way. [CR]* Full promotion and relegation - With full relegation and promotion across the leagues managers could quickly find themselves heading to non-league football and the sack if they fail to perform.[CR]* Press Conferences - Face the full glare of the media with post match press conferences and be ready to explain your on pitch actions to the waiting press.</plot>
    <genre>Sports, Strategy</genre>
    <boxart1>ephsOdE.jpg</boxart1>
    <clearlogo1>ilnrYKp.png</clearlogo1>
    <boxart2>AG6nozT.png</boxart2>
  </game>
  <game name="Charge! Tank Squad (USA, PSP Mini)">
    <description>Charge! Tank Squad (USA, PSP Mini)</description>
	<groups>PSP Mini</groups>
    <rom name="pspminis/Charge%21%20Tank%20Squad%20%28USA%29.cso" size="8011141"/>
    <studio>Sony Computer Entertainment America</studio>
    <releasedate>22/04/2010</releasedate>
    <plot>A monstrous assault is taking place on your PSP(r) system and it's up to you, the tank commander, to wipe out the relentless invading enemy forces. You must stay on deadly alert as these armies are devious and will change up their attack style to overpower you. Deploy all types of weapons and seize power ups in a crusade to save your base before your energy and your funding run out!</plot>
    <genre>Shooter</genre>
    <boxart1>2avK3ul.jpg</boxart1>
    <clearlogo1>Y9xVMuB.png</clearlogo1>
    <boxart2>fLVeaMs.png</boxart2>
  </game>
  <game name="Chopper I (USA, PSP Mini)">
    <description>Chopper I (USA, PSP Mini)</description>
	<groups>PSP Mini</groups>
    <rom name="pspminis/Chopper%20I%20%28USA%29.cso" size="39572742"/>
    <boxart1>3LyaZLB.jpg</boxart1>
    <clearlogo1>n5NGNd2.png</clearlogo1>
    <boxart2>OdgUE14.png</boxart2>
  </game>
  <game name="Circles, Circles, Circles (USA, PSP Mini)">
    <description>Circles, Circles, Circles (USA, PSP Mini)</description>
	<groups>PSP Mini</groups>
    <rom name="pspminis/Circles%2C%20Circles%2C%20Circles%20%28USA%29.cso" size="10045115"/>
    <studio>GameShastra</studio>
    <releasedate>19/11/2009</releasedate>
    <plot>The game idea of the circles is inspired from a war strategy called "Chakravigua" described in the Indian epic Mahabharata. The Sanskrit word Chakravigua means Circle strategy where a battalion forms a circle around the king to protect him.[CR]Circle puzzle is designed in similar fashion. The player's circles (Blue small circles) are distributed in border of big circle where the objective is to move the blue circle toward zero to conquer it. Defending player's circles (orange small circles) are distributed around the golden zero where the object is to destroy the all the blue circles. [CR]Moving the circle around works based on simple logic which described in game mechanics section. The player can destroy the opponent circles using simple math skills like (5+3 =?), (4-2 =?). [CR]Features[CR]*   Three difficulty modes (Easy, Medium and Hard). [CR]*   40 levels in each mode [CR]*    120 total levels</plot>
    <genre>Puzzle</genre>
    <boxart1>eZO31GQ.jpg</boxart1>
    <clearlogo1>KwcCUCG.png</clearlogo1>
    <snapshot1>Ixchvf4.png</snapshot1>
    <boxart2>l5dntuC.png</boxart2>
    <snapshot2>DyiZhPH.png</snapshot2>
  </game>
  <game name="Coconut Dodge (USA, PSP Mini)">
    <description>Coconut Dodge (USA, PSP Mini)</description>
	<groups>PSP Mini</groups>
    <rom name="pspminis/Coconut%20Dodge%20%28USA%29.cso" size="22654758"/>
    <studio>Futurlab</studio>
    <releasedate>31/08/2010</releasedate>
    <plot>Coconut Dodge is an arcade game in which a player must dodge falling coconuts, weave through airborne mazes and play beach ball keepy-uppy to collect giant shiny treasures. The game starts quite easy and gradually ramps up to insane levels of coco-bullet action.[CR]What makes the game addictive is the combination of the predictable mazes and the random coconuts and beach balls. It makes the experience similar to a racing game, where the first few attempts at a new track are difficult, but once you've learnt the track, you can hone your movements to perfection whilst confidently dealing with the other cars.[CR]Coconut Dodge works in a similar way as you learn to memorise and master the mazes. Most of the mazes in the game have two different routes; one that is nice and easy, and one that is more difficult. The difficult route always has more valuable treasure in it. So, when you come across a maze you can get through it quite easily, which makes the game suitable for some quick casual play on the bus. However, to get the most treasure and a high score, you have to learn some pretty complex movements that require good rhythm and very high precision.</plot>
    <genre>Action</genre>
    <videoid>WKEWd-eBdk4</videoid>
    <boxart1>RPqTQ9y.jpg</boxart1>
    <clearlogo1>iBcowiu.png</clearlogo1>
    <snapshot1>WKAVzZo.png</snapshot1>
    <boxart2>Li1USYE.png</boxart2>
    <snapshot2>4wFJiHD.png</snapshot2>
    <snapshot3>WvNPEeq.png</snapshot3>
  </game>
  <game name="Cohort Chess (USA, PSP Mini)">
    <description>Cohort Chess (USA, PSP Mini)</description>
	<groups>PSP Mini</groups>
    <rom name="pspminis/Cohort%20Chess%20%28USA%29.cso" size="8123040"/>
    <studio>CoHort Studios</studio>
    <releasedate>07/06/2011</releasedate>
    <plot>Whether a learner or aspiring Grandmaster, this addictively playable and finely polished chess simulator is a must for your collection. [CR]Featuring enticing graphics, progressive stages of difficulty and endless hours of gameplay; COHORT CHESS(tm) is easy to play, but difficult to master. [CR]FOUR GAME MODES: [CR]- Single Player[CR]Play against characterized opponents with different levels of skill. There are handy Hints and Undo functions built-in to help you. [CR]- Two Player[CR]Challenge your friends and family. [CR]- Problems[CR]Tackle 24 individual puzzles by achieving checkmate in just 1, 2 or 3 moves. [CR]- Tutorial [CR]Extensive basics and tactical tutorials to help improve your own skills. [CR]Packed with impressive features, the Single Player mode even includes mid game saves for when you are on the go - ideal for the commuter.</plot>
    <genre>Strategy, Board Game</genre>
    <boxart1>HLeLt1w.jpg</boxart1>
    <clearlogo1>v9q3r03.png</clearlogo1>
    <boxart2>pNNtIZM.png</boxart2>
  </game>
  <game name="Core Blaster (USA, PSP Mini)">
    <description>Core Blaster (USA, PSP Mini)</description>
	<groups>PSP Mini</groups>
    <rom name="pspminis/Core%20Blaster%20%28USA%29.cso" size="32010413"/>
    <studio>RingZero Game Studio</studio>
    <releasedate>15/02/2011</releasedate>
    <plot>Fire in the hole! There's a leak in the main reactor and thousands of deadly atomic cores are on the loose. Don't let the cores pass through the gate! [CR]Powerful blasters are at your disposal. Use them strategically to destroy the radioactive cores. [CR]Combine the right weapons, and crush these hectic hazards before they cause the explosion of the whole engine.</plot>
    <genre>Strategy</genre>
    <boxart1>KWhE5lq.jpg</boxart1>
    <clearlogo1>FG8noWN.png</clearlogo1>
    <boxart2>wpMP64O.png</boxart2>
  </game>
  <game name="Crime Spree (Europe, PSP Mini)">
    <description>Crime Spree (Europe, PSP Mini)</description>
	<groups>PSP Mini</groups>
    <rom name="pspminis/Crime%20Spree%20%28Europe%29.cso" size="14528294"/>
    <studio>GameShastra</studio>
    <genre>Action</genre>
    <boxart1>YQ533xG.jpg</boxart1>
  </game>
  <game name="Cubixx (USA, PSP Mini)">
    <description>Cubixx (USA, PSP Mini)</description>
	<groups>PSP Mini</groups>
    <rom name="pspminis/Cubixx%20%28USA%29.cso" size="25262286"/>
    <plot>Cubixx HD is a puzzle game developed by UK-based studio Laughing Jackal released on the PlayStation Network in Europe on August 17, 2011 [1] and September 20, 2011 in North America.[2] It is the HD sequel to Cubixx, a 2009 PlayStation mini title.</plot>
    <boxart1>lOODzRZ.jpg</boxart1>
  </game>
  <game name="D-Cube Planet (USA, PSP Mini)">
    <description>D-Cube Planet (USA, PSP Mini)</description>
	<groups>PSP Mini</groups>
    <rom name="pspminis/D-Cube%20Planet%20%28USA%29.cso" size="11907604"/>
    <studio>GameShastra</studio>
    <releasedate>30/07/2017</releasedate>
    <plot>The goal of the game is to move the alien to its destination. The alien is trapped in an array of cubes. The player can move the alien and the cubes. The alien can be moved in all four directions based on empty spaces available around him. Cubes can be moved only in the directions indicated by the arrow marks on the cubes. So the player has to move the alien and the cubes wisely to make path for the alien to collect the spare parts and other interesting elements in the world. [CR]Features [CR]*   Three difficulty mode (Easy, Medium and Hard)[CR]*  40 levels in each mode [CR]*    Totally 120 levels</plot>
    <genre>Puzzle</genre>
    <videoid>CeCcPf-uKuA</videoid>
    <boxart1>JP9IV90.jpg</boxart1>
    <clearlogo1>w8dPa6O.png</clearlogo1>
    <snapshot1>6e1eEcw.png</snapshot1>
    <boxart2>y5H3UG4.png</boxart2>
    <snapshot2>6UlqZ1w.png</snapshot2>
    <snapshot3>yUDZCCD.png</snapshot3>
  </game>
  <game name="Days of Thunder (USA, PSP Mini)">
    <description>Days of Thunder (USA, PSP Mini)</description>
	<groups>PSP Mini</groups>
    <rom name="pspminis/Days%20of%20Thunder%20%28USA%29.cso" size="48975329"/>
    <boxart1>k9ufN6O.jpg</boxart1>
    <clearlogo1>afVYQPI.png</clearlogo1>
    <boxart2>1CCXgKm.png</boxart2>
  </game>
  <game name="Defenders of the Mystic Garden (USA, PSP Mini)">
    <description>Defenders of the Mystic Garden (USA, PSP Mini)</description>
	<groups>PSP Mini</groups>
    <rom name="pspminis/Defenders%20of%20the%20Mystic%20Garden%20%28USA%29.cso" size="54352462"/>
    <studio>Twisted Dragon Media</studio>
    <releasedate>10/04/2012</releasedate>
    <plot>Defenders of the Mystic Garden is a play on the popular Tower Defense genre of games. Players will find that various animals and insects are wreaking havoc on our backyard garden gnomes and stealing their strawberries. It's up to you to place and command your defenses. Instead of static towers you place one of four unit types. These units can also be moved or set to patrol between two points. [CR]12 challenging levels of play spread out over 4 unit themed environments. [CR]4 Playable Tower Units, each with differing strategies, each with unique voice-overs and SFX during in-game events. They are the Warrior, Ranger, Fire Mage and Ice Mage. [CR]16 challenges for added re-playability with progress tracking (examples: defeating a certain number of enemies with patrolling units, clearing a level with no strawberries being taken, and different ways to clear a level). [CR]16 enemies to defeat, collect, and study. [CR]Can you keep all the strawberries?</plot>
    <genre>Strategy</genre>
    <boxart1>vhDEoMc.jpg</boxart1>
    <clearlogo1>ZOFdls7.png</clearlogo1>
    <boxart2>z99bkWM.png</boxart2>
  </game>
  <game name="Deflector (USA, PSP Mini)">
    <description>Deflector (USA, PSP Mini)</description>
	<groups>PSP Mini</groups>
    <rom name="pspminis/Deflector%20%28USA%29.cso" size="7766610"/>
    <studio>GameShastra</studio>
    <releasedate>28/01/2010</releasedate>
    <plot>Your objective is to control a laser beam towards its destination. In each level you are given a laser source and its destination. You need to redirect the laser beam from its source to destination using objects like mirrors and prisms. But beware! There are valuable objects in the way, you must work around those objects and not let the laser touch them, else they will explode and you start afresh on that level.[CR]Every level poses a different difficulty, where you have been given a particular budget to buy objects. You must finish within the given budget and find your way through different obstacles that lay in between the laser and its destination.[CR]There are 90 unique levels with 3 different difficulty modes to test your puzzle skills to deflect the laser to its destination</plot>
    <genre>Puzzle</genre>
    <boxart1>8Y0U9qb.jpg</boxart1>
    <clearlogo1>3YwFo6P.png</clearlogo1>
    <boxart2>k6AKBY4.png</boxart2>
  </game>
  <game name="Denki Blocks! (USA, PSP Mini)">
    <description>Denki Blocks! (USA, PSP Mini)</description>
	<groups>PSP Mini</groups>
    <rom name="pspminis/Denki%20Blocks%21%20%28USA%29.cso" size="9182689"/>
    <boxart1>tC8v8NK.jpg</boxart1>
    <clearlogo1>Bvqr9Xg.png</clearlogo1>
    <boxart2>2eX5nFK.png</boxart2>
  </game>
  <game name="Digi-Tiles (USA, PSP Mini)">
    <description>Digi-Tiles (USA, PSP Mini)</description>
	<groups>PSP Mini</groups>
    <rom name="pspminis/Digi-Tiles%20%28USA%29.cso" size="5220737"/>
    <studio>Sony Computer Entertainment America</studio>
    <releasedate>04/03/2010</releasedate>
    <plot>Challenge your puzzle-solving skills in this math-based game by completing formulas to clear away tiles. Game modes include standard mode with 99 puzzles, and a non-stop survival mode.</plot>
    <genre>Puzzle</genre>
    <boxart1>UoHSXXL.jpg</boxart1>
    <clearlogo1>okaOWmt.png</clearlogo1>
    <boxart2>ZITJhTV.png</boxart2>
  </game>
  <game name="Doodle Fit (USA, PSP Mini)">
    <description>Doodle Fit (USA, PSP Mini)</description>
	<groups>PSP Mini</groups>
    <rom name="pspminis/Doodle%20Fit%20%28USA%29.cso" size="12437002"/>
    <rating>3.50</rating>
    <nplayers>1</nplayers>
    <releasedate>24/08/2011</releasedate>
    <plot>Puzzle game addiction meets doodle-style graphics! Your task is simple: fit the given sets of blocks into given shapes. Drag the blocks inside and outside in search for the layout that covers the whole shape. A level is complete when all blocks have been used and there's no more space free in the shape.</plot>
    <genre>Puzzle</genre>
    <videoid>J3ncBMf0F1A</videoid>
    <boxart1>2m4QND1.jpg</boxart1>
  </game>
  <game name="Doodle Pool (USA, PSP Mini)">
    <description>Doodle Pool (USA, PSP Mini)</description>
	<groups>PSP Mini</groups>
    <rom name="pspminis/Doodle%20Pool%20%28USA%29.cso" size="10355897"/>
    <studio>Big Head Games</studio>
    <releasedate>22/03/2011</releasedate>
    <plot>Play 8 ball US, 9 ball US and 8 ball UK rules, one player, two player, Time Trial (against the clock) and Shot in the Dark modes all drawn by a doodle, it's fun, casual and seriously addictive! Already a major hit Doodle Pool is destined to be a future classic, quick bite sized gaming but maddingly addictive enough to keep you at it for hours.</plot>
    <genre>Sports</genre>
    <boxart1>UTpgelj.jpg</boxart1>
    <clearlogo1>SZTmBu1.png</clearlogo1>
    <boxart2>CaYB9O5.png</boxart2>
  </game>
  <game name="Dr. Maybee and the Adventures of Scarygirl (USA, PSP Mini)">
    <description>Dr. Maybee and the Adventures of Scarygirl (USA, PSP Mini)</description>
	<groups>PSP Mini</groups>
    <rom name="pspminis/Dr.%20Maybee%20and%20the%20Adventures%20of%20Scarygirl%20%28USA%29.cso" size="14063137"/>
    <nplayers>1</nplayers>
    <studio>Tikgames</studio>
    <releasedate>17/08/2011</releasedate>
    <plot>Based on the Scarygirl graphic novel created by acclaimed artist Nathan Jurevicius, Dr Maybee and the Adventures of Scarygirl is a marvelous adventure through the Scarygirl universe, as she attempts to discover the identity of the mysterious, bearded man haunting her dreams. With help from her friends, the quick-witted Bunniguru and Blister the giant octopus, she will journey from her treehouse home in the forest to an overwhelmingly unfriendly city in her quest to locate Dr Maybee.[CR]Features[CR]Surreal Art by Nathan Jurevicius: Scarygirl's fantastic landscape and creatures are both beautiful and bizarre to behold[CR]Scarygirl and Friends: Calling them a 'colorful' cast of characters would be an understatement. Scarygirl, the part-octopus girl who dresses like a pirate, has a tentacle for her right hand and has naught but a bone for her left, is the star here, though each friendly or treacherous creature she meets will certainly be unique[CR]It's a Completist's Paradise: In each level, players can search high and low for hundreds of gems, fish, and other items to collect.</plot>
    <genre>Action</genre>
    <boxart1>62rjBkq.jpg</boxart1>
  </game>
  <game name="Dr. Mini Games (USA, PSP Mini)">
    <description>Dr. Mini Games (USA, PSP Mini)</description>
	<groups>PSP Mini</groups>
    <rom name="pspminis/Dr.%20Mini%20Games%20%28USA%29.cso" size="11792587"/>
  </game>
  <game name="Dracula - Undead Awakening (USA, PSP Mini)">
    <description>Dracula - Undead Awakening (USA, PSP Mini)</description>
	<groups>PSP Mini</groups>
    <rom name="pspminis/Dracula%20-%20Undead%20Awakening%20%28USA%29.cso" size="11951991"/>
    <nplayers>1</nplayers>
    <studio>Chillingo Ltd.</studio>
    <releasedate>26/11/2009</releasedate>
    <plot>In this chilling top-down shooter, you play a vampire hunter must combat hordes of undead enemies like zombies, ghouls, werewolves, vampire brides and more. Can you stand the night?</plot>
    <genre>Action</genre>
    <videoid>6zHf9fxwWEg</videoid>
    <boxart1>fKqh87j.jpg</boxart1>
    <clearlogo1>8fw3Ysm.png</clearlogo1>
    <snapshot1>N8C2U6L.png</snapshot1>
    <boxart2>q3FCWMa.png</boxart2>
  </game>
  <game name="Drums Challenge (USA, PSP Mini)">
    <description>Drums Challenge (USA, PSP Mini)</description>
	<groups>PSP Mini</groups>
    <rom name="pspminis/Drums%20Challenge%20%28USA%29.cso" size="48339302"/>
    <studio>Sanuk Games</studio>
    <releasedate>31/05/2011</releasedate>
    <plot>Dive into musical battles with the world's best drummers.[CR]Have fun playing on a virtual drum kit and challenge drummers of many different styles![CR]Show your skills: your opponent show off on a sequence of drum beats?!? Replicate it with the perfect timing! [CR]Win challenges to earn special drum parts and complete your FreeStyle drum kit. [CR]Features:[CR]- Styles: Jazz, Blues, Funk, Country, Metal, Punk Rock, Latin and Reggae![CR]- 25 drum battles[CR]- 8 different drums kits[CR]- Freestyle drum kit with 11 parts to collect</plot>
    <boxart1>nRpg8Jw.jpg</boxart1>
    <clearlogo1>2Hke3Ct.png</clearlogo1>
    <boxart2>3YFAJvF.png</boxart2>
  </game>
  <game name="Duael Invaders (USA, PSP Mini)">
    <description>Duael Invaders (USA, PSP Mini)</description>
	<groups>PSP Mini</groups>
    <rom name="pspminis/Duael%20Invaders%20%28USA%29.cso" size="15118731"/>
  </game>
  <game name="Ducati Challenge (USA, PSP Mini)">
    <description>Ducati Challenge (USA, PSP Mini)</description>
	<groups>PSP Mini</groups>
    <rom name="pspminis/Ducati%20Challenge%20%28USA%29.cso" size="60004087"/>
    <studio>Digital Tales S.R.L.</studio>
    <releasedate>28/02/2012</releasedate>
    <plot>Get ready for breathtaking challenges and unique thrills riding official Ducati motorbikes (Monster 1100 EVO, Hypermotard 1100 EVO SP, Diavel Carbon, Multistrada 1200 S, Streetfighter S and Superbike 1198 SP) in a graphically stunning 3D racing game. [CR]Wheelies, stoppies, overtaking, high speed and steering precision make Ducati Challenge a must-have game for Ducati and motorbike fans alike. [CR]Fast race tracks, winding mountain roads, narrow medieval village streets, bustling metropolises and hot desert valleys will make the perfect locations for breathtaking challenges. [CR]Game Modes: [CR]1) CHAMPIONSHIP: 3 competitions of increasing difficulty and challenges.[CR]2) QUICK CHALLENGE: pick your ride and track and just jump into the race. [CR]The rich game Extras, including 25 unlockable achievements and 90 exclusive Ducati images, will be the icing on the cake for all Ducati and motorbike fans alike.</plot>
    <genre>Racing, Vehicle Simulation</genre>
    <boxart1>BZqVWs9.jpg</boxart1>
    <clearlogo1>GDAENgx.png</clearlogo1>
    <boxart2>Bslja8K.png</boxart2>
  </game>
  <game name="Dynogems (USA, PSP Mini)">
    <description>Dynogems (USA, PSP Mini)</description>
	<groups>PSP Mini</groups>
    <rom name="pspminis/Dynogems%20%28USA%29.cso" size="16719875"/>
  </game>
  <game name="Earthshield (USA, PSP Mini)">
    <description>Earthshield (USA, PSP Mini)</description>
	<groups>PSP Mini</groups>
    <rom name="pspminis/Earthshield%20%28USA%29.cso" size="5876453"/>
    <studio>Sony Computer Entertainment America</studio>
    <releasedate>04/03/2010</releasedate>
    <plot>Defend the planet against alien invaders in this classic top-down arcade shooter. Multiply your score faster by making enemies appear faster with the shoulder buttons.</plot>
    <genre>Action, Shooter</genre>
    <boxart1>4gvgjDa.jpg</boxart1>
    <clearlogo1>YbBQ7ri.png</clearlogo1>
    <boxart2>MPtze8Y.png</boxart2>
  </game>
  <game name="Echoes (USA, PSP Mini)">
    <description>Echoes (USA, PSP Mini)</description>
	<groups>PSP Mini</groups>
    <rom name="pspminis/Echoes%20%28USA%29.cso" size="24383467"/>
    <nplayers>1</nplayers>
    <studio>Halfbrick</studio>
    <releasedate>19/11/2009</releasedate>
    <plot>Race to collect crystals while dodging the Echoes shadowing your footsteps in this innovative, seat-of-your-pants arcade game. Halfbrick Echoes is an action puzzle game in which players collect crystals within many surreal, artistic worlds. As each crystal is collected, an enemy called an Echo will spawn. Echoes are translucent versions of the player's hat icon, and they will walk the exact same path the hat walked between collecting crystals. The goal is to successfully complete the level by collecting all the crystals. Coming into contact with an Echo will result in one life being lost.</plot>
    <genre>Puzzle</genre>
    <videoid>DXQQ1m_oHIk</videoid>
    <boxart1>mCk70h5.jpg</boxart1>
  </game>
  <game name="Edge (USA, PSP Mini)">
    <description>Edge (USA, PSP Mini)</description>
	<groups>PSP Mini</groups>
    <rom name="pspminis/Edge%20%28USA%29.cso" size="20129643"/>
    <nplayers>1</nplayers>
    <releasedate>02/12/2010</releasedate>
    <plot>The gameplay involves guiding a cube around 48 levels collecting coloured prisms, taking care not to fall off the paths. The player can make the cube climb over steps. By balancing the cube along the edge of a wall or space, players can hang across certain edges in order to cross large gaps.</plot>
    <genre>Puzzle</genre>
    <videoid>wDS4b0qHgSo</videoid>
    <boxart1>K00HFOm.jpg</boxart1>
    <banner1>FdkpgO7.jpg</banner1>
    <snapshot1>RIAeniV.png</snapshot1>
    <boxart2>bqYlp8q.jpg</boxart2>
    <boxart3>lzYY3HA.png</boxart3>
  </game>
  <game name="Enchanted Cavern (Europe, PSP Mini)">
    <description>Enchanted Cavern (Europe, PSP Mini)</description>
	<groups>PSP Mini</groups>
    <rom name="pspminis/Enchanted%20Cavern%20%28Europe%29.cso" size="29729913"/>
    <studio>Alawar Entertainment</studio>
    <releasedate>06/11/2012</releasedate>
    <plot>The moment you step through the mouth of the cave, your eyes behold an amazing sight: the walls are lined with thousands of glittering jewels! By matching groups of precious stones, you'll be able to work your way toward a treasure of untold value! Featuring exhilarating gameplay, stunning visuals and special logic challenges that will test your mental mettle, Enchanted Cavern is a journey the entire family will enjoy!</plot>
    <genre>Puzzle</genre>
    <boxart1>63gbjys.jpg</boxart1>
    <clearlogo1>HmZC9se.png</clearlogo1>
    <boxart2>rW0fAU7.png</boxart2>
  </game>
  <game name="Enigmo (USA, PSP Mini)">
    <description>Enigmo (USA, PSP Mini)</description>
	<groups>PSP Mini</groups>
    <rom name="pspminis/Enigmo%20%28USA%29.cso" size="13733733"/>
    <studio>Beatshapers</studio>
    <releasedate>15/03/2011</releasedate>
    <plot>Enigmo is a unique 3D puzzle game where you manipulate slides, bumpers, and other pieces to control streams of flowing liquid. Liquids (water, oil, and lava) fall from "droppers" and will bounce around the walls of a puzzle. You move and rotate the various puzzle pieces in order to divert the flow of the falling droplets so that they can reach their target. The faster you complete each level, the more bonus you will receive, the higher position in high scores table you get.</plot>
    <genre>Puzzle</genre>
    <videoid>6XB8naKG1yM</videoid>
    <boxart1>EPJdzha.jpg</boxart1>
    <clearlogo1>kWtxsFr.png</clearlogo1>
    <snapshot1>UsyiGE3.png</snapshot1>
    <boxart2>xZGuet0.png</boxart2>
    <snapshot2>EbZ8qQe.png</snapshot2>
    <snapshot3>cOy1Vzq.png</snapshot3>
  </game>
  <game name="Epyx's Impossible Mission (Europe, PSP Mini)">
    <description>Epyx's Impossible Mission (Europe, PSP Mini)</description>
	<groups>PSP Mini</groups>
    <rom name="pspminis/Epyx%27s%20Impossible%20Mission%20%28Europe%29.cso" size="36618005"/>
    <studio>System 3 Software</studio>
    <releasedate>14/09/2007</releasedate>
    <plot>In six hours the evil Professor Elvin Atombender's nuclear missiles will launch and destroy strategic locations on the earth. Only one agent can infiltrate his secret base and undertake this Impossible Mission.[CR]The goal of Impossible Mission is to acquire nine passwords and bring these to Atombender's Control Room in time to shut down the rockets. Unfortunately these passcodes (contained on punch cards) have been broken into four pieces each, and each piece hidden in computers, furniture, and waste bins throughout the base. On top of that Atombender has an entire army of robots patrolling the base. If a robot touches or shocks the agent then ten minutes are removed from the clock and the room is reset. The agent can jump over robots, but the only way to stop them is to expend a specific item on a room's computer terminal, and even that only disables them for a few seconds.[CR]The 2007 release of the game has a few improvements over the original version, mostly to improve the graphics and make the game easier. The player can select one of three agents, although all of them possess the same abilities. Robots are now color coded according to what they are capable of doing (yellow only patrol, red patrol and shock, blue can follow and shock), but some aspects of each robot's personality can still only be figured out by watching or approaching them. Finally an easy mode has been added that adds an extra two hours to the clock and marks rooms which you have cleared out of items. The original mode with the original graphics can also be played, as well as a "mixed" mode that uses the old avatar graphics, makes all robots the same color, but keeps any other graphical upgrades.</plot>
    <genre>Action, Platform, Puzzle</genre>
    <boxart1>8MxCPbv.jpg</boxart1>
    <clearlogo1>Q1CCMYY.png</clearlogo1>
    <boxart2>RQ1CuD9.png</boxart2>
  </game>
  <game name="Express Raider (USA, PSP Mini)">
    <description>Express Raider (USA, PSP Mini)</description>
	<groups>PSP Mini</groups>
    <rom name="pspminis/Express%20Raider%20%28USA%29.cso" size="5644888"/>
    <studio>G1M2</studio>
    <releasedate>15/06/2010</releasedate>
    <plot>Your aim in life is to be the greatest train robber in the Wild West, a multi-stage task. Your character has plenty of attacking kicks and punches to use on anyone who gets in his way, starting with the local banker, and then some coyotes roaming the plains, who are easier dodged than killed. After this, you find yourself atop the train, attacking a succession of guards in one-on-one beat 'em up duels, each of which must be won outright within the time limit to avoid losing a life. Many of these shoot at you, so dodge their shots as you attack them. The game offers a practice mode, in which you have 32 lives to try to improve your skills, and a 'normal' mode in which you have unlimited continues as long as you can reach the high-score table with each continue - in this mode, as in the 'advanced' mode in which you must always start again from scratch, you have 5 lives</plot>
    <genre>Platform, Shooter, Beat 'em Up</genre>
    <boxart1>n3i90m7.jpg</boxart1>
    <clearlogo1>TTlJdmP.png</clearlogo1>
    <boxart2>97okcrF.png</boxart2>
  </game>
  <game name="Family Games (USA, PSP Mini)">
    <description>Family Games (USA, PSP Mini)</description>
	<groups>PSP Mini</groups>
    <rom name="pspminis/Family%20Games%20%28USA%29.cso" size="27268466"/>
    <studio>Icon Games Entertainment</studio>
    <releasedate>04/01/2011</releasedate>
    <plot>A collection of classic family pen and paper game favorites. Timeless favorites for all the family. Includes Squares (Dots), Nine Men's Morris (Mill), Safe Cracker, Matchsticks, Noughts and Crosses (Tic-Tac-Toe), 4 In-A-Row, BattleFleet and Hangman. [CR]* Includes 8 super addictive classic games.[CR]* Numerous rule sets and game variations - so many ways to play! [CR]* Fun for all the family - up to 4 players can compete in Tournament mode. [CR]* 20 special secret bottlecap rewards to unlock.</plot>
    <genre>Puzzle, Education</genre>
    <boxart1>wkgLyMD.png</boxart1>
    <clearlogo1>nJPBCft.png</clearlogo1>
  </game>
  <game name="Farm Frenzy (USA, PSP Mini)">
    <description>Farm Frenzy (USA, PSP Mini)</description>
	<groups>PSP Mini</groups>
    <rom name="pspminis/Farm%20Frenzy%20%28USA%29.cso" size="25593488"/>
    <studio>Alawar Entertainment</studio>
    <releasedate>29/07/2017</releasedate>
    <plot>Farm Frenzy is a straightforward time-management game, where the player controls a farm, raising animals and selling products to the market. The main game screen is mostly occupied by a central bare patch of land where the farm animals roam, surrounded by a series of farm implements and machines. All necessary actions are performed with clicks over interactive hotspots of the scenery.[CR]The objective is displayed at the start of the level, usually requiring a certain amount of resources, money or other goals. Initially, the player has to click on the well to collect water and on the ground to grow the grass that feeds most of the livestock. The animals can be purchased from a tab at the top, to eat the turf and generate products every few moments. Geese lay eggs, sheep shed cotton, cows produce milk, and all these resources have to be collected and stacked on boxes at the bottom storage shed. The boxes have to be shipped to the market by clicking on the truck, that takes a few moments to make the transportation of all the selected goods. A small animation at the bottom-right shows the vehicle going back and forth between the farm and the city.[CR]Dangerous bears appear randomly on the farm, and kill any animal that cross their paths. They have to be quickly contained on cages, and afterwards collected on boxes to be sold as a product. If the cage remains untouched on the field for too long, the bear eventually breaks free and runs out of the farm. The storage space at the bottom is limited, and sometimes bears and other products can't be stored on time and disappear after a while.[CR]The structures surrounding the game field are used to process the raw materials produced by the farm into more refined products, like powdered eggs, cheese, baked goods and other items. The stars received after completing a level have to be spent on upgrades to the machines on the shop screen, to make them more efficient and unlock new levels. There is no time limit to complete each stage, but finishing within a specific time frame, shown at the top, gives awards and bonus stars.</plot>
    <genre>Strategy</genre>
    <rating>2.50</rating>
    <boxart1>gLlg8xN.jpg</boxart1>
    <clearlogo1>nWYIkmD.png</clearlogo1>
    <snapshot1>h2GVbqr.png</snapshot1>
    <boxart2>kXneqpB.png</boxart2>
    <snapshot2>GBuh8jw.png</snapshot2>
  </game>
  <game name="Farm Frenzy - Pizza Party (USA, PSP Mini)">
    <description>Farm Frenzy - Pizza Party (USA, PSP Mini)</description>
	<groups>PSP Mini</groups>
    <rom name="pspminis/Farm%20Frenzy%20-%20Pizza%20Party%20%28USA%29.cso" size="17499824"/>
    <studio>Alawar Entertainment</studio>
    <plot>Do you like pizza as much as we do? Then you'll love the pepperoni-packed sequel to the No. 1 arcade farming sim - Farm Frenzy 2: Pizza Party! At first, you'll grow crops, feed animals and collect produce, and then you'll turn your goods into the ingredients you need to make a variety of pizzas. From China to Germany and Italy to New York City (where pizza is considered one of the main food groups), people from around the world will enjoy your mouthwatering creations!As you master the fast-paced point-and-click gameplay, you'll fend off bears, purchase buildings that produce different ingredients and upgrade your vehicles so you can transport more goods. You'll also enjoy some of the zaniest animations ever created for a casual game! Don't miss all the fun in Farm Frenzy 2: Pizza Party!</plot>
    <genre>Strategy</genre>
    <boxart1>ibPBFAv.jpg</boxart1>
    <clearlogo1>3p5vvfg.png</clearlogo1>
    <boxart2>QrTsJf4.png</boxart2>
  </game>
  <game name="Farm Frenzy 2 (USA, PSP Mini)">
    <description>Farm Frenzy 2 (USA, PSP Mini)</description>
	<groups>PSP Mini</groups>
    <rom name="pspminis/Farm%20Frenzy%202%20%28USA%29.cso" size="17344832"/>
    <studio>Alawar Entertainment</studio>
    <releasedate>29/07/2017</releasedate>
    <plot>Farm Frenzy is a straightforward time-management game, where the player controls a farm, raising animals and selling products to the market. The main game screen is mostly occupied by a central bare patch of land where the farm animals roam, surrounded by a series of farm implements and machines. All necessary actions are performed with clicks over interactive hotspots of the scenery.[CR]The objective is displayed at the start of the level, usually requiring a certain amount of resources, money or other goals. Initially, the player has to click on the well to collect water and on the ground to grow the grass that feeds most of the livestock. The animals can be purchased from a tab at the top, to eat the turf and generate products every few moments. Geese lay eggs, sheep shed cotton, cows produce milk, and all these resources have to be collected and stacked on boxes at the bottom storage shed. The boxes have to be shipped to the market by clicking on the truck, that takes a few moments to make the transportation of all the selected goods. A small animation at the bottom-right shows the vehicle going back and forth between the farm and the city.[CR]Dangerous bears appear randomly on the farm, and kill any animal that cross their paths. They have to be quickly contained on cages, and afterwards collected on boxes to be sold as a product. If the cage remains untouched on the field for too long, the bear eventually breaks free and runs out of the farm. The storage space at the bottom is limited, and sometimes bears and other products can't be stored on time and disappear after a while.[CR]The structures surrounding the game field are used to process the raw materials produced by the farm into more refined products, like powdered eggs, cheese, baked goods and other items. The stars received after completing a level have to be spent on upgrades to the machines on the shop screen, to make them more efficient and unlock new levels. There is no time limit to complete each stage, but finishing within a specific time frame, shown at the top, gives awards and bonus stars.</plot>
    <genre>Strategy</genre>
    <rating>2.50</rating>
    <boxart1>gLlg8xN.jpg</boxart1>
    <clearlogo1>nWYIkmD.png</clearlogo1>
    <snapshot1>h2GVbqr.png</snapshot1>
    <boxart2>kXneqpB.png</boxart2>
    <snapshot2>GBuh8jw.png</snapshot2>
  </game>
  <game name="Farm Frenzy 3 (USA, PSP Mini)">
    <description>Farm Frenzy 3 (USA, PSP Mini)</description>
	<groups>PSP Mini</groups>
    <rom name="pspminis/Farm%20Frenzy%203%20%28USA%29.cso" size="34688418"/>
    <studio>Alawar Entertainment</studio>
    <releasedate>29/07/2017</releasedate>
    <plot>Farm Frenzy is a straightforward time-management game, where the player controls a farm, raising animals and selling products to the market. The main game screen is mostly occupied by a central bare patch of land where the farm animals roam, surrounded by a series of farm implements and machines. All necessary actions are performed with clicks over interactive hotspots of the scenery.[CR]The objective is displayed at the start of the level, usually requiring a certain amount of resources, money or other goals. Initially, the player has to click on the well to collect water and on the ground to grow the grass that feeds most of the livestock. The animals can be purchased from a tab at the top, to eat the turf and generate products every few moments. Geese lay eggs, sheep shed cotton, cows produce milk, and all these resources have to be collected and stacked on boxes at the bottom storage shed. The boxes have to be shipped to the market by clicking on the truck, that takes a few moments to make the transportation of all the selected goods. A small animation at the bottom-right shows the vehicle going back and forth between the farm and the city.[CR]Dangerous bears appear randomly on the farm, and kill any animal that cross their paths. They have to be quickly contained on cages, and afterwards collected on boxes to be sold as a product. If the cage remains untouched on the field for too long, the bear eventually breaks free and runs out of the farm. The storage space at the bottom is limited, and sometimes bears and other products can't be stored on time and disappear after a while.[CR]The structures surrounding the game field are used to process the raw materials produced by the farm into more refined products, like powdered eggs, cheese, baked goods and other items. The stars received after completing a level have to be spent on upgrades to the machines on the shop screen, to make them more efficient and unlock new levels. There is no time limit to complete each stage, but finishing within a specific time frame, shown at the top, gives awards and bonus stars.</plot>
    <genre>Strategy</genre>
    <rating>2.50</rating>
    <boxart1>gLlg8xN.jpg</boxart1>
    <clearlogo1>nWYIkmD.png</clearlogo1>
    <snapshot1>h2GVbqr.png</snapshot1>
    <boxart2>kXneqpB.png</boxart2>
    <snapshot2>GBuh8jw.png</snapshot2>
  </game>
  <game name="Feisty Feet (USA, PSP Mini)">
    <description>Feisty Feet (USA, PSP Mini)</description>
	<groups>PSP Mini</groups>
    <rom name="pspminis/Feisty%20Feet%20%28USA%29.cso" size="14096537"/>
    <rating>5.00</rating>
    <genre>Platform</genre>
    <boxart1>TmVSoT1.jpg</boxart1>
  </game>
  <game name="Fieldrunners (USA, PSP Mini)">
    <description>Fieldrunners (USA, PSP Mini)</description>
	<groups>PSP Mini</groups>
    <rom name="pspminis/Fieldrunners%20%28USA%29.cso" size="28838721"/>
    <nplayers>1</nplayers>
    <studio>Subatomic</studio>
    <releasedate>01/10/2009</releasedate>
    <plot>In Fieldrunners, your goal is to defend and control a field using a diverse selection of upgradeable towers over countless waves of enemies, fighting off many land and air combatants to achieve the ultimate victory![CR]Upgraded for PlayStation Portable, this edition of Fieldrunners includes additional content, from new maps and towers to new fieldrunners! Also, exclusive to PSP version is themed music and enhanced graphics painstakingly reworked to make your experience all the more satisfying as you thrash your enemies.</plot>
    <genre>Strategy</genre>
    <boxart1>ToGY3BH.jpg</boxart1>
  </game>
  <game name="Fighting Fantasy - Talisman of Death (USA, PSP Mini)">
    <description>Fighting Fantasy - Talisman of Death (USA, PSP Mini)</description>
	<groups>PSP Mini</groups>
    <rom name="pspminis/Fighting%20Fantasy%20-%20Talisman%20of%20Death%20%28USA%29.cso" size="30722448"/>
    <nplayers>1</nplayers>
    <studio>Sony Computer Entertainment</studio>
    <releasedate>17/08/2011</releasedate>
    <plot>This version of Fighting Fantasy: Talisman of Death features a Tarot Card character generation system, and the classic dice-rolling rule set you know and love, with optional all-new Battle and Test Your Luck systems for bold adventurers to explore.</plot>
    <genre>Role-Playing</genre>
    <videoid>OEzqSbbvE9s</videoid>
    <boxart1>DXHbMm0.png</boxart1>
    <clearlogo1>vu6JgSz.png</clearlogo1>
    <snapshot1>Cx2NMl4.jpg</snapshot1>
    <boxart2>lV0CYHU.png</boxart2>
    <snapshot2>YoULJDU.jpg</snapshot2>
  </game>
  <game name="Fighting Fantasy - The Warlock of Firetop Mountain (USA, PSP Mini)">
    <description>Fighting Fantasy - The Warlock of Firetop Mountain (USA, PSP Mini)</description>
	<groups>PSP Mini</groups>
    <rom name="pspminis/Fighting%20Fantasy%20-%20The%20Warlock%20of%20Firetop%20Mountain%20%28USA%29.cso" size="31118911"/>
    <studio>Aspyr</studio>
    <plot>Fighting Fantasy: The Warlock of Firetop Mountain is a first person shooter action RPG for the Nintendo DS developed by Big Blue Bubble and published by Aspyr in North America on November 25, 2009. The game is loosely based on the roleplaying gamebook of the same name.</plot>
    <genre>Action, Role-Playing</genre>
    <boxart1>wFoJWvs.jpg</boxart1>
    <clearlogo1>HDziVr6.png</clearlogo1>
    <boxart2>XroPVmX.png</boxart2>
  </game>
  <game name="Finger Connection (USA, PSP Mini)">
    <description>Finger Connection (USA, PSP Mini)</description>
	<groups>PSP Mini</groups>
    <rom name="pspminis/Finger%20Connection%20%28USA%29.cso" size="6437003"/>
    <nplayers>2</nplayers>
    <studio>Sony Computer Entertainment</studio>
    <releasedate>04/05/2010</releasedate>
    <plot>Ready for a finger connection? Start by placing your fingers on the PSP(r) screen. Each round you will have to maneuver your fingers around to different spots on the game board. The longer you can last, the higher the chance of you and your partner having a finger connection. Are you ready?</plot>
    <genre>Action</genre>
    <boxart1>717xeTh.jpg</boxart1>
    <clearlogo1>llfXpP4.png</clearlogo1>
    <snapshot1>gf50z5M.png</snapshot1>
    <boxart2>01reCtG.png</boxart2>
    <snapshot2>LuWNG9H.png</snapshot2>
  </game>
  <game name="Fish Tank (USA, PSP Mini)">
    <description>Fish Tank (USA, PSP Mini)</description>
	<groups>PSP Mini</groups>
    <rom name="pspminis/Fish%20Tank%20%28USA%29.cso" size="8308696"/>
    <studio>iFun4all S.A.</studio>
    <releasedate>05/04/2011</releasedate>
    <plot>Fish Tank is a first "Match-3" game that not only offers lots of fun with finding groups of fishes in the same colors on the grid, but also offers player way to navigate new swimming fishes into desired place on the grid. [CR]Because of that you are not only entertained by normal matching game mechanics but also with dynamic, reflex based gameplay! [CR]Game offers: [CR]- free play mode for quick bursts of fun play[CR]- three difficulty levels for different intensity of fun[CR]- 9 different power up types to enhance your playing experience[CR]- 24 levels to face with[CR]- 72 medals to collect to make gameplay last longer</plot>
    <genre>Puzzle</genre>
    <boxart1>nmuLmzb.png</boxart1>
    <clearlogo1>TW4IY6H.png</clearlogo1>
  </game>
  <game name="Flick Fishing (USA, PSP Mini)">
    <description>Flick Fishing (USA, PSP Mini)</description>
	<groups>PSP Mini</groups>
    <rom name="pspminis/Flick%20Fishing%20%28USA%29.cso" size="47595388"/>
    <studio>Gameshastra Inc.</studio>
    <releasedate>26/10/2010</releasedate>
    <plot>An arcade sports fishing game where the player goes fishing at different locations on the map to get the best fishing experience!!! [CR]The player has to cast the line and with a skillful combination of bait, location and technique has to hook a fish. Once the fish gets hooked to the line, just reel it in. The player has 9 types of baits to tackle with and the bigger the fish, the more strength it takes to reel it in however try not to reel in too fast to avoid snapping the line and losing the fish. There are various types of fishes to catch ranging from carp to the blue marlin. Enjoy Fishing!!!</plot>
    <genre>Sports</genre>
    <boxart1>xOYNk1Y.png</boxart1>
    <clearlogo1>szORcu9.png</clearlogo1>
  </game>
  <game name="Floating Cloud God Saves the Pilgrims (USA, PSP Mini)">
    <description>Floating Cloud God Saves the Pilgrims (USA, PSP Mini)</description>
	<groups>PSP Mini</groups>
    <rom name="pspminis/Floating%20Cloud%20God%20Saves%20the%20Pilgrims%20%28USA%29.cso" size="19535921"/>
    <nplayers>1</nplayers>
    <studio>Dakko Dakko</studio>
    <releasedate>29/06/2006</releasedate>
    <plot>Floating Cloud God Saves the Pilgrims is a Playstation Mini game for PSP and Vita.  [CR]Floating Cloud God Saves the Pilgrims is exactly that, a 2D shooter built around the eponymous deity (controlled by the player) and his quest to protect eight pilgrims in their journey across perilous territories.[CR]Your own shots just knock their hats off, but getting hit by anything else will kill a pilgrim and send their spirit floating off with a sad little wail. This is bad not only because the pilgrims are a de facto health bar (losing them all ends the game) but powering up Cloud God depends on harvesting their love - juicy little hearts that pop up whenever you kill an enemy and increase in size as you blast more.[CR]You must get all of the love (given form as hearts) that they release, which then makes you much more powerful than you already are. You increase in size, look more menacing, and your attacks are more powerful. The pilgrims get the most excited when they witness ambushing ghosts and ghouls get annihilated by you. When they are excited, they produce more love, meaning more power to you.[CR]However, you have to be very careful when shooting. You grow weaker with every shot, so try not to channel your inner war-freak and have a little restraint, for the good of both yourself and the pilgrims. You also lose some of your steam if you get hit by enemy forces. And sometimes, the situation calls to for you to sacrifice your mightiness and provide cover to the pilgrims from the enemy assault with your own self.[CR]There are two types of attack: the normal shot (by pressing X), and the bomb shot (by pressing Circle). The direction of the normal shot depends on what direction you are pressing, so there is some strategy to what part of the screen you should be shooting from. Being too far from your pilgrims is very dangerous but allows you to cover more ground, while launching a full frontal assault can protect your pilgrims by absorbing all the incoming fire. You have to think through, in real time, what tactics you would like to employ. You can always get in the middle, then rush forward, then get to a safe distance; mix and match, and you got yourself going.[CR]The bomb shot is used if you are above the enemy. But that's not all, as some enemies can't be killed with the bomb shot, only with the normal shot, and vice versa. There are also enemies where you have to inflict bomb shot damage first before switching to the normal shot to take them out.[CR]Enemies are varied, and they look good, even if they are vile and evil. There are boss fights, too, to keep you on your toes.  The Cloud God's powers and the heart system mesh so well that any enemy can be destroyed in a blink - so they've got to be deceptive, sneaky, and sometimes numerous. Paper lanterns send out an arcing flame on death, red-eyed foxes hide in the scenery, imps swoop to carry off unlucky pilgrims and bobbing doll heads send out swarms of kisses. Hands start clawing up from the ground, crows dive-bomb your crew, and demons with phallic noses launch them as languorous, looping rockets. The cheeky oriental stylings are gorgeous, transforming symbols into everything from freaky momiji to dick-nosed devils.[CR]As this suggests, one of the reasons Floating Cloud God is such a pleasure to play is its visual inventiveness, which has room enough for everything from Wario tributes to what looks like a crying poo. This big lump of a thing, which is introduced in a level called The Saddest Enemy, explodes into gobbets of mini-poo that are very useful for building up a heart multiplier. Perhaps they're babies? That would explain the sadness.[CR]Floating Cloud God has bags more where that came from, and despite the Minis tag has plenty of room to breathe (there are seven worlds with 27 stages, including boss fights). And it keeps on surprising. The controls are simplicity itself: left stick to move, one button to shoot and one to bomb. But you soon realise the subtlety of how shooting affects movement and vice-versa, which fairly soon you're depending on against every enemy pattern. The pilgrims, too, are loosely tied to Cloud God during some sections, and learning how to manage their momentum is another little learning curve.[CR]The final touch is a minor detail that ties up everything. The pilgrims' hats can be improved. There's no in-game benefit to this, beyond looking much more awesome, and it's done by completing stages without losing a single pilgrim. Obviously, if you start this process on the first level and never lose a pilgrim, the hats just keep getting better.[CR]Seems like such a small thing, doesn't it? Soon nothing but a perfect run will do. The restart option is accessible, knowing, and tempting. Every time a pilgrim fell, it was too much to take - I didn't see their tiny spirit float off to heaven so much as all my future headwear ambitions. And to be fair, by that point I had four dudes with top hats, two with octopus heads and two with space hero helmets. You can't be replacing any of them with Norman and his brown cap just because some demon gets a lucky shot in.[CR]That's the best thing about Floating Cloud God Saves the Pilgrims. You do want to save them, and not just because they represent 'health'. The hats are a big part of it, but just as much is the sense of pride in being a badass god - harvesting power at the right moment to smash through oncoming waves, battling desperate rear-guard actions against hails of deadly kisses and throwing yourself in bodily as a last resort (which sometimes works!). The little yelp as a pilgrim goes down is a sharp reprimand, a blow to the daydreams of an all-conquering deity.[CR]This description was compiled from the following reviews:[CR]http://www.eurogamer.net/articles/2012-04-19-floating-cloud-god-saves-the-pilgrims-review[CR]http://www.pspminis.com/8859/floating-cloud-god-saves-the-pilgrims-review-if-the-indication-of-a-good-game-is-a-lengthy-title-then-that-rule-applies-here/</plot>
    <genre>Shooter</genre>
    <boxart1>tNZqvVY.jpg</boxart1>
    <snapshot1>whpiZOx.jpg</snapshot1>
  </game>
  <game name="Fly Fu (USA, PSP Mini)">
    <description>Fly Fu (USA, PSP Mini)</description>
	<groups>PSP Mini</groups>
    <rom name="pspminis/Fly%20Fu%20%28USA%29.cso" size="22289224"/>
    <studio>Invictus Games</studio>
    <releasedate>20/07/2010</releasedate>
    <plot>Fly Fu is a side-scrolling beat-'em-up game with characters designed from photographs of dead insects mixed with doodle art. [CR]Your girlfriend, Kate Moth, a fluffy moth was kidnapped by evil spiders and dragged away to the suburb. [CR]You are not a common housefly but trained to fight. Being a Kung-Fu master, only you can save your love from the claws of the evil insects! [CR]Five chapters are waiting for you to complete! Each chapter ends with a unique boss, where you fight against the strongest members of The Cuticulous Gang. [CR]Features[CR]- watch the famous 'dead fly art' in smooth motion[CR]- experience the intense doodle violence with heated Kung Fu action[CR]- fight your way through bees, wasps, lady bugs and more than 20 different insects[CR]- get really mad at insects bugging around and GO BERSERK! [CR]- arm yourself with matchsticks and needle-pins to gain more fist power[CR]- play story mode accompanied with cutscenes with twists on plot[CR]- put your endurance to the test in survival mode</plot>
    <genre>Beat 'em Up</genre>
    <boxart1>VJbwAvq.png</boxart1>
    <clearlogo1>FEsb7ej.png</clearlogo1>
  </game>
  <game name="Flying Hamster, The (USA, PSP Mini)">
    <description>Flying Hamster, The (USA, PSP Mini)</description>
	<groups>PSP Mini</groups>
    <rom name="pspminis/Flying%20Hamster%2C%20The%20%28USA%29.cso" size="47956981"/>
    <nplayers>1</nplayers>
    <studio>The Game Atelier</studio>
    <releasedate>07/12/2010</releasedate>
    <plot>Take control of Newton, the flying hamster in this action-frenzy horizontal shooter. You will fly across six unique environments, from the sunflower fields to the big Japanese city or the crazy ancient Egypt. Eight freaky weapons are scattered among the levels, and you'll need them all to take on the more than 35 different enemies (sneaky penguins, anti-air cows, exploding foxes, ninja squirrels, toaster-robots...) as well as the six dreadful and unpredictable bosses.</plot>
    <genre>Shooter</genre>
    <boxart1>wZnbvPE.jpg</boxart1>
    <clearlogo1>PcEPKvS.png</clearlogo1>
  </game>
  <game name="Forest Puzzle (USA, PSP Mini)">
    <description>Forest Puzzle (USA, PSP Mini)</description>
	<groups>PSP Mini</groups>
    <rom name="pspminis/Forest%20Puzzle%20%28USA%29.cso" size="17905672"/>
    <studio>IBA Group</studio>
    <releasedate>21/12/2010</releasedate>
    <plot>Forest puzzle is the game in which you need to save strange creatures called Sparks on 60 challenging levels in 3 different game modes. Deadly creatures like Golems,[CR]Zombies, Firebats and Ghosts will be pursuing you. Complete levels and save enough Sparks to unlock new, more challenging stages.[CR]Find the way to Exit Portal through the numerous puzzles in Puzzle mode.[CR]Rush to Exit Portal in Time trial mode. Do not forget about Sparks[CR]Survive long enough to complete the level in Survival mode with endless dangerous creatures. There is no exit - how long would you live?</plot>
    <genre>Puzzle</genre>
    <videoid>1LXfVw4VqOA</videoid>
    <boxart1>6wMXnUY.jpg</boxart1>
    <clearlogo1>E9n8Ofg.png</clearlogo1>
    <snapshot1>zw0Vmg3.png</snapshot1>
    <boxart2>DIGXTjJ.png</boxart2>
    <snapshot2>xBF81mB.png</snapshot2>
    <snapshot3>KiksucQ.png</snapshot3>
  </game>
  <game name="Fort Commander - King's Gambit (USA, PSP Mini)">
    <description>Fort Commander - King's Gambit (USA, PSP Mini)</description>
	<groups>PSP Mini</groups>
    <rom name="pspminis/Fort%20Commander%20-%20King%27s%20Gambit%20%28USA%29.cso" size="10613660"/>
    <studio>Immersive Games</studio>
    <releasedate>05/10/2010</releasedate>
    <plot>Fort Commander(tm) is a twist on the classic tower defense genre set in the Mogul conquest period. You play the role of the commander of the Mogul army. You must defeat two opposing kingdoms - Lodi and Sur - in a total of 14 missions including two Assault and two Survival. The gameplay is built around the strategy for expanding and controlling the Mogul empire. In Campaign mode, you defend your tower until the enemy population is depleted and then you conquer their tower. In Assault mode, you charge the enemy tower until you deplete their population. In Survival mode, you hold out for as long as possible against an ever increasing enemy force.</plot>
    <genre>Strategy</genre>
    <boxart1>5kyld5Z.png</boxart1>
    <clearlogo1>08ILYAf.png</clearlogo1>
  </game>
  <game name="Fort Commander II - Counterattack (USA, PSP Mini)">
    <description>Fort Commander II - Counterattack (USA, PSP Mini)</description>
	<groups>PSP Mini</groups>
    <rom name="pspminis/Fort%20Commander%20II%20-%20Counterattack%20%28USA%29.cso" size="10908345"/>
    <studio>Immersive Games</studio>
    <releasedate>09/11/2010</releasedate>
    <plot>Fort Commander(tm) is a twist on the classic tower defense genre set in the Mogul conquest period. You play the role of the commander of the Mogul army. You must defeat two opposing kingdoms - Malwa and Bengal - in a total of 14 missions including two Assault and two Survival. The game play is built around the strategy for expanding and controlling the Mogul empire. In Campaign mode, you defend your tower until the enemy population is depleted and then you conquer their tower. In Assault mode, you charge the enemy tower until you deplete their population. In Survival mode, you hold out for as long as possible against an ever increasing enemy force.</plot>
    <genre>Strategy</genre>
    <boxart1>s7euE0P.png</boxart1>
  </game>
  <game name="Fortix (USA, PSP Mini)">
    <description>Fortix (USA, PSP Mini)</description>
	<groups>PSP Mini</groups>
    <rom name="pspminis/Fortix%20%28USA%29.cso" size="29037473"/>
  </game>
  <game name="Free Shot Frenzy (Europe, PSP Mini)">
    <description>Free Shot Frenzy (Europe, PSP Mini)</description>
	<groups>PSP Mini</groups>
    <rom name="pspminis/Free%20Shot%20Frenzy%20%28Europe%29.cso" size="10743666"/>
  </game>
  <game name="Freekscape - Escape From Hell (USA, PSP Mini)">
    <description>Freekscape - Escape From Hell (USA, PSP Mini)</description>
	<groups>PSP Mini</groups>
    <rom name="pspminis/Freekscape%20-%20Escape%20From%20Hell%20%28USA%29.cso" size="56481551"/>
    <studio>Creat Studios Inc</studio>
    <releasedate>08/04/2010</releasedate>
    <plot>Freekscape: Escape from Hell is a 2.5D puzzle platformer. The protagonist is the horned demon Freek who is left behind in hell because he does not enjoy torturing souls. That is why he is tasked with housekeeping chores instead by his master Beel. Working alone, he discovers the key to the treasure room, steals a trident and attempts to escape hell to reach heaven. To complete levels the exit needs to be reached. Levels are accessed one by one on a large world map and they branch out at a certain point with multiple paths.[CR]Puzzles are based on platforming and using the abilities of different creatures. Freek can use his trident to skewer other minions, carry them around or use them as a pogo stick to jump higher. One type of creature rushes and can knock Freek over large gaps. Another type acts as a trampoline. Creatures can sometimes be dropped into the lava to create safe passages. A hug block rushes to hug you. By taking it out up to three can be skewered to use them as a bridge. Creatures are summoned through portals at specific locations. Freek can also draw their attention by whistling. Freek has his own portals that act as checkpoints when he passes them. Some levels require you to locate a number of peppers to unlock a pepper portal before a level can be finished. The D-pad can be used to look around while the analog stick control movement.</plot>
    <genre>Action</genre>
    <videoid>I2TUfApLX_Q</videoid>
    <boxart1>5jZUXtl.jpg</boxart1>
    <clearlogo1>KEqzBXh.png</clearlogo1>
    <snapshot1>cujkSRE.png</snapshot1>
    <snapshot2>HLqqNbV.png</snapshot2>
    <snapshot3>TjHBXgQ.png</snapshot3>
  </game>
  <game name="Funky Punch (USA, PSP Mini)">
    <description>Funky Punch (USA, PSP Mini)</description>
	<groups>PSP Mini</groups>
    <rom name="pspminis/Funky%20Punch%20%28USA%29.cso" size="20164947"/>
    <rating>2.00</rating>
    <studio>Solus Game</studio>
    <releasedate>01/10/2009</releasedate>
    <plot>In the unique world of Funkyville, a musical power called the Funky Flow has empowered some with amazing abilities. But Klyde has evil plans afoot and has built an army of Emoticons to do his bidding and control the flow for himself.</plot>
    <genre>Action, Fighting</genre>
    <videoid>rA_IfodhM-0</videoid>
    <boxart1>ALlt2kg.jpg</boxart1>
    <snapshot1>O93n7fn.png</snapshot1>
    <snapshot2>RrcBglO.png</snapshot2>
    <snapshot3>XACxsPQ.png</snapshot3>
  </game>
  <game name="Future Fight (Europe, PSP Mini)">
    <description>Future Fight (Europe, PSP Mini)</description>
	<groups>PSP Mini</groups>
    <rom name="pspminis/Future%20Fight%20%28Europe%29.cso" size="18255971"/>
  </game>
  <game name="Galcon Labs (USA, PSP Mini)">
    <description>Galcon Labs (USA, PSP Mini)</description>
	<groups>PSP Mini</groups>
    <rom name="pspminis/Galcon%20Labs%20%28USA%29.cso" size="17692983"/>
    <studio>Beatshapers</studio>
    <releasedate>27/09/2011</releasedate>
    <plot>Conquer the Galaxy like never before! Galcon Labs is an awesome high-paced galactic arcade-strategy game. Send swarms of ships to defeat enemy planets and conquer the universe! [CR]Exclusively designed for PlayStation(r)Minis campaign mode to unlock the four innovative new game modes to you:[CR]Billiards: 'Moving Planets' - need we say more? With a constantly changing battlefield this game never has a dull moment. [CR]Stealth: Enemy ships become invisible, changing Galcon into a game of inter-galactic hide and seek! [CR]Crash: Ships battle in mid-flight, bringing a whole different twist to the classic gameplay. You can now defeat the enemy in the air! [CR]Assassin: Each opponent is assigned a target. The first player to annihilate their target wins the round! [CR]Galcon Labs: Conquer the galaxy in five minutes!</plot>
    <genre>Action, Strategy</genre>
    <boxart1>rEpXKLA.jpg</boxart1>
  </game>
  <game name="Gamocracy One - Legend of Robot (USA, PSP Mini)">
    <description>Gamocracy One - Legend of Robot (USA, PSP Mini)</description>
	<groups>PSP Mini</groups>
    <rom name="pspminis/Gamocracy%20One%20-%20Legend%20of%20Robot%20%28USA%29.cso" size="12202154"/>
    <nplayers>1</nplayers>
    <releasedate>16/08/2011</releasedate>
    <plot>Legend of Robot is something very special. It is the product of the Gamocracy project, in which The Bearded Ladies invited the PlayStation(r) community forum members to design a game. The result is an awesome platformer with some very unique game mechanics and colorful characters.[CR]In true Gamocracy spirit here is the salespitch from one of the forum members : [CR]Have you ever considered what it'd be like to throw your own head off and use it as a platform or weapon? How about turning your arms into energy canons and magnets? In Legend of Robot you can do all of these things! [CR]It's evident that some of you DO think about these things, because you- the best and brightest of the community, designed it! [CR]- Vincent Pavey</plot>
    <genre>Platform</genre>
    <boxart1>thmUAYX.png</boxart1>
    <clearlogo1>Ymj2ALr.png</clearlogo1>
    <snapshot1>HREh7lN.png</snapshot1>
    <fanart1>WbBucUc.jpg</fanart1>
    <snapshot2>FkTJEWh.png</snapshot2>
  </game>
  <game name="Gang Wars (USA, PSP Mini)">
    <description>Gang Wars (USA, PSP Mini)</description>
	<groups>PSP Mini</groups>
    <rom name="pspminis/Gang%20Wars%20%28USA%29.cso" size="15452993"/>
  </game>
  <game name="Gold Fever (USA, PSP Mini)">
    <description>Gold Fever (USA, PSP Mini)</description>
	<groups>PSP Mini</groups>
    <rom name="pspminis/Gold%20Fever%20%28USA%29.cso" size="9642944"/>
    <studio>Tik Games, Creat Studios</studio>
    <releasedate>15/06/2010</releasedate>
    <plot>Take a trip back in time to explore the great American Gold Rush in this well-designed arcade puzzle game. Flip coins to make matches and mine your way to Gold Country, California. Gold Fever will challenge even the most dedicated puzzle players. Clever power ups and stunning graphics promise hours of enjoyable gameplay.[CR]* 160 strike-it-rich levels [CR]* New power ups, coins and challenges as you progress</plot>
    <genre>Puzzle</genre>
    <boxart1>s4HojtM.jpg</boxart1>
    <snapshot1>gkpkqMz.png</snapshot1>
    <boxart2>s8eMp36.png</boxart2>
    <snapshot2>0M3hsWu.png</snapshot2>
    <snapshot3>m4VUVxq.png</snapshot3>
  </game>
  <game name="Gold Medalist (USA, PSP Mini)">
    <description>Gold Medalist (USA, PSP Mini)</description>
	<groups>PSP Mini</groups>
    <rom name="pspminis/Gold%20Medalist%20%28USA%29.cso" size="12693143"/>
  </game>
  <game name="Golf Mania (USA, PSP Mini)">
    <description>Golf Mania (USA, PSP Mini)</description>
	<groups>PSP Mini</groups>
    <rom name="pspminis/Golf%20Mania%20%28USA%29.cso" size="56688207"/>
    <nplayers>1</nplayers>
    <plot>Golf Mania features over 90 holes of golfing mayhem that is easy to learn but tough to master. [CR]With single and multiplayer gaming on classic grass courses and modern courses built upon incredible gravity defying glass towers, Golf Mania offers hours of gameplay for the whole family.</plot>
    <genre>Sports</genre>
    <year>2012</year>
    <boxart1>diZK9uo.jpg</boxart1>
    <clearlogo1>zjeSQ16.png</clearlogo1>
    <snapshot1>eX5TEg7.png</snapshot1>
    <snapshot2>Mhj5Bmo.png</snapshot2>
  </game>
  <game name="GreenTechPlus (Europe, PSP Mini)">
    <description>GreenTechPlus (Europe, PSP Mini)</description>
	<groups>PSP Mini</groups>
    <rom name="pspminis/GreenTechPlus%20%28Europe%29.cso" size="20234164"/>
  </game>
  <game name="Guerrilla War (USA, PSP Mini)">
    <description>Guerrilla War (USA, PSP Mini)</description>
	<groups>PSP Mini</groups>
    <rom name="pspminis/Guerrilla%20War%20%28USA%29.cso" size="18620318"/>
  </game>
  <game name="HAL 21 (USA, PSP Mini)">
    <description>HAL 21 (USA, PSP Mini)</description>
	<groups>PSP Mini</groups>
    <rom name="pspminis/HAL%2021%20%28USA%29.cso" size="3516752"/>
  </game>
  <game name="HISTORY - Egypt - Engineering an Empire (USA, PSP Mini)">
    <description>HISTORY - Egypt - Engineering an Empire (USA, PSP Mini)</description>
	<groups>PSP Mini</groups>
    <rom name="pspminis/HISTORY%20-%20Egypt%20-%20Engineering%20an%20Empire%20%28USA%29.cso" size="23654314"/>
  </game>
  <game name="HISTORY - Ice Road Truckers (USA, PSP Mini)">
    <description>HISTORY - Ice Road Truckers (USA, PSP Mini)</description>
	<groups>PSP Mini</groups>
    <rom name="pspminis/HISTORY%20-%20Ice%20Road%20Truckers%20%28USA%29.cso" size="20001580"/>
  </game>
  <game name="Hello Flowerz (USA, PSP Mini)">
    <description>Hello Flowerz (USA, PSP Mini)</description>
	<groups>PSP Mini</groups>
    <rom name="pspminis/Hello%20Flowerz%20%28USA%29.cso" size="15362113"/>
    <studio>Virtual Toys</studio>
    <releasedate>29/06/2010</releasedate>
    <plot>Welcome to Hello Flowerz, the gardening game where you have fun with flowers. Sow your favorite flowers and look after them every day, helping them grow into healthy, beautiful flowers. Use your flowers to create wonderful bouquets and enter them in regular competitions. Landscape your own gardens, transplant flowers and arrange various items. Put on your gloves, grab your tools and start showing off your flowers!</plot>
    <genre>Life Simulation</genre>
    <videoid>i6JZqBYZqN8</videoid>
    <boxart1>r40eKDW.jpg</boxart1>
    <snapshot1>bxg7jFp.png</snapshot1>
    <snapshot2>LuokpgT.png</snapshot2>
    <snapshot3>NElUBCg.png</snapshot3>
  </game>
  <game name="Heracles Chariot Racing (USA, PSP Mini)">
    <description>Heracles Chariot Racing (USA, PSP Mini)</description>
	<groups>PSP Mini</groups>
    <rom name="pspminis/Heracles%20Chariot%20Racing%20%28USA%29.cso" size="41914472"/>
    <studio>Neko Entertainment</studio>
    <releasedate>17/12/2009</releasedate>
    <plot>Ride the Chariots of the Gods![CR]The famous Heracles has take on a challenge like none he has ever faced! Our hero will have to beat his opponents in a race across mythological kingdoms and be the first to reach the top of Mount Olympus.[CR]You can play as Heracles and help him return the sacred trophy, or play as one of the other varied mythological characters from Satyr to Poseidon and claim the prize for yourself![CR]Race through 3 racing cups across 10 courses set in 5 mythic landscapes and use awesome fantasy weaponry to defeat your opponents: Zeus' lightning rods, tridents, fireballs and more!</plot>
    <genre>Racing</genre>
    <videoid>zjC9fvJqQ78</videoid>
    <boxart1>ywWR4OX.jpg</boxart1>
    <snapshot1>KBVuN1L.png</snapshot1>
    <boxart2>9vcSorw.png</boxart2>
    <snapshot2>pTDBG9R.png</snapshot2>
    <snapshot3>VydyH36.png</snapshot3>
  </game>
  <game name="Hero of Sparta (USA, PSP Mini)">
    <description>Hero of Sparta (USA, PSP Mini)</description>
	<groups>PSP Mini</groups>
    <rom name="pspminis/Hero%20of%20Sparta%20%28USA%29.cso" size="52302163"/>
  </game>
  <game name="Hive Sweeper (Europe, PSP Mini)">
    <description>Hive Sweeper (Europe, PSP Mini)</description>
	<groups>PSP Mini</groups>
    <rom name="pspminis/Hive%20Sweeper%20%28Europe%29.cso" size="9874516"/>
    <studio>Skylon Games</studio>
    <releasedate>25/08/2010</releasedate>
    <plot>Play the classic mine sweeper game as you've never played it before! Hive sweeper offers unlimited number of the classic game set in the unique atmosphere of a hive. Be careful! Crazy graphics, chilling music, will soon make you a number one addict to Hive Sweeper. [CR]What is more!!! Have you ever got bored of playing minesweeper alone? Now with Hive Sweeper it is no longer possible! [CR]MULTIPLAYER mode offers you the chance to play wirelessly over Bluetooth or you can always play online if you have wifi or internet connection. Invite your friend or find an opponent via Game Center. Anyway, get ready for the ultimate battle![CR]Test your brain power, smartness and patience in the 3 types of game style each coming with different cell shapes. Find your challenge! In addition to the classic square board you may choose hexagon or triangle grid as well.[CR]What is more each board type comes with 15 difficulty levels. You are the one who can set the parameters. Decide the size of your board and the number of mines! This way you can start with easy boards or really-really hard ones if you like. Adjust the time and challenge yourself. Or you need a bit more practice? Then set the unlimited time mode![CR]Collect your hive points to unlock all the features of the game. The more you play with the game the more hive points you get. Not patient enough? You get the chance to earn FREE hive points really easily! Not content with this? You may buy hive points for a very small amount if you wish.[CR]Now for a limited time with 99 Hive Points for free! (Internet connection required.)[CR]Are you an absolute beginner? Or an expert already? Hive sweeper is the mine sweeper for you![CR]FEATURES: [CR]-unique atmosphere, graphics and chilling music[CR]-retina display support[CR]-3 types of board: triangle, hexagon, square[CR]-3 board sizes in each board type: small, medium, large[CR]-you can set the time of your game or choose unlimited time-mode[CR]-you can set the number of mines[CR]-number of remaining mines and time display during game[CR]-constantly breakable time record[CR]-easy to control: zoom in-and-out with multitouch and scroll with one finger[CR]-single tap to clear a spot, long tap to mark a flag[CR]-smooth and fast gameplay: tap a clear spot with no surrounding mines and neighbours open automatically[CR]-first touch guaranteed not to hit a mine[CR]-listen to your favourite music while playing with Hive Sweeper[CR]-Open feint supported leaderboard and challenging achievements[CR]MULTIPLAYER options:[CR]-play over Bluetooth or Game Center[CR]-adjustable types of board, number of mines and time[CR]-if your game ends you may ask for revenge</plot>
    <genre>Puzzle</genre>
    <videoid>Z35r5vu082w</videoid>
    <boxart1>GvpV69v.jpg</boxart1>
    <snapshot1>HoEcXeU.png</snapshot1>
    <snapshot2>YCF1hr4.png</snapshot2>
    <snapshot3>itiXVGD.png</snapshot3>
  </game>
  <game name="Homerun Hitters (USA, PSP Mini)">
    <description>Homerun Hitters (USA, PSP Mini)</description>
	<groups>PSP Mini</groups>
    <rom name="pspminis/Homerun%20Hitters%20%28USA%29.cso" size="7780134"/>
    <nplayers>2</nplayers>
    <studio>Sony Computer Entertainment</studio>
    <releasedate>22/04/2010</releasedate>
    <plot>Step up to the plate in Homerun Hitters. Play solo or against a friend as you launch fastballs, curveballs, shoots and more! Head out to the ballpark and choose from 4 teams and play up to 9 inning in this fun back to basics baseball game.</plot>
    <genre>Sports</genre>
    <videoid>eaWwx8NpSbc</videoid>
    <boxart1>95p9PSK.png</boxart1>
    <snapshot1>tzcjybs.png</snapshot1>
    <snapshot2>sBqv0jr.png</snapshot2>
  </game>
  <game name="Hotel Mogul (USA, PSP Mini)">
    <description>Hotel Mogul (USA, PSP Mini)</description>
	<groups>PSP Mini</groups>
    <rom name="pspminis/Hotel%20Mogul%20%28USA%29.cso" size="22481910"/>
  </game>
  <game name="Hungry Giraffe (USA, PSP Mini)">
    <description>Hungry Giraffe (USA, PSP Mini)</description>
	<groups>PSP Mini</groups>
    <rom name="pspminis/Hungry%20Giraffe%20%28USA%29.cso" size="23419409"/>
    <nplayers>1</nplayers>
    <studio>Laughing Jackal</studio>
    <releasedate>21/02/2012</releasedate>
    <plot>It sucks when you're hungry. Sometimes you just want to bury your face into a burger, or tear into a taco. Out on the African savannah, a Hungry Giraffe feels your pain.[CR]A 20 foot tall, 1200kg animal like the giraffe needs to chow down on tons of food each day, just to stay alive. But, oh no! All the tastiest leaves have been eaten, while up in the sky endless quantities of snacks, fruit and junk food hover just out of reach![CR]Hungry Giraffe features the world's largest and hungriest even-toed ungulate. Through skilful steering of his neck, you can propel your half-starved giraffe on his twisty-turny upward journey, chomping on strawberries, fries, sandwiches and naughtier treats.[CR]But beware! The skies are also strewn with hazards. Poison, Anvils and non-prescription Drugs also hover up there, ready to send unwary giraffes plummeting to earth.[CR]Hungry Giraffe is by FAR the greatest giraffe-feeding game of all time! Dare you miss out?</plot>
    <genre>Puzzle</genre>
    <boxart1>hm5Sq1q.jpg</boxart1>
    <clearlogo1>FL26Ak8.png</clearlogo1>
  </game>
  <game name="Hysteria Project (USA, PSP Mini)">
    <description>Hysteria Project (USA, PSP Mini)</description>
	<groups>PSP Mini</groups>
    <rom name="pspminis/Hysteria%20Project%20%28USA%29.cso" size="83820897"/>
  </game>
  <game name="Hysteria Project 2 (USA, PSP Mini)">
    <description>Hysteria Project 2 (USA, PSP Mini)</description>
	<groups>PSP Mini</groups>
    <rom name="pspminis/Hysteria%20Project%202%20%28USA%29.cso" size="94166706"/>
  </game>
  <game name="I Kill Zombies (USA, PSP Mini)">
    <description>I Kill Zombies (USA, PSP Mini)</description>
	<groups>PSP Mini</groups>
    <rom name="pspminis/I%20Kill%20Zombies%20%28USA%29.cso" size="45584340"/>
    <studio>Open Emotion Studios</studio>
    <plot>Its time to maim and murder your way to the top of an exiting new game show! I Kill Zombies see's you trapped inside a giant arena fending off the forces of the undead as one of three characters. Do you have what it takes to survive? Who kills zombies? I Kill Zombies!!!</plot>
    <genre>Action</genre>
    <boxart1>QqyYoq6.jpg</boxart1>
  </game>
  <game name="I Must Run! (USA, PSP Mini)">
    <description>I Must Run! (USA, PSP Mini)</description>
	<groups>PSP Mini</groups>
    <rom name="pspminis/I%20Must%20Run%21%20%28USA%29.cso" size="9706966"/>
  </game>
  <game name="Idiot Squad (USA, PSP Mini)">
    <description>Idiot Squad (USA, PSP Mini)</description>
	<groups>PSP Mini</groups>
    <rom name="pspminis/Idiot%20Squad%20%28USA%29.cso" size="17839610"/>
  </game>
  <game name="Ikari III - The Rescue (USA, PSP Mini)">
    <description>Ikari III - The Rescue (USA, PSP Mini)</description>
	<groups>PSP Mini</groups>
    <rom name="pspminis/Ikari%20III%20-%20The%20Rescue%20%28USA%29.cso" size="41641383"/>
  </game>
  <game name="Ikari Warriors (USA, PSP Mini)">
    <description>Ikari Warriors (USA, PSP Mini)</description>
	<groups>PSP Mini</groups>
    <rom name="pspminis/Ikari%20Warriors%20%28USA%29.cso" size="14118895"/>
  </game>
  <game name="Ikari Warriors II - Victory Road (USA, PSP Mini)">
    <description>Ikari Warriors II - Victory Road (USA, PSP Mini)</description>
	<groups>PSP Mini</groups>
    <rom name="pspminis/Ikari%20Warriors%20II%20-%20Victory%20Road%20%28USA%29.cso" size="17568139"/>
    <studio>SNK Playmore USA Corp.</studio>
    <releasedate>22/11/2011</releasedate>
    <plot>Heavy on the action, Ikari Warriors became a favorite both in the arcades and on home consoles. To fuel that frenzy, SNK and Tradewest teamed up again for a sequel, Victory Road, released later that same year.[CR]This time, the Ikari Warriors take on more cosmic foes, battling rock-headed beasts, one-eyed green men and other odd creatures.</plot>
    <genre>Action, Shooter</genre>
    <boxart1>747prOT.jpg</boxart1>
    <clearlogo1>RqF5wTx.png</clearlogo1>
    <boxart2>wkodh6C.png</boxart2>
  </game>
  <game name="Impossible Game, The (USA, PSP Mini)">
    <description>Impossible Game, The (USA, PSP Mini)</description>
	<groups>PSP Mini</groups>
    <rom name="pspminis/Impossible%20Game%2C%20The%20%28USA%29.cso" size="11404159"/>
  </game>
  <game name="Influence (USA, PSP Mini)">
    <description>Influence (USA, PSP Mini)</description>
	<groups>PSP Mini</groups>
    <rom name="pspminis/Influence%20%28USA%29.cso" size="53802944"/>
    <studio>Sony Computer Entertainment</studio>
    <releasedate>22/06/2010</releasedate>
    <plot>Try your hand at INFLUENCE(tm). A new puzzle game where you have the power to clear all obstacles in your way to achieve victory. Move your character across a double sided game board as you use your influence to clear out cubes in as few moves as possible. Flip the stage 180 degrees and and strategize your moves to take out multiple rows and levels in a single turn. How far does your influence extend?</plot>
    <genre>Puzzle</genre>
    <videoid>izXfxJeJH0E</videoid>
    <boxart1>ZWL7X8f.jpg</boxart1>
    <snapshot1>mwY2Bzo.png</snapshot1>
    <boxart2>pOCmxn3.png</boxart2>
    <snapshot2>lJgaE7Y.png</snapshot2>
    <snapshot3>ezi7Lau.png</snapshot3>
  </game>
  <game name="International Snooker (Europe, PSP Mini)">
    <description>International Snooker (Europe, PSP Mini)</description>
	<groups>PSP Mini</groups>
    <rom name="pspminis/International%20Snooker%20%28Europe%29.cso" size="4692714"/>
    <rating>0.75</rating>
    <studio>Big Head Games</studio>
    <releasedate>22/12/2009</releasedate>
    <plot>Quite possibly the most realistic Snooker game to come to any gaming platform, working closely with Michaela Tabb the worlds most famous Snooker and Pool referee Big Head Games have crafted the ultimate cue sports simulation, with easy to pickup and play controls and months of gameplay as you fight through a pro players career.</plot>
    <genre>Sports</genre>
    <boxart1>d9TqRQE.jpg</boxart1>
    <snapshot1>u6yiUzV.png</snapshot1>
    <snapshot2>ynSNm74.png</snapshot2>
  </game>
  <game name="Jane's Hotel (USA, PSP Mini)">
    <description>Jane's Hotel (USA, PSP Mini)</description>
	<groups>PSP Mini</groups>
    <rom name="pspminis/Jane%27s%20Hotel%20%28USA%29.cso" size="24886560"/>
    <studio>Beatshapers Limited</studio>
    <releasedate>14/01/2011</releasedate>
    <plot>You start as a small 2 star hotel owner at the town suburbs and work your way to the top by upgrading accommodations and achieving an excellent reputation. Keep an eye on customer moods and make them happy by serving them fine drinks and dainty meals, or simply offering perfect room service. We will make your stay unforgettable!</plot>
    <genre>Strategy</genre>
    <videoid>ZQmpWA82oqc</videoid>
    <boxart1>I8SGOf0.jpg</boxart1>
    <snapshot1>ihkQLrv.png</snapshot1>
    <snapshot2>vVD4GSo.png</snapshot2>
    <snapshot3>6xClUTu.png</snapshot3>
  </game>
  <game name="Jelly Pops (USA, PSP Mini)">
    <description>Jelly Pops (USA, PSP Mini)</description>
	<groups>PSP Mini</groups>
    <rom name="pspminis/Jelly%20Pops%20%28USA%29.cso" size="10958623"/>
  </game>
  <game name="JellyCar 2 (USA, PSP Mini)">
    <description>JellyCar 2 (USA, PSP Mini)</description>
	<groups>PSP Mini</groups>
    <rom name="pspminis/JellyCar%202%20%28USA%29.cso" size="23246892"/>
  </game>
  <game name="Jetpack Joyride (USA, PSP Mini)">
    <description>Jetpack Joyride (USA, PSP Mini)</description>
	<groups>PSP Mini</groups>
    <rom name="pspminis/Jetpack%20Joyride%20%28USA%29.cso" size="22206623"/>
  </game>
  <game name="Jewel Keepers - Easter Island (USA, PSP Mini)">
    <description>Jewel Keepers - Easter Island (USA, PSP Mini)</description>
	<groups>PSP Mini</groups>
    <rom name="pspminis/Jewel%20Keepers%20-%20Easter%20Island%20%28USA%29.cso" size="17390978"/>
    <studio>Nordcurrent</studio>
    <releasedate>16/11/2010</releasedate>
    <plot>Welcome to Jewel Keepers: Easter Island - an addictive match-three arcade action game with mind-blowing visuals and engaging storyline! This game will keep you entertained for hours, as you travel across Easter Island and help to unveil its mysteries.[CR]More fun from Nordcurrent: - 101-in-1 Games - a collection of 101 games in one app. Frequent chart topper in USA, UK, Australia, and many other countries! - Urbanix - an enhanced version of Xonix and Qix, with new modes of play, new worlds and enemies! - Robin Hood: Return of Richard - help Robin to defeat the villains and restore peace in this action game!</plot>
    <genre>Puzzle</genre>
    <videoid>qiGdsvJ1ATM</videoid>
    <boxart1>sARPepq.jpg</boxart1>
    <snapshot1>AdMqMY6.png</snapshot1>
    <snapshot2>XYc18Pb.png</snapshot2>
    <snapshot3>z5DaxkB.png</snapshot3>
  </game>
  <game name="Kahoots (USA, PSP Mini)">
    <description>Kahoots (USA, PSP Mini)</description>
	<groups>PSP Mini</groups>
    <rom name="pspminis/Kahoots%20%28USA%29.cso" size="25476879"/>
  </game>
  <game name="Kaleidoscope - Interactive Synaesthesia Project (USA, PSP Mini)">
    <description>Kaleidoscope - Interactive Synaesthesia Project (USA, PSP Mini)</description>
	<groups>PSP Mini</groups>
    <rom name="pspminis/Kaleidoscope%20-%20Interactive%20Synaesthesia%20Project%20%28USA%29.cso" size="49214809"/>
    <studio>iSquared Games</studio>
    <releasedate>05/06/2012</releasedate>
    <plot>Kaleidoscope consists of level-paintings, which differ in style and behavior, yet are controlled in a similar fashion with the help of just four buttons. The simplicity of the controls is overcompensated by the rich audio/visual experience presented within the game. Player's responses to a constantly changing environment shall have an impact on both image and audio. This creates an illusion of a player being simultaneously a painter of the current image and a composer of the music heard. In addition to that, each level in Kaleidoscope has a clear defined goal, which opens up doors of an infinite synaesthesia world to the masses.</plot>
    <genre>Action, Shooter</genre>
    <boxart1>qKMTpix.jpg</boxart1>
  </game>
  <game name="Karimogi (USA, PSP Mini)">
    <description>Karimogi (USA, PSP Mini)</description>
	<groups>PSP Mini</groups>
    <rom name="pspminis/Karimogi%20%28USA%29.cso" size="7854285"/>
    <nplayers>1</nplayers>
    <studio>StormBasic</studio>
    <releasedate>18/01/2011</releasedate>
    <plot>Karimogi is an alien that needs you! The situation is critical. Cranes are dropping bricks everywhere and Karimogi needs your help to push them around and put them in order or he will never see his spaceship again. Arrange the bricks into rows and they will then disappear. But be careful, you must stay very alert because any brick could crush you!</plot>
    <genre>Puzzle</genre>
    <boxart1>LULF5EI.jpg</boxart1>
  </game>
  <game name="Karoshi (Europe, PSP Mini)">
    <description>Karoshi (Europe, PSP Mini)</description>
	<groups>PSP Mini</groups>
    <rom name="pspminis/Karoshi%20%28Europe%29.cso" size="10746120"/>
    <studio>YoYo Games</studio>
    <releasedate>06/04/2011</releasedate>
    <plot>Karoshi has been played by millions to date to high acclaim.[CR]We've been taught we need to survive. We need to reach the end, save the princess and be the hero. [CR]That's all well and good, but it's getting boring. Who says it has to be this way?[CR]Mr Karoshi is an overworked Japanese salary man who's had enough and his only goal is to end it all. You control him to work through the fast logic puzzles trying to find hilarious ways to his demise in this highly original puzzle platformer with a twist.[CR]It's not as easy as it sounds!! You need to think cleverly and sometimes 'outside the box' to find a solution. [CR]So forget everything you know so far! Join the millions of people already playing Karoshi and download it on your PSP(tm) today![CR]Features:[CR]* 50 unique levels[CR]*   Dark Humour[CR]*    Collect all the coins[CR]*  Catchy soundtrack by Jake Almond</plot>
    <genre>Action</genre>
    <boxart1>2xVkiTj.jpg</boxart1>
  </game>
  <game name="Knight Fortix 2 (USA, PSP Mini)">
    <description>Knight Fortix 2 (USA, PSP Mini)</description>
	<groups>PSP Mini</groups>
    <rom name="pspminis/Knight%20Fortix%202%20%28USA%29.cso" size="97984678"/>
  </game>
  <game name="L.A. Gridlock (Europe, PSP Mini)">
    <description>L.A. Gridlock (Europe, PSP Mini)</description>
	<groups>PSP Mini</groups>
    <rom name="pspminis/L.A.%20Gridlock%20%28Europe%29.cso" size="23160151"/>
    <studio>Immersive Games Limited</studio>
    <releasedate>11/04/2012</releasedate>
    <plot>Los Angeles is under siege from gangs roaming in vehicles. They attack ordinary citizens mercilessly. The city's Mayor appoints you the City Police Chief. Your brief is to eliminate the thugs and regain control of your city. You will direct and control the forces at your disposal to outwit the enemy. Your mission is to direct car chases in hot pursuit of the criminals using all resources available to you. [CR]Car chases across the streets of Los Angeles! Place police vehicles on the roads of L.A. in order to hunt down the thugs before they escape. Zoom in to watch car chases unfold along the famous streets of L.A. [CR]An action game of strategy and car chases with:[CR]*    4 Famous L.A. locations![CR]*   8 Levels of play![CR]*  17 Cars and bikes to play with![CR]*    60+ Waves of thugs to defeat![CR]*  100s of exploding vehicles!</plot>
    <genre>Strategy</genre>
    <boxart1>t9FuInm.jpg</boxart1>
  </game>
  <game name="Labyrinth (USA, PSP Mini)">
    <description>Labyrinth (USA, PSP Mini)</description>
	<groups>PSP Mini</groups>
    <rom name="pspminis/Labyrinth%20%28USA%29.cso" size="10583189"/>
  </game>
  <game name="Left to Die in Zombhai (Europe, PSP Mini)">
    <description>Left to Die in Zombhai (Europe, PSP Mini)</description>
	<groups>PSP Mini</groups>
    <rom name="pspminis/Left%20to%20Die%20in%20Zombhai%20%28Europe%29.cso" size="22245304"/>
    <studio>iSquared Games</studio>
    <releasedate>31/08/2011</releasedate>
    <plot>Welcome to Zombhai, a city populated by zombies! What will it take you to survive? Featuring a wide range of weapons and locations this game will bring hours of fun.</plot>
    <genre>Shooter</genre>
    <boxart1>xGMqwID.png</boxart1>
  </game>
  <game name="Legend of Kunoichi (USA, PSP Mini)">
    <description>Legend of Kunoichi (USA, PSP Mini)</description>
	<groups>PSP Mini</groups>
    <rom name="pspminis/Legend%20of%20Kunoichi%20%28USA%29.cso" size="6886729"/>
    <studio>Sony Computer Entertainment</studio>
    <releasedate>04/03/2010</releasedate>
    <plot>Play as Mai, a ninja warrior, to defend your Shogun against waves of ninja attackers. Throw hammers to take them out and hold them off as long as you can so your Shogun can escape in this easy-to-play, arcade-style minigame.</plot>
    <genre>Action</genre>
    <videoid>q1nfHpfzLvg</videoid>
    <boxart1>FhhHCwD.jpg</boxart1>
    <snapshot1>1Vu006G.png</snapshot1>
    <snapshot2>hwQ7WqG.png</snapshot2>
    <snapshot3>7djM2R2.png</snapshot3>
  </game>
  <game name="Let's Golf (USA, PSP Mini)">
    <description>Let's Golf (USA, PSP Mini)</description>
	<groups>PSP Mini</groups>
    <rom name="pspminis/Let%27s%20Golf%20%28USA%29.cso" size="53726733"/>
    <studio>Gameloft</studio>
    <releasedate>24/11/2009</releasedate>
    <plot>As the name implies, Let's Golf! is a handheld-golf-game. The game features four fictitious golf courses in Fiji, England, USA and Scotland. The goal is of course to get the ball into the hole with the flag in as less strikes as possible. To make it harder for the players to meet that goal, the courses are littered with obstacles like hills and sand bunkers. In addition the wind decides too where the player's ball lands.[CR]As opposed to real life though, the player can influence the ball's flightpath during the flight by choosing in which direction it spins. This allows to compensate for wind and also for a bad angle at the strike. How hard the player hits the ball is decided by a gauge where the player needs to click at the right moment. The same goes for the angle. Although the game hands the player a club that it thinks fits the situation, he can also choose his own.</plot>
    <genre>Sports</genre>
    <videoid>DjfdVl-godY</videoid>
    <boxart1>mWmFrhr.jpg</boxart1>
    <clearlogo1>56mUKm6.jpg</clearlogo1>
    <snapshot1>RqqBaRn.png</snapshot1>
    <snapshot2>dCWOlXO.png</snapshot2>
    <snapshot3>4skQfFz.png</snapshot3>
  </game>
  <game name="Lock 'n' Chase (USA, PSP Mini)">
    <description>Lock 'n' Chase (USA, PSP Mini)</description>
	<groups>PSP Mini</groups>
    <rom name="pspminis/Lock%20%27n%27%20Chase%20%28USA%29.cso" size="3490283"/>
    <boxart1>PDiGm0Z.png</boxart1>
    <clearlogo1>Ab2kBjb.png</clearlogo1>
  </game>
  <game name="Love Cupid (USA, PSP Mini)">
    <description>Love Cupid (USA, PSP Mini)</description>
	<groups>PSP Mini</groups>
    <rom name="pspminis/Love%20Cupid%20%28USA%29.cso" size="7219542"/>
    <nplayers>2</nplayers>
    <studio>Sony Computer Entertainment</studio>
    <releasedate>11/05/2010</releasedate>
    <plot>Have you ever wondered what it would be like to be Cupid? In Love Cupid it is your job to help couples fall in love by shooting as many hearts as you can with your love arrows. Work together with a friend to collect the fallen hearts and increase the couple's affection by filling up their love meter. But be careful to avoid menaces in your way and corrupted bad hearts. Share the love!</plot>
    <genre>Action</genre>
    <videoid>2jVAkOGjnbI</videoid>
    <boxart1>5W9ZlmN.jpg</boxart1>
    <snapshot1>6u5PqoA.png</snapshot1>
    <boxart2>jdDaZ4s.jpg</boxart2>
    <snapshot2>U28wBGE.png</snapshot2>
    <snapshot3>53Asi4c.png</snapshot3>
  </game>
  <game name="M.O.Z.O.X. Space Salvager (USA, PSP Mini)">
    <description>M.O.Z.O.X. Space Salvager (USA, PSP Mini)</description>
	<groups>PSP Mini</groups>
    <rom name="pspminis/M.O.Z.O.X.%20Space%20Salvager%20%28USA%29.cso" size="31871085"/>
    <studio>Twisted Dragon Media</studio>
    <releasedate>04/01/2011</releasedate>
    <plot>Welcome to Twisted Dragon Media's debut title, M.O.Z.O.X. Space Salvager, are you up for the challenge? A high action arcade style space shooter with infinite levels of play. Use a combination of 4 weapons, and high maneuverability to dodge, weave, and blast your way to the next level. In each level of play you will eliminate enemy ships, weave your way through astroid fields, and outsmart a boss ship. Collect special weapons, shields, debris orbs(points), and multipliers along the way to improve your chances to get a high score. For added challenge the game can be played in "classic mode" as classic side scroller, or get in the middle of all the action in "action mode".</plot>
    <genre>Action</genre>
    <videoid>l9GpaG4lbqg</videoid>
    <boxart1>nvWmvxD.jpg</boxart1>
    <snapshot1>l3nwqTf.png</snapshot1>
    <boxart2>i3fwCCj.png</boxart2>
    <snapshot2>BdJruoh.png</snapshot2>
  </game>
  <game name="MENA Speed (Europe, PSP Mini)">
    <description>MENA Speed (Europe, PSP Mini)</description>
	<groups>PSP Mini</groups>
    <rom name="pspminis/MENA%20Speed%20%28Europe%29.cso" size="35500033"/>
    <studio>Quirkat</studio>
    <releasedate>16/11/2011</releasedate>
    <plot>Are you the MENA Speed champion? Customize and upgrade your car then accept challenges across different terrains. MENA Speed is the first drag race game with tracks in major cities across the Middle East, pumping up your adrenaline with screeching tires and burned rubber across the roads of Dubai, Amman, Kuwait and Cairo. [CR]Enjoy the different power-ups by upgrading your car engine, gearbox, cooling system, and manifold to improve your car's performance; and customize its look with different paint jobs, spoilers and rims; all with a wide range of options.</plot>
    <genre>Racing, Vehicle Simulation</genre>
    <boxart1>8PMcbVZ.jpg</boxart1>
  </game>
  <game name="Mad Blocker Alpha (USA, PSP Mini)">
    <description>Mad Blocker Alpha (USA, PSP Mini)</description>
	<groups>PSP Mini</groups>
    <rom name="pspminis/Mad%20Blocker%20Alpha%20%28USA%29.cso" size="18942106"/>
  </game>
  <game name="Mahjong Artifacts (USA, PSP Mini)">
    <description>Mahjong Artifacts (USA, PSP Mini)</description>
	<groups>PSP Mini</groups>
    <rom name="pspminis/Mahjong%20Artifacts%20%28USA%29.cso" size="38152462"/>
    <studio>G5 Entertainment AB</studio>
    <releasedate>15/06/2010</releasedate>
    <plot>Escape from the rush of modern life into immersive ancient atmosphere of Mahjongg Artifacts! This new fan-favorite comes with three game play modes which take you through five exotic cultures. It also comes with innovative game play twists, like Special Tiles that allow you to use new strategies to clear layouts, Bonuses for skillful play and Trophies for special accomplishments. Story Mode features epic quest for lost relics, in Classic mode you can choose the layout you want to play, and in the breathtaking Endless mode you remove tiles from an ever-rising tower of game pieces. [CR]- Story mode featuring 25 layouts[CR]- Classic mode with 100 layouts[CR]- Innovative Endless mode[CR]- 27 gorgeous backgrounds[CR]- Five beautifully drawn tilesets[CR]- Music tracks inspired by ancient cultures[CR]- Manual smooth zoom in/out and auto-zoom option [CR]The wealth of gameplay options, elegant new tile sets and easy-to-learn gameplay will earn Mahjonggg Artifacts a permanent place in your collection!</plot>
    <genre>Puzzle</genre>
    <videoid>ffxprW__aCk</videoid>
    <boxart1>1LTXq1E.jpg</boxart1>
    <snapshot1>jy1R9Id.png</snapshot1>
    <snapshot2>Gcle7yk.png</snapshot2>
  </game>
  <game name="Mahjong Artifacts - Chapter 2 (USA, PSP Mini)">
    <description>Mahjong Artifacts - Chapter 2 (USA, PSP Mini)</description>
	<groups>PSP Mini</groups>
    <rom name="pspminis/Mahjong%20Artifacts%20-%20Chapter%202%20%28USA%29.cso" size="21592008"/>
    <studio>G5 Entertainment AB</studio>
    <releasedate>22/10/2009</releasedate>
    <plot>Mahjongg Artifacts(r): Chapter 2 is highly addictive tile-matching game that takes mahjong games in an exciting new direction! Pair up tiles to dismantle hundreds of layouts. Utilize a selection of ground-breaking powerups, earn trophies, and enjoy the game`s beautiful graphics and rich audio. There's more than enough tile-matching action in Mahjongg Artifacts(r) 2 to have fun for months![CR]* Epic Quest Mode[CR]* Additional 99 levels in Classic Mode[CR]* Thrilling Endless Mode[CR]* Five Tile Sets[CR]* Ground-breaking Powerups[CR]* Gorgeous graphics and rich audio</plot>
    <genre>Puzzle</genre>
    <videoid>MA3BL-4dlpM</videoid>
    <boxart1>ETZmrZP.jpg</boxart1>
    <snapshot1>NDOEGQj.png</snapshot1>
    <snapshot2>j9by1Ri.png</snapshot2>
  </game>
  <game name="Mahjong Solitaire (USA, PSP Mini)">
    <description>Mahjong Solitaire (USA, PSP Mini)</description>
	<groups>PSP Mini</groups>
    <rom name="pspminis/Mahjong%20Solitaire%20%28USA%29.cso" size="10559390"/>
    <studio>Agetec</studio>
    <releasedate>29/06/2010</releasedate>
    <plot>Mahjong Solitaire is fun and simple game. Players remove matching pairs of tiles from an organized layering of tiles, trying to remove as many tiles as possible and as fast as they can.[CR]You are presented with 144 mahjong tiles arranged in an organized, three-dimensional heap. The goal is to match open pairs of identical tiles and remove them from the board, exposing the tiles under them for play. The game is finished when all pairs of tiles have been removed from the board or when there are no exposed pairs remaining, or when time runs out!</plot>
    <genre>Puzzle</genre>
    <videoid>FAB2k0mD5dI</videoid>
    <boxart1>Emk6qA8.jpg</boxart1>
    <snapshot1>JRl5FqG.png</snapshot1>
    <snapshot2>9VnbrnU.png</snapshot2>
    <snapshot3>lQlmd8Q.png</snapshot3>
  </game>
  <game name="Manic Monkey Mayhem (USA, PSP Mini)">
    <description>Manic Monkey Mayhem (USA, PSP Mini)</description>
	<groups>PSP Mini</groups>
    <rom name="pspminis/Manic%20Monkey%20Mayhem%20%28USA%29.cso" size="15828080"/>
    <studio>Code Monkeys</studio>
    <releasedate>25/03/2010</releasedate>
    <plot>As with most fights, nobody really knows where, how or when this rivalry started, but this group of monkeys have not stopped battling for as long as they can remember. Their chosen fighting style is the ancient art of Banana Flinging and although their manic screams of rage may insinuate uncontrolled anger, they are in fact highly accurate and adept banana flingers.[CR]Controlling one of eight monkeys you will compete in battle with a selection of others across eight different themed landscapes with several different game modes to excel in.[CR]All the monkeys will be positioned on small podiums each separated from their neighbours. Use your skills in banana flinging to knock the other players off their podiums, which will result in them losing a life. In some game modes there are crates separating each monkey which can be broken to access power-ups and ammunition, or to simply open up a clear path to launch an attack on your opponents.</plot>
    <genre>Action</genre>
    <videoid>g1YSEsom6nE</videoid>
    <boxart1>3BpPfh4.jpg</boxart1>
    <snapshot1>eVAM63P.png</snapshot1>
    <boxart2>Gxr37Lf.jpg</boxart2>
    <snapshot2>f9rsBps.png</snapshot2>
    <snapshot3>VYNqmcw.png</snapshot3>
  </game>
  <game name="Marbians, The (USA, PSP Mini)">
    <description>Marbians, The (USA, PSP Mini)</description>
	<groups>PSP Mini</groups>
    <rom name="pspminis/Marbians%2C%20The%20%28USA%29.cso" size="11209210"/>
    <studio>Nordisk Film Interactive</studio>
    <releasedate>13/12/2011</releasedate>
    <plot>On a mission to collect precious moon rocks, the adorable aliens, the Marbians, have crash landed in a dusty attic in New Mexico left untouched since the '40s. Now you must help them find their way back to their UFO and gather as many moon rocks as possible on your way. The Marbians is a fun physics-based puzzle adventure that offers 72 levels of tricky timing, peculiar precision and tremendous brain teasing for the whole family.</plot>
    <genre>Puzzle</genre>
    <boxart1>zcY9kEW.png</boxart1>
    <clearlogo1>7I51LDF.png</clearlogo1>
  </game>
  <game name="Marvin's Maze (USA, PSP Mini)">
    <description>Marvin's Maze (USA, PSP Mini)</description>
	<groups>PSP Mini</groups>
    <rom name="pspminis/Marvin%27s%20Maze%20%28USA%29.cso" size="3856105"/>
    <boxart1>OEN7RRq.png</boxart1>
    <clearlogo1>gL3ZPgs.png</clearlogo1>
  </game>
  <game name="Me Monstar - Hear Me Roar! (USA, PSP Mini)">
    <description>Me Monstar - Hear Me Roar! (USA, PSP Mini)</description>
	<groups>PSP Mini</groups>
    <rom name="pspminis/Me%20Monstar%20-%20Hear%20Me%20Roar%21%20%28USA%29.cso" size="40243500"/>
  </game>
  <game name="Mecho Wars (USA, PSP Mini)">
    <description>Mecho Wars (USA, PSP Mini)</description>
	<groups>PSP Mini</groups>
    <rom name="pspminis/Mecho%20Wars%20%28USA%29.cso" size="22453781"/>
  </game>
  <game name="Metara (Europe, PSP Mini)">
    <description>Metara (Europe, PSP Mini)</description>
	<groups>PSP Mini</groups>
    <rom name="pspminis/Metara%20%28Europe%29.cso" size="35412604"/>
    <studio>PlaygroundSquad</studio>
    <releasedate>19/01/2011</releasedate>
    <plot>Use your ship to build towers, defend your base and push the enemy back.[CR]Your ship got three different stances, four types of weapons and the ability to build turrets.[CR]Use these functions to conquer the variety of levels.[CR]The game contains different in-game objectives for each level, spread out on four different planets.[CR]Your main objective is to push the enemy back and defend the planet you are on through different hazardous stages.</plot>
    <genre>Action, Shooter</genre>
    <boxart1>iRFDpHo.jpg</boxart1>
  </game>
  <game name="Mighty Flip Champs! DX (USA, PSP Mini)">
    <description>Mighty Flip Champs! DX (USA, PSP Mini)</description>
	<groups>PSP Mini</groups>
    <rom name="pspminis/Mighty%20Flip%20Champs%21%20DX%20%28USA%29.cso" size="26766923"/>
  </game>
  <game name="MiniSquadron (USA, PSP Mini)">
    <description>MiniSquadron (USA, PSP Mini)</description>
	<groups>PSP Mini</groups>
    <rom name="pspminis/MiniSquadron%20%28USA%29.cso" size="30464426"/>
    <studio>Grip Digital</studio>
    <releasedate>22/03/2011</releasedate>
    <plot>MiniSquadron is a side scrolling shooter where the player takes control of a tiny little plane in dogfights against wave after wave of other similar little planes. Gameplay is similar to games like Sopwith and Triplane Turmoil. The player can move freely around in all directions and do various aerobatic manoeuvres such as loops, turns and rolls. In addition to shooting at the enemy planes the player also has avoid crashing. Fly to high and the plane begins to stall and to avoid crashing into the ground the player needs to turn around the nose and dive to regain control. The player can pick up various power ups that fall from the sky. These include extra health, increased speed and various special attacks such as airstrikes and very large laser beams.[CR]The game consists of eight levels each with twelve waves of enemy attacks. At the start the player only has one simple plane available put a further 55 can be unlocked through out the game. Each plane not only has its own look but differs in characteristics. Some planes are quick but weak while others might be bigger in size and have different weaponry. The player will come across many different enemies from simple planes similar to his own to animals and UFO's. Most are in the air but there are also some ground targets that need to be taken down.[CR]In addition to the wave after wave mode called classic there is also a survival mode and a multiplayer mode. Survival is a mode without an end. The player simple has to stay alive as long possible. The multiplayer is for two players and is played over a wi-fi network.</plot>
    <genre>Action</genre>
    <videoid>dFPn1P0QBMA</videoid>
    <boxart1>yIl9AWV.jpg</boxart1>
    <snapshot1>DAekHgj.png</snapshot1>
    <snapshot2>ufGtUV2.png</snapshot2>
  </game>
  <game name="Monochrome Racing (USA, PSP Mini)">
    <description>Monochrome Racing (USA, PSP Mini)</description>
	<groups>PSP Mini</groups>
    <rom name="pspminis/Monochrome%20Racing%20%28USA%29.cso" size="20253698"/>
    <studio>Nordcurrent UAB</studio>
    <releasedate>02/08/2011</releasedate>
    <plot>Screeching tires, the smell of burned rubber, the rush of adrenaline and enemies that are left in the dust-these are the emotions that drive real racers. However there is much more than this in the world of Monochrome Racing-there is the passion for color! Color is everything here, it is what you strive for, in the world where everything is in black and white. Color is your fuel, color gives you speed, color makes you stronger and ultimately makes you the true leader of the monochrome racing world.[CR]- More than 80 tracks to complete[CR]- More than 10 cars to choose from and upgrade[CR]- Numerous power ups and bonuses that makes your vehicle stronger and your enemies weaker[CR]- Mysterious monochrome world to immerse</plot>
    <genre>Racing</genre>
    <boxart1>AxKvGDK.jpg</boxart1>
  </game>
  <game name="Monopoly (USA, PSP Mini)">
    <description>Monopoly (USA, PSP Mini)</description>
	<groups>PSP Mini</groups>
    <rom name="pspminis/Monopoly%20%28USA%29.cso" size="62677270"/>
    <nplayers>4</nplayers>
    <studio>Electronic Arts</studio>
    <releasedate>15/04/2010</releasedate>
    <plot>The Monopoly video games promise a fresh take on the timeless classic with accessible gameplay for players of all ages and skill levels. The all-new digital gaming edition brings a party twist and features 4-player simultaneous play, ensuring that everyone is engaged and allowing the whole family to get involved in the fun and play together. Faster gameplay eliminates downtime freeing up players to wheel and deal their way through some of the most recognizable cities and landmarks from around the world. Families can fill up their passports as they try to unlock new and never-before-seen game boards or challenge each other to fun interactive mini-games like breaking out of the jail cell and running away with all the loot. Play in offline single or multi-player mode and compete to own it all and win!</plot>
    <genre>Board Game</genre>
    <videoid>A1yhXo4jy9c</videoid>
    <boxart1>2I2ZLL9.jpg</boxart1>
    <clearlogo1>6R7ksC3.png</clearlogo1>
  </game>
  <game name="Monsters (Probably) Stole My Princess (USA, PSP Mini)">
    <description>Monsters (Probably) Stole My Princess (USA, PSP Mini)</description>
	<groups>PSP Mini</groups>
    <rom name="pspminis/Monsters%20%28Probably%29%20Stole%20My%20Princess%20%28USA%29.cso" size="104514918"/>
  </game>
  <game name="Mr. Hat and the Magic Cube (Europe, PSP Mini)">
    <description>Mr. Hat and the Magic Cube (Europe, PSP Mini)</description>
	<groups>PSP Mini</groups>
    <rom name="pspminis/Mr.%20Hat%20and%20the%20Magic%20Cube%20%28Europe%29.cso" size="59452451"/>
    <studio>Bravo Game Studios SL</studio>
    <releasedate>30/03/2011</releasedate>
    <plot>Join Mr Hat and his friends in a wonderful adventure to reunite the stolen pieces of his cube and get back home. [CR]Along the way your child will learn the basics in: vocabulary, spelling, counting, memory, and coordination. All introduced with beautiful graphics, animations and videos that will keep you child (and you) entertained for hours! [CR]Featuring [CR]- 5 different learning zones, teaching the basics in vocabulary, spelling, counting, memory, and coordination. [CR]- Progressive learning curve to retain captivation [CR]- Beautiful 3d graphics, animations and videos to maximise engagement [CR]- Designed by experts in child behavior</plot>
    <genre>Education</genre>
    <boxart1>s8Li4en.jpg</boxart1>
  </game>
  <game name="Music Quiz (USA, PSP Mini)">
    <description>Music Quiz (USA, PSP Mini)</description>
	<groups>PSP Mini</groups>
    <rom name="pspminis/Music%20Quiz%20%28USA%29.cso" size="34775183"/>
  </game>
  <game name="Mystery of the Crystal Portal, The (USA, PSP Mini)">
    <description>Mystery of the Crystal Portal, The (USA, PSP Mini)</description>
	<groups>PSP Mini</groups>
    <rom name="pspminis/Mystery%20of%20the%20Crystal%20Portal%2C%20The%20%28USA%29.cso" size="84498617"/>
    <studio>G5 Entertainment AB</studio>
    <releasedate>06/07/2010</releasedate>
    <plot>Journalist Nicole Rankvist receives a letter from Robert, her archaeologist father, describing the discovery of the key for a powerful artifact called the Crystal Portal. When he goes missing, Nicole must find the scattered pieces of the key around the world.[CR]The Mystery of the Crystal Portal is a hidden object that replaces the traditional list of objects names with a different gameplay mechanic. The player has to click on certain objects in the scenery that open a circle around it with photographs of items that must be found and dragged to it. After picking all the required stuff, some of these container objects disappear to reveal a key item underneath them.[CR]Some of the objects have to be collected in one screen to be used in another place (for example, finding matches outside the house to light a fireplace inside). At the end of each stage/location there's a unique logic puzzle game to be solved, involving some of the objects that the player picked up.</plot>
    <genre>Adventure</genre>
    <boxart1>HB47TwN.jpg</boxart1>
  </game>
  <game name="Next Space, The (USA, PSP Mini)">
    <description>Next Space, The (USA, PSP Mini)</description>
	<groups>PSP Mini</groups>
    <rom name="pspminis/Next%20Space%2C%20The%20%28USA%29.cso" size="39792384"/>
    <studio>SNK Playmore Corporation</studio>
    <plot>Pilot a spaceship, collect various speed and weapon items to take down a multitude of enemies, and restore peace to the galaxy in this vertical scrolling shooter released by SNK in 1989.</plot>
    <genre>Action, Shooter</genre>
    <boxart1>rt8zIoA.jpg</boxart1>
  </game>
  <game name="Ninjamurai (USA, PSP Mini)">
    <description>Ninjamurai (USA, PSP Mini)</description>
	<groups>PSP Mini</groups>
    <rom name="pspminis/Ninjamurai%20%28USA%29.cso" size="29743942"/>
    <studio>Open Emotion Studios</studio>
    <releasedate>05/07/2011</releasedate>
    <plot>Takezou Nishimura is the offspring of a Ninja and Samurai and in his world he is seen as an aberration. He is known as "The Ninjamurai." Takezou must journey throughout the lands seeking out members of the evil Black Armor Corporation who are responsible for atrocities against his family and clan. Ninjamurai is an action platformer that contains over 20 levels, huge boss fights, various modes and difficulties, unlockable costumes and extra awards and statistics.</plot>
    <genre>Action</genre>
    <boxart1>l1bAI9b.jpg</boxart1>
  </game>
  <game name="Nocturnal (Europe, PSP Mini)">
    <description>Nocturnal (Europe, PSP Mini)</description>
	<groups>PSP Mini</groups>
    <rom name="pspminis/Nocturnal%20%28Europe%29.cso" size="68661996"/>
  </game>
  <game name="Nom Nation (Europe, PSP Mini)">
    <description>Nom Nation (Europe, PSP Mini)</description>
	<groups>PSP Mini</groups>
    <rom name="pspminis/Nom%20Nation%20%28Europe%29.cso" size="26315855"/>
    <studio>Playerthree</studio>
    <releasedate>16/05/2012</releasedate>
    <plot>Nom Nation is a delicious platform adventure.[CR]You play as Chef on a mission to rescue the Book of Nom from Jabber the Gut, head of the McFatass Corporation. Only the Noms can help you succeed. Harnessing their hidden powers is the key ingredient. [CR]- 11 levels[CR]- 5 nutritious worlds[CR]- A multitude of fun power-ups[CR]Take farting to a whole new level!</plot>
    <genre>Platform, Puzzle</genre>
    <boxart1>MMj9QPD.jpg</boxart1>
  </game>
  <game name="NormalTanks (USA, PSP Mini)">
    <description>NormalTanks (USA, PSP Mini)</description>
	<groups>PSP Mini</groups>
    <rom name="pspminis/NormalTanks%20%28USA%29.cso" size="13080855"/>
    <studio>Beatshapers</studio>
    <releasedate>29/04/2010</releasedate>
    <plot>NormalTanks is a fast-paced multi-directional top-down arcade shooter featuring classic run'n'gun gameplay with 3 difficulty settings. At the 8 challenging, dynamic and hazardous environments, inside the enemy bases or forests and mountains, you have to choose your battle tactics carefully to survive! [CR]Over the 30 dangerous enemies types on your heroic way, including various tanks, machines and helicopters, robots and biomechanical creatures, pillboxes and missile sites. Crash, kill and destroy them all to move forward and with help of the red star power-ups, which upgrades your tank abilities: cannon, machine gun, shield and speed. [CR]Some levels transform you to tiny mine-bot to stealth pass near the enemies and deactivate energy fields or to giant walking robot, which demolish everything on his way to the alien's hive! [CR]Try to finish the game without lost any life and save the universe the classic, old school arcade way!</plot>
    <genre>Action</genre>
    <boxart1>oszLAfX.jpg</boxart1>
  </game>
  <game name="Nova (USA, PSP Mini)">
    <description>Nova (USA, PSP Mini)</description>
	<groups>PSP Mini</groups>
    <rom name="pspminis/Nova%20%28USA%29.cso" size="88107312"/>
  </game>
  <game name="Numba (Europe, PSP Mini)">
    <description>Numba (Europe, PSP Mini)</description>
	<groups>PSP Mini</groups>
    <rom name="pspminis/Numba%20%28Europe%29.cso" size="20298242"/>
  </game>
  <game name="OMG-Z (USA, PSP Mini)">
    <description>OMG-Z (USA, PSP Mini)</description>
	<groups>PSP Mini</groups>
    <rom name="pspminis/OMG-Z%20%28USA%29.cso" size="36961527"/>
    <rating>3.00</rating>
    <nplayers>1</nplayers>
    <studio>Laughing Jackal</studio>
    <releasedate>17/08/2011</releasedate>
    <plot>Alert! Alert! OMG-Z! The City of Redfield has been hit by an outbreak of exploding zombies! For cool and unimportant reasons these suckers literally explode when shot, showering their zombie brethren with gore and causing chain reactions of showering zombie gibs with just a single bullet! Armed with this knowledge (and bullets coated in a zombie-exploding pathogen) your elite unit is dispatched to the epicentre of the outbreak. Your mission? Succeed where the police and army failed and clean up the city![CR]For reasons that aren't important right now, all but one of your team is killed before arriving at the outbreak's epicentre, leaving YOU to deal with thousands of zombies ALONE. Use your chain reaction skills to explore 81 waves of zombie hell across 32 environments. Earn 324 shiny medals and cold hard cash, and use it to buy 70 different upgrades all designed to MAKE ZOMBIES EXPLODE!</plot>
    <genre>Strategy</genre>
    <boxart1>6mOHbnX.png</boxart1>
  </game>
  <game name="One Epic Game (USA, PSP Mini)">
    <description>One Epic Game (USA, PSP Mini)</description>
	<groups>PSP Mini</groups>
    <rom name="pspminis/One%20Epic%20Game%20%28USA%29.cso" size="23333609"/>
    <nplayers>1</nplayers>
    <studio>Grip Games</studio>
    <releasedate>22/07/2011</releasedate>
    <plot>One Epic Game is an Infinity Runner video game developed by Czech company Grip Games. The game was released in 2011 for PlayStation 3, PlayStation Vita, PlayStation Portable, IOS and Android. The game is parody for multiple video game and movie cliches.[CR]The player controls an infinity running character. He can only jump or shoot. Jumping helps him avoid obstacles and traps while shooting kills enemies. Player can also kill enemies by jumping on their heads. There are multiple game modes in game. The main is story mode. There are missions with consistent story. There is a task in every mission (for example getting through 1000 metres, getting to finish with only one life or kill certain numbers of enemies). Every mission is set in one of five worlds - Zombie Outbreak, Nuclear Wasteland, World War II, Alien Invasion and Fantasy Kingdom. Story is told by comix scenes.[CR]Another mode is Free Run. In this mode layer chooses a World and then tries to make the highest possible score. [CR]The last mode is Challenges. Player chooses his task there and then he tries to fulfil it. He can also choose difficulty. For the lowest difficulty he gains bronze medal while for the hardest he gains gold medal. [CR]There are multiple weapons in game. Player starts with Pistol. He can also take another weapon on his way, for example Shotgun, Machine gun, Rocket launcher, Flamethrower or Laser. Every weapon behaves differently. When a player is hurt he loses his gained weapon and has to fight with a pistol again. Player can always carry only one weapon. Player can also take Heart, that gives him life, or jetpack, that allows him to fly. There is a checkpoint at every 1000 metres.</plot>
    <genre>Platform</genre>
    <boxart1>ZLJdKQ3.jpg</boxart1>
    <clearlogo1>5gFmY4E.png</clearlogo1>
    <snapshot1>Kn0nIVV.jpg</snapshot1>
  </game>
  <game name="One Two Boat Racing (USA, PSP Mini)">
    <description>One Two Boat Racing (USA, PSP Mini)</description>
	<groups>PSP Mini</groups>
    <rom name="pspminis/One%20Two%20Boat%20Racing%20%28USA%29.cso" size="5967683"/>
    <studio>Sony Computer Entertainment Inc.</studio>
    <releasedate>04/05/2010</releasedate>
    <plot>Welcome to the wet wild world of One Two Boat Racing, where you need to use your reflexes and speed to stay in the lead, beat the competition, and be the first to reach the finish line. But there is more to winning than just speed. You'll need to evade pylons, blow by rocks, and make sure to avoid sludge or face wasting precious seconds and losing the race.</plot>
    <genre>Racing</genre>
    <boxart1>ND4JfLi.jpg</boxart1>
  </game>
  <game name="Orbit (USA, PSP Mini)">
    <description>Orbit (USA, PSP Mini)</description>
	<groups>PSP Mini</groups>
    <rom name="pspminis/Orbit%20%28USA%29.cso" size="36806854"/>
  </game>
  <game name="Ozma Wars (USA, PSP Mini)">
    <description>Ozma Wars (USA, PSP Mini)</description>
	<groups>PSP Mini</groups>
    <rom name="pspminis/Ozma%20Wars%20%28USA%29.cso" size="2985466"/>
  </game>
  <game name="Pac-Man Championship Edition (USA, PSP Mini)">
    <description>Pac-Man Championship Edition (USA, PSP Mini)</description>
	<groups>PSP Mini</groups>
    <rom name="pspminis/Pac-Man%20Championship%20Edition%20%28USA%29.cso" size="23964027"/>
    <studio>Namco Bandai Games America</studio>
    <releasedate>01/02/2011</releasedate>
    <plot>Pac-Man: Championship Edition is a sequel, by the same developer Toru Iwatani, done in the style of the original classic. As before, you are Pac-Man and you are in a maze with dots, power pellets and hosts. The object is to eat the dots and avoid the ghosts, unless you eat a power pellet, which gives you the ability to eat the ghosts for a few seconds.[CR]What's new here is many different mazes and modes. This is designed from the ground up as a console game, so some arcade traditions are lost. The object is no longer to try to survive/get a high score without losing quarters, but to get a high score in a set time limit. You do still have a set number of lives, which makes your time end early if you lose all them.[CR]Unlike the original or its prodigy, Championship Edition isn't broken into distinct levels. Once you clear one side of the maze, a fruit appears on the other side. Eating the fruit regenerates the empty half with new walls, dots, power pellets, etc and increases the game speed.[CR]The iPhone version of the game adds two additional modes. In "Mission Mode", you must clear a specific goal set by the game at the beginning of play (such as eating two apples, or eating eight ghosts consecutively). In "Challenge Mode", you must aim to achieve the top score for each course, but this time the ghosts have been sped up so that they are initially much faster.[CR]The look is a bright neon which evokes the classic Pac-Man but takes advantage of nearly 30 years of increased computer power.</plot>
    <genre>Action</genre>
    <boxart1>iL9SGAy.jpg</boxart1>
  </game>
  <game name="Pachisi (Europe, PSP Mini)">
    <description>Pachisi (Europe, PSP Mini)</description>
	<groups>PSP Mini</groups>
    <rom name="pspminis/Pachisi%20%28Europe%29.cso" size="32190234"/>
    <studio>Sony Computer Entertainment Europe</studio>
    <releasedate>03/12/2009</releasedate>
    <plot>The game is played on a board shaped like a symmetrical cross. The big square in the center of the board called as "Charkoni" is the starting and finishing position of the gotis or pawns. Player's objective is to move all the gotis around the board and then back to charkoni before other player does the same. A players' pieces move around the board based upon the outcome of the 'Passa', a rectangular dice used as an element of chance.</plot>
    <genre>Board Game</genre>
    <boxart1>96UuyU9.jpg</boxart1>
  </game>
  <game name="Pallurikio (USA, PSP Mini)">
    <description>Pallurikio (USA, PSP Mini)</description>
	<groups>PSP Mini</groups>
    <rom name="pspminis/Pallurikio%20%28USA%29.cso" size="22409550"/>
  </game>
  <game name="Panda Craze (USA, PSP Mini)">
    <description>Panda Craze (USA, PSP Mini)</description>
	<groups>PSP Mini</groups>
    <rom name="pspminis/Panda%20Craze%20%28USA%29.cso" size="10899637"/>
    <studio>Tikgames</studio>
    <releasedate>15/09/2010</releasedate>
    <plot>Dig, drill, and blast your way through ice and rock in this epic puzzle adventure![CR]Guide Tik-Ling the panda through caves, forests, mountains, and deserts on the way to her home, the bamboo forest. The concept is simple: collect all of the magical lanterns in each level to unlock a magic portal to the next level. Actually getting to the lanterns without getting stuck in the process, however, is not so simple! Dig, drill, and blast your way through ice and rock in this epic puzzle adventure!</plot>
    <genre>Platform, Puzzle</genre>
    <boxart1>WF156N8.jpg</boxart1>
  </game>
  <game name="Paper Wars - Cannon Fodder (USA, PSP Mini)">
    <description>Paper Wars - Cannon Fodder (USA, PSP Mini)</description>
	<groups>PSP Mini</groups>
    <rom name="pspminis/Paper%20Wars%20-%20Cannon%20Fodder%20%28USA%29.cso" size="11859440"/>
    <studio>iFun4all</studio>
    <releasedate>06/10/2010</releasedate>
    <plot>Paper Wars Cannon Fodder is a tower defense video game developed by several Polish and Hungarian outsourced programmers of iFun4all team, in the cheapest way you can imagine. What's the so-called brilliant goal of the game? You would never guess. It is about destroying all enemies! The same well-known thrilling story, hordes of cold-blooded enemies trying to survive the Armageddon! There are some additional goals to be achieved in different missions and levels - watch your right! The game can be played by up to four players in co-op mode. If you think you need some extraordinary power-ups, you can get them during three campaigns: Classic, Winter Assault and Cyber Wars. ,,Hand made" graphics, soviet style military music and annoying sound effects make players eager to complete each level and collect medals for their outstanding efforts.</plot>
    <genre>Strategy</genre>
    <boxart1>oUU2yUG.jpg</boxart1>
  </game>
  <game name="Phase Shift - Threats Beyond the Network (Asia, PSP Mini)">
    <description>Phase Shift - Threats Beyond the Network (Asia, PSP Mini)</description>
	<groups>PSP Mini</groups>
    <rom name="pspminis/Phase%20Shift%20-%20Threats%20Beyond%20the%20Network%20%28Asia%29.cso" size="38716945"/>
    <studio>Dark Potato Studios</studio>
    <releasedate>07/08/2013</releasedate>
    <plot>Phase Shift follows the story of Xargis, a genius programmer fighting against cyber terrorism in the future.[CR]Defeat your enemies and protect The Network![CR]Visually represented as a "Ship Battle", Phase Shift presents a unique 2D Arcade Shooter game with a warp mechanic, providing a vibrant and dynamic game-play.</plot>
    <genre>Shooter</genre>
    <boxart1>pGKEWFC.jpg</boxart1>
  </game>
  <game name="Pile Up! Bakery (USA, PSP Mini)">
    <description>Pile Up! Bakery (USA, PSP Mini)</description>
	<groups>PSP Mini</groups>
    <rom name="pspminis/Pile%20Up%21%20Bakery%20%28USA%29.cso" size="6642590"/>
    <nplayers>2</nplayers>
    <studio>Sony Computer Entertainment Inc.</studio>
    <releasedate>29/04/2010</releasedate>
    <plot>Can you make a mountain out of sweets and candies? Drop cakes, pies, and more from your assembly line and pile them up to the sky! You are up against the clock so you need to place each sweet in just the right spot to help build your tower of treats as high as possible. Things start simple but you will soon find it's not quite as easy as taking candy from a baby.</plot>
    <genre>Action</genre>
    <boxart1>HIFTqG5.jpg</boxart1>
  </game>
  <game name="Pinball Dreams (USA, PSP Mini)">
    <description>Pinball Dreams (USA, PSP Mini)</description>
	<groups>PSP Mini</groups>
    <rom name="pspminis/Pinball%20Dreams%20%28USA%29.cso" size="5145641"/>
  </game>
  <game name="Pinball Duel (USA, PSP Mini)">
    <description>Pinball Duel (USA, PSP Mini)</description>
	<groups>PSP Mini</groups>
    <rom name="pspminis/Pinball%20Duel%20%28USA%29.cso" size="7948329"/>
    <nplayers>2</nplayers>
    <studio>Sony Computer Entertainment Inc.</studio>
    <releasedate>29/04/2010</releasedate>
    <plot>Face off against the computer or a friend in the crazy frenetic world of double sided Pinball Duel. With two balls being catapulted around the pinball arena, nail the timing and use your flippers to smack them at just the right angle. Tag the bonus target marks to win big prizes, unleash more balls and work to reach the coveted 10,000 point mark. Trying to catch up, but running out of luck, be devious and tilt the board to gain an advantage!</plot>
    <genre>Action</genre>
    <boxart1>VpDwubq.jpg</boxart1>
  </game>
  <game name="Pinball Fantasies (USA, PSP Mini)">
    <description>Pinball Fantasies (USA, PSP Mini)</description>
	<groups>PSP Mini</groups>
    <rom name="pspminis/Pinball%20Fantasies%20%28USA%29.cso" size="6274449"/>
  </game>
  <game name="Pipe Madness (USA, PSP Mini)">
    <description>Pipe Madness (USA, PSP Mini)</description>
	<groups>PSP Mini</groups>
    <rom name="pspminis/Pipe%20Madness%20%28USA%29.cso" size="8214844"/>
    <nplayers>1</nplayers>
    <studio>The Bearded Ladies Consulting</studio>
    <releasedate>18/01/2011</releasedate>
    <plot>Put together some pipes -- pronto! In Pipe Madness, you must rush to complete your pipeline before the liquid catches up with you or all of your hard work will be ruined. Combat the flowing liquid over endless levels and reach that unbeatable high score. Maximize your bonuses by building intricate pipe networks.</plot>
    <genre>Puzzle</genre>
    <boxart1>KZ0g0CM.jpg</boxart1>
  </game>
  <game name="Pix'n Love Rush (USA, PSP Mini)">
    <description>Pix'n Love Rush (USA, PSP Mini)</description>
	<groups>PSP Mini</groups>
    <rom name="pspminis/Pix%27n%20Love%20Rush%20%28USA%29.cso" size="13445151"/>
  </game>
  <game name="Piyotama (Europe, PSP Mini)">
    <description>Piyotama (Europe, PSP Mini)</description>
	<groups>PSP Mini</groups>
    <rom name="pspminis/Piyotama%20%28Europe%29.cso" size="29240336"/>
  </game>
  <game name="Prehistoric Isle (USA, PSP Mini)">
    <description>Prehistoric Isle (USA, PSP Mini)</description>
	<groups>PSP Mini</groups>
    <rom name="pspminis/Prehistoric%20Isle%20%28USA%29.cso" size="28513325"/>
  </game>
  <game name="Prisoners of War (USA, PSP Mini)">
    <description>Prisoners of War (USA, PSP Mini)</description>
	<groups>PSP Mini</groups>
    <rom name="pspminis/Prisoners%20of%20War%20%28USA%29.cso" size="40115369"/>
  </game>
  <game name="Psycho Soldier (USA, PSP Mini)">
    <description>Psycho Soldier (USA, PSP Mini)</description>
	<groups>PSP Mini</groups>
    <rom name="pspminis/Psycho%20Soldier%20%28USA%29.cso" size="16324124"/>
  </game>
  <game name="Puzzle Scape (Europe, PSP Mini)">
    <description>Puzzle Scape (Europe, PSP Mini)</description>
	<groups>PSP Mini</groups>
    <rom name="pspminis/Puzzle%20Scape%20%28Europe%29.cso" size="93842937"/>
    <gamefaqs_url>http://www.gamefaqs.com/psp/936775-puzzle-scape</gamefaqs_url>
    <studio>Got Game Entertainment</studio>
    <releasedate>06/06/2007</releasedate>
    <plot>Puzzle Scape is a block busting game where the player arranges same colored blocks to 2x2 formations to explode them. All adjacent same colored blocks will also explode in a chain reaction. The player can move the blocks by swapping two adjacent blocks horizontally. There are several power-ups to aid the player. The game modes include two single player modes and several multiplayer modes including a co-op mode.</plot>
    <genre>Action</genre>
    <boxart1>xwum1Nh.jpg</boxart1>
    <clearlogo1>NIc1u2j.png</clearlogo1>
    <boxart2>ACTOpRj.jpg</boxart2>
    <boxart3>VtUcunN.png</boxart3>
    <boxart4>Tneo96U.png</boxart4>
  </game>
  <game name="Quiz Animania (USA, PSP Mini)">
    <description>Quiz Animania (USA, PSP Mini)</description>
	<groups>PSP Mini</groups>
    <rom name="pspminis/Quiz%20Animania%20%28USA%29.cso" size="11309197"/>
    <studio>Sony Computer Entertainment Inc.</studio>
    <releasedate>11/05/2010</releasedate>
    <plot>Can you correctly identify a duck by only looking at a zoomed in picture of its bill? How about spotting an rhino by just by a flashing image of its rump? Quiz Animania is a lighthearted game that will challenge your knowledge of the animal kingdom. Animal lovers will have their wits tested as they race to identify animals before time runs out. For big bonuses look for chance questions that could be your shot to earn loads of points and come back from behind to beat your friends. Play solo in the certification mode or head-to-head with a friend. Good Luck![CR]Recommended for two players and playable using a single PSP(r) system.</plot>
    <genre>Life Simulation</genre>
    <boxart1>ewL0Phf.jpg</boxart1>
  </game>
  <game name="Ramen Heaven (USA, PSP Mini)">
    <description>Ramen Heaven (USA, PSP Mini)</description>
	<groups>PSP Mini</groups>
    <rom name="pspminis/Ramen%20Heaven%20%28USA%29.cso" size="7248013"/>
    <studio>Sony Computer Entertainment Inc.</studio>
    <releasedate>04/05/2010</releasedate>
    <plot>Slurp up the fun in the quirky PSP(r) soup game Ramen Heaven. Use your chopsticks to collect bubbles of oil floating on the soup, and place them in your spoon to eat up, increasing your satisfaction gauge. A bowl of ramen has never had so many obstacles in it, knock into an egg and your oil bubble will split up, braise a naruto, and it may pop altogether. Heat up the fun by grabbing a friend and competing head to head! [CR]Recommended for one or two players and playable using a single PSP(r) system.</plot>
    <genre>Action</genre>
    <boxart1>FK0Fr2f.jpg</boxart1>
  </game>
  <game name="Rasmus Klump and the Big Maze (Denmark, PSP Mini)">
    <description>Rasmus Klump and the Big Maze (Denmark, PSP Mini)</description>
	<groups>PSP Mini</groups>
    <rom name="pspminis/Rasmus%20Klump%20and%20the%20Big%20Maze%20%28Denmark%29.cso" size="15433098"/>
  </game>
  <game name="Rasmus Klump in Pingonesien (Denmark, PSP Mini)">
    <description>Rasmus Klump in Pingonesien (Denmark, PSP Mini)</description>
	<groups>PSP Mini</groups>
    <rom name="pspminis/Rasmus%20Klump%20in%20Pingonesien%20%28Denmark%29.cso" size="8230655"/>
  </game>
  <game name="Rasmus Klump is Saving the Chickens (Denmark, PSP Mini)">
    <description>Rasmus Klump is Saving the Chickens (Denmark, PSP Mini)</description>
	<groups>PSP Mini</groups>
    <rom name="pspminis/Rasmus%20Klump%20is%20Saving%20the%20Chickens%20%28Denmark%29.cso" size="8542304"/>
  </game>
  <game name="Red Bull X-Fighters (USA, PSP Mini)">
    <description>Red Bull X-Fighters (USA, PSP Mini)</description>
	<groups>PSP Mini</groups>
    <rom name="pspminis/Red%20Bull%20X-Fighters%20%28USA%29.cso" size="14360619"/>
    <studio>Xendex</studio>
    <releasedate>15/06/2010</releasedate>
    <plot>With Red Bull X-Fighters, gamers around the world can now experience the thrill and excitement of the best Freestyle Motocross riders in the world on Xbox LIVE Arcade and PC. The game puts you, the player, on centre stage of the Red Bull X-Fighters World Tour. Take your bike, launch from huge ramps and pull off truly stunning and jaw-dropping tricks while up to 40 feet in the air. Do you have what it takes to wow the crowd and pull out all stops in the attempt to finish as overall champion? But don't expect this to be an easy challenge. You've got to master the right level of acceleration and braking, balance your body and all the while performing death-defying maneuvers on 100-foot leaps - don't crash or it will ruin your run.</plot>
    <genre>Sports</genre>
    <boxart1>CJ8OkaX.jpg</boxart1>
  </game>
  <game name="Reef Aquarium (USA, PSP Mini)">
    <description>Reef Aquarium (USA, PSP Mini)</description>
	<groups>PSP Mini</groups>
    <rom name="pspminis/Reef%20Aquarium%20%28USA%29.cso" size="9839155"/>
    <studio>Biart Studio</studio>
    <releasedate>29/04/2010</releasedate>
    <plot>Download the magnificent coral reefs of the deep blue to your console. Feel the atmosphere of the underwater world and watch its inhabitants swimming around you. You will see the most vivid ocean fishes there. Fish library will help you to find out more about these amazing creatures. And do not forget to feed fish and play with them - fish are very easy to get upset.</plot>
    <genre>Life Simulation</genre>
    <boxart1>MiOjYmB.png</boxart1>
  </game>
  <game name="Retro Cave Flyer (USA, PSP Mini)">
    <description>Retro Cave Flyer (USA, PSP Mini)</description>
	<groups>PSP Mini</groups>
    <rom name="pspminis/Retro%20Cave%20Flyer%20%28USA%29.cso" size="16289587"/>
    <studio>Big Head Games</studio>
    <releasedate>25/02/2010</releasedate>
    <plot>Guide your landing craft through 23 challenging levels, solving puzzles and avoiding hazards whilst finding and saving the stranded scientists. Get them all back to the mothership before the planet goes super nova. Great gameplay, perfect physics, vibrant visuals and a storming soundtrack make this the best lunar lander arcade puzzler available. [CR]All game code, art, design (c) Big Head Games Ltd. 2010 Music: Stage One composed by Space Manoeuvres, (c) 1999 Hooj Choons. All rights reserved. [CR]Purchase or use of this item is subject to the PlayStation(r)Network Terms of Service and User Agreement. If you do not wish to accept all these terms, do not purchase or use this item. This item has been sublicensed to you by Sony Computer Entertainment America. One-time license fee for downloads to up to 2 console systems and 2 portable systems that are associated with the purchasing account.</plot>
    <boxart1>eabr2DL.jpg</boxart1>
  </game>
  <game name="Revoltin' Youth (USA, PSP Mini)">
    <description>Revoltin' Youth (USA, PSP Mini)</description>
	<groups>PSP Mini</groups>
    <rom name="pspminis/Revoltin%27%20Youth%20%28USA%29.cso" size="74941126"/>
    <nplayers>1</nplayers>
    <studio>Open Emotion Studios</studio>
    <releasedate>27/09/2011</releasedate>
    <plot>The evil Big-Wig has covered the characters town in crummy marketing gibberish. It's up to you to control three rebellious characters through 50+ levels of headache inducing puzzles in Revoltin' Youth, a puzzle/platformer game featuring a unique pixel-art style and a robust soundtrack.</plot>
    <genre>Platform, Puzzle</genre>
    <boxart1>CZXgNOP.jpg</boxart1>
    <snapshot1>P3i4j2B.jpg</snapshot1>
  </game>
  <game name="Robin Hood - The Return of Richard (USA, PSP Mini)">
    <description>Robin Hood - The Return of Richard (USA, PSP Mini)</description>
	<groups>PSP Mini</groups>
    <rom name="pspminis/Robin%20Hood%20-%20The%20Return%20of%20Richard%20%28USA%29.cso" size="57526189"/>
  </game>
  <game name="Rocks N' Rockets (USA, PSP Mini)">
    <description>Rocks N' Rockets (USA, PSP Mini)</description>
	<groups>PSP Mini</groups>
    <rom name="pspminis/Rocks%20N%27%20Rockets%20%28USA%29.cso" size="7654775"/>
    <nplayers>1</nplayers>
    <studio>Creat Studios</studio>
    <releasedate>15/06/2010</releasedate>
    <plot>Thousands of meteors are heading towards earth! Are you ready to take the hero's seat in this mesmerizing arcade game?[CR]Are you ready to take the hero's seat in this mesmerizing arcade game? We hope so. Civilization is threatened by a terrifying, multi-phased meteor attack--thousands of strange meteors are heading towards Earth! Your mission is to protect our cities by controlling a rocket launcher that is built to protect each city.[CR]Features[CR]* Waves of increasingly destructive meteors[CR]* Innovative power ups[CR]* Over 100 exciting levels</plot>
    <genre>Shooter</genre>
    <boxart1>pTxxU9e.jpg</boxart1>
  </game>
  <game name="Ronnie O'Sullivan's Snooker (USA, PSP Mini)">
    <description>Ronnie O'Sullivan's Snooker (USA, PSP Mini)</description>
	<groups>PSP Mini</groups>
    <rom name="pspminis/Ronnie%20O%27Sullivan%27s%20Snooker%20%28USA%29.cso" size="19274997"/>
    <studio>PlayerOne</studio>
    <releasedate>03/10/2012</releasedate>
    <plot>Here with Ronnie O'Sullivan's Snooker, you play through the highlights of Ronnie's career culminating in his most famous World Championship wins. Have you got what it takes to re-create his many stunning victories?[CR]Ronnie guides you through the game, giving advice, even taking you back to his home table where you can refine your skills in his very own practice room.[CR]Memory Stick Duo(tm) Compatible: 2MB[CR]Download of this product is subject to the Sony Entertainment Network Terms of Service/User Agreement and any specific additional conditions applying to this product. If you do not wish to accept these terms, do not download this product. See Terms of Service for more important information.[CR]One time fee for use of downloads on up to 2 activated compatible Home Console systems and 3 activated compatible Portable Console systems.[CR]See Health Warnings for important health information before using this product.[CR]Library programs (c)Sony Computer Entertainment Inc. exclusively licensed to Sony Computer Entertainment Europe. Software Usage Terms apply, See eu.playstation.com/legal for full usage rights.[CR]Ronnie O'Sullivan and his name, likeness, image and biographical data have been used under license from Ronnie O'Sullivan. The use of the names or images of any other snooker players, events, organizations, tournaments or venues within this game are intended as factual biographical references only and this game is NOT endorsed by such third parties.</plot>
    <genre>Sports</genre>
    <boxart1>4cDPSVN.jpg</boxart1>
  </game>
  <game name="Route 66 (USA, PSP Mini)">
    <description>Route 66 (USA, PSP Mini)</description>
	<groups>PSP Mini</groups>
    <rom name="pspminis/Route%2066%20%28USA%29.cso" size="52673543"/>
    <studio>Gameshastra Inc.</studio>
    <releasedate>11/01/2010</releasedate>
    <plot>Mad" Madeleine Mayflower is a professional biker that, after competing for more than twenty years, decides to take a break from the race circuit, traveling with her motorcycle to explore the historical route 66 alongside her grandfather.[CR]Route 66 is a straightforward hidden object game, where the objective is to find all the items from a list at the bottom of the screen, on picturesque locations around the United States filled with assorted paraphernalia. The hint button is a badge at the bottom-right, that shows the position of one of the required objects when activated.[CR]Three mini-games appear between each location, giving extra hints to the player when completed. They are implementations of classic games like Simon with checkers pieces, a matching game with bottle taps and Reversi/Othello.</plot>
    <genre>Board Game</genre>
    <boxart1>ec0n61J.png</boxart1>
  </game>
  <game name="Rumble Trucks (USA, PSP Mini)">
    <description>Rumble Trucks (USA, PSP Mini)</description>
	<groups>PSP Mini</groups>
    <rom name="pspminis/Rumble%20Trucks%20%28USA%29.cso" size="31409262"/>
    <nplayers>1</nplayers>
    <studio>Playerthree</studio>
    <releasedate>15/11/2011</releasedate>
    <plot>Rumble Trucks is an exciting 3D racing game with 9 vehicles and 24 tracks across 3 unique worlds.[CR]You can race along dense jungle tracks, challenging spooky cemetary courses and all action warzone battlefield assault courses.[CR]Tricks, jumps, trophies and achievements all go to make Rumble Trucks an excellent fully featured PSP minis title.[CR]Ready steady RUMBLE!</plot>
    <genre>Racing</genre>
    <boxart1>DCyaQrj.png</boxart1>
  </game>
  <game name="Run Ghost Run (USA, PSP Mini)">
    <description>Run Ghost Run (USA, PSP Mini)</description>
	<groups>PSP Mini</groups>
    <rom name="pspminis/Run%20Ghost%20Run%20%28USA%29.cso" size="9749229"/>
    <studio>StormBASIC S.L.</studio>
    <releasedate>14/06/2011</releasedate>
    <plot>An infernal storm begins and you think that an old castle could be your salvation. You will soon discover that this is one of the worst decisions you have ever made. The doors close and you begin to try and find a way out, but what you don't know is that you will never be alone. Shoot, jump, run and try to avoid the hundreds of ghosts who never want you to leave. Enjoy 36 levels and 2 game modes of this fun and super addictive adventure. The longest night of your life has just begun...</plot>
    <genre>Platform, Shooter</genre>
    <boxart1>RJzQC1L.jpg</boxart1>
  </game>
  <game name="SAR - Search and Rescue (USA, PSP Mini)">
    <description>SAR - Search and Rescue (USA, PSP Mini)</description>
	<groups>PSP Mini</groups>
    <rom name="pspminis/SAR%20-%20Search%20and%20Rescue%20%28USA%29.cso" size="17769107"/>
  </game>
  <game name="Sasuke Vs. Commander (USA, PSP Mini)">
    <description>Sasuke Vs. Commander (USA, PSP Mini)</description>
	<groups>PSP Mini</groups>
    <rom name="pspminis/Sasuke%20Vs.%20Commander%20%28USA%29.cso" size="4613654"/>
  </game>
  <game name="Shapo (USA, PSP Mini)">
    <description>Shapo (USA, PSP Mini)</description>
	<groups>PSP Mini</groups>
    <rom name="pspminis/Shapo%20%28USA%29.cso" size="8799728"/>
    <studio>TikGames</studio>
    <releasedate>10/10/2010</releasedate>
    <plot>Shapo is a challenge that will keep you on the edge![CR]Shapo is a challenge that will keep you on the edge! Balance the scales as you place shapes made of different materials. Play more than 150 levels in Classic or Puzzle mode to unlock the greatest wonders of the world. Stunning art brings 15 wonders of the world to life! Enjoy exciting power ups such as the material bomb and line bomb. Each ball and shape has a different weight so be careful when placing your pieces![CR]*Classic Mode: Create lines to remove balls. Match sequential lines and watch the combo multiplier grow![CR]*Puzzle Mode: Complete increasingly complicated levels by filling the grid with the given balls.</plot>
    <genre>Puzzle</genre>
    <boxart1>M8dZtWu.jpg</boxart1>
  </game>
  <game name="Sheep Defense (USA, PSP Mini)">
    <description>Sheep Defense (USA, PSP Mini)</description>
	<groups>PSP Mini</groups>
    <rom name="pspminis/Sheep%20Defense%20%28USA%29.cso" size="6124458"/>
    <studio>Sony Computer Entertainment Inc.</studio>
    <releasedate>15/04/2010</releasedate>
    <plot>Hungry bears and crazy wolves are after your flock of soft, fluffy sheep and it's up to you and a friend to control two brave, valiant sheep dogs and protect the herd. Howl, bark or even unleash a super powered growl to scare away ferocious invaders. But bark too much and your stamina may decrease leaving you temporarily powerless to protect your cute cuddly friends. [CR]Recommended for two players and playable on a single PSP(r) system only.</plot>
    <genre>Action</genre>
    <boxart1>tDK6jf3.jpg</boxart1>
  </game>
  <game name="Shift Extended (USA, PSP Mini)">
    <description>Shift Extended (USA, PSP Mini)</description>
	<groups>PSP Mini</groups>
    <rom name="pspminis/Shift%20Extended%20%28USA%29.cso" size="8306412"/>
    <studio>Zallag S.A.S</studio>
    <releasedate>19/01/2011</releasedate>
    <plot>SHIFT is a successful game that has already puzzled the mind of over 14 million players around the world. It is now finally coming to the PlayStation(r)3 and the PSP(tm) in a new 'extended' version with new levels and gameplay mechanics.[CR]As a subject of a science experiment, you have to escape the 120 levels of the game and avoid all the carefully crafted traps. Fortunately you have a unique power called 'SHIFT': floor, ceiling, walls...everything is reversed by pressing a single button![CR]Will you be able to get out alive of this experiment?[CR]Be extra careful as the number of traps doubled in this version!</plot>
    <boxart1>g49D1Vc.jpg</boxart1>
  </game>
  <game name="Shogi (USA, PSP Mini)">
    <description>Shogi (USA, PSP Mini)</description>
	<groups>PSP Mini</groups>
    <rom name="pspminis/Shogi%20%28USA%29.cso" size="10340969"/>
  </game>
  <game name="Sky Force (USA, PSP Mini)">
    <description>Sky Force (USA, PSP Mini)</description>
	<groups>PSP Mini</groups>
    <rom name="pspminis/Sky%20Force%20%28USA%29.cso" size="30317468"/>
    <studio>Infinite Dreams Inc.</studio>
    <plot>Sky Force is a vertically scrolling shoot 'em up video game series created by the Polish video game developer Infinite Dreams Inc.. The gameplay is reminiscent of Capcom's 19XX series and Seibu Kaihatsu's Raiden series, featuring a weapon upgrade system and large end of stage bosses.[CR]Sky Force Reloaded:[CR]The second outing was initially released for Symbian, Pocket PC and Palm webOS in 2006 and was later released for iOS (2009), Iphone ios 7 (2010) and PSP (2011). The PSP version of "Sky Force Reloaded" was simply named "Sky Force". The 2D graphics style of the first title was combined with some 3D polygon objects like destructible towers. It received a remake for mobile in 2016, with a PC, PlayStation 4, and Xbox One versions released in 2017, and also a Nintendo Switch version released in 2018.</plot>
    <genre>Shooter</genre>
    <year>2011</year>
    <boxart1>eCQ6Gbd.jpg</boxart1>
    <clearlogo1>1Kyo3Pi.png</clearlogo1>
    <snapshot1>r5M9Wiq.jpg</snapshot1>
  </game>
  <game name="Smashbreak (USA, PSP Mini)">
    <description>Smashbreak (USA, PSP Mini)</description>
	<groups>PSP Mini</groups>
    <rom name="pspminis/Smashbreak%20%28USA%29.cso" size="5295724"/>
    <plot>Use paddles on either side of the screen to deflect balls and break the blocks in the middle. Collect power-ups and use your SMASH ability to send the ball flying and break multiple blocks at once. Two-player mode lets two people play on a single PS3(tm) system or PSP(r) system to play head to head.</plot>
    <genre>Action</genre>
    <boxart1>ih68RpB.jpg</boxart1>
  </game>
  <game name="Snake Warriors - Training (USA, PSP Mini)">
    <description>Snake Warriors - Training (USA, PSP Mini)</description>
	<groups>PSP Mini</groups>
    <rom name="pspminis/Snake%20Warriors%20-%20Training%20%28USA%29.cso" size="33209937"/>
    <studio>Crystal Games</studio>
    <releasedate>19/04/2011</releasedate>
    <plot>Choose from nine characters and start your career as a Snake Master in Snake Warriors: Training. Show your talent as a driver at the race tracks in Snake Race and demonstrate your patience and skill in avoiding hitting your own body in Classic Training. But are you sure you can also do this in the dark in Night Training? [CR]If you possess all these skills, then show you have an excellent memory in the Snake Memory game, but beware: in some levels you will even need to combine all your talents with numerical skills. If you turn out to be good at all these games and you have also mastered picking up moving items in Hunting Targets, you will be heading for a successful career in which you can unlock many pieces of clothing for your snake as well as medals throughout the 75 levels. [CR]Specifications: [CR]- 75 levels[CR]- 5 games[CR]- 9 characters[CR]- 3 save slots</plot>
    <genre>Action, Puzzle</genre>
    <boxart1>2X0mMd5.jpg</boxart1>
  </game>
  <game name="Sneezies (USA, PSP Mini)">
    <description>Sneezies (USA, PSP Mini)</description>
	<groups>PSP Mini</groups>
    <rom name="pspminis/Sneezies%20%28USA%29.cso" size="10646022"/>
  </game>
  <game name="Snowy - The Bear's Adventures (USA, PSP Mini)">
    <description>Snowy - The Bear's Adventures (USA, PSP Mini)</description>
	<groups>PSP Mini</groups>
    <rom name="pspminis/Snowy%20-%20The%20Bear%27s%20Adventures%20%28USA%29.cso" size="19290457"/>
    <studio>Alawar Entertainment</studio>
    <releasedate>30/08/2011</releasedate>
    <plot>Help the white bear Snowy to get to Arctic. Could it be possible for a little white bear to withstand a whole army of evil monsters? For sure, if we're talking about charming and fearless Snowy. Armed to the teeth with the snowballs, he is turning his enemies into large balls of snow and ice figures. But this snowballs throwing champion doesn't want to do any harm, he simply wants to get back home to Arctic and collect as many prizes and bonuses on his way as possible. And he will make it! But only with your help. Attention: During the game play, more then 10000 snowballs will be made. All of the monsters will be defrosted afterwards. No white bears will get hurt.</plot>
    <genre>Action, Platform</genre>
    <boxart1>hYdbBQ3.jpg</boxart1>
  </game>
  <game name="Solitaire (USA, PSP Mini)">
    <description>Solitaire (USA, PSP Mini)</description>
	<groups>PSP Mini</groups>
    <rom name="pspminis/Solitaire%20%28USA%29.cso" size="11457974"/>
  </game>
  <game name="Space Shooter for Two Bucks!, A (USA, PSP Mini)">
    <description>Space Shooter for Two Bucks!, A (USA, PSP Mini)</description>
	<groups>PSP Mini</groups>
    <rom name="pspminis/Space%20Shooter%20for%20Two%20Bucks%21%2C%20A%20%28USA%29.cso" size="54010274"/>
  </game>
  <game name="Spaceball Revolution (USA, PSP Mini)">
    <description>Spaceball Revolution (USA, PSP Mini)</description>
	<groups>PSP Mini</groups>
    <rom name="pspminis/Spaceball%20Revolution%20%28USA%29.cso" size="21029796"/>
  </game>
  <game name="Speedball 2 - Evolution (USA, PSP Mini)">
    <description>Speedball 2 - Evolution (USA, PSP Mini)</description>
	<groups>PSP Mini</groups>
    <rom name="pspminis/Speedball%202%20-%20Evolution%20%28USA%29.cso" size="48238637"/>
  </game>
  <game name="Spot the Differences! (USA, PSP Mini)">
    <description>Spot the Differences! (USA, PSP Mini)</description>
	<groups>PSP Mini</groups>
    <rom name="pspminis/Spot%20the%20Differences%21%20%28USA%29.cso" size="78364911"/>
  </game>
  <game name="Stand O'Food (USA, PSP Mini)">
    <description>Stand O'Food (USA, PSP Mini)</description>
	<groups>PSP Mini</groups>
    <rom name="pspminis/Stand%20O%27Food%20%28USA%29.cso" size="11651640"/>
    <studio>G5 Entertainment AB</studio>
    <releasedate>10/12/2009</releasedate>
    <plot>Stand O'Food is a fastfood restaurant simulator with where you need to cook up veggie, omelet, beef, chicken or fish burgers, before the long line of impatient customers becomes too big. If you earn money for each session, you can upgrade your restaurant with music, dressings, faster cooking, and other improvements. This is a fast, instant play game with more than 100 levels and 80 different burger recipes.</plot>
    <genre>Life Simulation</genre>
    <boxart1>iqlUiDk.jpg</boxart1>
  </game>
  <game name="Star Hammer Tactics (USA, PSP Mini)">
    <description>Star Hammer Tactics (USA, PSP Mini)</description>
	<groups>PSP Mini</groups>
    <rom name="pspminis/Star%20Hammer%20Tactics%20%28USA%29.cso" size="5878306"/>
    <studio>Black Lab Games</studio>
    <plot>When Novus falls, will you be its saviour? Take command of the infamous NSG-14 as Lieutenant Fredan Dyce in Campaign mode, or battle your friends for supremacy in 'hotseat' Skirmish mode.[CR]With every ship of Naval Strike Group 14 under your direct command, launch missiles to annihilate your enemies from afar or close in for explosive ship-to-alien broadsides. [CR]* Engaging turn-based tactical battles : individually control each ship in your fleet [CR]* Easy-to-learn rules; learn to play in minutes! [CR]* OPERATION STAR HAMMER : In this epic Campaign, play as Lieutenant Fredan Dyce, earn promotions within the Alliance Navy and come face-to-face with the single greatest threat to the safety of your homeworld, Novus. [CR]* Skirmish modes : create your own custom fleet, then duel against a friend in "hotseat" multiplayer, or take on the challenging AI</plot>
    <genre>Action, Strategy</genre>
    <year>2010</year>
    <boxart1>obnhCVa.jpg</boxart1>
  </game>
  <game name="Stellar Attack (USA, PSP Mini)">
    <description>Stellar Attack (USA, PSP Mini)</description>
	<groups>PSP Mini</groups>
    <rom name="pspminis/Stellar%20Attack%20%28USA%29.cso" size="35154111"/>
  </game>
  <game name="Stick Man Rescue (USA, PSP Mini)">
    <description>Stick Man Rescue (USA, PSP Mini)</description>
	<groups>PSP Mini</groups>
    <rom name="pspminis/Stick%20Man%20Rescue%20%28USA%29.cso" size="7760656"/>
  </game>
  <game name="Street Smart (USA, PSP Mini)">
    <description>Street Smart (USA, PSP Mini)</description>
	<groups>PSP Mini</groups>
    <rom name="pspminis/Street%20Smart%20%28USA%29.cso" size="30383396"/>
  </game>
  <game name="Sudoku (USA, PSP Mini)">
    <description>Sudoku (USA, PSP Mini)</description>
	<groups>PSP Mini</groups>
    <rom name="pspminis/Sudoku%20%28USA%29.cso" size="30686754"/>
    <gamefaqs_url>http://www.gamefaqs.com/psp/935443-sudoku</gamefaqs_url>
    <boxart1>uY3Rrdu.jpg</boxart1>
    <boxart2>2TuY349.jpg</boxart2>
  </game>
  <game name="Super Fruitfall Deluxe (Europe, PSP Mini)">
    <description>Super Fruitfall Deluxe (Europe, PSP Mini)</description>
	<groups>PSP Mini</groups>
    <rom name="pspminis/Super%20Fruitfall%20Deluxe%20%28Europe%29.cso" size="8988937"/>
    <nplayers>1</nplayers>
    <studio>System 3</studio>
    <releasedate>07/07/2009</releasedate>
    <plot>Move your fruit around the grid, group them together and watch as they disappear from your screen.[CR]Organise your fruits into straight lines or cunningly stack them on top of each other to clear more than one fruit type and earn big bonuses.[CR]Take on level after level of fruity puzzle action within the time limit.</plot>
    <genre>Puzzle</genre>
    <boxart1>4ETO83u.jpg</boxart1>
  </game>
  <game name="Supermarket Mania (USA, PSP Mini)">
    <description>Supermarket Mania (USA, PSP Mini)</description>
	<groups>PSP Mini</groups>
    <rom name="pspminis/Supermarket%20Mania%20%28USA%29.cso" size="37605422"/>
    <studio>G5 Entertainment AB</studio>
    <releasedate>18/05/2010</releasedate>
    <plot>Supermarket Mania, at its core, operates as a time management sim set in a grocery store. Or rather, five grocery stores. With a large 50-stage story mode, players take control of Nikki and must manage time and products to keep grocery stores stocked for customers. Besides just working to keep stores stocked, players have to deal with a competing grocery store. By working with speed and dedication, players earn enough cash to upgrade their grocery stores to better compete with the rival store. [CR]Besides the large story mode, the game also features an alternate "Endless Shift" mode with bonuses, five total shops, and seven different types of customers. Supermarket Mania features over a dozen different products to manage, and over twenty upgrades for the stores. [CR]Gameplay is seen and controlled on the bottom (touch) screen of the Nintendo DSi, and the game is viewed from an isometric angle similar to classic Sims games or old PC strategy titles. The top screen is largely used for statistics and other information.</plot>
    <genre>Life Simulation</genre>
    <videoid>RXPAQoiLPrY</videoid>
    <boxart1>URUND5f.jpg</boxart1>
    <snapshot1>cQioVTb.png</snapshot1>
    <snapshot2>fQEdHke.png</snapshot2>
    <snapshot3>DsXXmSV.png</snapshot3>
  </game>
  <game name="Swap Zap (Europe, PSP Mini)">
    <description>Swap Zap (Europe, PSP Mini)</description>
	<groups>PSP Mini</groups>
    <rom name="pspminis/Swap%20Zap%20%28Europe%29.cso" size="16998738"/>
    <studio>PlaygroundSquad</studio>
    <releasedate>16/02/2011</releasedate>
    <plot>Pam can run and jump around in an increasingly hazardous space-truck, dodging falling blocks and dangers that slowly fill the cargo holds.[CR]Enemies pop out of the space-trucks nooks and corners to gnaw at our heroine.[CR]As if that wasn't enough Pam needs to collect all power cores in each level in order to start her ship.[CR]The only tool available to her is the Swap-Zapper which enables its user to change places with anything it zaps![CR]With this tool Pam can instantly climb to high places, teleport blocks to crush enemies, zap away ticking time bombs and switch places with sharp cargo falling straight for her.[CR]Each level of the game takes place in a cargo container of the huge space truck.[CR]The objective of each level is to collect all the power cores needed to open the airlock into the next hold, effectively shrinking the distance between Pam and the control room of the spacecraft.</plot>
    <genre>Action, Puzzle</genre>
    <boxart1>1tFAja6.jpg</boxart1>
  </game>
  <game name="Sweet Reversi (USA, PSP Mini)">
    <description>Sweet Reversi (USA, PSP Mini)</description>
	<groups>PSP Mini</groups>
    <rom name="pspminis/Sweet%20Reversi%20%28USA%29.cso" size="7827335"/>
    <studio>Sony Computer Entertainment Inc.</studio>
    <releasedate>15/04/2010</releasedate>
    <plot>Outsmart your friends and take all of their macaroons for yourself in this tasty take on the reversi game. Stay on your toes, strategize and make sure you are always thinking several steps ahead as you trap your opponent's macaroons and turn them into yours in this deliciously fun puzzle game.</plot>
    <genre>Strategy</genre>
    <boxart1>ewkrK3Z.jpg</boxart1>
  </game>
  <game name="TNK III (USA, PSP Mini)">
    <description>TNK III (USA, PSP Mini)</description>
	<groups>PSP Mini</groups>
    <rom name="pspminis/TNK%20III%20%28USA%29.cso" size="7088471"/>
  </game>
  <game name="Tehra - Dark Warrior (USA, PSP Mini)">
    <description>Tehra - Dark Warrior (USA, PSP Mini)</description>
	<groups>PSP Mini</groups>
    <rom name="pspminis/Tehra%20-%20Dark%20Warrior%20%28USA%29.cso" size="52410324"/>
  </game>
  <game name="Telegraph Crosswords (USA, PSP Mini)">
    <description>Telegraph Crosswords (USA, PSP Mini)</description>
	<groups>PSP Mini</groups>
    <rom name="pspminis/Telegraph%20Crosswords%20%28USA%29.cso" size="9512430"/>
    <studio>Sanuk Games</studio>
    <releasedate>01/06/2010</releasedate>
    <plot>Play crossword puzzles from the 'Telegraph' like you've never played them before![CR]Discover a whopping 500 puzzles of multiple types. You're in for many hours of gameplay![CR]With its handy interface and intuitive controls, this game transfigures the classic pen-and-paper experience.[CR]Notable features include:[CR]* A huge selection of quick puzzles, cryptic puzzles and general knowledge puzzles!* Registration of best times in the Hall of Fame.* Interactive hints prevent you from being stuck!* Auto-save as you go: you can stop and resume a puzzle at any time!</plot>
    <genre>Puzzle</genre>
    <boxart1>0mRpJiP.jpg</boxart1>
  </game>
  <game name="Telegraph Sudoku &amp; Kakuro (USA, PSP Mini)">
    <description>Telegraph Sudoku &amp; Kakuro (USA, PSP Mini)</description>
	<groups>PSP Mini</groups>
    <rom name="pspminis/Telegraph%20Sudoku%20%26%20Kakuro%20%28USA%29.cso" size="12085015"/>
    <nplayers>1</nplayers>
    <studio>Sanuk Games</studio>
    <releasedate>15/04/2010</releasedate>
    <plot>Play number-puzzles from the 'Telegraph' like you've never played them before! Discover a whopping 500 puzzles of multiple types. You're in for many hours of game play![CR]* Sudoku: Classic 9x9 Sudoku grids in 4 levels of difficulty.[CR]* Mini-Sudoku: Easier 6x6 grids.[CR]* Sudoku-X: 9x9 grids in which the diagonals must also be filled with all numbers from 1 to 9.[CR]* Jigsaw Sudoku: 9x9 grids with uncommon box shapes.[CR]* Kakuro: With its handy interface and intuitive controls, this game transfigures the classic pen-and-paper experience.</plot>
    <genre>Puzzle</genre>
    <boxart1>nQ1zgAg.jpg</boxart1>
  </game>
  <game name="Terminator, The (USA, PSP Mini)">
    <description>Terminator, The (USA, PSP Mini)</description>
	<groups>PSP Mini</groups>
    <rom name="pspminis/Terminator%2C%20The%20%28USA%29.cso" size="11876935"/>
    <studio>Big Head Games</studio>
    <releasedate>11/10/2010</releasedate>
    <plot>The Terminator for PSP is an explosive top-down all action shooter with an episodic Story Mode and endless Quick Play mode.[CR]The player is Kyle Reese and the objective is to help him progress through several levels to access Skynet's core. Visually, the environment is virtually the same--a desolated area full of wreckage and debris. In addition, an intense soundtrack is included as well as the weapons fire and explosion sound effects.</plot>
    <genre>Action</genre>
    <videoid>8DMBgWz9hlA</videoid>
    <boxart1>tGeMgLh.png</boxart1>
    <snapshot1>olp5VVp.png</snapshot1>
    <boxart2>hlIZMrj.png</boxart2>
    <snapshot2>gVjYOrZ.jpg</snapshot2>
  </game>
  <game name="Tetraminos (USA, PSP Mini)">
    <description>Tetraminos (USA, PSP Mini)</description>
	<groups>PSP Mini</groups>
    <rom name="pspminis/Tetraminos%20%28USA%29.cso" size="9586416"/>
    <boxart1>5znMTYI.png</boxart1>
    <clearlogo1>d5sQ8SB.png</clearlogo1>
  </game>
  <game name="Tetris (USA, PSP Mini)">
    <description>Tetris (USA, PSP Mini)</description>
	<groups>PSP Mini</groups>
    <rom name="pspminis/Tetris%20%28USA%29.cso" size="28783912"/>
  </game>
  <game name="This is Football Management (Europe, PSP Mini)">
    <description>This is Football Management (Europe, PSP Mini)</description>
	<groups>PSP Mini</groups>
    <rom name="pspminis/This%20is%20Football%20Management%20%28Europe%29.cso" size="14879775"/>
    <boxart1>Y9HMZ7O.png</boxart1>
    <clearlogo1>ScaYaQx.png</clearlogo1>
  </game>
  <game name="Tiger Trouble (Europe, PSP Mini)">
    <description>Tiger Trouble (Europe, PSP Mini)</description>
	<groups>PSP Mini</groups>
    <rom name="pspminis/Tiger%20Trouble%20%28Europe%29.cso" size="30408943"/>
    <studio>GameShastra</studio>
    <releasedate>03/12/2009</releasedate>
    <plot>The game is played against asymmetrical opponents where one controls three Tigers and the other controls 15 Goats. Objective of the Tigers is to hunt down the Goats while the Goats attempt to lock the Tigers ability to move. [CR]Players can choose to be either Tiger or Goat. Both require different playing strategy. The arrangement of pieces, method of play and the rules of capture vary from game to game.</plot>
    <genre>Strategy, Board Game</genre>
    <boxart1>lsOZx5r.jpg</boxart1>
    <clearlogo1>5ckXTac.png</clearlogo1>
    <boxart2>1XDtbRW.png</boxart2>
  </game>
  <game name="Time Soldiers (USA, PSP Mini)">
    <description>Time Soldiers (USA, PSP Mini)</description>
	<groups>PSP Mini</groups>
    <rom name="pspminis/Time%20Soldiers%20%28USA%29.cso" size="16332495"/>
  </game>
  <game name="Tiny Hawk (Europe, PSP Mini)">
    <description>Tiny Hawk (Europe, PSP Mini)</description>
	<groups>PSP Mini</groups>
    <rom name="pspminis/Tiny%20Hawk%20%28Europe%29.cso" size="6758280"/>
  </game>
  <game name="Tonzurakko (USA, PSP Mini)">
    <description>Tonzurakko (USA, PSP Mini)</description>
	<groups>PSP Mini</groups>
    <rom name="pspminis/Tonzurakko%20%28USA%29.cso" size="5741308"/>
  </game>
  <game name="Top Gun (USA, PSP Mini)">
    <description>Top Gun (USA, PSP Mini)</description>
	<groups>PSP Mini</groups>
    <rom name="pspminis/Top%20Gun%20%28USA%29.cso" size="50990395"/>
    <boxart1>D5ct0S2.jpg</boxart1>
    <clearlogo1>RAj6TSU.png</clearlogo1>
    <boxart2>C27DWJN.png</boxart2>
  </game>
  <game name="Top Trumps - NBA All Stars (USA, PSP Mini)">
    <description>Top Trumps - NBA All Stars (USA, PSP Mini)</description>
	<groups>PSP Mini</groups>
    <rom name="pspminis/Top%20Trumps%20-%20NBA%20All%20Stars%20%28USA%29.cso" size="16398069"/>
    <boxart1>DlKyDdk.jpg</boxart1>
    <clearlogo1>qwievwe.png</clearlogo1>
    <boxart2>NQyz35x.png</boxart2>
  </game>
  <game name="Touch Racing Nitro (Europe, PSP Mini)">
    <description>Touch Racing Nitro (Europe, PSP Mini)</description>
	<groups>PSP Mini</groups>
    <rom name="pspminis/Touch%20Racing%20Nitro%20%28Europe%29.cso" size="24930917"/>
    <genre>Racing</genre>
    <boxart1>5qGogfX.jpg</boxart1>
  </game>
  <game name="Touchdown Fever (USA, PSP Mini)">
    <description>Touchdown Fever (USA, PSP Mini)</description>
	<groups>PSP Mini</groups>
    <rom name="pspminis/Touchdown%20Fever%20%28USA%29.cso" size="46677254"/>
  </game>
  <game name="Trailblazer (USA, PSP Mini)">
    <description>Trailblazer (USA, PSP Mini)</description>
	<groups>PSP Mini</groups>
    <rom name="pspminis/Trailblazer%20%28USA%29.cso" size="27199378"/>
    <boxart1>Imy48Mm.jpg</boxart1>
    <clearlogo1>W6QIqH5.png</clearlogo1>
    <boxart2>HQtETYm.png</boxart2>
  </game>
  <game name="Treasures of Montezuma, The (USA, PSP Mini)">
    <description>Treasures of Montezuma, The (USA, PSP Mini)</description>
	<groups>PSP Mini</groups>
    <rom name="pspminis/Treasures%20of%20Montezuma%2C%20The%20%28USA%29.cso" size="16670466"/>
    <boxart1>mj3UR7e.png</boxart1>
    <clearlogo1>7iADkHY.png</clearlogo1>
  </game>
  <game name="Twin Blades (USA, PSP Mini)">
    <description>Twin Blades (USA, PSP Mini)</description>
	<groups>PSP Mini</groups>
    <rom name="pspminis/Twin%20Blades%20%28USA%29.cso" size="51848172"/>
  </game>
  <game name="Urbanix (USA, PSP Mini)">
    <description>Urbanix (USA, PSP Mini)</description>
	<groups>PSP Mini</groups>
    <rom name="pspminis/Urbanix%20%28USA%29.cso" size="17421835"/>
    <boxart1>4WbhngV.jpg</boxart1>
    <clearlogo1>J0e2vtJ.png</clearlogo1>
    <boxart2>JXKYRqB.png</boxart2>
  </game>
  <game name="VT Tennis (USA, PSP Mini)">
    <description>VT Tennis (USA, PSP Mini)</description>
	<groups>PSP Mini</groups>
    <rom name="pspminis/VT%20Tennis%20%28USA%29.cso" size="32087432"/>
    <studio>Virtual Toys</studio>
    <releasedate>25/05/2010</releasedate>
    <plot>VT TennisTM is the most competitive and addictive tennis game for the PSP. Virtual Toys' experience in this kind of games will help you become the new international circuit champion. Train your budding tennis star to serve, lob and smash your way to victory with precision swipes in all directions, using its innovative controls! Advance your player statistics in this fast-paced tournament of game modes, featuring Quickmatch, Tennis School and World Championship! Play a quick singles or doubles match on one of the available courts. In quick match mode, you can modify all the game settings such as the game difficulty, sex of your player and the number of games and sets per match. There are various locked courts which you can only play once you have progressed in career mode. The objective in career mode is to become number 1 in the world rankings. To do this, the player will have to unlock courts as he competes in championships all over the world. At the start of career mode, the player will see himself in last place in the rankings. From this moment on, you must battle your way up to be among the top players. You can play on all types of surface: grass, clay and hard courts and learn the best techniques for winning each tournament on the different surfaces. Seventeen tough courts, each more difficult than the last, stand between you and your final victory.</plot>
    <genre>Sports</genre>
    <videoid>MTFgpVUT_H8</videoid>
    <boxart1>GXTh4qt.jpg</boxart1>
    <clearlogo1>wBlhv9j.png</clearlogo1>
    <snapshot1>t6Bp2LG.png</snapshot1>
    <boxart2>uMyORoi.png</boxart2>
    <snapshot2>OmioFgk.png</snapshot2>
  </game>
  <game name="Vanguard (USA, PSP Mini)">
    <description>Vanguard (USA, PSP Mini)</description>
	<groups>PSP Mini</groups>
    <rom name="pspminis/Vanguard%20%28USA%29.cso" size="3852458"/>
  </game>
  <game name="Vanguard II (USA, PSP Mini)">
    <description>Vanguard II (USA, PSP Mini)</description>
	<groups>PSP Mini</groups>
    <rom name="pspminis/Vanguard%20II%20%28USA%29.cso" size="3154592"/>
    <rating>1.50</rating>
    <boxart1>1ANeeCy.png</boxart1>
    <clearlogo1>KIArBch.png</clearlogo1>
  </game>
  <game name="Vector TD (USA, PSP Mini)">
    <description>Vector TD (USA, PSP Mini)</description>
	<groups>PSP Mini</groups>
    <rom name="pspminis/Vector%20TD%20%28USA%29.cso" size="12485648"/>
    <rating>5.00</rating>
    <nplayers>1</nplayers>
    <releasedate>04/03/2010</releasedate>
    <plot>In this entry in the popular tower defense genre, players aim to eliminate the Vectoid threat before they reach the end of the path. You do this by constructing towers along the path to attack oncoming Vectoids. Success is not based solely on the types of tower you select, but where you place them and what upgrade and bonus options you take.[CR]At your disposal are eleven flavors of towers, each of which can be upgraded to level 10 (increasing the tower's damage and range). The Green Lasers, for example, lock onto one Vectoid and deal ongoing damage. The Red Spammer fires heat-seeking rockets at random targets in range. Blue Ray towers drain power and cause Vectoids to slow down. The in-game guide lists each tower in detail. Every few waves you'll also be rewarded with a Yellow Energy Cell, which you can use to purchase one of three Boosts. Damage and Range Booster towers can be placed on a grid to increase the stats of other towers around it.[CR]Vector TD for PSP features eight maps (two Beginner, three Normal, three Extreme) as well as all eleven tower and seven enemy types of the original Flash version. Exclusive to the minis version is a brand-new control interface -- you'll be able to select each gri' using the D-pad or analog stick and place/upgrade towers.</plot>
    <genre>Strategy</genre>
    <boxart1>kxRM7u5.jpg</boxart1>
    <clearlogo1>n64uYIs.png</clearlogo1>
    <snapshot1>dERDmDu.jpg</snapshot1>
  </game>
  <game name="Velocity (USA, PSP Mini)">
    <description>Velocity (USA, PSP Mini)</description>
	<groups>PSP Mini</groups>
    <rom name="pspminis/Velocity%20%28USA%29.cso" size="79584456"/>
  </game>
  <game name="Vempire (USA, PSP Mini)">
    <description>Vempire (USA, PSP Mini)</description>
	<groups>PSP Mini</groups>
    <rom name="pspminis/Vempire%20%28USA%29.cso" size="12700763"/>
  </game>
  <game name="Vibes (USA, PSP Mini)">
    <description>Vibes (USA, PSP Mini)</description>
	<groups>PSP Mini</groups>
    <rom name="pspminis/Vibes%20%28USA%29.cso" size="62800236"/>
    <nplayers>1</nplayers>
    <releasedate>08/06/2010</releasedate>
    <plot>Welcome to a brand new era of rhythm! Let Vibes take you on a heart-pounding, button-bashing journey through a huge variety of music tracks. Your accuracy, timing and finger speed will be taken to the limit in this unique test of rhythm. Follow the pattern of music and chase the big combos and high scores! Amaze yourself by beating all the difficulty levels which push your fingers to breaking point! Do you have what it takes to become number one?</plot>
    <genre>Music</genre>
    <videoid>T7l3MY9AfPk</videoid>
    <boxart1>St9BBvb.png</boxart1>
    <clearlogo1>og4cZk1.png</clearlogo1>
    <boxart2>8prT8Xk.png</boxart2>
  </game>
  <game name="Wackylands Boss (USA, PSP Mini)">
    <description>Wackylands Boss (USA, PSP Mini)</description>
	<groups>PSP Mini</groups>
    <rom name="pspminis/Wackylands%20Boss%20%28USA%29.cso" size="19314058"/>
    <boxart1>COnE6yC.jpg</boxart1>
    <clearlogo1>YUejCG5.png</clearlogo1>
    <boxart2>yUNIwOY.png</boxart2>
  </game>
  <game name="War of Sonria (Europe, PSP Mini)">
    <description>War of Sonria (Europe, PSP Mini)</description>
	<groups>PSP Mini</groups>
    <rom name="pspminis/War%20of%20Sonria%20%28Europe%29.cso" size="36125779"/>
    <boxart1>Hdl3SMt.jpg</boxart1>
    <clearlogo1>jleyjML.png</clearlogo1>
    <boxart2>QFhXuTI.png</boxart2>
  </game>
  <game name="Where is my Heart (USA, PSP Mini)">
    <description>Where is my Heart (USA, PSP Mini)</description>
	<groups>PSP Mini</groups>
    <rom name="pspminis/Where%20is%20my%20Heart%20%28USA%29.cso" size="59627610"/>
  </game>
  <game name="Who's That Flying (USA, PSP Mini)">
    <description>Who's That Flying (USA, PSP Mini)</description>
	<groups>PSP Mini</groups>
    <rom name="pspminis/Who%27s%20That%20Flying%20%28USA%29.cso" size="83009813"/>
  </game>
  <game name="Widget's Odyssey (USA, PSP Mini)">
    <description>Widget's Odyssey (USA, PSP Mini)</description>
	<groups>PSP Mini</groups>
    <rom name="pspminis/Widget%27s%20Odyssey%20%28USA%29.cso" size="52947703"/>
    <boxart1>jrXrqhO.jpg</boxart1>
  </game>
  <game name="Widget's Odyssey 2 (USA, PSP Mini)">
    <description>Widget's Odyssey 2 (USA, PSP Mini)</description>
	<groups>PSP Mini</groups>
    <rom name="pspminis/Widget%27s%20Odyssey%202%20%28USA%29.cso" size="63375831"/>
    <boxart1>jrXrqhO.jpg</boxart1>
  </game>
  <game name="Wizorb (USA, PSP Mini)">
    <description>Wizorb (USA, PSP Mini)</description>
	<groups>PSP Mini</groups>
    <rom name="pspminis/Wizorb%20%28USA%29.cso" size="18536491"/>
    <rating>3.50</rating>
    <boxart1>TNaYPEq.jpg</boxart1>
    <clearlogo1>fCIPDtJ.png</clearlogo1>
    <boxart2>QX57lq6.png</boxart2>
  </game>
  <game name="World Ping Pong Championship (Europe, PSP Mini)">
    <description>World Ping Pong Championship (Europe, PSP Mini)</description>
	<groups>PSP Mini</groups>
    <rom name="pspminis/World%20Ping%20Pong%20Championship%20%28Europe%29.cso" size="9971508"/>
    <boxart1>PyQmyyc.jpg</boxart1>
    <clearlogo1>WblgpIf.png</clearlogo1>
    <boxart2>N98VUwg.png</boxart2>
  </game>
  <game name="Yeti Sports Pengu Throw (USA, PSP Mini)">
    <description>Yeti Sports Pengu Throw (USA, PSP Mini)</description>
	<groups>PSP Mini</groups>
    <rom name="pspminis/Yeti%20Sports%20Pengu%20Throw%20%28USA%29.cso" size="7314807"/>
    <studio>Hands-On Mobile</studio>
    <genre>Platform</genre>
    <boxart1>74trRlp.jpg</boxart1>
    <clearlogo1>plhdNyf.png</clearlogo1>
    <boxart2>JIhwl6F.png</boxart2>
  </game>
  <game name="Young Thor (USA, PSP Mini)">
    <description>Young Thor (USA, PSP Mini)</description>
	<groups>PSP Mini</groups>
    <rom name="pspminis/Young%20Thor%20%28USA%29.cso" size="60882539"/>
    <boxart1>SinAAhr.jpg</boxart1>
  </game>
  <game name="Yummy Yummy Cooking Jam (USA, PSP Mini)">
    <description>Yummy Yummy Cooking Jam (USA, PSP Mini)</description>
	<groups>PSP Mini</groups>
    <rom name="pspminis/Yummy%20Yummy%20Cooking%20Jam%20%28USA%29.cso" size="19847522"/>
    <boxart1>o1xb2Vn.jpg</boxart1>
    <clearlogo1>8c2xUCR.png</clearlogo1>
    <boxart2>QnB9Dk6.png</boxart2>
  </game>
  <game name="Zenonia (USA, PSP Mini)">
    <description>Zenonia (USA, PSP Mini)</description>
	<groups>PSP Mini</groups>
    <rom name="pspminis/Zenonia%20%28USA%29.cso" size="22049497"/>
    <rating>3.00</rating>
    <studio>GAMEVIL</studio>
    <releasedate>12/10/2010</releasedate>
    <plot>Zenonia is an action role-playing game created, developed, and published by Gamevil for iOS, Android, PlayStation Portable, Nintendo DSi, Zeebo and Windows Mobile. It was released on the App Store on May 24, 2009 and on the Google Play Store on March 27, 2010. It was released for the PlayStation Portable on October 12, 2010.[CR]The main character, Regret, is controlled through use of an on-screen d-pad, which is located in the lower left corner of the screen. There are many side quests that the player can choose to complete in order to further explore the world. The main storyline can be changed by the player depending on whether they decide to make certain choices that will cause their character's alignment to shift more quickly towards good or evil. There are four classes in which the player can choose from: Paladin, Warrior, or Assassin, each having a unique fighting style. The game also features hundreds of different weapons, and a full class skill tree for each of the classes. Gamevil claims that Zenonia has 40 hours of gameplay.[CR]Regret's in-game appearance changes based upon his equipped weapon and armor set.</plot>
    <genre>Action, Role-Playing</genre>
    <boxart1>VSkt1g6.jpg</boxart1>
    <clearlogo1>U909m49.png</clearlogo1>
    <boxart2>sKB1Lxr.png</boxart2>
  </game>
  <game name="Zombie Racers (USA, PSP Mini)">
    <description>Zombie Racers (USA, PSP Mini)</description>
	<groups>PSP Mini</groups>
    <rom name="pspminis/Zombie%20Racers%20%28USA%29.cso" size="62938058"/>
    <nplayers>1</nplayers>
    <studio>Big Head Games</studio>
    <releasedate>02/06/2011</releasedate>
    <plot>Take on the best Zombie Racers in this automotive zombie bloodfest.[CR]*Story Mode: race and kill zombies, use zombie kills to upgrade your car, come first to unlock the next track.[CR]*Free Roaming Mode: go anywhere, use weapons on zombies and each other, compete in three new game modes, Dusk To Dawn, 666 Zombies and Every Last Drop.[CR]*Unlock new cars and tracks.[CR]*10 cars, from pickups and monster 4x4s to drift cars and even a golf cart.[CR]*14 tracks, from a forest and a cornfield to an airport and shopping mall.[CR]*Punk soundtrack from Bankrupt.</plot>
    <genre>Racing</genre>
    <boxart1>mRtLrtt.jpg</boxart1>
    <clearlogo1>txNPUg6.png</clearlogo1>
    <snapshot1>6PkrJMa.jpg</snapshot1>
    <boxart2>dcc5a6s.png</boxart2>
    <snapshot2>KFcJOa3.jpg</snapshot2>
  </game>
  <game name="Zombie Tycoon (USA, PSP Mini)">
    <description>Zombie Tycoon (USA, PSP Mini)</description>
	<groups>PSP Mini</groups>
    <rom name="pspminis/Zombie%20Tycoon%20%28USA%29.cso" size="60870584"/>
    <boxart1>PyqcBhB.jpg</boxart1>
  </game>
</datafile>