<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<datafile>
	<header>
		<emu_name>Quake</emu_name>
		<emu_description>Standalone Game</emu_description>
		<emu_category>Port</emu_category>
		<emu_version>04012018</emu_version>
		<emu_date>9/14/2016</emu_date>
		<emu_author>Lefty420</emu_author>
		<emu_visibility>visible</emu_visibility>
		<emu_homepage>https://archive.org</emu_homepage>
		<emu_baseurl>https://archive.org/download/</emu_baseurl>
		<emu_launcher>retroplayer</emu_launcher>
		<emu_default_addon>none</emu_default_addon>
		<emu_ext_launch_cmd>none</emu_ext_launch_cmd>
		<emu_downloadpath>default</emu_downloadpath>
		<emu_postdlaction>unzip_and_launch_file</emu_postdlaction>
		<emu_comment>Quake is a first-person shooter video game, developed by id Software and published by GT Interactive in 1996</emu_comment>
		<emu_thumb>WDoG1Dr.jpg</emu_thumb>
		<emu_banner>H5UVnr8.jpg</emu_banner>
		<emu_fanart>jsk2VsS.jpg</emu_fanart>
		<emu_logo>43hjv6B.png</emu_logo>
		<emu_trailer>5WzyVjx-SXM</emu_trailer>
	</header>
	<game name="Quake">
		<description>Quake</description>
		<rom name="quakes_and_missionpacks/quake_1.zip" size="22020096" />
		<title_clean>Quake</title_clean>
		<plot>Quake is a first-person shooter video game, developed by id Software and published by GT Interactive in 1996. It features music composed by Trent Reznor and Nine Inch Nails.[CR]It is the first game in the Quake series. In the game, players must find their way through various maze-like, medieval environments while battling a variety of monsters using a wide array of weapons.[CR]The successor to id Software's Doom series, Quake built upon the technology and gameplay of its predecessor. Unlike the Doom engine before it, the Quake engine offered full real-time 3D rendering and had early support for 3D acceleration through OpenGL. After Doom helped popularize multiplayer deathmatches, Quake added various multiplayer options. Online multiplayer became increasingly common, with the QuakeWorld update and software such as QuakeSpy making the process of finding and playing against others on the Internet easier and more reliable.[CR]Programmer Michael Abrash had stated in a 2013 interview that Quake is his favourite game "of all time."</plot>
		<releasedate>06/22/1996</releasedate>
		<year>1999</year>
		<genre>FPS</genre>
		<nplayers>1</nplayers>
		<thegamesdb_id>777</thegamesdb_id>
		<videoid>5WzyVjx-SXM</videoid>
		<giantbomb_url>https://www.giantbomb.com/quake/3030-8015/</giantbomb_url>
		<boxart1>M4KIVpw.png</boxart1>
		<banner1>171sMlm.jpg</banner1>
		<fanart1>jsk2VsS.jpg</fanart1>
		<clearlogo1>dfPD2j3.png</clearlogo1>
		<emu_command>pak0.pak</emu_command>
	</game>
	<game name="Quake Mission Pack 1 - Scourge of Armagon">
		<description>Quake Mission Pack 1 - Scourge of Armagon</description>
		<rom name="quakes_and_missionpacks/quake_hipnotic.zip" size="50855936" />
		<title_clean>Quake Mission Pack 1 Scourge of Armagon</title_clean>
		<plot>Quake Mission Pack 1: Scourge of Armagon is the first official mission pack for Quake, developed by Hipnotic Software and released on February 28, 1997.[CR]After Ranger defeats Shub-Niggurath, he returns home to find Armagon has taken over Quake's forces and plans on destroying Earth using the Rift. Therefore, the hero must once again venture into the dark realms of Quake and defeat the armies of evil.</plot>
		<releasedate>02/28/1997</releasedate>
		<year>1997</year>
		<genre>FPS</genre>
		<nplayers>1</nplayers>
		<thegamesdb_id>777</thegamesdb_id>
		<videoid>_26ocyo8rQo</videoid>
		<giantbomb_url>https://www.giantbomb.com/quake/3030-8015/</giantbomb_url>
		<boxart1>VQ3B0Ir.png</boxart1>
		<banner1>G6SjClx.jpg</banner1>
		<fanart1>K4OpFAe.jpg</fanart1>
		<clearlogo1>dfPD2j3.png</clearlogo1>
		<emu_command>hipnotic.pak</emu_command>
	</game>
	<game name="Quake Mission Pack 2 - Dissolution of Eternity">
		<description>Quake Mission Pack 2 - Dissolution of Eternity</description>
		<rom name="quakes_and_missionpacks/quake_rogue.zip" size="53057946" />
		<title_clean>Quake Mission Pack 1 Scourge of Armagon</title_clean>
		<plot>Quake Mission Pack 2: Dissolution of Eternity is the second official mission pack released for Quake, developed by Rogue Entertainment and released on March 31, 1997, an exact month after the first expansion.[CR]Having defeated Armagon, the hero returns to Earth. However, things seem very wrong - apparently Quake has initiated yet another dark scheme to subjugate our world by altering the course of time itself. The hero is determined to put an end to Quake once and for all, and therefore boldly enters the dark realms again for one final confrontation to end the entire evil once and for all.</plot>
		<releasedate>03/31/1997</releasedate>
		<year>1997</year>
		<genre>FPS</genre>
		<nplayers>1</nplayers>
		<thegamesdb_id>777</thegamesdb_id>
		<videoid>zVHC0xWd8uY</videoid>
		<giantbomb_url>https://www.giantbomb.com/quake/3030-8015/</giantbomb_url>
		<boxart1>X5uZl9n.png</boxart1>
		<banner1>5qixLME.jpg</banner1>
		<fanart1>bng60Km.jpg</fanart1>
		<clearlogo1>dfPD2j3.png</clearlogo1>
		<emu_command>rogue.pak</emu_command>
	</game>
	<game name="Quake - Quoth">
		<description>Quake - Quoth</description>
		<rom name="quakes_and_missionpacks/quake_quoth.zip" size="76231475" />
		<title_clean>Quake Quoth</title_clean>
		<plot>Quoth is an expansion pack for the Quake single player campaign.[CR]It is not intended as a series of thematically connected maps with additional custom content, as other packs are. The intention is to provide quality custom content for Q1 mappers and players in a single pak file. There are maps included in the pak, but there are also larger maps using the content already released separately by both Kell and necros, and more maps will surely follow.</plot>
		<releasedate>09/03/2008</releasedate>
		<year>2008</year>
		<genre>FPS</genre>
		<nplayers>1</nplayers>
		<thegamesdb_id>777</thegamesdb_id>
		<videoid>d16LhD3B9PE</videoid>
		<giantbomb_url>https://www.giantbomb.com/quake/3030-8015/</giantbomb_url>
		<boxart1>4UYcQ6t.jpg</boxart1>
		<banner1>0Lg2IHp.jpg</banner1>
		<fanart1>w9858E5.jpg</fanart1>
		<clearlogo1>dfPD2j3.png</clearlogo1>
		<emu_command>quoth.pak</emu_command>
	</game>
</datafile>