<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<datafile>
	<header>
		<emu_name>Internet Archive Best Of - Point and Click</emu_name>
		<emu_description>Point and Click</emu_description>
		<emu_category>Best of, PC</emu_category>
		<emu_version>03132019</emu_version>
		<emu_date>07/01/2016</emu_date>
		<emu_author>Zach Morris</emu_author>
		<emu_visibility>visible</emu_visibility>
		<emu_homepage>http://www.scummvm.org</emu_homepage>
		<emu_baseurl>https://archive.org/download/</emu_baseurl>
		<emu_launcher>retroplayer</emu_launcher>
		<emu_default_addon>none</emu_default_addon>
		<emu_ext_launch_cmd>none</emu_ext_launch_cmd>
		<emu_downloadpath>default</emu_downloadpath>
		<emu_postdlaction>unzip_and_launch_scummvm_file</emu_postdlaction>
		<emu_comment>Whether you were a fan of Sierra and LucasArts's fantastic point-and-click adventures or its remarkable licensed games, there's a good chance you have fond, nostalgic memories of the projects they spawned.  Though the companies have shut down, their legacy will live on in the developers it inspired to make their own games, to create their own worlds, and to tell their own stories.[CR]This collection honors the point and click adventure game legacy.</emu_comment>
		<emu_thumb>gZzNdfS.jpg</emu_thumb>
		<emu_banner>fQMpZXh.jpg</emu_banner>
		<emu_fanart>HAENC3o.jpg</emu_fanart>
		<emu_logo>waChIgv.png</emu_logo>
		<emu_trailer>KWstXVvaiR4</emu_trailer>
	</header>
  <game name="Beneath a Steel Sky (Floppy VGA)">
    <description>Beneath a Steel Sky (Floppy VGA)</description>
    <title_clean>Beneath a Steel Sky</title_clean>
    <rom name="The_Complete_ScummVM_Collection_v2/The_Complete_ScummVM%20Collection%20v2.0.zip/The_Complete_ScummVM%20Collection%20v2.0%2FWorking%2FBeneath%20a%20Steel%20Sky%20%28Floppy%20VGA%29.zip" size="7773436"/>
    <rating>4.86</rating>
    <nplayers>1</nplayers>
    <releasedate>03/01/1994</releasedate>
    <plot>Beneath a Steel Sky is a 1994 cyberpunk science-fiction point-and-click adventure game developed by Revolution Software and published by Virgin Interactive Entertainment for MS-DOS and Amiga home computers. The game was made available as freeware for PC platforms in 2003. Set in a dystopian future, the player assumes the role of Robert Foster, who was stranded in a wasteland known as the Gap as a child and adopted by a group of local Aboriginals, gradually adjusting to his life in the wilderness. After many years, armed security officers arrive, killing the locals and taking Robert back to Union City. He escapes and soon uncovers the corruption which lies at the heart of society.</plot>
    <ESRB>T - Teen</ESRB>
    <genre>Adventure</genre>
    <studio>Virgin Interactive Entertainment</studio>
    <emu_command>sky</emu_command>
    <boxart1>cmA4GCI.jpg</boxart1>
    <banner1>U2nnpqy.jpg</banner1>
    <clearlogo1>IlekH4Z.png</clearlogo1>
    <snapshot1>EQVmTIw.png</snapshot1>
    <fanart1>tJl0QSJ.jpg</fanart1>
    <boxart2>qlQXA33.jpg</boxart2>
    <snapshot2>tbrmu1c.png</snapshot2>
    <boxart3>QVHqClK.jpg</boxart3>
    <boxart4>bdY8l1g.png</boxart4>
    <boxart5>r1MPvAi.jpg</boxart5>
    <snapshot10>2q3GUCz.png</snapshot10>
    <snapshot3>WIip1oi.gif</snapshot3>
    <snapshot4>tWPNHfK.gif</snapshot4>
    <snapshot5>bWJAr8a.png</snapshot5>
    <snapshot6>NYBf7sN.png</snapshot6>
    <snapshot7>nsWx5wa.png</snapshot7>
    <snapshot8>aj7jyNU.png</snapshot8>
    <snapshot9>DCAH3UQ.png</snapshot9>
  </game>
  <game name="Broken Sword 1 The Shadow of the Templar (CD Windows)">
    <description>Broken Sword 1 The Shadow of the Templar (CD Windows)</description>
    <title_clean>Broken Sword 1 The Shadow of the Templar</title_clean>
    <rom name="The_Complete_ScummVM_Collection_v2/The_Complete_ScummVM%20Collection%20v2.0.zip/The_Complete_ScummVM%20Collection%20v2.0%2FWorking%2FBroken%20Sword%201%20The%20Shadow%20of%20the%20Templar%20%28CD%20Windows%29.zip" size="721934975"/>
    <rating>4.20</rating>
    <nplayers>1</nplayers>
    <releasedate>30/09/1996</releasedate>
    <plot>George Stobbart is an American tourist on holiday in Paris in the autumn. The story opens with Georges quiet coffee at a café rudely interrupted by the explosion of a bomb planted by a man dressed up as a clown. He sets off investigating the explosion and, gradually, he and photo-journalist Nico Collard are drawn into a globe-trotting adventure involving conspiracies, cults and murder, all revolving around the Knights Templar.[CR]The game, which was a critical and commercial success, was released as Circle of Blood in the United States.</plot>
    <genre>Adventure</genre>
    <ESRB>ESRB - T (Teen)</ESRB>
    <studio>Virgin Interactive Entertainment</studio>
    <emu_command>sword1</emu_command>
    <boxart1>XIzw3ZQ.jpg</boxart1>
    <banner1>8bkff2g.png</banner1>
    <clearlogo1>Zbb2C0V.png</clearlogo1>
    <snapshot1>SrQl8tf.png</snapshot1>
    <fanart1>kpF4YGU.jpg</fanart1>
    <boxart2>E92k9QL.png</boxart2>
    <snapshot2>Nl6YG4V.jpg</snapshot2>
  </game>
  <game name="Broken Sword 2 The Smoking Mirror (CD Windows)">
    <description>Broken Sword 2 The Smoking Mirror (CD Windows)</description>
    <title_clean>Broken Sword 2 The Smoking Mirror</title_clean>
    <rom name="The_Complete_ScummVM_Collection_v2/The_Complete_ScummVM%20Collection%20v2.0.zip/The_Complete_ScummVM%20Collection%20v2.0%2FWorking%2FBroken%20Sword%202%20The%20Smoking%20Mirror%20%28CD%20Windows%29.zip" size="716199432"/>
    <rating>4.68</rating>
    <nplayers>1</nplayers>
    <releasedate>31/10/1997</releasedate>
    <plot>Broken Sword II: The Smoking Mirror is a point-and-click adventure video game originally released on Microsoft Windows and PlayStation in 1997. It was re-released on Microsoft Windows, OS X and iOS as a remastered edition in 2010 and on Android in 2012. It is the second installment in the Broken Sword series, and the first game in the series that does not follow the Knights Templar storyline. The player assumes the role of George Stobbart, a young American who is an eyewitness to the kidnapping of his girlfriend Nicole Collard.</plot>
    <ESRB>ESRB - T (Teen)</ESRB>
    <studio>Virgin Interactive Entertainment</studio>
    <genre>Adventure</genre>
    <emu_command>sword2</emu_command>
    <boxart1>OFODNFJ.png</boxart1>
    <banner1>JSQaU7d.png</banner1>
    <clearlogo1>WCAHkJd.png</clearlogo1>
    <snapshot1>YW7hKY8.png</snapshot1>
    <fanart1>Ejd4VVJ.jpg</fanart1>
    <boxart2>NkPyETa.jpg</boxart2>
    <snapshot2>EQNImUO.jpg</snapshot2>
    <boxart3>pVQ94Xb.png</boxart3>
    <fanart2>bdQ8hgH.jpg</fanart2>
    <fanart3>wsnVJzO.jpg</fanart3>
    <fanart4>P78Hps4.jpg</fanart4>
    <snapshot3>SQdqUEp.jpg</snapshot3>
    <snapshot4>VweG0h7.jpg</snapshot4>
  </game>
  <game name="Codename Iceman (Floppy DOS)">
    <description>Codename Iceman (Floppy DOS)</description>
    <title_clean>Codename Iceman</title_clean>
    <rom name="The_Complete_ScummVM_Collection_v2/The_Complete_ScummVM%20Collection%20v2.0.zip/The_Complete_ScummVM%20Collection%20v2.0%2FWorking%2FCodename%20Iceman%20%28Floppy%20DOS%29.zip" size="2454832"/>
    <genre>Adventure, Simulation</genre>
    <plot>In the beginning of the 21st century, Earth is experiencing a global oil shortage. Surprisingly, Tunisia remains one of the few countries still in possession of large quantities of high-quality oil. USA and Soviet governments race each other in their attempts to purchase as much oil as possible. Finally, the Soviets take a step further and kidnap the US ambassador, hoping to provoke an international incident. Naval Officer Johnny Westland is sent to Tunisia with the order of rescuing the ambassador and preventing further escalation of the conflict.[CR]Code-Name: Iceman is primarily an adventure game similar to Sierra's other works in that genre. The player navigates the protagonist in eight different directions from third-person view, and types text commands to interact with the environment. The command "Look" may be typed separately and lead to different text descriptions depending on where on screen the protagonist is positioned. The game is similar to Police Quest series in that it relies on realistic procedures, in this case military instructions, first aid, etc. The player may reach dead ends and resort to restoring an earlier save if some of these procedures are not followed properly. In addition, a considerable portion of the game consists of submarine simulation, requiring the player to navigate a submarine and fight enemy craft.</plot>
    <studio>Sierra On-Line</studio>
    <emu_command>iceman</emu_command>
    <boxart1>VTY0HW9.jpg</boxart1>
    <boxart2>1Nscjar.jpg</boxart2>
    <boxart3>iqCVtBz.jpg</boxart3>
    <clearlogo1>mYOscX5.png</clearlogo1>
    <snapshot1>WeEgjkT.gif</snapshot1>
    <snapshot10>RfUmpgV.png</snapshot10>
    <snapshot2>OvnIq45.gif</snapshot2>
    <snapshot3>XG6Anm0.gif</snapshot3>
    <snapshot4>rheSoW6.gif</snapshot4>
    <snapshot5>jouSVHO.gif</snapshot5>
    <snapshot6>lkX6Zsm.gif</snapshot6>
    <snapshot7>mkegzcO.gif</snapshot7>
    <snapshot8>e27y7Dh.gif</snapshot8>
    <snapshot9>GiFNtxF.gif</snapshot9>
  </game>
  <game name="Day Of the Tentacle (Floppy DOS)">
    <description>Day Of the Tentacle (Floppy DOS)</description>
    <title_clean>Day Of the Tentacle</title_clean>
    <rom name="The_Complete_ScummVM_Collection_v2/The_Complete_ScummVM%20Collection%20v2.0.zip/The_Complete_ScummVM%20Collection%20v2.0%2FWorking%2FDay%20Of%20the%20Tentacle%20%28Floppy%20DOS%29.zip" size="7822251"/>
    <genre>Adventure</genre>
    <plot>Purple Tentacle, one of the crazy Dr. Fred's creations, drinks contaminated water from Dr. Fred's Sludge-o-matic. He mutates into an insane genius and grows arms, and now he's plotting to take over the world. In an effort to stop him, Dr. Fred sends three friends, Bernard, Hoagie and Laverne back in time to yesterday, in order for them to turn off the Sludge-o-matic and stop the sludge from spilling into the river, thus preventing the whole incident. Naturally, the cheap doctor uses a fake diamond over a real one in his time machine, which blows up sending Hoagie 200 years into the past and Laverne 200 years into the future. Now the player must bring back Hoagie and Laverne, with the help of the time machine's ability to move objects between time periods, and then stop evil Purple from taking over the world.Day of the Tentacle is a point-and-click adventure game and a sequel to Maniac Mansion. The player controls Bernard, and later also Hoagie and Laverne, being able to switch between them at any time. By using the commands at the bottom of the screen, the character can pick up items, use them on other things, talk to people and more. Any of the three friends can also send his items across time to another friend. The game takes place in the same area, but in three different eras, and thus affecting history takes a vital part in some puzzles. For instance, Hoagie can hide an item in the 18th century, and Laverne discovers it in the 23rd century - but by then, the item may have been affected by time and changed its properties. The CD version of the game contains voice-overs for all the dialogues.</plot>
    <studio>Erbe Software, Funsoft, LucasArts Entertainment Company LLC, Softgold Computerspiele GmbH</studio>
    <emu_command>tentacle</emu_command>
    <boxart1>DerEP2J.jpg</boxart1>
    <boxart2>2JwBJdR.jpg</boxart2>
    <boxart3>VYIsrqd.jpg</boxart3>
    <snapshot1>ooRMDof.gif</snapshot1>
    <snapshot10>Y5q7uze.gif</snapshot10>
    <snapshot2>yfrwH51.gif</snapshot2>
    <snapshot3>CgGjl53.gif</snapshot3>
    <snapshot4>3bO1vZp.gif</snapshot4>
    <snapshot5>B5ZPUmc.gif</snapshot5>
    <snapshot6>fYhiZpY.gif</snapshot6>
    <snapshot7>mS3gAQC.gif</snapshot7>
    <snapshot8>Ev7ZDvj.gif</snapshot8>
    <snapshot9>nIC76x6.gif</snapshot9>
  </game>
  <game name="Discworld 1 (CD DOS v2)">
    <description>Discworld 1 (CD DOS v2)</description>
    <title_clean>Discworld 1</title_clean>
    <rom name="The_Complete_ScummVM_Collection_v2/The_Complete_ScummVM%20Collection%20v2.0.zip/The_Complete_ScummVM%20Collection%20v2.0%2FWorking%2FDiscworld%201%20%28CD%20DOS%20v2%29.zip" size="162470486"/>
    <genre>Adventure</genre>
    <plot>This adventure game puts the player in the shoes of Rincewind, a wizard whose sole purpose in life is to stay alive. He appears to be very good at it as well, because apparently the universe has decided to continuously challenge him. The game takes place in the humorous fantasy world created by Terry Pratchett. The world is called the Discworld, as it is actually a flat disc carried on the backs of four gigantic elephants, which themselves stand on the back of an even larger turtle.The story is loosely based on the novel "Guards! Guards!". Both in the book and the game, a dragon is summoned by a group of mysterious conspirators and now terrorizes the city state of Ankh-Morpork. Being the most expendable wizard of the Unseen University, Rincewind is given the task to get rid of the beast (only in the game though; in the book, the city's nightwatch has to deal with the problem).Discworld is a classical point-and-click adventure game with a few original features. For example, Rincewind's inventory is limited to two objects, and the majority of his belongings is stored in the Luggage, an intelligent chest with dozens of little feet. Furthermore, at a certain point in the game the player gains access to a time-traveling device and has to send Rincewind to the past and back in order to solve some of the puzzles.</plot>
    <studio>Dro Soft, Psygnosis Limited</studio>
    <emu_command>dw</emu_command>
    <boxart1>iCSYDxh.jpg</boxart1>
    <boxart2>YSL0SYa.jpg</boxart2>
    <boxart3>OCeQ8yc.jpg</boxart3>
    <snapshot1>2kkATyu.gif</snapshot1>
    <snapshot10>NTyGdkG.png</snapshot10>
    <snapshot2>IwO3iKV.gif</snapshot2>
    <snapshot3>QQHUh1H.gif</snapshot3>
    <snapshot4>iaIgtux.gif</snapshot4>
    <snapshot5>AWS5Vhs.gif</snapshot5>
    <snapshot6>nMb7Ayy.png</snapshot6>
    <snapshot7>WVKcfhZ.png</snapshot7>
    <snapshot8>TQjH15g.png</snapshot8>
    <snapshot9>fc7MAj7.png</snapshot9>
  </game>
  <game name="Discworld 2 (CD DOS)">
    <description>Discworld 2 (CD DOS)</description>
    <title_clean>Discworld 2</title_clean>
    <rom name="The_Complete_ScummVM_Collection_v2/The_Complete_ScummVM%20Collection%20v2.0.zip/The_Complete_ScummVM%20Collection%20v2.0%2FWorking%2FDiscworld%202%20%28CD%20DOS%29.zip" size="722797309"/>
    <genre>Adventure</genre>
    <plot>This adventure game puts the player in the shoes of Rincewind, a wizard whose sole purpose in life is to stay alive. He appears to be very good at it as well, because apparently the universe has decided to continuously challenge him. The game takes place in the humorous fantasy world created by Terry Pratchett. The world is called the Discworld, as it is actually a flat disc carried on the backs of four gigantic elephants, which themselves stand on the back of an even larger turtle.The story is loosely based on the novel "Guards! Guards!". Both in the book and the game, a dragon is summoned by a group of mysterious conspirators and now terrorizes the city state of Ankh-Morpork. Being the most expendable wizard of the Unseen University, Rincewind is given the task to get rid of the beast (only in the game though; in the book, the city's nightwatch has to deal with the problem).Discworld is a classical point-and-click adventure game with a few original features. For example, Rincewind's inventory is limited to two objects, and the majority of his belongings is stored in the Luggage, an intelligent chest with dozens of little feet. Furthermore, at a certain point in the game the player gains access to a time-traveling device and has to send Rincewind to the past and back in order to solve some of the puzzles.</plot>
    <studio>Dro Soft, Psygnosis Limited</studio>
    <emu_command>dw2</emu_command>
    <boxart1>iCSYDxh.jpg</boxart1>
    <boxart2>YSL0SYa.jpg</boxart2>
    <boxart3>OCeQ8yc.jpg</boxart3>
    <snapshot1>2kkATyu.gif</snapshot1>
    <snapshot10>NTyGdkG.png</snapshot10>
    <snapshot2>IwO3iKV.gif</snapshot2>
    <snapshot3>QQHUh1H.gif</snapshot3>
    <snapshot4>iaIgtux.gif</snapshot4>
    <snapshot5>AWS5Vhs.gif</snapshot5>
    <snapshot6>nMb7Ayy.png</snapshot6>
    <snapshot7>WVKcfhZ.png</snapshot7>
    <snapshot8>TQjH15g.png</snapshot8>
    <snapshot9>fc7MAj7.png</snapshot9>
  </game>
  <game name="Dragonsphere (CD DOS)">
    <description>Dragonsphere (CD DOS)</description>
    <title_clean>Dragonsphere</title_clean>
    <rom name="The_Complete_ScummVM_Collection_v2/The_Complete_ScummVM%20Collection%20v2.0.zip/The_Complete_ScummVM%20Collection%20v2.0%2FSVN%2FDragonsphere%20%28CD%20DOS%29.zip" size="63486014"/>
    <emu_command>dragoncd</emu_command>
    <plot>The young Callash has been just crowned the king of Gran Callahach. Twenty years ago the land was in grave peril, as the evil sorcerer Sanwe planned to conquer and ruin it. But he old king's court wizard Ner-Tom magically imprisoned Sanwe using the powers of the Dragonsphere spell. The sorcerer swore to avenge his humiliation once the spell's energy runs out. Now, this time has come, and the young hero must defeat Sanwe before he breaks free. As he approaches the sorcerer's prison, he is yet to realize that dealing with Sanwe will lead to startling realizations concerning his own self, and unravel a new sinister plot.[CR]Dragonsphere is a graphic adventure in the classic third-person LucasArts and Sierra style, and the third adventure game by MicroProse, similar visually and gameplay-wise to Rex Nebular and the Cosmic Gender Bender. The interaction with the game world is performed by applying one of the ten different verb commands to objects and people. Additionally, each object has several unique, specific verb commands that can be applied giving the player quite a number of possible combinations of object usage and sometimes more straight forward resolution to the problem. The game contains vast amounts of unique text responses to player's actions and branching dialogue with characters. Some of them are fatal for the main character so they need to be chosen wisely or accordingly to the presented facts and observations. The puzzles are, for the most part, inventory-based. The game features hand-painted backgrounds and some digitized animation.</plot>
    <boxart1>Db16Goo.jpg</boxart1>
    <boxart2>81bFSUU.jpg</boxart2>
    <snapshot1>DPyVK13.gif</snapshot1>
  </game>
  <game name="Full Throttle (CD DOS)">
    <description>Full Throttle (CD DOS)</description>
    <title_clean>Full Throttle</title_clean>
    <rom name="The_Complete_ScummVM_Collection_v2/The_Complete_ScummVM%20Collection%20v2.0.zip/The_Complete_ScummVM%20Collection%20v2.0%2FWorking%2FFull%20Throttle%20%28CD%20DOS%29.zip" size="262665469"/>
    <rating>3.93</rating>
    <nplayers>1</nplayers>
    <releasedate>30/04/1995</releasedate>
    <plot>Full Throttle is a graphic adventure game developed by LucasArts and designed by Tim Schafer. The game was released on April 20, 1995 for MS-DOS, Microsoft Windows and Mac OS. It was Schafer's first game as project lead and head writer and designer, after having worked on other LucasArts titles including The Secret of Monkey Island (1990), Monkey Island 2: LeChuck's Revenge (1991), and Day of the Tentacle (1993). Set in the near future, the game's story follows Ben, the leader of a biker gang, who is framed for the murder of a beloved motorcycle manufacturing mogul and seeks to clear his and his gang's names. A remastered version of the game was developed by Double Fine Productions and was released in April 2017 for Microsoft Windows, PlayStation 4 and PlayStation Vita.[CR]Full Throttle was LucasArts' eleventh adventure game overall and the tenth to use the company's in-house game engine, SCUMM. It featured full motion video and action sequences, using LucasArts' INSANE animation engine, which was previously utilized in Star Wars: Rebel Assault II: The Hidden Empire. It was the first LucasArts game to be released for Microsoft Windows and the first to be distributed only on CD-ROM. It also introduced a contextual pie menu through which the player controls interactions with objects and characters. In contrast to other computer games of the era, which mostly relied on in-house talent for their voice acting, Full Throttle used mostly professional voice actors, including Roy Conrad as Ben, Mark Hamill as the villainous Adrian Ripburger, Hamilton Camp as the elderly Malcolm Corley, and Kath Soucie as Ben's ally Maureen. It was one of the few LucasArts games to use licensed music, featuring songs by San Francisco-area rock band The Gone Jackals.</plot>
    <ESRB>T - Teen</ESRB>
    <genre>Adventure</genre>
    <studio>LucasArts Entertainment Company LLC</studio>
    <emu_command>ft</emu_command>
    <videoid>qj_1s_X3I-0</videoid>
    <banner1>gcqdn2O.jpg</banner1>
    <boxart1>X1m9MXq.jpg</boxart1>
    <boxart2>31WeQLH.jpg</boxart2>
    <boxart3>QYKfhtl.jpg</boxart3>
    <clearlogo1>DX0Xibv.png</clearlogo1>
    <fanart1>9hD7iwp.jpg</fanart1>
    <snapshot1>iywG6cn.jpg</snapshot1>
    <snapshot10>vYixI4J.gif</snapshot10>
    <snapshot2>NgK0NfR.jpg</snapshot2>
    <snapshot3>IUkPeFP.jpg</snapshot3>
    <snapshot4>WEPgywA.jpg</snapshot4>
    <snapshot5>tXMl6Zg.jpg</snapshot5>
    <snapshot6>pum5nng.jpg</snapshot6>
    <snapshot7>KLgzEt3.jpg</snapshot7>
    <snapshot8>GbIe1Pm.jpg</snapshot8>
    <snapshot9>8gNuEzp.gif</snapshot9>
  </game>
  <game name="Gabriel Knight 2 The Beast Within (CD, DOS)">
    <description>Gabriel Knight 2 The Beast Within (CD, DOS)</description>
    <title_clean>Gabriel Knight 2 The Beast Within</title_clean>
    <rom name="The_Complete_ScummVM_Collection_v2/The_Complete_ScummVM%20Collection%20v2.0.zip/The_Complete_ScummVM%20Collection%20v2.0%2FWorking%2FGabriel%20Knight%202%20The%20Beast%20Within%20%28CD%2C%20DOS%29.zip" size="2811282728"/>
    <plot>The Beast Within: A Gabriel Knight Mystery is a direct sequel to Gabriel Knight: Sins of the Fathers, the first in the supernatural mystery adventure series telling the story of a bookstore owner and writer Gabriel Knight, the last offspring of generations of Schattenjaegers (shadow hunters), whose task is to fight the evil forces that abound in the world.[CR]After leaving New Orleans, Gabriel moves to the Ritter Castle in Bavaria, Germany, his family heritage. One day, a group of peasants approach the castle, and the elder tells Gabriel about a terrible death of a little girl, who was killed by a vicious wolf. Suspecting the wolf could be a supernatural creature, the peasant asks the Schattenjaeger to purge the evil. The investigation brings Gabriel and his assistant Grace Nakimura to the mysterious Hunter Society and to Bavaria's dark past.[CR]The game utilizes a cast of live actors and full-motion video technology: the actors are filmed over photorealistic images of Munich and its surroundings, and nearly every interaction with the environment leads to a FMV sequence. Despite its visual style, The Beast Within is not an interactive movie, but a full-fledged adventure game with many dialogues, detective work to do, and puzzles to solve. Unlike the first game, it is entirely controlled through point-and-click actions - all the icons have been replaced by a single cursor. Both Gabriel and Grace are available as playable characters during different chapters of the story.</plot>
    <boxart1>4jfiEDI.jpg</boxart1>
    <boxart2>QByUh1b.jpg</boxart2>
    <snapshot1>9aBNbON.gif</snapshot1>
    <emu_command>gk2</emu_command>
  </game>
  <game name="Gabriel Knight Sins Of The Fathers (Floppy DOS)">
    <description>Gabriel Knight Sins Of The Fathers (Floppy DOS)</description>
    <title_clean>Gabriel Knight Sins Of The Fathers</title_clean>
    <rom name="The_Complete_ScummVM_Collection_v2/The_Complete_ScummVM%20Collection%20v2.0.zip/The_Complete_ScummVM%20Collection%20v2.0%2FWorking%2FGabriel%20Knight%20Sins%20Of%20The%20Fathers%20%28Floppy%20DOS%29.zip" size="15184625"/>
    <rating>4.00</rating>
    <nplayers>1</nplayers>
    <releasedate>17/12/1993</releasedate>
    <plot>Gabriel Knight is a wise-cracking bookstore owner and would-be author. He is the last in a long line of Shadow Hunters, those fated to fight supernatural forces of evil. Tormented by terrifying nightmares, he must spend every waking moment scouring the side streets and back alleys of New Orleans for the key to his dark past. One day, a blood-chilling murder shocks the inhabitants of the city. The police detective assigned to investigate the crime is Gabriels friend. In the beginning Gabriel collects evidence in hope of using the material for his new novel; but soon he finds himself personally involved in the investigation, and plunges deeper into the world of secret societies and murderous cults.[CR]Gabriel Knight: Sins of the Fathers is a third-person puzzle-solving adventure game. Created by Jane Jensen, the game differs from Sierras Quest games (e.g. Space Quest) by having a realistic setting and focusing (despite its supernatural elements and humor) on mature themes and detective work. In this way it is more similar to the companys earlier Laura Bow games. [CR]The games icon-based interface is the same as in Sierras previous titles, with verb commands that allow interaction with the game world and its inhabitants. Though the game still has plenty of inventory-based puzzles characteristic for classic adventure, its gameplay is heavily inclined towards dialogue. Typically, Gabriel will have to interrogate other characters, choosing conversation topics and thus gradually finding clues and advancing towards the mysterys solution.[CR]The games locations are done in hand-painted style. The CD version of the game adds full voice-overs to the dialogues, as well as narrators voice to text descriptions.</plot>
    <emu_command>gk1</emu_command>
    <boxart1>6Vx6utN.jpg</boxart1>
    <clearlogo1>WcCP5VM.png</clearlogo1>
    <snapshot1>0BzNie1.png</snapshot1>
    <boxart2>qgjfE7W.jpg</boxart2>
    <snapshot2>7VF3LTq.png</snapshot2>
    <boxart3>JE2eFs3.jpg</boxart3>
  </game>
  <game name="Gold Rush! (Floppy DOS)">
    <description>Gold Rush! (Floppy DOS)</description>
    <title_clean>Gold Rush!</title_clean>
    <rom name="The_Complete_ScummVM_Collection_v2/The_Complete_ScummVM%20Collection%20v2.0.zip/The_Complete_ScummVM%20Collection%20v2.0%2FWorking%2FGold%20Rush%21%20%28Floppy%20DOS%29.zip" size="1140587"/>
    <nplayers>1</nplayers>
    <studio>Sierra On-Line</studio>
    <plot>Gold Rush! (later retitled California: Gold Rush!) is a graphic adventure game originally released by Sierra On-Line in 1988. It was designed by Doug and Ken MacNeill.</plot>
    <genre>Adventure</genre>
    <rating>3.5</rating>
    <releasedate>18/07/1988</releasedate>
    <emu_command>goldrush</emu_command>
    <boxart1>KDR8WtM.jpg</boxart1>
    <clearlogo1>GpJIngv.png</clearlogo1>
    <snapshot1>kp10KYt.png</snapshot1>
    <fanart1>Bo68VS9.jpg</fanart1>
    <boxart2>dOK9i34.jpg</boxart2>
    <snapshot2>niZgjBz.png</snapshot2>
    <boxart3>2qZ8IKc.png</boxart3>
    <boxart4>des2KRA.jpg</boxart4>
    <snapshot10>kL5bEgt.gif</snapshot10>
    <snapshot3>mFLDVyw.gif</snapshot3>
    <snapshot4>ER6mUIL.gif</snapshot4>
    <snapshot5>y8nG2TD.gif</snapshot5>
    <snapshot6>TSdznB0.gif</snapshot6>
    <snapshot7>u3BYekV.gif</snapshot7>
    <snapshot8>GKP1IrU.gif</snapshot8>
    <snapshot9>OqBQb8Y.gif</snapshot9>
  </game>
  <game name="Hero Quest So You Want To Be A Hero (Floppy DOS)">
    <description>Hero Quest So You Want To Be A Hero (Floppy DOS)</description>
    <title_clean>Hero Quest So You Want To Be A Hero</title_clean>
    <rom name="The_Complete_ScummVM_Collection_v2/The_Complete_ScummVM%20Collection%20v2.0.zip/The_Complete_ScummVM%20Collection%20v2.0%2FWorking%2FHero%20Quest%20So%20You%20Want%20To%20Be%20A%20Hero%20%28Floppy%20DOS%29.zip" size="2617693"/>
    <nplayers>1</nplayers>
    <studio>Sierra On-Line</studio>
    <releasedate>10/01/1989</releasedate>
    <plot>As a graduate of the Famous Adventurers Correspondence School, you have journeyed to Spielburg valley to seek your fame. And boy is there fame to be had. An ogress has cursed the baron. Brigands and monsters lurk in the forest.[CR]The fame and fortune is there for the taking, youve just got to stay alive and figure out how to get it.</plot>
    <genre>Adventure</genre>
    <ESRB>ESRB - E (Everyone)</ESRB>
    <rating>4.1</rating>
    <emu_command>qfg1</emu_command>
    <boxart1>wJrBAhm.jpg</boxart1>
    <clearlogo1>1IaMrcf.png</clearlogo1>
    <snapshot1>i5IZJol.png</snapshot1>
    <fanart1>8zd8fQH.jpg</fanart1>
    <boxart2>VXL18on.jpg</boxart2>
    <snapshot2>5e7hxSn.png</snapshot2>
    <boxart3>XhK2Cy5.png</boxart3>
    <snapshot10>Xcey3Mc.gif</snapshot10>
    <snapshot3>tBoaSPj.gif</snapshot3>
    <snapshot4>vT9OcZ4.gif</snapshot4>
    <snapshot5>Yn4HGsm.gif</snapshot5>
    <snapshot6>CSUfTn4.gif</snapshot6>
    <snapshot7>P4m3i26.gif</snapshot7>
    <snapshot8>1Jtzd22.gif</snapshot8>
    <snapshot9>dgf2JZj.gif</snapshot9>
  </game>
  <game name="I Have No Mouth and I Must Scream (CD DOS)">
    <description>I Have No Mouth and I Must Scream (CD DOS)</description>
    <title_clean>I Have No Mouth and I Must Scream</title_clean>
    <rom name="The_Complete_ScummVM_Collection_v2/The_Complete_ScummVM%20Collection%20v2.0.zip/The_Complete_ScummVM%20Collection%20v2.0%2FWorking%2FI%20Have%20No%20Mouth%20and%20I%20Must%20Scream%20%28CD%20DOS%29.zip" size="417779310"/>
    <rating>4.10</rating>
    <nplayers>1</nplayers>
    <releasedate>31/10/1995</releasedate>
    <plot>I Have No Mouth, and I Must Scream is a point-and-click adventure game based upon Harlan Ellisons short story of the same title, developed by The Dreamers Guild, co-designed by Ellison and published by Cyberdreams in 1995. The games story is set in a world where an evil computer named AM has destroyed all of humanity except for five people, whom he has been keeping alive and torturing for the past 109 years. Each survivor has a fatal flaw in their character, and in an attempt to crush their spirits, AM has constructed a metaphorical adventure for each that preys upon their weaknesses. To succeed in the game, the player must make choices to prove that humans are better than machines, because they have the ability to redeem themselves. Woven into the fabric of the story are ethical dilemmas dealing with issues such as insanity, rape, paranoia and genocide.</plot>
    <ESRB>ESRB - T (Teen)</ESRB>
    <studio>Cyberdreams</studio>
    <genre>Adventure</genre>
    <emu_command>ihnm</emu_command>
    <boxart1>2dqfkU0.jpg</boxart1>
    <banner1>CR3IvVO.jpg</banner1>
    <clearlogo1>20LGuJx.png</clearlogo1>
    <snapshot1>Q0tHovy.png</snapshot1>
    <fanart1>vbvI26Y.jpg</fanart1>
    <boxart2>fkNIgQK.jpg</boxart2>
    <snapshot2>RWGsayO.jpg</snapshot2>
    <boxart3>fiBykuE.jpg</boxart3>
    <boxart4>BebYYvq.png</boxart4>
    <boxart5>5gIptFY.jpg</boxart5>
    <snapshot10>pSYAjkF.png</snapshot10>
    <snapshot3>NqJekrU.jpg</snapshot3>
    <snapshot4>1XF38LI.jpg</snapshot4>
    <snapshot5>6P3Cu24.jpg</snapshot5>
    <snapshot6>0GGVHjJ.jpg</snapshot6>
    <snapshot7>3ZCwGQ1.jpg</snapshot7>
    <snapshot8>4xVDSZK.jpg</snapshot8>
    <snapshot9>YTGjSk7.png</snapshot9>
  </game>
  <game name="Indiana Jones and the Fate of Atlantis (Floppy DOS)">
    <description>Indiana Jones and the Fate of Atlantis (Floppy DOS)</description>
    <title_clean>Indiana Jones and the Fate of Atlantis</title_clean>
    <rom name="The_Complete_ScummVM_Collection_v2/The_Complete_ScummVM%20Collection%20v2.0.zip/The_Complete_ScummVM%20Collection%20v2.0%2FWorking%2FIndiana%20Jones%20and%20the%20Fate%20of%20Atlantis%20%28Floppy%20DOS%29.zip" size="6852418"/>
    <rating>4.00</rating>
    <nplayers>1</nplayers>
    <releasedate>15/06/1992</releasedate>
    <plot>Indiana Jones and the Fate of Atlantis is a point-and-click adventure game by LucasArts originally released in 1992. Almost a year later, it was reissued on CD-ROM as an enhanced talkie edition with full voice acting and digitized sound effects. In 2009, this version was also released as an unlockable extra of the Wii action game Indiana Jones and the Staff of Kings, and as a digitally distributed Steam title. The seventh game to use the script language SCUMM, Fate of Atlantis has the player explore environments and interact with objects and characters by using commands constructed with predetermined verbs. It features three unique paths to select, influencing story development, gameplay and puzzles. The game used an updated SCUMM engine and required a 286-based PC, although it still runs as a real-mode DOS application. The CD talkie version required EMS memory enabled to load the voice data.</plot>
    <ESRB>ESRB - E (Everyone)</ESRB>
    <studio>Victor Entertainment Inc.</studio>
    <genre>Adventure</genre>
    <emu_command>atlantis</emu_command>
    <videoid>lncARrPO8Qo</videoid>
    <banner1>nUaHSoW.jpg</banner1>
    <boxart1>iE1gr4x.jpg</boxart1>
    <boxart2>N2h7dd8.jpg</boxart2>
    <boxart3>l7eX4IW.jpg</boxart3>
    <clearlogo1>skfMNa7.png</clearlogo1>
    <fanart1>jHPkKep.jpg</fanart1>
    <snapshot1>Vc7syJ0.jpg</snapshot1>
    <snapshot10>9put2wY.gif</snapshot10>
    <snapshot2>rylGyHa.jpg</snapshot2>
    <snapshot3>13XjWbC.gif</snapshot3>
    <snapshot4>qcb8wT2.gif</snapshot4>
    <snapshot5>Yz5hioF.gif</snapshot5>
    <snapshot6>E2UMiV7.gif</snapshot6>
    <snapshot7>pyFIwcj.gif</snapshot7>
    <snapshot8>lUNNZIj.gif</snapshot8>
    <snapshot9>Rtckwjs.gif</snapshot9>
  </game>
  <game name="Indiana Jones and the Last Crusade (Floppy DOS VGA)">
    <description>Indiana Jones and the Last Crusade (Floppy DOS VGA)</description>
    <title_clean>Indiana Jones and the Last Crusade</title_clean>
    <rom name="The_Complete_ScummVM_Collection_v2/The_Complete_ScummVM%20Collection%20v2.0.zip/The_Complete_ScummVM%20Collection%20v2.0%2FWorking%2FIndiana%20Jones%20and%20the%20Last%20Crusade%20%28Floppy%20DOS%20VGA%29.zip" size="3257111"/>
    <nplayers>1</nplayers>
    <ESRB>ESRB - T (Teen)</ESRB>
    <plot>It is 1938 and adventurer Indiana Jones is joined by his father on this quest, preventing Adolf Hitler from capturing the Holy Grail. He will have to deal with Nazi guards, the Luftwaffe and enemy spies as he tries to stop the tyrannical Nazi leader. The Graphic Adventure uses the same SCUMM gameplay system as the previous Maniac Mansion. Most of the screen is used for a visual rendition of the current scene. At the bottom of the screen are words, which can be clicked on using the mouse to activate their functions. For example, objects can be picked up, used, pushed or pulled, and turned on and off. Most locations are from the movie, but some further scenes are added. In keeping with Indiana's action-man persona, the game also features pure action scenes. Unlike most Lucasfilm adventures, you can die.</plot>
    <studio>Fujitsu Interactive</studio>
    <rating>4.7</rating>
    <genre>Adventure</genre>
    <releasedate>02/07/1989</releasedate>
    <emu_command>indy3</emu_command>
    <boxart1>PEueFX9.png</boxart1>
    <snapshot1>1GhoHDs.png</snapshot1>
    <banner1>C8ou6UI.png</banner1>
    <boxart2>CX6LVHb.jpg</boxart2>
    <boxart3>Z5Xaurz.jpg</boxart3>
    <clearlogo1>tdl37Ns.png</clearlogo1>
    <fanart1>Rqj6D8y.jpg</fanart1>
    <snapshot10>6ulq5JP.gif</snapshot10>
    <snapshot2>nxs3FoS.jpg</snapshot2>
    <snapshot3>f4ocIlL.jpg</snapshot3>
    <snapshot4>WUxj3Na.jpg</snapshot4>
    <snapshot5>JDUSgXl.jpg</snapshot5>
    <snapshot6>kOuVXua.jpg</snapshot6>
    <snapshot7>PD6FTN4.jpg</snapshot7>
    <snapshot8>IAn4Dca.jpg</snapshot8>
    <snapshot9>v7H0ELu.gif</snapshot9>
  </game>
  <game name="King's Quest 1 - Quest for the Crown (Floppy DOS VGA Remake)">
    <description>King's Quest 1 - Quest for the Crown (Floppy DOS VGA Remake)</description>
    <title_clean>King's Quest 1 - Quest for the Crown</title_clean>
    <rom name="The_Complete_ScummVM_Collection_v2/The_Complete_ScummVM%20Collection%20v2.0.zip/The_Complete_ScummVM%20Collection%20v2.0%2FWorking%2FKing%27s%20Quest%201%20-%20Quest%20for%20the%20Crown%20%28Floppy%20DOS%20VGA%20Remake%29.zip" size="2036003"/>
    <nplayers>1</nplayers>
    <ESRB>ESRB - E (Everyone)</ESRB>
    <plot>King's Quest- Quest for the Crown is a remake of King's Quest using Chris Jones' Adventure Game Studio engine. Unlike Sierra's own earlier remake of the same game, this version features VGA graphics, an icon-based point-and-click interface, voices (optional) and MP3 music (optional). In 2009 AGD Interactive released King's Quest I VGA 4.0, which can be considered a remake of their original 2001 remake. It contains the following enhancements- Newly enhanced game backgrounds and character dialog portraits A new no dead-ends gameplay mode (optional) to ensure that the game can be completed from any point Full narrator speech and lip-syncing for all characters Windows Vista support Native Ogg Theora movies, which means in-game cutscenes and movies will now play in Linux and PC emulations under Macs Full digital speech and music tracks are now included as part of the download rather than being separate downloads</plot>
    <studio>Sierra On-Line</studio>
    <rating>3.4</rating>
    <genre>Adventure</genre>
    <emu_command>kq1sci</emu_command>
    <boxart1>jO22iVp.jpg</boxart1>
    <boxart2>nWsHPdS.jpg</boxart2>
    <snapshot1>rGY0zzU.jpg</snapshot1>
    <snapshot2>oCgQNln.jpg</snapshot2>
  </game>
  <game name="King's Quest 2 - Romancing the Throne (Floppy DOS)">
    <description>King's Quest 2 - Romancing the Throne (Floppy DOS)</description>
    <title_clean>King's Quest 2 - Romancing the Throne</title_clean>
    <rom name="The_Complete_ScummVM_Collection_v2/The_Complete_ScummVM%20Collection%20v2.0.zip/The_Complete_ScummVM%20Collection%20v2.0%2FWorking%2FKing%27s%20Quest%202%20-%20Romancing%20the%20Throne%20%28Floppy%20DOS%29.zip" size="298321"/>
    <nplayers>1</nplayers>
    <studio>Sierra On-Line</studio>
    <releasedate>05/01/1985</releasedate>
    <plot>After having recovered the three treasures, King Graham has been crowned king. Now having needing a queen for companionship, Graham searches the land for a maiden, but to no avail, so he turns to the magic mirror for help. The mirror shows him a beautiful girl locked away in a quartz tower in a faraway land of Kolyma, and must find three keys that are used to unlock the door that will lead to her.</plot>
    <genre>Adventure</genre>
    <ESRB>ESRB - E (Everyone)</ESRB>
    <rating>3.1</rating>
    <emu_command>kq2</emu_command>
    <boxart1>nIbVdwF.jpg</boxart1>
    <banner1>HLAnEu6.jpg</banner1>
    <clearlogo1>LWT0Jvn.png</clearlogo1>
    <snapshot1>muL3lAE.png</snapshot1>
    <fanart1>WVHqwst.jpg</fanart1>
    <boxart2>kVUPp70.jpg</boxart2>
    <snapshot2>2HKUzWO.png</snapshot2>
    <boxart3>TcTlrZN.jpg</boxart3>
    <boxart4>Ynebpmf.png</boxart4>
    <boxart5>HriiSW3.jpg</boxart5>
    <snapshot10>qhak6gj.gif</snapshot10>
    <snapshot3>YxkoUya.gif</snapshot3>
    <snapshot4>1Xw3ouV.gif</snapshot4>
    <snapshot5>aSkmKjB.gif</snapshot5>
    <snapshot6>YHDyUYc.gif</snapshot6>
    <snapshot7>GhJviEG.gif</snapshot7>
    <snapshot8>mZ8jKuU.gif</snapshot8>
    <snapshot9>Il6hPaJ.gif</snapshot9>
  </game>
  <game name="King's Quest 3 - To Heir is Human (Floppy DOS)">
    <description>King's Quest 3 - To Heir is Human (Floppy DOS)</description>
    <title_clean>King's Quest 3 - To Heir is Human</title_clean>
    <rom name="The_Complete_ScummVM_Collection_v2/The_Complete_ScummVM%20Collection%20v2.0.zip/The_Complete_ScummVM%20Collection%20v2.0%2FWorking%2FKing%27s%20Quest%203%20-%20To%20Heir%20is%20Human%20%28Floppy%20DOS%29.zip" size="391143"/>
    <nplayers>1</nplayers>
    <ESRB>ESRB - E (Everyone)</ESRB>
    <plot>King Graham and Queen Valanice had two children, Alexander and Rosella, and the kingdom was once peaceful. It wasn't long until Alexander was snatched from his crib and things started to take a turn for the worse. A three-headed dragon threatens the ever-peaceful Daventry, and requires a maiden to be sacrificed every year. Rosella is the chosen one. Meanwhile, in a secluded house atop a mountain in the land of Llewdor, the evil wizard called Manannan keeps a young lad named Gwydion as his slave, forcing him to do menial tasks as he prepares his spells and observes the country through his telescope. Gwydion must find a way to outsmart the wizard, escape, and eventually discover the truth about his own identity. King's Quest III- To Heir is Human is an adventure game similar in basic gameplay mechanics to its predecessor The player navigates Gwydion with arrow keys and interacts with the environment by typing verb and noun combination commands. Llewdor consists of interconnected screens that loop once the player character reaches the border of the land. Throughout the course of the game, Gwydion will also travel to other locations and have a magic map at his disposal, allowing him to teleport to different areas. There are more items to collect in this installment, and more complex actions required to execute, raising the difficulty level. A large part of the game proceeds in real time, with Mannanan following his own schedule, forcing the player to plan and time his actions. There is also a time limit imposed on the game's first major quest.</plot>
    <studio>Sierra On-Line</studio>
    <rating>3.8</rating>
    <genre>Adventure</genre>
    <releasedate>18/07/1986</releasedate>
    <emu_command>kq3</emu_command>
    <boxart1>9jO0Hkw.jpg</boxart1>
    <boxart2>jalOZFh.jpg</boxart2>
    <boxart3>U0lQkJ1.jpg</boxart3>
    <clearlogo1>OBPQTeQ.png</clearlogo1>
    <snapshot1>h9GCnsd.gif</snapshot1>
    <snapshot10>cTU0MYl.gif</snapshot10>
    <snapshot2>yOLZZim.gif</snapshot2>
    <snapshot3>iti5djf.gif</snapshot3>
    <snapshot4>1PDvVBf.gif</snapshot4>
    <snapshot5>LGNX6Ih.gif</snapshot5>
    <snapshot6>Npo629m.gif</snapshot6>
    <snapshot7>7KYsJa7.gif</snapshot7>
    <snapshot8>a31YIv8.gif</snapshot8>
    <snapshot9>I7s1Ant.gif</snapshot9>
  </game>
  <game name="King's Quest 4 - The Perils of Rosella (Floppy DOS, SCI)">
    <description>King's Quest 4 - The Perils of Rosella (Floppy DOS, SCI)</description>
    <title_clean>King's Quest 4 - The Perils of Rosella</title_clean>
    <rom name="The_Complete_ScummVM_Collection_v2/The_Complete_ScummVM%20Collection%20v2.0.zip/The_Complete_ScummVM%20Collection%20v2.0%2FWorking%2FKing%27s%20Quest%204%20-%20The%20Perils%20of%20Rosella%20%28Floppy%20DOS%2C%20SCI%29.zip" size="2878157"/>
    <nplayers>1</nplayers>
    <ESRB>ESRB - E (Everyone)</ESRB>
    <plot>King Graham and Queen Valanice were glad to have their children back. Graham thinks that it is time to pass onto them his old adventurers' hat. When he throws it across the room, he suffers a heart attack and collapses on the floor, and he is carried off to bed. The only way that Graham's health can be restored is by retrieving the magic fruit in the faraway land of Tamir. A beautiful fairy called Genesta offers Rosella the chance to be transported to the land, and find the fruit. But once she gets transported, she cannot be sent back unless she helps the fairy regain her talisman that was stolen by the evil witch, Lolotte. King's Quest IV- The Perils of Rosella is the first game in the series to have a female protagonist. Rosella will meet characters that will either help or hinder her. The player moves Rosella around with arrow keys, and have her perform actions by typing commands. Unlike the previous King's Quest games, which used the AGI engine, this installment uses the new SCI engine with more detailed graphics; the most visible effect is that the game is paused while the player is typing, giving unlimited time to complete even the longest commands. An AGI version of the game, however, was released as well. Gameplay-wise, the game is similar to the first two installments of the series, with a large interconnected world open for exploration and no time limit imposed. The game is the first in the series to have a day and night cycle; certain actions can be performed only during a specific time.</plot>
    <studio>Sierra On-Line</studio>
    <rating>3.8</rating>
    <genre>Adventure</genre>
    <releasedate>23/09/1988</releasedate>
    <emu_command>kq4sci</emu_command>
    <boxart1>919aaMs.jpg</boxart1>
    <boxart2>ZCi4iDy.jpg</boxart2>
    <boxart3>vPrcHJY.jpg</boxart3>
    <clearlogo1>JWVmXlF.png</clearlogo1>
    <snapshot1>apdhC29.gif</snapshot1>
    <snapshot10>dtwTpgK.png</snapshot10>
    <snapshot2>mWkVoc3.gif</snapshot2>
    <snapshot3>gEjVQbj.gif</snapshot3>
    <snapshot4>PP6cyfT.gif</snapshot4>
    <snapshot5>zKCNjAb.gif</snapshot5>
    <snapshot6>mTZLOKs.gif</snapshot6>
    <snapshot7>wFQh32r.gif</snapshot7>
    <snapshot8>iSOuea2.gif</snapshot8>
    <snapshot9>rDAjZiM.gif</snapshot9>
  </game>
  <game name="King's Quest 5 - Absence Makes the Heart go Yonder (Floppy DOS)">
    <description>King's Quest 5 - Absence Makes the Heart go Yonder (Floppy DOS)</description>
    <title_clean>King's Quest 5 - Absence Makes the Heart go Yonder</title_clean>
    <rom name="The_Complete_ScummVM_Collection_v2/The_Complete_ScummVM%20Collection%20v2.0.zip/The_Complete_ScummVM%20Collection%20v2.0%2FWorking%2FKing%27s%20Quest%205%20-%20Absence%20Makes%20the%20Heart%20go%20Yonder%20%28Floppy%20DOS%29.zip" size="8800340"/>
    <rating>3.00</rating>
    <nplayers>1</nplayers>
    <releasedate>11/09/1990</releasedate>
    <plot>Dark powers summon a cold wind from the north. The terrifying gust surrounds Sir Grahams castle, and mysteriously sweeps his fortress and family into the prison of oblivion. Its a bitter omen that chills the bones of every man, woman and child in the once peaceful Kingdom of Daventry. Who or what is responsible for this royal theft, and the misery that ravages the heart of Daventry? Has the ruthless wizard Manannan cast another evil spell? Or are the Black Forest Witch and the unforgiving Ice Queen using sinister powers to promote their wicked cause? Only you can answer these questions, as you assume the role of Sir Graham, then set forth on an adventure that will test your intelligence, challenge your skill and rip your courage to shreds.</plot>
    <genre>Adventure</genre>
    <ESRB>ESRB - E (Everyone)</ESRB>
    <studio>Sierra On-Line</studio>
    <emu_command>kq5</emu_command>
    <boxart1>urQkRsU.jpg</boxart1>
    <banner1>KoVoATe.png</banner1>
    <clearlogo1>ZuhXgH7.png</clearlogo1>
    <snapshot1>pcnwmT2.png</snapshot1>
    <fanart1>vfMzn5Q.jpg</fanart1>
    <boxart2>sV6ZWMV.jpg</boxart2>
    <snapshot2>5iQKjEq.png</snapshot2>
    <boxart3>51E9oor.jpg</boxart3>
    <boxart4>ZOJxMLR.png</boxart4>
    <boxart5>OVOOy2v.jpg</boxart5>
    <snapshot10>ZgInj3p.png</snapshot10>
    <snapshot3>6gxs8EM.gif</snapshot3>
    <snapshot4>blvBvWf.gif</snapshot4>
    <snapshot5>Pp6CnIv.gif</snapshot5>
    <snapshot6>FwJOV6g.gif</snapshot6>
    <snapshot7>iSRCEnQ.gif</snapshot7>
    <snapshot8>z0g2yXd.gif</snapshot8>
    <snapshot9>McEfx6k.gif</snapshot9>
  </game>
  <game name="King's Quest 6 - Heir Today, Gone Tomorrow (Floppy DOS)">
    <description>King's Quest 6 - Heir Today, Gone Tomorrow (Floppy DOS)</description>
    <title_clean>King's Quest 6 - Heir Today, Gone Tomorrow</title_clean>
    <rom name="The_Complete_ScummVM_Collection_v2/The_Complete_ScummVM%20Collection%20v2.0.zip/The_Complete_ScummVM%20Collection%20v2.0%2FWorking%2FKing%27s%20Quest%206%20-%20Heir%20Today%2C%20Gone%20Tomorrow%20%28Floppy%20DOS%29.zip" size="12106233"/>
    <rating>3.50</rating>
    <nplayers>1</nplayers>
    <releasedate>30/09/1992</releasedate>
    <plot>For months Prince Alexander of Daventry has shut himself away from the world, thinking only of Princess Cassima, who he met while imprisoned in the previous game. Eventually he can take it no longer, and he hires a ship to search for the Land of the Green Isles located on the edge of the world. After months of searching he finally sets sight upon the island kingdom, only for a freak storm to strike the ship, destroying it and leaving him the only survivor. His troubles are far from over, however, as he soon finds out that the King and Queen have passed away, the Greens Isles are on the brink of war, and his beloved Princess Cassima may even be held prisoner by the royal vizier.</plot>
    <genre>Adventure</genre>
    <ESRB>ESRB - E (Everyone)</ESRB>
    <studio>Sierra On-Line</studio>
    <emu_command>kq6</emu_command>
    <boxart1>9RYOqQN.jpg</boxart1>
    <banner1>ZUPUkTV.jpg</banner1>
    <clearlogo1>NxM1XGh.png</clearlogo1>
    <snapshot1>Yeo9Tvw.png</snapshot1>
    <fanart1>6QrLPBI.jpg</fanart1>
    <boxart2>2liqJDi.jpg</boxart2>
    <snapshot2>FErPGcK.jpg</snapshot2>
    <boxart3>cYqrXww.jpg</boxart3>
    <boxart4>QPO3qJA.png</boxart4>
    <boxart5>GHuEShu.jpg</boxart5>
    <snapshot10>a3hhGG8.gif</snapshot10>
    <snapshot3>3epkJkQ.gif</snapshot3>
    <snapshot4>Q6Un33Q.gif</snapshot4>
    <snapshot5>FkU1XNC.gif</snapshot5>
    <snapshot6>DMXE8pN.gif</snapshot6>
    <snapshot7>Wpe1Qpl.gif</snapshot7>
    <snapshot8>wnKgUDY.gif</snapshot8>
    <snapshot9>cZIqKQg.gif</snapshot9>
  </game>
  <game name="King's Quest 7 - The Princeless Bride (CD DOS)">
    <description>King's Quest 7 - The Princeless Bride (CD DOS)</description>
    <title_clean>King's Quest 7 - The Princeless Bride</title_clean>
    <rom name="The_Complete_ScummVM_Collection_v2/The_Complete_ScummVM%20Collection%20v2.0.zip/The_Complete_ScummVM%20Collection%20v2.0%2FWorking%2FKing%27s%20Quest%207%20-%20The%20Princeless%20Bride%20%28CD%20DOS%29.zip" size="334936878"/>
    <nplayers>1</nplayers>
    <releasedate>23/11/1994</releasedate>
    <plot>The name of this entry, The Princeless Bride, is a pun on the title of the novel and film The Princess Bride. Like most Kings Quest titles, it is also a reference to the plot: Princess Rosella is soon to be a bride, but ends up in another world shortly before her marriage. It is the only entry in the series to feature Queen Valanice in a major role, and also the only one in which King Graham is not shown or mentioned at all (with one minor exception in version 1.4).[note 1] Sierra marketed the game as an improvement in the series by stating that completion of earlier KQ adventures was not necessary to fully enjoy the game, even though the final chapter revealed a strong connection to the events of Kings Quest IV.</plot>
    <genre>Adventure</genre>
    <emu_command>kq7</emu_command>
    <boxart1>v6iBJSB.jpg</boxart1>
    <banner1>D7iuMYs.png</banner1>
    <clearlogo1>gCoUSrk.png</clearlogo1>
    <snapshot1>7qfQTHE.png</snapshot1>
    <boxart2>MNpKVno.jpg</boxart2>
    <snapshot2>D3vEByX.png</snapshot2>
    <boxart3>AQ2mBtz.jpg</boxart3>
    <boxart4>6p50VBX.jpg</boxart4>
  </game>
  <game name="Laura Bow 1 - The Colonels Bequest (Floppy DOS)">
    <description>Laura Bow 1 - The Colonels Bequest (Floppy DOS)</description>
    <title_clean>Laura Bow 1 - The Colonels Bequest</title_clean>
    <rom name="The_Complete_ScummVM_Collection_v2/The_Complete_ScummVM%20Collection%20v2.0.zip/The_Complete_ScummVM%20Collection%20v2.0%2FWorking%2FLaura%20Bow%201%20-%20The%20Colonels%20Bequest%20%28Floppy%20DOS%29.zip" size="3122715"/>
    <studio>Sierra On-Line</studio>
    <plot>A murder mystery, taking place at a spooky plantation in the 1920s. College student Laura Bow is invited by her friend Lillian to come along to what has to be the most dysfunctional family gathering ever. The only problem is, various members of the family begin to mysteriously disappear! Done in the traditional Sierra adventure game style.</plot>
    <genre>Adventure</genre>
    <nplayers>1</nplayers>
    <ESRB>ESRB - T (Teen)</ESRB>
    <rating>3.8</rating>
    <emu_command>laurabow</emu_command>
    <boxart1>oqWPXA5.jpg</boxart1>
    <boxart2>hM5x3zh.jpg</boxart2>
    <boxart3>4EQiEVd.jpg</boxart3>
    <snapshot1>0tyLssV.gif</snapshot1>
    <snapshot10>u1q8581.gif</snapshot10>
    <snapshot2>478L1HV.gif</snapshot2>
    <snapshot3>xVIZbHS.png</snapshot3>
    <snapshot4>XOASYTf.gif</snapshot4>
    <snapshot5>EG51Zof.gif</snapshot5>
    <snapshot6>TDIpVS9.gif</snapshot6>
    <snapshot7>IiopKXX.gif</snapshot7>
    <snapshot8>8rMVHzA.gif</snapshot8>
    <snapshot9>gb3YOe4.gif</snapshot9>
  </game>
  <game name="Laura Bow 2 - The Dagger of Amon-Ra (Floppy DOS)">
    <description>Laura Bow 2 - The Dagger of Amon-Ra (Floppy DOS)</description>
    <title_clean>Laura Bow 2 - The Dagger of Amon-Ra</title_clean>
    <rom name="The_Complete_ScummVM_Collection_v2/The_Complete_ScummVM%20Collection%20v2.0.zip/The_Complete_ScummVM%20Collection%20v2.0%2FWorking%2FLaura%20Bow%202%20-%20The%20Dagger%20of%20Amon-Ra%20%28Floppy%20DOS%29.zip" size="6348354"/>
    <nplayers>1</nplayers>
    <ESRB>ESRB - T (Teen)</ESRB>
    <plot>One year after the events described in The Colonel's Bequest, Laura Bow, fresh out of college, is hired by a New York newspaper to write a story about the newest exhibit acquired by the local Leyendecker Museum, an ancient Egyptian dagger. However, during a party to celebrate the opening of the museum's new section, someone is murdered, the dagger is stolen, and Laura, after asking to be allowed to investigate, is locked in with the rest of the guests. This sets the stage for a series of murders, and it is up to Laura to find the person responsible for them. The Dagger of Amon Ra plays similarly to the The Colonel's Bequest, focusing primarily on exploration and clue-gathering rather than on solving puzzles, although there are more instances of inventory item collection and usage in the sequel. With the exception of the introductory act, the entire game is set in the museum. The player navigates Laura through its rooms and interacts with characters to gather information and uncover their true motives. The game's clock advances when it is triggered by certain actions or simply by moving from location to location. Some information and events may only be available in specific places and at specific times. Near the end of the game Laura will be asked to make a case to to the coroner, which involves answering a series of questions concerning the crimes. Depending on his playing style, clues discovered, and deductive skills, the player may or may not have the correct answers to all the questions. Unlike its predecessor - and like most other contemporary Sierra adventures - the game utilizes an icon-based interface instead of typing verb-object commands to interact with the environments. Topics can also be chosen from a list when the player selects the Ask command. The CD version features full speech, including narration.</plot>
    <studio>Sierra On-Line</studio>
    <rating>3.7</rating>
    <genre>Adventure</genre>
    <emu_command>laurabow2</emu_command>
    <boxart1>egEuHGs.jpg</boxart1>
    <boxart2>MIGM8Cm.jpg</boxart2>
    <boxart3>ClqO18p.jpg</boxart3>
    <snapshot1>9mx8eQB.gif</snapshot1>
    <snapshot10>TFk3I50.gif</snapshot10>
    <snapshot2>sjxNnLh.gif</snapshot2>
    <snapshot3>cCQa2x2.png</snapshot3>
    <snapshot4>pazB8pw.png</snapshot4>
    <snapshot5>tyRRynb.gif</snapshot5>
    <snapshot6>9PFPqEG.gif</snapshot6>
    <snapshot7>dxwo75q.gif</snapshot7>
    <snapshot8>hXcWdn2.png</snapshot8>
    <snapshot9>d8K9eVZ.gif</snapshot9>
  </game>
  <game name="Leisure Suit Larry 2 - Goes looking for Love (In Several Wrong Places) (Floppy DOS)">
    <description>Leisure Suit Larry 2 - Goes looking for Love (In Several Wrong Places) (Floppy DOS)</description>
    <title_clean>Leisure Suit Larry 2 - Goes looking for Love</title_clean>
    <rom name="The_Complete_ScummVM_Collection_v2/The_Complete_ScummVM%20Collection%20v2.0.zip/The_Complete_ScummVM%20Collection%20v2.0%2FWorking%2FLeisure%20Suit%20Larry%202%20-%20Goes%20looking%20for%20Love%20%28In%20Several%20Wrong%20Places%29%20%28Floppy%20DOS%29.zip" size="1674844"/>
    <nplayers>1</nplayers>
    <studio>Sierra On-Line</studio>
    <releasedate>27/10/1988</releasedate>
    <plot>Leisure Suit Larry Goes Looking for Love (In Several Wrong Places) is the second game in Al Lowes Leisure Suit Larry series. Continuing the plot of the previous game, the swinging single Larry Laffer has finally found his true love and is happily living with her. Right? Wrong!.. Because Larry is mercilessly thrown out by his great love and is left all alone, penniless, and womanless, in Los Angeles. Accidentally, Larry comes into contact with KGB agents who will pursue him all over the globe from now on. And there is also the evil doctor Noontonyt plotting evil schemes on a remote tropical island... Looks like Larry will have to forget about his women-related problems for now... or is it so?[CR]The second game in the series introduces an improved engine (allowing for full-screen graphics and mouse control for movement). As opposed to the first game, which relied on exploration of one large area, the sequel has a more linear progression, the player being continuously taken to new locations as dictated by the plot. There are less puzzles in this installment than in the previous game; however, the number of ways to die has increased, danger awaiting Larry in most places he visits.</plot>
    <genre>Adventure</genre>
    <emu_command>lsl2</emu_command>
    <boxart1>ReQq0H3.jpg</boxart1>
    <banner1>ZMopslP.jpg</banner1>
    <clearlogo1>CK8PMCe.png</clearlogo1>
    <snapshot1>RYeiG8r.png</snapshot1>
    <fanart1>n7CSFBl.png</fanart1>
    <boxart2>2yu6jE7.jpg</boxart2>
    <snapshot2>0sfKR6u.png</snapshot2>
    <boxart3>oJ89HbB.jpg</boxart3>
    <boxart4>YsMlJWH.png</boxart4>
    <snapshot10>GJIepy2.png</snapshot10>
    <snapshot3>6AWoOfI.png</snapshot3>
    <snapshot4>KAKSIb5.png</snapshot4>
    <snapshot5>pRgWHpO.gif</snapshot5>
    <snapshot6>4GKJlaw.png</snapshot6>
    <snapshot7>LvvFtQv.gif</snapshot7>
    <snapshot8>xCHCQUk.gif</snapshot8>
    <snapshot9>UR9ODyS.png</snapshot9>
  </game>
  <game name="Leisure Suit Larry 3 - Passionate Patti in Pursuit of the Pulsating Pectorals (Floppy DOS)">
    <description>Leisure Suit Larry 3 - Passionate Patti in Pursuit of the Pulsating Pectorals (Floppy DOS)</description>
    <title_clean>Leisure Suit Larry 3 - Passionate Patti in Pursuit of the Pulsating Pectorals</title_clean>
    <rom name="The_Complete_ScummVM_Collection_v2/The_Complete_ScummVM%20Collection%20v2.0.zip/The_Complete_ScummVM%20Collection%20v2.0%2FWorking%2FLeisure%20Suit%20Larry%203%20-%20Passionate%20Patti%20in%20Pursuit%20of%20the%20Pulsating%20Pectorals%20%28Floppy%20DOS%29.zip" size="2282084"/>
    <studio>Sierra On-Line</studio>
    <releasedate>11/01/1989</releasedate>
    <plot>Leisure Suit Larry III: Passionate Patti in Pursuit of the Pulsating Pectorals is the third entry in the Leisure Suit Larry series of graphical adventure games published by Sierra On-Line. It was developed for multiple platforms including DOS, Atari ST and Amiga. The game utilizes Sierras Creative Interpreter (SCI0), resulting in a graphic style similar to its immediate predecessor, as well as a larger repertoire of MIDI music.</plot>
    <genre>Adventure</genre>
    <nplayers>1</nplayers>
    <ESRB>ESRB - M (Mature)</ESRB>
    <rating>3.9</rating>
    <emu_command>lsl3</emu_command>
    <boxart1>mKzA6wP.jpg</boxart1>
    <banner1>2V4D1Jn.jpg</banner1>
    <clearlogo1>3eUeS75.png</clearlogo1>
    <snapshot1>Dd7l66q.png</snapshot1>
    <fanart1>V1okmiM.png</fanart1>
    <boxart2>JyIjWs5.jpg</boxart2>
    <snapshot2>8fhz582.png</snapshot2>
    <boxart3>1CwDYTi.jpg</boxart3>
    <boxart4>BG811AD.png</boxart4>
    <snapshot10>xxPBjRW.gif</snapshot10>
    <snapshot3>FLYb0p2.png</snapshot3>
    <snapshot4>XSi3rYt.png</snapshot4>
    <snapshot5>qlsY2iU.png</snapshot5>
    <snapshot6>JMvwVvQ.gif</snapshot6>
    <snapshot7>z0e2lzL.gif</snapshot7>
    <snapshot8>bcNdOvH.gif</snapshot8>
    <snapshot9>BTMDUqa.png</snapshot9>
  </game>
  <game name="Leisure Suit Larry 5 - Passionate Patty Does a Little Undercover Work (Floppy DOS)">
    <description>Leisure Suit Larry 5 - Passionate Patty Does a Little Undercover Work (Floppy DOS)</description>
    <title_clean>Leisure Suit Larry 5 - Passionate Patty Does a Little Undercover Work</title_clean>
    <rom name="The_Complete_ScummVM_Collection_v2/The_Complete_ScummVM%20Collection%20v2.0.zip/The_Complete_ScummVM%20Collection%20v2.0%2FWorking%2FLeisure%20Suit%20Larry%205%20-%20Passionate%20Patty%20Does%20a%20Little%20Undercover%20Work%20%28Floppy%20DOS%29.zip" size="7474888"/>
    <rating>3.75</rating>
    <studio>Sierra On-Line</studio>
    <releasedate>09/07/1991</releasedate>
    <plot>Leisure Suit Larry 5: Passionate Patti Does a Little Undercover Work is the fourth entry in the Leisure Suit Larry series of graphical adventure games published by Sierra On-Line. It is the first title in the series to have 256-color graphics and a fully icon-based interface. The title of the game is misleading, as there is no Leisure Suit Larry 4.</plot>
    <genre>Adventure</genre>
    <nplayers>1</nplayers>
    <ESRB>ESRB - M (Mature)</ESRB>
    <emu_command>lsl5</emu_command>
    <boxart1>Jm11aQg.jpg</boxart1>
    <banner1>Sas8871.jpg</banner1>
    <clearlogo1>wpwY2Ed.png</clearlogo1>
    <snapshot1>XOY44Jp.png</snapshot1>
    <boxart2>PfH0EOK.jpg</boxart2>
    <snapshot2>MoIFcSH.png</snapshot2>
    <boxart3>mPz7i2s.jpg</boxart3>
    <boxart4>1kxK1ZV.png</boxart4>
    <snapshot10>SrlXa1C.gif</snapshot10>
    <snapshot3>yCWhdOi.gif</snapshot3>
    <snapshot4>dnvTX3F.gif</snapshot4>
    <snapshot5>NDzO00J.gif</snapshot5>
    <snapshot6>PrAcbiw.gif</snapshot6>
    <snapshot7>pogcFgs.gif</snapshot7>
    <snapshot8>ZSJZuSm.gif</snapshot8>
    <snapshot9>thDyVEV.gif</snapshot9>
  </game>
  <game name="Leisure Suit Larry 6 - Shape Up or Slip Out (Floppy DOS)">
    <description>Leisure Suit Larry 6 - Shape Up or Slip Out (Floppy DOS)</description>
    <title_clean>Leisure Suit Larry 6 - Shape Up or Slip Out</title_clean>
    <rom name="The_Complete_ScummVM_Collection_v2/The_Complete_ScummVM%20Collection%20v2.0.zip/The_Complete_ScummVM%20Collection%20v2.0%2FWorking%2FLeisure%20Suit%20Larry%206%20-%20Shape%20Up%20or%20Slip%20Out%20%28Floppy%20DOS%29.zip" size="9504284"/>
    <rating>3.00</rating>
    <nplayers>1</nplayers>
    <studio>Sierra On-Line</studio>
    <plot>Leisure Suit Larry 6: Shape Up or Slip Out! is the fifth entry in the Leisure Suit Larry series of graphical adventure games published by Sierra On-Line. Originally developed for DOS, a remake was produced in CD-ROM format a year after its release. The enhanced version of the game offers revamped graphics in SVGA resolution and voice acting, a first for the series. Both versions use an icon interface similar to other Sierra games of the time, but unlike most Sierra games, the icon bar is visible at all times.</plot>
    <genre>Adventure</genre>
    <ESRB>ESRB - M (Mature)</ESRB>
    <releasedate>18/07/1993</releasedate>
    <emu_command>lsl6</emu_command>
    <boxart1>qB8HWxv.jpg</boxart1>
    <banner1>eLmQ8Bk.jpg</banner1>
    <clearlogo1>lktZC1c.png</clearlogo1>
    <snapshot1>Zb4brv7.png</snapshot1>
    <fanart1>obnWV8z.jpg</fanart1>
    <boxart2>LBZqTXR.jpg</boxart2>
    <snapshot2>cx8fB1T.jpg</snapshot2>
    <boxart3>j4N8Ydr.jpg</boxart3>
    <boxart4>yT3jw8r.png</boxart4>
    <snapshot10>E8lHDTe.png</snapshot10>
    <snapshot3>ISejFHl.gif</snapshot3>
    <snapshot4>D05NoZu.png</snapshot4>
    <snapshot5>EWhEYvm.png</snapshot5>
    <snapshot6>Zxv43EG.png</snapshot6>
    <snapshot7>PSI2XAl.gif</snapshot7>
    <snapshot8>Rv7ZwSH.png</snapshot8>
    <snapshot9>qtIYCBx.png</snapshot9>
  </game>
  <game name="Leisure Suit Larry in the Land of the Lounge Lizards (Floppy DOS VGA Remake)">
    <description>Leisure Suit Larry in the Land of the Lounge Lizards (Floppy DOS VGA Remake)</description>
    <title_clean>Leisure Suit Larry in the Land of the Lounge Lizards</title_clean>
    <rom name="The_Complete_ScummVM_Collection_v2/The_Complete_ScummVM%20Collection%20v2.0.zip/The_Complete_ScummVM%20Collection%20v2.0%2FWorking%2FLeisure%20Suit%20Larry%20in%20the%20Land%20of%20the%20Lounge%20Lizards%20%28Floppy%20DOS%20VGA%20Remake%29.zip" size="3217739"/>
    <nplayers>1</nplayers>
    <ESRB>ESRB - M (Mature)</ESRB>
    <plot>Leisure Suit Larry 1- In the Land of the Lounge Lizards is a remake of the first game in the Leisure Suit Larry series. It introduces a new interface. Instead of typing commands, the player performs the desired actions by choosing appropriate icons, and then clicking on objects on the screen to interact with them. The graphics are now 256 color VGA. There is also much more music than in the original version, and it supports more advanced sound formats.</plot>
    <studio>Sierra On-Line</studio>
    <rating>3.9</rating>
    <genre>Adventure</genre>
    <releasedate>04/06/1987</releasedate>
    <emu_command>lsl1sci</emu_command>
    <videoid>XqXpWJhsuaI</videoid>
    <boxart1>10Yga2U.jpg</boxart1>
    <boxart2>6GkM3r4.jpg</boxart2>
    <boxart3>crtUd1X.jpg</boxart3>
    <clearlogo1>Ripv3GX.png</clearlogo1>
    <snapshot1>g3vlbld.png</snapshot1>
    <snapshot10>5OB9d2T.png</snapshot10>
    <snapshot2>qqIk5UO.png</snapshot2>
    <snapshot3>U6LTRF0.gif</snapshot3>
    <snapshot4>ZVF0nkG.gif</snapshot4>
    <snapshot5>EhKCPOn.gif</snapshot5>
    <snapshot6>CQRMWOO.png</snapshot6>
    <snapshot7>MSxy08y.png</snapshot7>
    <snapshot8>3VOf8jU.png</snapshot8>
    <snapshot9>VUCxtnc.gif</snapshot9>
  </game>
  <game name="Loom (Floppy DOS EGA)">
    <description>Loom (Floppy DOS EGA)</description>
    <title_clean>Loom</title_clean>
    <rom name="The_Complete_ScummVM_Collection_v2/The_Complete_ScummVM%20Collection%20v2.0.zip/The_Complete_ScummVM%20Collection%20v2.0%2FWorking%2FLoom%20%28Floppy%20DOS%20EGA%29.zip" size="1177435"/>
    <rating>3.00</rating>
    <nplayers>1</nplayers>
    <releasedate>01/01/1990</releasedate>
    <plot>Long after the passing of the Second Shadow, when dragons ruled the twilight sky and the stars were bright and numerous, came the Age of the Great Guilds. Blacksmiths. Shepherds. Clerics. Each dedicated to the absolute control of secret knowledge.[CR]Another such Guild was the Weavers. Over the centuries, their craft transcended the limits of physical cloth, until they wove the very fabric of reality itself. Now, a strange power has swept the Weavers into oblivion, leaving behind one Weaver boy to unravel the mystery. Help young Bobbin rescue his Guild...and you just might save the universe from an unspeakable catastrophe.[CR]An Extraordinary adventure with an interface of magic…[CR]Stunning, high-resolution, 3D landscapes.[CR]Sophisticated score and musical effects.[CR]Detailed animation and special effects.[CR]Elegant point 'n' click control of characters, objects and magic spells.[CR]No burdensome typing, mapping, or inventory management.[CR]An easy and engaging game for beginners and veterans alike.</plot>
    <genre>Adventure</genre>
    <studio>Lucasfilm Games LLC</studio>
    <emu_command>loom</emu_command>
    <banner1>SG8kG13.png</banner1>
    <boxart1>R24jE6T.jpg</boxart1>
    <boxart2>wRcCPQ8.jpg</boxart2>
    <boxart3>cMuLmvj.jpg</boxart3>
    <clearlogo1>q9HMgya.png</clearlogo1>
    <snapshot1>EmAj0Cq.jpg</snapshot1>
    <snapshot10>dcRklYp.gif</snapshot10>
    <snapshot2>Dn88msT.jpg</snapshot2>
    <snapshot3>ae4RpQH.jpg</snapshot3>
    <snapshot4>rlMsncG.jpg</snapshot4>
    <snapshot5>ibLV4p4.jpg</snapshot5>
    <snapshot6>nH2fQCC.jpg</snapshot6>
    <snapshot7>qZ2U0SO.jpg</snapshot7>
    <snapshot8>1ubmcfP.jpg</snapshot8>
    <snapshot9>SHEyLvj.png</snapshot9>
  </game>
  <game name="Maniac Mansion (Floppy DOS v2 Enhanced)">
    <description>Maniac Mansion (Floppy DOS v2 Enhanced)</description>
    <title_clean>Maniac Mansion</title_clean>
    <rom name="The_Complete_ScummVM_Collection_v2/The_Complete_ScummVM%20Collection%20v2.0.zip/The_Complete_ScummVM%20Collection%20v2.0%2FWorking%2FManiac%20Mansion%20%28Floppy%20DOS%20v2%20Enhanced%29.zip" size="333759"/>
    <rating>3.10</rating>
    <studio>Jaleco</studio>
    <releasedate>10/05/1987</releasedate>
    <plot>Maniac Mansion is a 1987 graphic adventure video game developed and published by Lucasfilm Games. It follows teenage protagonist Dave Miller as he attempts to rescue his girlfriend from a mad scientist, whose mind has been enslaved by a sentient meteor. The player uses a point-and-click interface to guide Dave and two of his six playable friends through the scientists mansion while solving puzzles and avoiding dangers. Gameplay is non-linear, and the game must be completed in different ways based on the players choice of characters. Initially released for the Commodore 64 and Apple II, Maniac Mansion was Lucasfilm Games first self-published product.</plot>
    <genre>Adventure</genre>
    <nplayers>1</nplayers>
    <ESRB>ESRB - E (Everyone)</ESRB>
    <emu_command>maniac</emu_command>
    <boxart1>RqAgDUj.png</boxart1>
    <banner1>vvQFVKe.jpg</banner1>
    <clearlogo1>7gIwDW7.png</clearlogo1>
    <snapshot1>BNYVa33.png</snapshot1>
    <boxart2>jV1Xom0.jpg</boxart2>
    <snapshot2>PPBMpnM.png</snapshot2>
    <boxart3>XjzjXS0.jpg</boxart3>
    <boxart4>rUMpEuZ.png</boxart4>
    <snapshot10>29myrCy.png</snapshot10>
    <snapshot3>AsuWyiS.jpg</snapshot3>
    <snapshot4>JNalpkv.jpg</snapshot4>
    <snapshot5>HzuKMHY.jpg</snapshot5>
    <snapshot6>Ba61Way.jpg</snapshot6>
    <snapshot7>fV2K5CZ.jpg</snapshot7>
    <snapshot8>Wv7TOdq.jpg</snapshot8>
    <snapshot9>KXXQdDQ.gif</snapshot9>
  </game>
  <game name="Monkey Island 2 LeChuck's Revenge (Floppy DOS VGA)">
    <description>Monkey Island 2 LeChuck's Revenge (Floppy DOS VGA)</description>
    <title_clean>Monkey Island 2 LeChuck's Revenge</title_clean>
    <rom name="The_Complete_ScummVM_Collection_v2/The_Complete_ScummVM%20Collection%20v2.0.zip/The_Complete_ScummVM%20Collection%20v2.0%2FWorking%2FMonkey%20Island%202%20LeChuck%27s%20Revenge%20%28Floppy%20DOS%20VGA%29.zip" size="6819120"/>
    <rating>4.41</rating>
    <nplayers>1</nplayers>
    <releasedate>12/01/1991</releasedate>
    <plot>Monkey Island 2: LeChucks Revenge is an adventure game developed and published by LucasArts in 1991. It was the second game of the Monkey Island series, following The Secret of Monkey Island, and the sixth LucasArts game to use the SCUMM engine. It was the first game to use the iMUSE sound system.</plot>
    <ESRB>ESRB - E10+ (Everyone 10+)</ESRB>
    <studio>Lucasfilm Games LLC</studio>
    <genre>Adventure</genre>
    <emu_command>monkey2</emu_command>
    <boxart1>J1ErOXo.jpg</boxart1>
    <boxart2>F5nAD33.jpg</boxart2>
    <boxart3>inbPLfi.jpg</boxart3>
    <clearlogo1>MBcwJNm.png</clearlogo1>
    <fanart1>SB5iR3O.jpg</fanart1>
    <fanart2>rxTJHp7.jpg</fanart2>
    <snapshot1>E4GyX3a.jpg</snapshot1>
    <snapshot10>pCVQxWx.gif</snapshot10>
    <snapshot2>vGK5Ch3.jpg</snapshot2>
    <snapshot3>V4XWmmz.jpg</snapshot3>
    <snapshot4>WpwlHhv.jpg</snapshot4>
    <snapshot5>vMohg9E.jpg</snapshot5>
    <snapshot6>7vgPsdf.jpg</snapshot6>
    <snapshot7>A03Hqsh.jpg</snapshot7>
    <snapshot8>EUwNvQb.jpg</snapshot8>
    <snapshot9>l2mwq2Y.gif</snapshot9>
  </game>
  <game name="Myst (CD Windows)">
    <description>Myst (CD Windows)</description>
    <title_clean>Myst</title_clean>
    <rom name="The_Complete_ScummVM_Collection_v2/The_Complete_ScummVM%20Collection%20v2.0.zip/The_Complete_ScummVM%20Collection%20v2.0%2FWorking%2FMyst%20%28CD%20Windows%29.zip" size="456607356"/>
    <rating>4.50</rating>
    <studio>Broderbund</studio>
    <releasedate>17/03/1995</releasedate>
    <plot>Myst is a graphic adventure puzzle video game designed by the brothers Robyn and Rand Miller. It was developed by Cyan, Inc., published by Brøderbund, and initially released on the Macintosh platform in 1993. Remakes and ports of the game have been released for platforms including the Sega Saturn, PlayStation, 3DO, Microsoft Windows, Atari Jaguar CD, CD-i, AmigaOS, PlayStation Portable, Nintendo DS, iOS, OS X, and Android.</plot>
    <genre>Action</genre>
    <boxart1>qrmVVYS.jpg</boxart1>
    <emu_command>myst</emu_command>
  </game>
  <game name="Police Quest 1 - In Pursuite of the Death Angel (Floppy DOS VGA Remake)">
    <description>Police Quest 1 - In Pursuite of the Death Angel (Floppy DOS VGA Remake)</description>
    <title_clean>Police Quest 1 - In Pursuite of the Death Angel</title_clean>
    <rom name="The_Complete_ScummVM_Collection_v2/The_Complete_ScummVM%20Collection%20v2.0.zip/The_Complete_ScummVM%20Collection%20v2.0%2FWorking%2FPolice%20Quest%201%20-%20In%20Pursuite%20of%20the%20Death%20Angel%20%28Floppy%20DOS%20VGA%20Remake%29.zip" size="14296437"/>
    <studio>Sierra</studio>
    <plot>This enhanced remake of Police Quest has been completely re-drawn using 256-color VGA graphics. Instead of the text-based interface of the original version, the remake features icons corresponding to the commands Walk, Look, Touch, and Talk for interaction with the game world.[CR]The two versions also have some gameplay-related differences. The driving sequences from the original game have been simplified: the player is no longer required to physically navigate the car and input is limited to making the right turns while the car is driven automatically, and occasionally braking at stop signs. The mandatory poker mini-game during the final segment of the game has been made optional. A few puzzles have different solutions, though not all of those are simplified, and in some instances the puzzles have become more complex in the remake.[CR]Story-wise, the game remains the same for the most part, but it also includes re-written and additional dialogue not seen in the earlier version.</plot>
    <genre>Adventure</genre>
    <nplayers>1</nplayers>
    <ESRB>ESRB - T (Teen)</ESRB>
    <rating>3.9</rating>
    <emu_command>pq1sci</emu_command>
    <boxart1>98lcAgW.jpg</boxart1>
    <boxart2>0yp6ALj.jpg</boxart2>
    <boxart3>OYj6Yrg.jpg</boxart3>
    <snapshot1>hevlhcE.png</snapshot1>
    <snapshot10>F1w1iTj.jpg</snapshot10>
    <snapshot2>cXNXgzq.png</snapshot2>
    <snapshot3>6iH2A1V.jpg</snapshot3>
    <snapshot4>PUkplnL.jpg</snapshot4>
    <snapshot5>mvwSH37.jpg</snapshot5>
    <snapshot6>xHiCvpq.jpg</snapshot6>
    <snapshot7>KMnk2IX.jpg</snapshot7>
    <snapshot8>ca63ejR.jpg</snapshot8>
    <snapshot9>S0k3LSU.jpg</snapshot9>
  </game>
  <game name="Police Quest 2 - The Vengeance (Floppy DOS)">
    <description>Police Quest 2 - The Vengeance (Floppy DOS)</description>
    <title_clean>Police Quest 2 - The Vengeance</title_clean>
    <rom name="The_Complete_ScummVM_Collection_v2/The_Complete_ScummVM%20Collection%20v2.0.zip/The_Complete_ScummVM%20Collection%20v2.0%2FWorking%2FPolice%20Quest%202%20-%20The%20Vengeance%20%28Floppy%20DOS%29.zip" size="1849130"/>
    <nplayers>1</nplayers>
    <ESRB>ESRB - T (Teen)</ESRB>
    <plot>Little time has passed since the events of Police Quest, when Sonny Bonds climbed the ranks of the Lytton police department and became the key element in the arrest of Jesse Bains, the notorious drug lord. After the trial, Sonny's application to the Homicide division was accepted and proposed to Marie, who had her prostitution charges dropped and started a new life away from the streets. Life was good - until Bains escaped, taking advantage of a low-security prison and an inexperienced correctional officer. Sonny is now in danger from a vengeful Bains and is saddled with his new chain-smoker partner Keith. Sonny goes to the field again to capture Bains, but things are about to get awfully personal... Using Sierra's new SCI engine, the graphics are more vibrant than in the first game, but gameplay remains basically the same, with the player ordering Sonny to move to a place in the scene (either using the directional keys or the new mouse interface) and a parser interface to interact with the game world. Game sequences are more varied, and include a shooting range, an underwater search or searching the inside of an escape vehicle. The driving sequences are gone, and the player can relax while reading the chatter between Sonny and Keith as they move from location to location. The approach to the game, however, is radically different. While the first (for a large part) is based on street police work, this sequel is oriented into forensics field work such as collecting evidences that link Bains into the happenings of the game.</plot>
    <studio>Sierra On-Line</studio>
    <rating>3.6</rating>
    <genre>Adventure</genre>
    <releasedate>18/07/1988</releasedate>
    <emu_command>pq2</emu_command>
    <boxart1>sAAYEy6.jpg</boxart1>
    <boxart2>COanpvV.jpg</boxart2>
    <boxart3>tGK5iCA.jpg</boxart3>
    <clearlogo1>7NGmP96.png</clearlogo1>
    <snapshot1>DyvZcH6.png</snapshot1>
    <snapshot10>DEPwraC.png</snapshot10>
    <snapshot2>89Bmg1p.png</snapshot2>
    <snapshot3>zdtnqxn.png</snapshot3>
    <snapshot4>VQCVvJ5.png</snapshot4>
    <snapshot5>FnFZdxR.png</snapshot5>
    <snapshot6>sy0f99i.png</snapshot6>
    <snapshot7>I427IqP.png</snapshot7>
    <snapshot8>jZju4mJ.png</snapshot8>
    <snapshot9>oNU8GUU.png</snapshot9>
  </game>
  <game name="Police Quest 3 - The Kindred (Floppy DOS)">
    <description>Police Quest 3 - The Kindred (Floppy DOS)</description>
    <title_clean>Police Quest 3 - The Kindred</title_clean>
    <rom name="The_Complete_ScummVM_Collection_v2/The_Complete_ScummVM%20Collection%20v2.0.zip/The_Complete_ScummVM%20Collection%20v2.0%2FWorking%2FPolice%20Quest%203%20-%20The%20Kindred%20%28Floppy%20DOS%29.zip" size="5465709"/>
    <nplayers>1</nplayers>
    <ESRB>ESRB - T (Teen)</ESRB>
    <plot>Sonny Bonds, the sergeant of Lytton police department, thought he could finally enjoy peaceful life with his wife Marie after the drug lord Jessie Bains has been put away for good. However, a series of gruesome murders perpetrated by a sinister cult known as The Kindred shocks the city. Marie becomes a victim of their attack and falls into a coma. It becomes Sonny's very personal mission to track down the attackers and make them pay for their crimes. The Kindred is the third installment of the Police Quest series, its events taking place after those described in The Vengeance. The game brings back some of the elements of the first game, such as a modified version of driving sequences and police procedures unrelated to the main plot the protagonist must go through. Computer work is particularly emphasized, requiring the player to perform tasks such as using facial composite software or figuring out murder patterns by studying a map. Like other Sierra adventures of the time, the game uses an icon-based interface for interaction with the environment.</plot>
    <studio>Sierra On-Line</studio>
    <rating>3.8</rating>
    <genre>Adventure</genre>
    <releasedate>18/10/1991</releasedate>
    <emu_command>pq3</emu_command>
    <boxart1>F8xd4Q5.jpg</boxart1>
    <boxart2>H8ikcjP.jpg</boxart2>
    <boxart3>Pun0eoB.jpg</boxart3>
    <clearlogo1>BMAFyLe.png</clearlogo1>
    <snapshot1>K9GxyUW.jpg</snapshot1>
    <snapshot10>vnCVnvX.gif</snapshot10>
    <snapshot2>CKS7Lh0.jpg</snapshot2>
    <snapshot3>vLao3cn.jpg</snapshot3>
    <snapshot4>rjpAR6g.jpg</snapshot4>
    <snapshot5>ezoSp8e.jpg</snapshot5>
    <snapshot6>KDo1QrP.jpg</snapshot6>
    <snapshot7>djAfwzN.png</snapshot7>
    <snapshot8>zAxYvF0.png</snapshot8>
    <snapshot9>HPe4vMe.gif</snapshot9>
  </game>
  <game name="Police Quest 4 - Open Season (Floppy DOS)">
    <description>Police Quest 4 - Open Season (Floppy DOS)</description>
    <title_clean>Police Quest 4 - Open Season</title_clean>
    <rom name="The_Complete_ScummVM_Collection_v2/The_Complete_ScummVM%20Collection%20v2.0.zip/The_Complete_ScummVM%20Collection%20v2.0%2FWorking%2FPolice%20Quest%204%20-%20Open%20Season%20%28Floppy%20DOS%29.zip" size="19178612"/>
    <nplayers>1</nplayers>
    <studio>Sierra</studio>
    <plot>Police Quest: Open Season is the fourth installment in the Police Quest series. It abandons the story arc of the previous three games, introducing a new setting and a new protagonist, homicide detective John Carey of the Los Angeles Police Department. Carey finds his best friend and ex-partner, Officer Bob Hickman, murdered in an alley in the Southern part of the city. An eight-year-old boy named Bobby Washington has been murdered as well. Carey begins an investigation that leads him deep into the criminal life of the city and a hunt for a maniacal murderer.[CR]The game utilizes Sierras traditional icon-based interface for interaction with the environment and generally follows an adventure format. However, it focuses on realistic police procedures even more than the previous games in the series. Much of the gameplay is dedicated to examining crime scenes, questioning suspects, and conducting a by-the-book investigation. There is a considerable degree of freedom in the interaction, allowing the player to perform actions not connected to the main story, some of which will, however, lead to the protagonists death. The game utilizes digitized photorealistic images for its visuals.</plot>
    <genre>Adventure</genre>
    <emu_command>pq4</emu_command>
    <boxart1>sxdj918.jpg</boxart1>
    <snapshot1>6El1Ly3.jpg</snapshot1>
    <boxart2>rFBWsdr.jpg</boxart2>
    <snapshot2>1UrjAOB.png</snapshot2>
    <boxart3>2AAVmsp.jpg</boxart3>
  </game>
  <game name="Quest for Glory 1 - So You Want to be a Hero (Floppy DOS VGA Remake)">
    <description>Quest for Glory 1 - So You Want to be a Hero (Floppy DOS VGA Remake)</description>
    <title_clean>Quest for Glory 1 - So You Want to be a Hero</title_clean>
    <rom name="The_Complete_ScummVM_Collection_v2/The_Complete_ScummVM%20Collection%20v2.0.zip/The_Complete_ScummVM%20Collection%20v2.0%2FWorking%2FQuest%20for%20Glory%201%20-%20So%20You%20Want%20to%20be%20a%20Hero%20%28Floppy%20DOS%20VGA%20Remake%29.zip" size="6833674"/>
    <nplayers>1</nplayers>
    <studio>Sierra</studio>
    <releasedate>25/06/1992</releasedate>
    <plot>Quest for Glory I: So You Want To Be A Hero is a remake of Heros Quest: So You Want To Be A Hero.[CR]The remake features 256-color VGA graphics. Locations have been re-drawn, and character portraits appear during conversations. This version also has an icon-based interface instead of the text input of the original, very similar to the one used by Sierra for their adventure titles. The player selects dialogue choices from a dialogue menu, as opposed to typing in conversation topics in the earlier release. A few changes have been made to the dialogue, adding (or altering) some of the easter eggs and references to other games.[CR]Combat now features clay models for the enemies and stop-motion animation. The perspective has been switched to an over-the-shoulder view farther away from the player. Battle commands (two types of attacks, parry, and dodge) are displayed as icons on a shield in the corner of the screen. The player can switch to the spell menu at any time, and also click the middle of the screen to escape from combat.</plot>
    <genre>Adventure</genre>
    <ESRB>ESRB - E (Everyone)</ESRB>
    <rating>4.1</rating>
    <emu_command>qfg1vga</emu_command>
    <boxart1>BkymNEA.jpg</boxart1>
    <clearlogo1>jwoGAgq.png</clearlogo1>
    <snapshot1>DpGR5tf.png</snapshot1>
    <fanart1>acU5QHi.jpg</fanart1>
    <boxart2>HOWCiJG.jpg</boxart2>
    <snapshot2>HsyUriu.png</snapshot2>
    <boxart3>P5j5mQA.jpg</boxart3>
    <boxart4>yddYRIH.png</boxart4>
    <snapshot10>1Fsf5aH.gif</snapshot10>
    <snapshot3>3N9CGwR.gif</snapshot3>
    <snapshot4>PJ5UmCa.gif</snapshot4>
    <snapshot5>APGapDa.gif</snapshot5>
    <snapshot6>Dar7WQX.gif</snapshot6>
    <snapshot7>DUjQHDS.gif</snapshot7>
    <snapshot8>BtK0wQq.gif</snapshot8>
    <snapshot9>djajQQU.gif</snapshot9>
  </game>
  <game name="Quest for Glory 2 - Trial by Fire (Floppy DOS)">
    <description>Quest for Glory 2 - Trial by Fire (Floppy DOS)</description>
    <title_clean>Quest for Glory 2 - Trial by Fire</title_clean>
    <rom name="The_Complete_ScummVM_Collection_v2/The_Complete_ScummVM%20Collection%20v2.0.zip/The_Complete_ScummVM%20Collection%20v2.0%2FWorking%2FQuest%20for%20Glory%202%20-%20Trial%20by%20Fire%20%28Floppy%20DOS%29.zip" size="4528846"/>
    <nplayers>1</nplayers>
    <ESRB>ESRB - E (Everyone)</ESRB>
    <plot>Quest for Glory II- Trial by Fire is a remake of the earlier game game of the same name. It features 256-color VGA graphics (as opposed to the original's 16-color EGA) and an icon-based interface very similar to that of the third game. All the original locations, dialogues, and gameplay elements have been preserved. Though the interface is mouse-based, the player still has the options of choosing topics during conversations by typing them, along with selecting them from a menu. The remake features additional dialogue options and easter eggs connected to subsequent installments of the series. There is also an option to simplify the maze-like layout of the town Shapeir; the street names in the town are displayed when highlighted, allowing easier navigation. Combat preserves the available commands of the original version, adding the possibility of advancing and retreating on the battle screens. Another new feature is the option to set battles on auto, customizing the hero's actions.</plot>
    <studio>Sierra On-Line</studio>
    <rating>4.0</rating>
    <genre>Adventure, RPG</genre>
    <releasedate>18/07/1990</releasedate>
    <emu_command>qfg2</emu_command>
    <videoid>MzPHJur9xT8</videoid>
    <boxart1>gqr2Wys.jpg</boxart1>
    <boxart2>xD8312Q.jpg</boxart2>
    <boxart3>bp3lztj.jpg</boxart3>
    <clearlogo1>l2OCDtk.png</clearlogo1>
    <snapshot1>e2sbvfn.gif</snapshot1>
    <snapshot10>04Eql9H.gif</snapshot10>
    <snapshot2>G4nFoYy.gif</snapshot2>
    <snapshot3>5WSUeH9.gif</snapshot3>
    <snapshot4>PG0BeUm.gif</snapshot4>
    <snapshot5>o6WkP14.gif</snapshot5>
    <snapshot6>xPCYDzY.gif</snapshot6>
    <snapshot7>VmfmSVB.gif</snapshot7>
    <snapshot8>7C29EAo.gif</snapshot8>
    <snapshot9>d3ZSvaL.gif</snapshot9>
  </game>
  <game name="Quest for Glory 3 - The Wages of War (Floppy DOS)">
    <description>Quest for Glory 3 - The Wages of War (Floppy DOS)</description>
    <title_clean>Quest for Glory 3 - The Wages of War</title_clean>
    <rom name="The_Complete_ScummVM_Collection_v2/The_Complete_ScummVM%20Collection%20v2.0.zip/The_Complete_ScummVM%20Collection%20v2.0%2FWorking%2FQuest%20for%20Glory%203%20-%20The%20Wages%20of%20War%20%28Floppy%20DOS%29.zip" size="6908442"/>
    <nplayers>1</nplayers>
    <ESRB>ESRB - E (Everyone)</ESRB>
    <plot>Wages of War is the third game in the Quest for Glory series. It is set in the Africa-like world of Tarna, where the hero travels with paladin Rakeesh, his new Liontaur friend he has met in the previous game. Shortly after his arrival, the hero learns about the conflict between the human Simbani tribe and the seemingly malevolent neighboring Leopardmen. It is now time for our hero to become a skillful diplomat and prevent an upcoming war between the two nations. The basic gameplay system is similar to that of the two preceding games. The game has an adventure-like structure and gameplay elements, including puzzles to solve, inventory items to use, and characters to talk to, as well as a role-playing system with combat and character development. As in the predecessors, the player character can be either a fighter, a thief, or a mage; in this installment, the paladin class is selectable from the beginning of the game (unlike the previous game, where the hero could only earn the title of a paladin during the course of the story). Saved characters from the previous game can be imported. Like in the earlier Quest for Glory games, the main character's parameters increase directly after battles or by repeatedly performing various actions. New to the series is an overworld map on which the hero travels between locations. Hostile encounters may occur randomly while traversing the map. Combat system is similar to the predecessors, with real-time battles where the player selects various offensive and defensive options. Graphics engine and interface in this installment are the same as in the remake of the first game- it has 256-color graphics and an icon-based interface which was used by Sierra for their contemporary adventure games.</plot>
    <studio>Sierra On-Line</studio>
    <rating>3.8</rating>
    <emu_command>qfg3</emu_command>
    <boxart1>dWxrZyC.jpg</boxart1>
    <boxart2>0s6z3Z3.jpg</boxart2>
    <snapshot1>xgwa9NW.gif</snapshot1>
  </game>
  <game name="Quest for Glory 4 - Shadows Of Darkness (Floppy DOS)">
    <description>Quest for Glory 4 - Shadows Of Darkness (Floppy DOS)</description>
    <title_clean>Quest for Glory 4 - Shadows Of Darkness</title_clean>
    <rom name="The_Complete_ScummVM_Collection_v2/The_Complete_ScummVM%20Collection%20v2.0.zip/The_Complete_ScummVM%20Collection%20v2.0%2FSVN%2FQuest%20for%20Glory%204%20-%20Shadows%20Of%20Darkness%20%28Floppy%20DOS%29.zip" size="13557215"/>
    <plot>You've saved the world, twice... You just want to bask in the glory of victory and maybe take a vacation. Without warning, youre magically transported from Tarna to a dark, gloomy place. Welcome to Mordavia, a land full of charm... and danger.</plot>
    <genre>Adventure</genre>
    <emu_command>qfg4</emu_command>
    <boxart1>rFcVn4K.jpg</boxart1>
    <snapshot1>Rac7dFb.png</snapshot1>
    <fanart1>Xmj7snF.png</fanart1>
    <boxart2>SHKgTt8.jpg</boxart2>
    <boxart3>SVsLGeq.jpg</boxart3>
  </game>
  <game name="Riven (CD Windows)">
    <description>Riven (CD Windows)</description>
    <title_clean>Riven</title_clean>
    <rom name="The_Complete_ScummVM_Collection_v2/The_Complete_ScummVM%20Collection%20v2.0.zip/The_Complete_ScummVM%20Collection%20v2.0%2FWorking%2FRiven%20%28CD%20Windows%29.zip" size="2186520237"/>
    <emu_command>riven</emu_command>
    <plot>After the Stranger has rescued Atrus, the master of linking books, from the imprisonment caused by his sons, a new task awaits the hero. Atrus's wife, Catherine, has been taken by Gehn, his own father. Gehn has appointed himself as the one to rule the Age of Riven, and has driven his world to collapse. Now he holds Catherine hostage on Riven, hoping that his son will restore the book link to the Age and free him from there. The Stranger is requested by Atrus to travel to Riven and find a way to rescue Catherine.[CR]Riven is a sequel to Myst, and is very similar to its predecessor in gameplay style, controls, and visual presentation. The game world is presented as a series of computer-generated still screens; the player explores it in a point-and-click fashion. Interaction with the environment is possible only when said environment is highlighted as a "hot spot", and is also performed by simple clicking. Like its predecessor, Riven is heavy on puzzles, which rarely include using inventory items, but usually involve understanding and manipulating the complex environments and machinery of the game world.</plot>
    <boxart1>lwl0THT.jpg</boxart1>
    <boxart2>8VMuFQo.jpg</boxart2>
    <snapshot1>XXxllpP.jpg</snapshot1>
  </game>
  <game name="Sam and Max Hit the Road (Floppy DOS)">
    <description>Sam and Max Hit the Road (Floppy DOS)</description>
    <title_clean>Sam and Max Hit the Road</title_clean>
    <rom name="The_Complete_ScummVM_Collection_v2/The_Complete_ScummVM%20Collection%20v2.0.zip/The_Complete_ScummVM%20Collection%20v2.0%2FWorking%2FSam%20and%20Max%20Hit%20the%20Road%20%28Floppy%20DOS%29.zip" size="8393806"/>
    <ESRB>T - Teen</ESRB>
    <genre>Adventure</genre>
    <nplayers>1</nplayers>
    <plot>Sam and Max, Canine Shamus and hyperkinetic rabbity thing, are the freelance police. Private investigators who receive missions from and are answerable to "The Commissioner". Upon the completion of a rescue mission from the clutches of a mad scientist, Sam and Max drive through the opening credits and immediately receive a new assignment: Bruno the Bigfoot is missing from the circus and seems to have kidnapped Trixie, the Giraffe-Neck Girl. Sam and Max are on the case and will follow the mystery all across the United States, even if it takes them to such locations as The World's Largest Ball of Twine and The Mount Rushmore Dinosaur Tarpit.[CR]Sam and Max Hit the Road is a side-scrolling point-and-click  adventure game. The player directly controls Sam, though Max will usually follow closely behind and is even available to use directly as an item in the inventory. Sam is able to be directed anywhere on the screen, Look at objects, try to use objects, try to speak to objects and use items from his inventory on objects. Sam and Max must unravel the mystery piece by piece in order to unlock new locations on their map. They can travel between these locations at any time by using the car keys on their police car. During conversation, the player is able to make Sam ask questions of persons, speak non-sequitur exclamations, or ask about specific objects, people, and locations (which are also unlocked as clues are discovered).[CR]The game also features a variety of mini-games, which can be accessed at any time once found. These include Highway-Sufring: a game where the player must jump over exit signs on the interstate, Car Bomb: A variant on Battleship, A Sam and Max coloring book and a Sam and Max dress-up game and Wak-A-Rat.</plot>
    <rating>4.1</rating>
    <releasedate>18/07/1993</releasedate>
    <studio>LucasArts Entertainment Company LLC</studio>
    <emu_command>samnmax</emu_command>
    <videoid>OtaCwN6wOAw</videoid>
    <boxart1>cC2fECO.jpg</boxart1>
    <boxart2>jFWtJKD.jpg</boxart2>
    <boxart3>XpDyJJC.jpg</boxart3>
    <clearlogo1>Rfh2fmQ.png</clearlogo1>
    <fanart1>3EYcezp.jpg</fanart1>
    <fanart2>CBH3ntZ.jpg</fanart2>
    <fanart3>f33CwnF.jpg</fanart3>
    <snapshot1>1Hrkl5d.jpg</snapshot1>
    <snapshot10>MdGxHqc.png</snapshot10>
    <snapshot2>uLmYV7c.png</snapshot2>
    <snapshot3>rF4DQ3p.png</snapshot3>
    <snapshot4>5DIL21C.png</snapshot4>
    <snapshot5>zEuW0sx.png</snapshot5>
    <snapshot6>HPhR7sL.png</snapshot6>
    <snapshot7>T5b7SwT.png</snapshot7>
    <snapshot8>Hl0bltJ.png</snapshot8>
    <snapshot9>RCDJzup.png</snapshot9>
  </game>
  <game name="Simon the Sorcerer 1 (Floppy DOS)">
    <description>Simon the Sorcerer 1 (Floppy DOS)</description>
    <title_clean>Simon the Sorcerer 1</title_clean>
    <rom name="The_Complete_ScummVM_Collection_v2/The_Complete_ScummVM%20Collection%20v2.0.zip/The_Complete_ScummVM%20Collection%20v2.0%2FWorking%2FSimon%20the%20Sorcerer%201%20%28Floppy%20DOS%29.zip" size="4462039"/>
    <genre>Adventure</genre>
    <plot>Simon is just an ordinary boy living in modern-day England. One day, his dog Chippy discovers a chest with a book inside, entitled Ye Olde Spellbooke. Without thinking too much, Simon throws the book on the floor; as a result, a portal opens, teleporting the boy and his dog into a fantasy world. Simon is promptly captured by goblins bent on cooking and eating him, but manages to escape. Soon he realizes that he must play the role of an apprentice sorcerer and rescue a benevolent wizard called Calypso from an evil one, aptly named Sordid.Simon the Sorcerer is a point-and-click adventure game very similar to contemporary LucasArts titles (in particular Monkey Island) in concept and gameplay. It features twelve verbs displayed on the screen at all times for interaction with the environment. Objects that can be interacted with are highlighted when the player hovers the mouse cursor over them. The puzzles are inventory-based: Simon will have to collect and carry a large amount of items in order to advance in the game. Almost every character comes with an extended dialogue tree to explore. Most of the conversation choices are used for a humorous effect and are not required to pursue. Like in LucasArts' adventures, it is impossible to get irrevocably stuck or die in Simon the Sorcerer. The game world consists of dozens of interconnected screens, most of which are accessible from the very beginning. Although there is usually only one way to solve the puzzles, the player can work on multiple tasks at once, and exploration occupies a large portion of the game. Whenever an important location is discovered, it is marked on the map for instant access, so that the player is not required to retrace his steps in order to revisit it. The game frequently parodies popular fairy tales and fantasy works and sometimes breaks the fourth wall as Simon directly talks to the player, acknowledging he is a character in a computer game.</plot>
    <studio>Adventuresoft Ltd., Adventure Soft Publishing Ltd., Infocom</studio>
    <emu_command>simon1</emu_command>
    <boxart1>LcaZPWM.png</boxart1>
    <snapshot1>wRlgEVW.png</snapshot1>
    <boxart2>ZypIc84.jpg</boxart2>
    <boxart3>G3eUKVQ.jpg</boxart3>
    <snapshot10>bmxUR3M.gif</snapshot10>
    <snapshot2>QkOtFkH.png</snapshot2>
    <snapshot3>1fLzD2X.gif</snapshot3>
    <snapshot4>rjMcZ12.gif</snapshot4>
    <snapshot5>tOKg8UX.gif</snapshot5>
    <snapshot6>s3MGFQF.gif</snapshot6>
    <snapshot7>TA80faA.gif</snapshot7>
    <snapshot8>3k1qt7E.gif</snapshot8>
    <snapshot9>yCPpivL.gif</snapshot9>
  </game>
  <game name="Simon the Sorcerer 2 (Floppy DOS)">
    <description>Simon the Sorcerer 2 (Floppy DOS)</description>
    <title_clean>Simon the Sorcerer 2</title_clean>
    <rom name="The_Complete_ScummVM_Collection_v2/The_Complete_ScummVM%20Collection%20v2.0.zip/The_Complete_ScummVM%20Collection%20v2.0%2FWorking%2FSimon%20the%20Sorcerer%202%20%28Floppy%20DOS%29.zip" size="10408814"/>
    <genre>Adventure</genre>
    <plot>Simon is just an ordinary boy living in modern-day England. One day, his dog Chippy discovers a chest with a book inside, entitled Ye Olde Spellbooke. Without thinking too much, Simon throws the book on the floor; as a result, a portal opens, teleporting the boy and his dog into a fantasy world. Simon is promptly captured by goblins bent on cooking and eating him, but manages to escape. Soon he realizes that he must play the role of an apprentice sorcerer and rescue a benevolent wizard called Calypso from an evil one, aptly named Sordid.Simon the Sorcerer is a point-and-click adventure game very similar to contemporary LucasArts titles (in particular Monkey Island) in concept and gameplay. It features twelve verbs displayed on the screen at all times for interaction with the environment. Objects that can be interacted with are highlighted when the player hovers the mouse cursor over them. The puzzles are inventory-based: Simon will have to collect and carry a large amount of items in order to advance in the game. Almost every character comes with an extended dialogue tree to explore. Most of the conversation choices are used for a humorous effect and are not required to pursue. Like in LucasArts' adventures, it is impossible to get irrevocably stuck or die in Simon the Sorcerer. The game world consists of dozens of interconnected screens, most of which are accessible from the very beginning. Although there is usually only one way to solve the puzzles, the player can work on multiple tasks at once, and exploration occupies a large portion of the game. Whenever an important location is discovered, it is marked on the map for instant access, so that the player is not required to retrace his steps in order to revisit it. The game frequently parodies popular fairy tales and fantasy works and sometimes breaks the fourth wall as Simon directly talks to the player, acknowledging he is a character in a computer game.</plot>
    <studio>Adventuresoft Ltd., Adventure Soft Publishing Ltd., Infocom</studio>
    <emu_command>simon2</emu_command>
    <boxart1>tsgj0AV.jpg</boxart1>
    <boxart2>ZypIc84.jpg</boxart2>
    <boxart3>G3eUKVQ.jpg</boxart3>
    <snapshot1>0Bi7G03.gif</snapshot1>
    <snapshot10>bmxUR3M.gif</snapshot10>
    <snapshot2>QkOtFkH.png</snapshot2>
    <snapshot3>1fLzD2X.gif</snapshot3>
    <snapshot4>rjMcZ12.gif</snapshot4>
    <snapshot5>tOKg8UX.gif</snapshot5>
    <snapshot6>s3MGFQF.gif</snapshot6>
    <snapshot7>TA80faA.gif</snapshot7>
    <snapshot8>3k1qt7E.gif</snapshot8>
    <snapshot9>yCPpivL.gif</snapshot9>
  </game>
  <game name="Space Quest 1 - The Sarien Encounter (Floppy DOS VGA Remake)">
    <description>Space Quest 1 - The Sarien Encounter (Floppy DOS VGA Remake)</description>
    <title_clean>Space Quest 1 - The Sarien Encounter</title_clean>
    <rom name="The_Complete_ScummVM_Collection_v2/The_Complete_ScummVM%20Collection%20v2.0.zip/The_Complete_ScummVM%20Collection%20v2.0%2FWorking%2FSpace%20Quest%201%20-%20The%20Sarien%20Encounter%20%28Floppy%20DOS%20VGA%20Remake%29.zip" size="5648279"/>
    <nplayers>1</nplayers>
    <ESRB>ESRB - T (Teen)</ESRB>
    <plot>Space Quest 1- Roger Wilco in the Sarien Encounter is a remake of the original release of Space Quest- Chapter I - The Sarien Encounter. The new version has enhanced graphics (256 color VGA) and soundblaster support. It uses the SCI game engine (point-and-click interface, icons along the top) rather than the AGI engine (mixed point-and-click with text parser). Some of the puzzles have been slightly changed to accommodate the new interface and it is also possible to skip the arcade part. There are a few additional scenes and more elaborate text descriptions, mostly enhancing the humorous effect.</plot>
    <studio>Sierra On-Line</studio>
    <rating>3.8</rating>
    <genre>Adventure</genre>
    <emu_command>sq1sci</emu_command>
    <boxart1>4cmiSwb.jpg</boxart1>
    <boxart2>fi0Jwuy.jpg</boxart2>
    <boxart3>HFfgcvD.jpg</boxart3>
    <snapshot1>076k68g.gif</snapshot1>
    <snapshot10>UE1isXR.gif</snapshot10>
    <snapshot2>heu40qQ.gif</snapshot2>
    <snapshot3>XA9cymJ.gif</snapshot3>
    <snapshot4>Aaf4bLd.gif</snapshot4>
    <snapshot5>074pFad.gif</snapshot5>
    <snapshot6>B3KQmTF.png</snapshot6>
    <snapshot7>IFr84Ds.gif</snapshot7>
    <snapshot8>1dHoZs1.gif</snapshot8>
    <snapshot9>3sTn90x.gif</snapshot9>
  </game>
  <game name="Space Quest 2 - Vohaul's Revenge (Floppy DOS)">
    <description>Space Quest 2 - Vohaul's Revenge (Floppy DOS)</description>
    <title_clean>Space Quest 2 - Vohaul's Revenge</title_clean>
    <rom name="The_Complete_ScummVM_Collection_v2/The_Complete_ScummVM%20Collection%20v2.0.zip/The_Complete_ScummVM%20Collection%20v2.0%2FWorking%2FSpace%20Quest%202%20-%20Vohaul%27s%20Revenge%20%28Floppy%20DOS%29.zip" size="384755"/>
    <nplayers>1</nplayers>
    <ESRB>ESRB - T (Teen)</ESRB>
    <plot>The ace janitor Roger Wilco thought he'd seen the last of Sludge Vohaul. However, like every evil scientist is supposed to, Vohaul returns with an even meaner scheme. This time he intends to infest the planet Xenon with thousands of genetically engineered door-to-door life insurance salesmen. The last thing he wants is Roger messing things up, and so the brave janitor is captured and brought to the planet Labion to spend the rest of his days working in Vohaul's mines. Fortunately, the shuttle that takes him to the mines crashes, and Roger is the only survivor. He will have to survive the dangers of the jungle planet Labion, and eventually stop Vohaul from executing his mad plan. Vohaul's Revenge is the sequel to The Sarien Encounter, and the second game in Sierra's humorous Space Quest series of adventure games. The player navigates Roger Wilco around with arrow keys, and interacts with the world by typing commands. Like in the previous game, there are many ways for the player character to die. Much of the gameplay is dedicated to avoiding the many traps and hazards Roger will meet on his way. Some actions must be performed quickly in order to prevent Roger from getting killed.</plot>
    <studio>Sierra On-Line</studio>
    <rating>3.6</rating>
    <genre>Adventure</genre>
    <releasedate>01/01/1987</releasedate>
    <emu_command>sq2</emu_command>
    <boxart1>YeCPgBr.jpg</boxart1>
    <boxart2>m7mkB2I.jpg</boxart2>
    <boxart3>k9DNRCJ.jpg</boxart3>
    <clearlogo1>W9S5HpP.png</clearlogo1>
    <snapshot1>Yga09xX.gif</snapshot1>
    <snapshot10>UJzUkNm.png</snapshot10>
    <snapshot2>qYIz1FJ.gif</snapshot2>
    <snapshot3>0ia6LNz.gif</snapshot3>
    <snapshot4>J58EUdQ.png</snapshot4>
    <snapshot5>Bpf3yDs.png</snapshot5>
    <snapshot6>EshbbkA.png</snapshot6>
    <snapshot7>a5nM7o3.png</snapshot7>
    <snapshot8>snUQaLZ.png</snapshot8>
    <snapshot9>C2AFeZZ.png</snapshot9>
  </game>
  <game name="Space Quest 3 - The Pirates of Pestulon (Floppy DOS)">
    <description>Space Quest 3 - The Pirates of Pestulon (Floppy DOS)</description>
    <title_clean>Space Quest 3 - The Pirates of Pestulon</title_clean>
    <rom name="The_Complete_ScummVM_Collection_v2/The_Complete_ScummVM%20Collection%20v2.0.zip/The_Complete_ScummVM%20Collection%20v2.0%2FWorking%2FSpace%20Quest%203%20-%20The%20Pirates%20of%20Pestulon%20%28Floppy%20DOS%29.zip" size="1857699"/>
    <nplayers>1</nplayers>
    <ESRB>ESRB - T (Teen)</ESRB>
    <plot>Narrowly escaping the events of Space Quest II- Vohaul's Revenge, Roger Wilco's escape pod floats through space. As just another metallic item of junk, it's soon picked up by an interstellar garbage hauler. Waking up in a pile of trash, quite familiar for this janitor-turned-hero, Roger Wilco must somehow escape. Once given access to the rest of the galaxy, he'll soon find himself having to avoid a collections cyborg for payments overdue, dealing with the corporate prison of software company Scummsoft, and having to digest the greasy food from the galaxy's finest hamburger joint. Space Quest 3 is a graphical adventure. The mouse is functional for movement and inventory access, however the game primarily relies on a text parser for specific commands and manipulation of objects on screen. In addition to the regular gameplay, there are also various mini-games, such as a simple non-scrolling arcade game Astro Chicken, as well as a radar screen representation for ship-to-ship space combat.</plot>
    <studio>Sierra On-Line</studio>
    <rating>4.0</rating>
    <genre>Adventure</genre>
    <releasedate>18/03/1989</releasedate>
    <emu_command>sq3</emu_command>
    <boxart1>GIizAeS.jpg</boxart1>
    <boxart2>wuC6eHx.jpg</boxart2>
    <boxart3>YXw0OPy.jpg</boxart3>
    <clearlogo1>6e74TEx.png</clearlogo1>
    <snapshot1>tzLIWeL.gif</snapshot1>
    <snapshot10>stUc1XT.png</snapshot10>
    <snapshot2>4metvt9.gif</snapshot2>
    <snapshot3>UYvRJY4.gif</snapshot3>
    <snapshot4>1ZOatIF.gif</snapshot4>
    <snapshot5>e4X70zk.gif</snapshot5>
    <snapshot6>TxzldOx.png</snapshot6>
    <snapshot7>U751mA8.png</snapshot7>
    <snapshot8>LuNYbYp.png</snapshot8>
    <snapshot9>RxzJxrh.png</snapshot9>
  </game>
  <game name="Space Quest 4 - Roger Wilco and the Time Rippers (Floppy DOS)">
    <description>Space Quest 4 - Roger Wilco and the Time Rippers (Floppy DOS)</description>
    <title_clean>Space Quest 4 - Roger Wilco and the Time Rippers</title_clean>
    <rom name="The_Complete_ScummVM_Collection_v2/The_Complete_ScummVM%20Collection%20v2.0.zip/The_Complete_ScummVM%20Collection%20v2.0%2FWorking%2FSpace%20Quest%204%20-%20Roger%20Wilco%20and%20the%20Time%20Rippers%20%28Floppy%20DOS%29.zip" size="6186026"/>
    <rating>4.67</rating>
    <nplayers>1</nplayers>
    <studio>Sierra On-Line</studio>
    <releasedate>03/04/1991</releasedate>
    <plot>Following his humorous adventures in previous game, Roger Wilco is relaxing at his favorite pub somewhere in time and space when heavily armed soldiers enter the room. Carrying a parting message from Rogers old nemesis, Sludge Vohaul, they plan to get rid of the janitorial hero, execution style. That is, until a man with an over-sized hair dryer helps Roger escape through a time rip into the future. Now Roger Wilco has woken up on his home planet, some time in a meta-fictional Space Quest XII. It is a grim, dystopian future: the series has gone to ruin without its hero, and Vohaul rules supreme. Roger must find a way to avoid Vohauls henchmen, fulfill his destiny, and learn about a few surprises that await him in his own future.</plot>
    <genre>Adventure</genre>
    <ESRB>ESRB - T (Teen)</ESRB>
    <emu_command>sq4</emu_command>
    <boxart1>4zVlm92.jpg</boxart1>
    <banner1>U8JTrsY.jpg</banner1>
    <clearlogo1>GRCdzWw.png</clearlogo1>
    <snapshot1>0tibmHc.png</snapshot1>
    <boxart2>jc1GDoV.jpg</boxart2>
    <snapshot2>fy8PEbo.png</snapshot2>
    <boxart3>H6Qa05G.jpg</boxart3>
    <boxart4>Xic94eb.png</boxart4>
    <snapshot10>jeaHzpf.png</snapshot10>
    <snapshot3>1TuzKkQ.gif</snapshot3>
    <snapshot4>OGdN4B3.gif</snapshot4>
    <snapshot5>R8quklj.png</snapshot5>
    <snapshot6>nLSbp37.png</snapshot6>
    <snapshot7>eNLtvfE.png</snapshot7>
    <snapshot8>ZKGeP6x.png</snapshot8>
    <snapshot9>8NnmFie.png</snapshot9>
  </game>
  <game name="Space Quest 5 - The Next Mutation (Floppy DOS)">
    <description>Space Quest 5 - The Next Mutation (Floppy DOS)</description>
    <title_clean>Space Quest 5 - The Next Mutation</title_clean>
    <rom name="The_Complete_ScummVM_Collection_v2/The_Complete_ScummVM%20Collection%20v2.0.zip/The_Complete_ScummVM%20Collection%20v2.0%2FWorking%2FSpace%20Quest%205%20-%20The%20Next%20Mutation%20%28Floppy%20DOS%29.zip" size="6775308"/>
    <nplayers>1</nplayers>
    <ESRB>ESRB - T (Teen)</ESRB>
    <plot>After travelling back and forth through time in the previous game, Roger Wilco is back in the Starfleet Acadamy, serving as both a cadet and a janitor. Cheating his way through the Starfleet Aptitude Test, Roger is finally given the rank of captain, his own ship (a garbage scow) and a mission- to explore strange new worlds (which no man in his right mind would explore), to seek out new life and new civilizations (which grew out of the massive amounts of trash Roger will collect on his way), to boldly go where no man has gone before. Step by step Roger will have to unveil a galaxy-wide biohazardous material dumping scheme, solve the mystery of the disappearance of a fellow Starfleet captain and his ship, and confront an agent of an old nemesis. Space Quest V- The Next Mutation is an adventure game in the Space Quest series. Like its brethren, it is characterized by humorous writing and situations, as well as plenty of opportunities for the hero to die horribly. The game is entirely mouse-controlled- the player interacts with the world by clicking on locations, people and objects on the screen, cycling between various actions (walking, looking, touching or taking, talking, etc.), by clicking the right mouse button or using the icon bar. The latter also contains icons that allow the player to access Roger's inventory, quit the game or change the settings. Commands for smelling and tasting have been removed, but a special icon for giving orders has been added. It can be used on any object or character in the game, but its actual purpose is to issue specific commands to the crew members- Roger's garbage scow, the Eureka, has a crew over which he presides. The game is plot-driven and contains cutscenes done in a comic book-like style. Plot development is linear, but each planet the protagonist visits usually consists of several screens and contains its own objectives and puzzles. There are also hazardous situations that may occur on the spaceship itself and must be dealt with.</plot>
    <studio>Sierra On-Line</studio>
    <rating>4.0</rating>
    <genre>Adventure</genre>
    <emu_command>sq5</emu_command>
    <boxart1>2KeU1NF.jpg</boxart1>
    <boxart2>AEzwIGM.jpg</boxart2>
    <boxart3>zbO2I8v.jpg</boxart3>
    <snapshot1>DbpiYqD.gif</snapshot1>
    <snapshot10>rXiosKO.png</snapshot10>
    <snapshot2>QzpNxA7.gif</snapshot2>
    <snapshot3>S47LZDm.png</snapshot3>
    <snapshot4>Q5BnGN5.png</snapshot4>
    <snapshot5>6myftp4.png</snapshot5>
    <snapshot6>o3jGUwP.png</snapshot6>
    <snapshot7>NBbLfaT.png</snapshot7>
    <snapshot8>uW7dVuU.png</snapshot8>
    <snapshot9>3FGxoMO.png</snapshot9>
  </game>
  <game name="The 7th Guest (CD DOS)">
    <description>The 7th Guest (CD DOS)</description>
    <title_clean>The 7th Guest</title_clean>
    <rom name="The_Complete_ScummVM_Collection_v2/The_Complete_ScummVM%20Collection%20v2.0.zip/The_Complete_ScummVM%20Collection%20v2.0%2FWorking%2FThe%207th%20Guest%20%28CD%20DOS%29.zip" size="744976694"/>
    <rating>3.30</rating>
    <studio>Virgin Interactive</studio>
    <releasedate>04/01/1993</releasedate>
    <plot>The 7th Guest, produced by Trilobyte and originally released by Virgin Games in 1993, is an interactive movie puzzle adventure game. It was one of the first computer video games to be released only on CD-ROM. The 7th Guest is a horror story told from the unfolding perspective of the player, as an amnesiac. The game received a great amount of press attention for making live action video clips a core part of its gameplay, for its unprecedented amount of pre-rendered 3D graphics, and for its adult content. In addition, the game was very successful, with over two million copies sold, and is widely regarded as a killer app that accelerated the sales of CD-ROM drives. The 7th Guest has subsequently been re-released on Apples app store for various systems such as the Mac. Bill Gates called The 7th Guest the new standard in interactive entertainment.</plot>
    <genre>Action</genre>
    <ESRB>T - Teen</ESRB>
    <nplayers>1</nplayers>
    <emu_command>t7g</emu_command>
    <boxart1>5mTI64P.jpg</boxart1>
    <clearlogo1>jw6ccdX.png</clearlogo1>
    <snapshot1>eoonmiv.png</snapshot1>
    <boxart2>SlSRS7q.jpg</boxart2>
    <snapshot2>Jj3dM7F.png</snapshot2>
    <boxart3>j7W9ZvR.png</boxart3>
    <videoid>P5-QKu87MIA</videoid>
    <fanart1>58QMPf0.jpg</fanart1>
  </game>
  <game name="The Black Cauldron (Floppy DOS)">
    <description>The Black Cauldron (Floppy DOS)</description>
    <title_clean>The Black Cauldron</title_clean>
    <rom name="The_Complete_ScummVM_Collection_v2/The_Complete_ScummVM%20Collection%20v2.0.zip/The_Complete_ScummVM%20Collection%20v2.0%2FWorking%2FThe%20Black%20Cauldron%20%28Floppy%20DOS%29.zip" size="292547"/>
    <nplayers>1</nplayers>
    <releasedate>07/01/1986</releasedate>
    <plot>The Black Cauldron is a 1985 American animated dark fantasy adventure film produced by Walt Disney Feature Animation in association with Silver Screen Partners II and released by Walt Disney Pictures. The 25th Disney animated feature film, it is loosely based on the first two books in The Chronicles of Prydain by Lloyd Alexander, a series of five novels that are, in turn, based on Welsh mythology.</plot>
    <genre>Adventure</genre>
    <rating>3.5</rating>
    <studio>Sierra On-Line</studio>
    <emu_command>bc</emu_command>
    <boxart1>BYlY3Or.jpg</boxart1>
    <clearlogo1>WBNL7LI.png</clearlogo1>
    <snapshot1>wf269Jj.png</snapshot1>
    <fanart1>7y6cgOG.jpg</fanart1>
    <boxart2>kDZ5UZU.jpg</boxart2>
    <snapshot2>VWZeSTH.png</snapshot2>
    <boxart3>MAcMDSD.png</boxart3>
    <boxart4>zYgLPMk.jpg</boxart4>
    <snapshot10>SgeDsRw.gif</snapshot10>
    <snapshot3>DR4NNC1.gif</snapshot3>
    <snapshot4>8w1BtOy.gif</snapshot4>
    <snapshot5>RTDst4H.gif</snapshot5>
    <snapshot6>VOHrTpr.gif</snapshot6>
    <snapshot7>vMsrCex.gif</snapshot7>
    <snapshot8>zOxElfD.gif</snapshot8>
    <snapshot9>iDLvD6X.gif</snapshot9>
  </game>
  <game name="The Curse Of Monkey Island (CD Windows)">
    <description>The Curse Of Monkey Island (CD Windows)</description>
    <title_clean>The Curse Of Monkey Island</title_clean>
    <rom name="The_Complete_ScummVM_Collection_v2/The_Complete_ScummVM%20Collection%20v2.0.zip/The_Complete_ScummVM%20Collection%20v2.0%2FWorking%2FThe%20Curse%20Of%20Monkey%20Island%20%28CD%20Windows%29.zip" size="882658254"/>
    <rating>4.06</rating>
    <nplayers>1</nplayers>
    <releasedate>31/10/1997</releasedate>
    <plot>The Curse of Monkey Island is an adventure game developed and published by LucasArts, and the third game in the Monkey Island series. It was released in 1997 and followed the successful games The Secret of Monkey Island and Monkey Island 2: LeChuck's Revenge. The game is the twelfth and last LucasArts game to use the SCUMM engine, which was extensively upgraded for its last outing before being replaced by the GrimE engine for the next game in the series, Escape from Monkey Island. The Curse of Monkey Island is the first Monkey Island game to include voice acting, and has a more cartoon-ish graphic style than the earlier games.</plot>
    <genre>Adventure</genre>
    <studio>LucasArts</studio>
    <emu_command>comi</emu_command>
    <boxart1>0JYdTGT.png</boxart1>
    <banner1>4byWi7A.png</banner1>
    <clearlogo1>B9jP0o0.png</clearlogo1>
    <snapshot1>bS1zKHp.png</snapshot1>
    <fanart1>wnsmgP2.jpg</fanart1>
    <boxart2>pBam6MJ.jpg</boxart2>
    <snapshot2>hH6TooN.png</snapshot2>
    <boxart3>7lWcojD.jpg</boxart3>
    <boxart4>6wZrov8.png</boxart4>
  </game>
  <game name="The Dig (CD DOS)">
    <description>The Dig (CD DOS)</description>
    <title_clean>The Dig</title_clean>
    <rom name="The_Complete_ScummVM_Collection_v2/The_Complete_ScummVM%20Collection%20v2.0.zip/The_Complete_ScummVM%20Collection%20v2.0%2FWorking%2FThe%20Dig%20%28CD%20DOS%29.zip" size="515835665"/>
    <rating>3.56</rating>
    <nplayers>1</nplayers>
    <releasedate>11/01/1995</releasedate>
    <plot>The Dig is a point-and-click adventure game developed by LucasArts and released in 1995 as a CD-ROM for PC and Macintosh computers. Like other LucasArts adventure games, it uses the SCUMM video game engine. It also features a full voice-acting cast, including notable voice actors Robert Patrick and Steven Blum, and a digital orchestral score. The game uses a combination of drawn two-dimensional artwork and limited, pre-rendered three-dimensional movies, with the latter created by Industrial Light and Magic.</plot>
    <ESRB>E - Everyone</ESRB>
    <genre>Adventure</genre>
    <studio>LucasArts Entertainment Company LLC</studio>
    <emu_command>dig</emu_command>
    <videoid>VaOtsqz6Rb0</videoid>
    <boxart1>eNlEqDz.jpg</boxart1>
    <boxart2>pSNtD76.jpg</boxart2>
    <boxart3>UWaca1Z.jpg</boxart3>
    <clearlogo1>kSD0VHf.png</clearlogo1>
    <fanart1>YpNz0qN.jpg</fanart1>
    <snapshot1>CuQ3rnP.jpg</snapshot1>
    <snapshot10>B3F6XGO.png</snapshot10>
    <snapshot2>5NkBiaQ.gif</snapshot2>
    <snapshot3>iiHq5PL.gif</snapshot3>
    <snapshot4>idPgMQr.png</snapshot4>
    <snapshot5>q8eUkyo.png</snapshot5>
    <snapshot6>0xgPbhk.png</snapshot6>
    <snapshot7>gEcau22.png</snapshot7>
    <snapshot8>eysrNpP.png</snapshot8>
    <snapshot9>Hw0AgzT.gif</snapshot9>
  </game>
  <game name="The Last Express (CD Windows)">
    <description>The Last Express (CD Windows)</description>
    <title_clean>The Last Express</title_clean>
    <rom name="The_Complete_ScummVM_Collection_v2/The_Complete_ScummVM%20Collection%20v2.0.zip/The_Complete_ScummVM%20Collection%20v2.0%2FSVN%2FThe%20Last%20Express%20%28CD%20Windows%29.zip" size="1346568765"/>
    <emu_command>lastexpress</emu_command>
    <plot>The Orient Express is about to depart from Paris to Constantinople. As the train slowly begins to move away from the station, a young, courageously looking man jumps on it from his motorcycle and makes his way inside. This man is an American doctor named Robert Cath, escaping from authorities as a suspect in the murder of a policeman. In the train, he finds the dead body of the person he was supposed to meet. Now he has to act quickly. The only way not to arise the suspicions of the police is to disguise himself as the murdered man. A very dangerous investigation begins, and the hero soon finds himself involved in a deep net of personal intrigues and political conspiracies.[CR]The Last Express is a real-time adventure game set in 1914, shortly before the outbreak of the World War, in a concrete historical and geographical environment. The game uses a simple point-and-click interface for interacting with people and objects, and navigating the character from a first-person perspective through pre-rendered backgrounds. From the moment the player gains control of Robert Cath, time begins to flow. If the player fails to solve a part of the mystery until the train arrives at the next station, certain events the player was supposed to prevent will occur, ending the game prematurely. It is impossible to permanently die in the game, as the player has the ability to rewind the clock in order to replay a specific period of time.</plot>
    <boxart1>zkbXKbn.jpg</boxart1>
    <boxart2>t32UPEa.jpg</boxart2>
    <snapshot1>DzWqUvG.png</snapshot1>
  </game>
  <game name="The Lost Files of Sherlock Holmes - The Case of the Rose Tattoo (CD DOS)">
    <description>The Lost Files of Sherlock Holmes - The Case of the Rose Tattoo (CD DOS)</description>
    <title_clean>The Lost Files of Sherlock Holmes - The Case of the Rose Tattoo</title_clean>
    <rom name="The_Complete_ScummVM_Collection_v2/The_Complete_ScummVM%20Collection%20v2.0.zip/The_Complete_ScummVM%20Collection%20v2.0%2FWorking%2FThe%20Lost%20Files%20of%20Sherlock%20Holmes%20-%20The%20Case%20of%20the%20Rose%20Tattoo%20%28CD%20DOS%29.zip" size="448499116"/>
    <nplayers>1</nplayers>
    <studio>Electronic Arts</studio>
    <releasedate>31/08/1996</releasedate>
    <plot>In October of 1889, the formula for a new and extraordinarily powerful explosive disappeared from the Ministry of Defense. Sherlocks brother Mycroft, an eccentric but influential government servant, launched an official though secret inquiry into the theft, but his effort was thwarted. Just before asking Sherlock to undertake an independent investigation of the theft, Mycroft was seriously injured in an explosion that leveled the Diogenes Club. Sherlock, believing his brother had been victimized by a random gas leak, retired disconsolate to 221B Baker St. Dr. Watson, with a little luck and much effort, managed to reanimate his friend by posing one critical question: What if the explosion that injured Mycroft had not been an accident? The answer to this query sent Holmes down a long and twisted road of discovery. Sherlock, for the first time in his career, acknowledged that his motivation was something other than a desire for justice. With single-minded ferocity he pursued, cajoled, questioned, and confronted suspects from smug Mayfair to the pitiful and dangerous East End. Gradually, through observation and deduction, he developed a picture of a huge criminal enterprise initiated by a masterful adversary. To penetrate this perilous conspiracy and frustrate its intent he solved several capital crimes. Holmes applied his customary courage, acumen, and intelligence to these daunting tasks. In so doing he quashed a potentially volatile international incident, defended the national security, protected the honor of the royal family, exonerated the innocent and delivered rough and swift punishment to the guilty. The shocking and surprising resolution of the case made it necessary to seal Watsons precious account for 100 years. That is how The Case of the Rose Tattoo became one of the Lost Files of Sherlock Holmes.[CR]The Case of the Rose Tattoo is part of the Lost Files of Sherlock Holmes kept by Dr. John H. Watson and the sequel to The Case of the Serrated Scalpel. Accompany Holmes as he sets foot in 50 locations and interacts with 90 characters. All the characters are costume and speech specific to Victorian London.</plot>
    <genre>Adventure</genre>
    <emu_command>rosetattoo</emu_command>
    <boxart1>8YHoR5Z.jpg</boxart1>
    <clearlogo1>PDvqNvq.png</clearlogo1>
    <snapshot1>ro17JSo.png</snapshot1>
    <boxart2>v0AbuCB.jpg</boxart2>
    <snapshot2>XJO3TCb.png</snapshot2>
    <boxart3>I10RQHl.jpg</boxart3>
  </game>
  <game name="The Lost Files of Sherlock Holmes - The Case of the Serrated Scalpel (CD DOS)">
    <description>The Lost Files of Sherlock Holmes - The Case of the Serrated Scalpel (CD DOS)</description>
    <title_clean>The Lost Files of Sherlock Holmes - The Case of the Serrated Scalpel</title_clean>
    <rom name="The_Complete_ScummVM_Collection_v2/The_Complete_ScummVM%20Collection%20v2.0.zip/The_Complete_ScummVM%20Collection%20v2.0%2FWorking%2FThe%20Lost%20Files%20of%20Sherlock%20Holmes%20-%20The%20Case%20of%20the%20Serrated%20Scalpel%20%28CD%20DOS%29.zip" size="7349517"/>
    <rating>5.00</rating>
    <nplayers>1</nplayers>
    <studio>Electronic Arts</studio>
    <releasedate>08/03/1992</releasedate>
    <plot>The Lost Files of Sherlock Holmes is an adventure game series developed by Mythos Software and published by the American computer game company Electronic Arts for DOS in the 1990s. The series contains The Case of the Serrated Scalpel (1992), and The Case of the Rose Tattoo (1996).</plot>
    <genre>Adventure</genre>
    <emu_command>scalpel</emu_command>
    <boxart1>BivAuN1.jpg</boxart1>
    <clearlogo1>R6ItLdy.png</clearlogo1>
    <snapshot1>VvYjUji.jpg</snapshot1>
  </game>
  <game name="The Neverhood (CD, Windows)">
    <description>The Neverhood (CD, Windows)</description>
    <title_clean>The Neverhood</title_clean>
    <rom name="The_Complete_ScummVM_Collection_v2/The_Complete_ScummVM%20Collection%20v2.0.zip/The_Complete_ScummVM%20Collection%20v2.0%2FWorking%2FThe%20Neverhood%20%28CD%2C%20Windows%29.zip" size="618676208"/>
    <nplayers>1</nplayers>
    <releasedate>31/10/1996</releasedate>
    <plot>The Neverhood (also called The Neverhood Chronicles, released in Japan as Klaymen Klaymen) is a 1996 point-and-click adventure game developed by The Neverhood, Inc. and published by DreamWorks Interactive. The game follows the adventure of a claymation character named Klaymen as he discovers his origins and his purpose in a world made entirely out of clay. When the game was originally released, it was unique in that it featured all of its animation done entirely in claymation, including all of the sets, rather than 2- or 3-dimensional computer graphics, like many other games at its time. The gameplay consists mostly of the player guiding the main character Klaymen around and solving puzzles to advance in the game. As the player advances through different areas of the game, there are various video sequences that help advance the plot. In addition to being unique, The Neverhood aimed at being quirky and humorous, as is evident by the characters, the music, and the plot sequence of the game.</plot>
    <genre>Adventure</genre>
    <emu_command>neverhood</emu_command>
    <boxart1>FUxWPjh.jpg</boxart1>
    <clearlogo1>mCcKwvH.png</clearlogo1>
    <snapshot1>258CEaW.png</snapshot1>
    <fanart1>uDiK3aZ.jpg</fanart1>
    <snapshot2>WCaOFQE.jpg</snapshot2>
  </game>
  <game name="The Secret of Monkey Island (Floppy DOS VGA)">
    <description>The Secret of Monkey Island (Floppy DOS VGA)</description>
    <title_clean>The Secret of Monkey Island</title_clean>
    <rom name="The_Complete_ScummVM_Collection_v2/The_Complete_ScummVM%20Collection%20v2.0.zip/The_Complete_ScummVM%20Collection%20v2.0%2FWorking%2FThe%20Secret%20of%20Monkey%20Island%20%28Floppy%20DOS%20VGA%29.zip" size="3268338"/>
    <rating>4.38</rating>
    <studio>Lucasfilm Games</studio>
    <plot>The Secret of Monkey Island is a 1990 point-and-click graphic adventure game developed and published by Lucasfilm Games. It takes place in a fantastic version of the Caribbean during the age of piracy. The player assumes the role of Guybrush Threepwood, a young man who dreams of becoming a pirate and explores fictional islands while solving puzzles.</plot>
    <genre>Adventure</genre>
    <releasedate>18/07/1990</releasedate>
    <emu_command>monkey</emu_command>
    <boxart1>Eb0HquG.png</boxart1>
    <clearlogo1>dfiaXP0.png</clearlogo1>
    <snapshot1>Vycd2ar.png</snapshot1>
    <fanart1>rwcJdtD.jpg</fanart1>
    <boxart2>u7RmxQC.jpg</boxart2>
    <snapshot2>YlONIZh.png</snapshot2>
    <boxart3>FxDCacF.jpg</boxart3>
    <boxart4>vRp8eis.png</boxart4>
    <snapshot3>vTWefQt.gif</snapshot3>
    <snapshot4>ak68xKq.gif</snapshot4>
  </game>
  <game name="Toonstruck (CD Windows)">
    <description>Toonstruck (CD Windows)</description>
    <title_clean>Toonstruck</title_clean>
    <rom name="The_Complete_ScummVM_Collection_v2/The_Complete_ScummVM%20Collection%20v2.0.zip/The_Complete_ScummVM%20Collection%20v2.0%2FWorking%2FToonstruck%20%28CD%20Windows%29.zip" size="909480331"/>
    <rating>5.00</rating>
    <nplayers>1</nplayers>
    <plot>Toonstruck is an adventure game released in 1996. The game features hand-drawn imagery and animated characters, but the protagonist Drew Blanc (played and voiced by actor Christopher Lloyd) is represented as a video-captured live action character interacting with the cartoon world around him. Toonstruck also features scan-line compressed FMV, including several animated sequences produced by Nelvana and Rainbow Animation, and was also one of the first video games to include stock music from APM Music, notably the classic Spooky Scherzo by Sam Fonteyn and Lonely Hearts Club A by David Bell.</plot>
    <genre>Adventure</genre>
    <emu_command>toon</emu_command>
    <boxart1>KO3T8B6.jpg</boxart1>
    <boxart2>zWGV37B.jpg</boxart2>
    <snapshot1>sdjpuvM.png</snapshot1>
  </game>
  <game name="Zak McKracken and the Alien Mindbenders (Floppy DOS v2)">
    <description>Zak McKracken and the Alien Mindbenders (Floppy DOS v2)</description>
    <title_clean>Zak McKracken and the Alien Mindbenders</title_clean>
    <rom name="The_Complete_ScummVM_Collection_v2/The_Complete_ScummVM%20Collection%20v2.0.zip/The_Complete_ScummVM%20Collection%20v2.0%2FWorking%2FZak%20McKracken%20and%20the%20Alien%20Mindbenders%20%28Floppy%20DOS%20v2%29.zip" size="549945"/>
    <rating>4.90</rating>
    <nplayers>1</nplayers>
    <studio>Lucasfilm Games</studio>
    <plot>The plot follows Zak (full name Francis Zachary McKracken), a writer for the National Inquisitor, a tabloid newspaper; Annie Larris, a freelance scientist; and Melissa China and Leslie Bennett, two Yale University coed students, in their attempt to prevent the nefarious alien Caponians (who have infiltrated the phone company) from slowly reducing the intelligence of everybody on Earth using a 60 Hz hum.</plot>
    <genre>Adventure</genre>
    <ESRB>ESRB - E (Everyone)</ESRB>
    <releasedate>18/07/1988</releasedate>
    <emu_command>zak</emu_command>
    <boxart1>6EmAgZz.jpg</boxart1>
    <clearlogo1>ghZddb3.png</clearlogo1>
    <snapshot1>TkPcUZi.png</snapshot1>
    <boxart2>FpqS8V5.jpg</boxart2>
    <snapshot2>lq4mjLr.jpg</snapshot2>
    <boxart3>NNRiD93.jpg</boxart3>
    <boxart4>0R7IuK0.png</boxart4>
    <snapshot10>YgNJEgA.gif</snapshot10>
    <snapshot3>9LqpaMO.jpg</snapshot3>
    <snapshot4>aTNrEwq.jpg</snapshot4>
    <snapshot5>uK0yQqh.jpg</snapshot5>
    <snapshot6>w4B1npn.jpg</snapshot6>
    <snapshot7>ac0Y4Uc.jpg</snapshot7>
    <snapshot8>QuWl3Ec.jpg</snapshot8>
    <snapshot9>FoU74Z7.gif</snapshot9>
  </game>
  <game name="Zork - Grand Inquisitor (DVD Windows)">
    <description>Zork - Grand Inquisitor (DVD Windows)</description>
    <title_clean>Zork - Grand Inquisitor</title_clean>
    <rom name="The_Complete_ScummVM_Collection_v2/The_Complete_ScummVM%20Collection%20v2.0.zip/The_Complete_ScummVM%20Collection%20v2.0%2FWorking%2FZork%20-%20Grand%20Inquisitor%20%28DVD%20Windows%29.zip" size="2245144214"/>
    <plot>Magic is banned in the Great Underground Empire, and the Grand Inquisitor Yannick (with the kind help of Frobozz Electric) has a stranglehold on the world of Zork, establishing a totalitarian regime. According to his own words, the goal of the new state is to shun magic, shun the appearance of magic, shun everything, and then shun shunning. Any opposing forces will be totemized, which is apparently a rather unpleasant procedure. The player character in the game is just that - the player character: Ageless, Faceless, Gender-Neutral, Culturally-Ambiguous Adventure Person (abbreviated AFGNCAAP), as the politically correct designation by the Dungeon Master Dalboz defines him/her (it?). Naturally, it is the heros duty to save the world by collecting a Cube of Foundation, the Skull of Yoruk, and the Coconut of Quendor, so that magic can return to the land and the Grand Inquisitor falls victim to his own shunning policies.[CR]Zork: Grand Inquisitor is the third in the row of graphical Zork games. It utilizes the same engine as its predecessor, with first-person perspective, 180 degree camera rotation, pre-rendered backgrounds, and live actors. Compared to the previous game, it is more similar in tone to the early, predominantly humorous Zork adventures, containing plenty of references to them.</plot>
    <boxart1>2j5wqJd.jpg</boxart1>
    <boxart2>6SoQBnH.jpg</boxart2>
    <snapshot1>FcNAMkv.png</snapshot1>
    <emu_command>zgi</emu_command>
  </game>
  <game name="Zork Nemesis - The Forbidden Lands (DVD DOS)">
    <description>Zork Nemesis - The Forbidden Lands (DVD DOS)</description>
    <title_clean>Zork Nemesis - The Forbidden Lands</title_clean>
    <rom name="The_Complete_ScummVM_Collection_v2/The_Complete_ScummVM%20Collection%20v2.0.zip/The_Complete_ScummVM%20Collection%20v2.0%2FWorking%2FZork%20Nemesis%20-%20The%20Forbidden%20Lands%20%28DVD%20DOS%29.zip" size="1298992760"/>
    <rating>3.50</rating>
    <studio>Activision</studio>
    <releasedate>29/02/1996</releasedate>
    <plot>Zork Nemesis: The Forbidden Lands is a graphical first person adventure game in the style of Myst, mixing logic puzzles with live-action FMV sequences which advance the story. The player views each location from a first-person perspective, and can rotate the camera 180 degrees to get a full view of your surroundings.[CR]Like other Zork installments, the game contains humorous elements, but in general its story and atmosphere are darker, including images and themes such as decapitated heads and human sacrifice.</plot>
    <genre>Adventure</genre>
    <emu_command>znemesis</emu_command>
    <boxart1>E013tTF.jpg</boxart1>
    <clearlogo1>AksLg69.jpg</clearlogo1>
    <snapshot1>TPUwixB.png</snapshot1>
    <boxart2>uxV7AZl.jpg</boxart2>
    <snapshot2>FAokSlJ.png</snapshot2>
  </game>
</datafile>