<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<datafile>
	<header>
		<emu_name>Sega SG-1000</emu_name>
		<emu_description>Sega SG-1000</emu_description>
		<emu_category>Sega, 1980s, Console, 8 Bit</emu_category>
		<emu_version>04012018</emu_version>
		<emu_date>03/03/2015</emu_date>
		<emu_author>Zach Morris</emu_author>
		<emu_visibility>visible</emu_visibility>
		<emu_homepage>http://www.no-intro.org</emu_homepage>
		<emu_baseurl>https://archive.org/download/</emu_baseurl>
		<emu_launcher>retroplayer</emu_launcher>
		<emu_default_addon>none</emu_default_addon>
		<emu_ext_launch_cmd>none</emu_ext_launch_cmd>
		<emu_downloadpath>default</emu_downloadpath>
		<emu_postdlaction>unzip_rom</emu_postdlaction>
		<emu_comment>No-Intro Sega SG-1000 list.  Filtered to remove duplicates, betas, etc.[CR]The SG-1000 is a cartridge-based home video game console manufactured by Sega and released in Japan, Australia, and other countries. This system marked Sega's first entry into the home video game hardware business, and provided the basis for the more successful Master System. The SG-1000's game library comprises 68 standard cartridge releases and 29 Sega Card releases. All of the SG-1000's games play on each model of the console, though 26 of the cartridge releases require the attached keyboard accessory or the SC-3000. In addition, all titles are fully compatible with the Mark III and Master System. Titles for the system include Flicky, Congo Bongo, Sega-Galaga, and Girl's Garden, the first video game directed by Sonic the Hedgehog creator Yuji Naka. The game library for the SG-1000 also included licensed titles, such as Golgo 13.[CR]Developer:  Sega[CR]Manufacturer:  Sega[CR]CPU:  NEC 780C[CR]Memory:  1kB RAM, 2kB VRAM[CR]Graphics:  N/A[CR]Sound:  Texas Instruments SN76489[CR]Display:  256x192 resolution, 16 colours, 32 on-screen sprites[CR]Media:  Cartridge, Cards[CR]Max Controllers:  2</emu_comment>
		<emu_thumb>jQftmGZ.jpg</emu_thumb>
		<emu_banner>lcCNIk9.jpg</emu_banner>
		<emu_fanart>x70sUhI.jpg</emu_fanart>
		<emu_logo>65UPq1J.png</emu_logo>
		<emu_trailer>SVYDqwI3ND4</emu_trailer>
	</header>
	<game name="007 James Bond (Japan) (v2.7) (Othello Multivision)">
		<description>007 James Bond (Japan) (v2.7) (Othello Multivision)</description>
		<rom crc="90160849" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Sega%20-%20SG-1000.zip/Sega%20-%20SG-1000%2F007%20James%20Bond%20%28Japan%29%20%28v2.7%29%20%28Othello%20Multivision%29.zip" sha1="88D8C1F56F06EC76BE285C29F41322A748F7C4DB" size="11812" />
		<title_clean>007 James Bond</title_clean>
		<plot>[CR][B]Overview:[/B][CR]The player takes control of Bond's famous Aston Martin car in a side-scrolling adventure through four stages based off of Bond films.[CR][B]Stages:[/B][CR]Diamonds Are Forever stage beginningThe four movie based stages are:Diamonds are ForeverMoonrakerFor Your Eyes OnlyThe Spy Who Loved meEach stage has a unique goal that needs to be accomplished, and a variety of enemies trying to stop you from completing your task.[CR][B]Gameplay:[/B][CR]Players travel through the stages, firing lasers or bullets to wipe out enemies. Bond's car is capable of travelling through land, air, and sea, depending on the stage. Obstacles must be avoided, and you will need to evade enemy fire.[CR]</plot>
		<releasedate>30/6/1983</releasedate>
		<giantbomb_url>https://www.giantbomb.com/james-bond-007/3030-7365/</giantbomb_url>
		<boxart1>KVWb07a.jpg</boxart1>
	</game>
	<game name="Bank Panic (Japan)">
		<description>Bank Panic (Japan)</description>
		<rom crc="D8A87095" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Sega%20-%20SG-1000.zip/Sega%20-%20SG-1000%2FBank%20Panic%20%28Japan%29.zip" sha1="8E1DC4D79C5BC45FC6112969EA9A2C68B3C86666" size="21280" />
		<title_clean>Bank Panic</title_clean>
		<plot>[CR][B]Overview:[/B][CR]Bank Panic is a Sega published Arcade game originally developed by Sanritsu. The goal is to scan a dozen doors in a Wild West frontier town bank, allowing innocent citizens to make bank deposits while shooting any outlaws or bombs that appear.Sega would later port the game on their Sega Mark 1 and Sega Mark 3 consoles, the latter of which is better known to Western gamers as the Master System. The game would receive various other ports for home computers as well.The game later influenced an iOS game named Westbang.[CR][B]Gameplay:[/B][CR]Each level contains 12 doors. From this doors can either enter customers with intention to deposit money or bandits that come to rob the bank. The player must allow the customer to make the deposit and shoot the outlaws before they shoot back.Each door has a counter attached to it. To pass the level every counter must be filled with at least one bag of money. There is a time limit to each level and if a counter has only one bag for too long it will disappear making the player to come back there again and wait for another deposit. From time to time, there will be time bombs placed in a door. In that case, another timer shows and the player must shoot the bomb before the timer runs out.The player loses a life if a bandit shoots them, if the bomb explodes, if the level timer reaches zero or if the player shoots an innocent customer. Sometimes bandits will hide behind customers. Some customers will be tied up and the player has to shoot the rope to free them. In this case, the customer gives 3 bags of money.Sometimes, especially at the beginning of each level, a small cowboy appears holding a gift that the player must shoot to get bonus points. The player gets point for receiving bags of money and shooting outlaws. If the player doesn&#8217;t shoot the bandit before he draws his gun (which the game considers an "unfair" kill and thus is worth less points), a very quick timer will appear and additional points will be granted to the player by shooting the bandit with as little time as possible left on the timer.[CR]Points scoring[CR]Points by shooting an outlaw:Before he draws his gun: 100 or 200 pointsWith the timer on 0.26-0.33: 300 pointsWith the timer on 0.21-0.25: 600 pointsWith the timer on 0.16-0.20: 700 pointsWith the timer on 0.11-0.15: 800 pointsWith the timer on 0.01-0.10: 1,000 pointsWith the timer on 0.00: 2,000 points for brown shirt gunmanWith the timer on 0.00: 3,000 points for green shirt gunmanWith the timer on 0.00: 5,000 points for red shirt gunmanDeposits:First bag of money: 200 pointsSecond bag of money: 400 pointsThird bag of money: 600 pointsFourth or more bag of money: 1,000 pointsShooting the rope on a customer who is tied up: 3 bags of money worth 1,000 points eachEnd of level bonuses:Money bags 1-12: 50 points eachMoney bags 13-24: 100 points eachMoney bags 25-36: 150 points eachMoney bags 37-48: 200 points eachOthers:Shooting the bomb: 100 pointsIf a woman is held up and the gunman is shot: 500 pointsIf a man is held up and the gunman is shot: 200 points[CR][B]Trivia:[/B][CR]In the last stages of the games, the boy who carries the hats is seen lifting up the woman client's skirts.Alessandro Giuriato and Gary A. Hatt share the official record for this game, with a maximum possible 9.999.999 points.[CR]</plot>
		<releasedate>31/12/1984</releasedate>
		<year>1985</year>
		<genre>Action</genre>
		<studio>SEGA Enterprises</studio>
		<nplayers>1</nplayers>
		<thegamesdb_id>33324</thegamesdb_id>
		<mobygames_url>https://www.mobygames.com/game/sg-1000/bank-panic</mobygames_url>
		<giantbomb_url>https://www.giantbomb.com/bank-panic/3030-11214/</giantbomb_url>
		<boxart1>fAyH2NM.jpg</boxart1>
		<boxart2>wUP9MbP.jpg</boxart2>
		<boxart3>EppC82z.jpg</boxart3>
		<clearlogo1>YqF5EiH.png</clearlogo1>
	</game>
	<game name="Black Onyx, The (Japan)">
		<description>Black Onyx, The (Japan)</description>
		<rom crc="26ECD094" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Sega%20-%20SG-1000.zip/Sega%20-%20SG-1000%2FBlack%20Onyx%2C%20The%20%28Japan%29.zip" sha1="7ECB9AC646346900046A61FF0242D6C90A812EDA" size="23357" />
		<title_clean>Black Onyx, The</title_clean>
		<plot>Rumor says that the legendary Black Onyx, an artifact that grants eternal youth and happiness to those who can find it, lies within the Black Tower near the town of Utsuro. You assemble a party of brave adventurers and venture into the tower, defeating monsters on your way to the great treasure.The Black Onyx is one of the first traditional role-playing games made by a Japanese company. It is similar in gameplay to early Wizardry and Ultima games with killing monsters and exploring dungeons, with dark, realistic visuals. The player creates a party (up to five members) and explores a maze-like 3D dungeon, fighting random enemies on the way. The heroes also meet adventurers who can be convinced to join the party. The combat engine is turn-based.</plot>
		<year>1987</year>
		<genre>RPG</genre>
		<studio>SEGA Enterprises</studio>
		<mobygames_url>https://www.mobygames.com/game/sg-1000/black-onyx</mobygames_url>
		<snapshot1>jmYPUcd.png</snapshot1>
	</game>
	<game name="Bomb Jack (Taiwan) (English Logo)">
		<description>Bomb Jack (Taiwan) (English Logo)</description>
		<rom crc="CDA3A335" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Sega%20-%20SG-1000.zip/Sega%20-%20SG-1000%2FBomb%20Jack%20%28Taiwan%29%20%28English%20Logo%29.zip" sha1="8D7B786283E5B42E34432ECF1B3744EAE00575DE" size="19496" />
		<title_clean>Bomb Jack</title_clean>
		<plot>[CR][B]Overview:[/B][CR]Take control of Jack and collect all the bombs in order to move to the next round.  This is not as easy as it sounds with numerous enemies such as birds, turtles and mummies getting in the way. Backgrounds for the Levels consist of real locations like; Miami Beach, the Sphynx or Sastle Neuschwanstein.   It has 99 levels but once you hit 99 the game jumps back to round 0. The individual levels do actually repeat themselves much earlier.[CR]</plot>
		<releasedate>31/12/1983</releasedate>
		<year>1985</year>
		<genre>Action</genre>
		<studio>SEGA Enterprises</studio>
		<mobygames_url>https://www.mobygames.com/game/sg-1000/bomb-jack</mobygames_url>
		<giantbomb_url>https://www.giantbomb.com/bomb-jack/3030-185/</giantbomb_url>
		<boxart1>9v3AYXy.jpg</boxart1>
		<boxart2>q8gXuoo.jpg</boxart2>
		<snapshot1>WQ3B1zP.png</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>8gJXnyV.png</snapshot2>
		<snapshot3>mFhYrYN.png</snapshot3>
		<snapshot4>PcjPXH5.png</snapshot4>
		<snapshot5>9eJMb99.png</snapshot5>
		<snapshot6>Ivv3tUU.png</snapshot6>
		<snapshot7>sDi23n5.png</snapshot7>
		<snapshot8>g5d8UPl.png</snapshot8>
		<snapshot9>eqQXloN.png</snapshot9>
		<snapshot10>kVNElB1.png</snapshot10>
	</game>
	<game name="Bomberman Special (Taiwan)">
		<description>Bomberman Special (Taiwan)</description>
		<rom crc="69FC1494" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Sega%20-%20SG-1000.zip/Sega%20-%20SG-1000%2FBomberman%20Special%20%28Taiwan%29.zip" sha1="D1D56BCD996DF94458F5901DC537A5E30021256B" size="15623" />
		<title_clean>Bomberman Special</title_clean>
	</game>
	<game name="Borderline (Japan, Europe)">
		<description>Borderline (Japan, Europe)</description>
		<rom crc="0B4BCA74" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Sega%20-%20SG-1000.zip/Sega%20-%20SG-1000%2FBorderline%20%28Japan%2C%20Europe%29.zip" sha1="B967340FA91D960F86548F15E6D25A8E7E2C5043" size="9673" />
		<title_clean>Borderline</title_clean>
		<plot>[CR][B]Overview:[/B][CR]The vertical scrolling run &amp; gun shooter elements anticipate titles such as Xevious and Front Line.The digging maze elements anticipate titles such as Dig Dug and Digger. [CR]</plot>
		<releasedate>30/4/1981</releasedate>
		<year>1983</year>
		<genre>Action</genre>
		<studio>SEGA Enterprises</studio>
		<videoid>Phm7KKb06ME</videoid>
		<thegamesdb_id>33326</thegamesdb_id>
		<mobygames_url>https://www.mobygames.com/game/sg-1000/borderline</mobygames_url>
		<giantbomb_url>https://www.giantbomb.com/borderline/3030-51180/</giantbomb_url>
		<boxart1>P1AoQwX.jpg</boxart1>
		<boxart2>LJaEoKD.jpg</boxart2>
		<snapshot1>abDaWII.png</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>bEtn3sG.png</snapshot2>
		<snapshot3>t1UZ80p.png</snapshot3>
		<snapshot4>ARkYajq.png</snapshot4>
		<snapshot5>M63PniD.png</snapshot5>
		<snapshot6>DA9qPPQ.png</snapshot6>
		<snapshot7>TDbnaP4.png</snapshot7>
		<snapshot8>3J4PicX.png</snapshot8>
	</game>
	<game name="Castle, The (Japan)">
		<description>Castle, The (Japan)</description>
		<rom crc="092F29D6" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Sega%20-%20SG-1000.zip/Sega%20-%20SG-1000%2FCastle%2C%20The%20%28Japan%29.zip" sha1="2681786BFFCCF58B59410C331865D30A4D027087" size="24565" />
		<title_clean>Castle, The</title_clean>
		<plot>The Castle (&#12470;&#12539;&#12461;&#12515;&#12483;&#12473;&#12523;) is video game developed by ASCII and released for the SG-1000 in 1986. It is a port of an MSX game of the same name, and is largely identical due to the similar hardware between the two machines. Due to the decline of the SG-1000 and emergence of the Sega Master System, the game was not released in Europe or Australia like many other SG-1000 games.[CR]The Castle was the last SG-1000 game to be released commercially by Sega on a cart, and the only SG-1000 to adopt packaging more akin to Sega Mark III games. The Black Onyx would be the very last SG-1000 game to be released by Sega, but this would be on card.[CR]The game has a fairly standard plot of rescuing a princess from a castle, though the game itself was considered very large for the time. It also contains a map system similar to that of later Metroid and Castlevania games.[CR]The Castle was followed by the MSX/NES game Castle Excellent later in the year. The MSX version was also brought independently to the SG-1000 in Taiwan.</plot>
		<releasedate>1/2/1986</releasedate>
		<year>1986</year>
		<genre>Action</genre>
		<studio>SEGA Enterprises</studio>
		<thegamesdb_id>35127</thegamesdb_id>
		<mobygames_url>https://www.mobygames.com/game/sg-1000/castle</mobygames_url>
		<giantbomb_url>https://www.giantbomb.com/the-castle/3030-9995/</giantbomb_url>
		<boxart1>kk90USy.jpg</boxart1>
		<boxart2>nNBR32G.jpg</boxart2>
		<boxart3>hJKG85M.jpg</boxart3>
	</game>
	<game name="Chack'n Pop (Japan)">
		<description>Chack'n Pop (Japan)</description>
		<rom crc="D37BDA49" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Sega%20-%20SG-1000.zip/Sega%20-%20SG-1000%2FChack%27n%20Pop%20%28Japan%29.zip" sha1="08B5C1135F9678465ECE6A886C948CE091637372" size="17246" />
		<title_clean>Chack'n Pop</title_clean>
		<plot>[CR][B]Overview:[/B][CR]Chack'n Pop is a single-screen Arcade game from Taito in which the player is a dexterous bird-like creature named Chack'n. The goal of each stage is to descend to the bottom corner to free a heart from its cage, then head back to the top to stop a little monster from cracking one of Chack'n's eggs. Chack'n is capable of walking along ceilings - sort of like the gravity-switching Captain Viridian of VVVVVV - and can also throw bombs that will eliminate enemies within the radius of their explosions. Enemies appear first as harmless eggs, but soon hatch into tenacious monsters that resemble the Blubbas of Bubble Bobble.The level design, enemies and other graphical flourishes resemble those of Bubble Bobble, Taito's next big Arcade hit and the game the developers are best known for after Space Invaders. Bubble Bobble honors its spiritual ancestor by reusing one of Chack'n Pop's stages. Like Bubble Bobble, Chack'n Pop also received various home versions after its initial Arcade release, including NES, MSX and Sega SG-1000 versions. It also appears in various Taito Arcade compilations, such as Taito Legends 2 for the PS2.[CR]</plot>
		<releasedate>1/1/1983</releasedate>
		<genre>Action</genre>
		<thegamesdb_id>33327</thegamesdb_id>
		<giantbomb_url>https://www.giantbomb.com/chackn-pop/3030-6040/</giantbomb_url>
		<boxart1>HRmYRYK.png</boxart1>
		<snapshot1>f2EwrBj.jpg</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>gwdOCRN.png</snapshot2>
		<snapshot3>Glubakn.jpg</snapshot3>
		<snapshot4>Zk69CFA.jpg</snapshot4>
	</game>
	<game name="Challenge Derby (Japan) (vB) (Othello Multivision)">
		<description>Challenge Derby (Japan) (vB) (Othello Multivision)</description>
		<rom crc="C5F014DC" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Sega%20-%20SG-1000.zip/Sega%20-%20SG-1000%2FChallenge%20Derby%20%28Japan%29%20%28vB%29%20%28Othello%20Multivision%29.zip" sha1="8A5E6C9B10C9A99C1EAAEE48374D1FEDE5966340" size="10603" />
		<title_clean>Challenge Derby</title_clean>
	</game>
	<game name="Champion Baseball (Japan) (40kB)">
		<description>Champion Baseball (Japan) (40kB)</description>
		<rom crc="C0C16FA7" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Sega%20-%20SG-1000.zip/Sega%20-%20SG-1000%2FChampion%20Baseball%20%28Japan%29%20%2840kB%29.zip" sha1="85E5C2F354B9110E5F7C7DFCC7AB9814598B7956" size="11251" />
		<title_clean>Champion Baseball</title_clean>
		<plot>  [CR]</plot>
		<releasedate>31/12/1983</releasedate>
		<giantbomb_url>https://www.giantbomb.com/champion-baseball/3030-35120/</giantbomb_url>
		<boxart1>Hr3vNQx.jpg</boxart1>
	</game>
	<game name="Champion Billiards (Japan)">
		<description>Champion Billiards (Japan)</description>
		<rom crc="62B21E31" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Sega%20-%20SG-1000.zip/Sega%20-%20SG-1000%2FChampion%20Billiards%20%28Japan%29.zip" sha1="F517E6A6123643A5E7E5FFF6B413139AFA412D8E" size="18729" />
		<title_clean>Champion Billiards</title_clean>
		<plot>Champion Billiards (&#12481;&#12515;&#12531;&#12500;&#12458;&#12531;&#12499;&#12522;&#12516;&#12540;&#12489;) is a simplistic billiards game built for the SG-1000. It is the first game in Compile's "Lunar Pool" series. It was not released outside of Japan.[CR]Unlike the other Champion Sports games, Champion Billiards is not an accurate representation of it's sport. Instead, Champion Billiards is a level-based physics game. The goal of each level is to use the red cue ball to sink the other balls.[CR]Trivia: Breaking open the yellow ball can release a yellow Flicky.</plot>
		<releasedate>31/12/1986</releasedate>
		<genre>Sports</genre>
		<thegamesdb_id>35134</thegamesdb_id>
		<giantbomb_url>https://www.giantbomb.com/champion-billiards/3030-35068/</giantbomb_url>
		<boxart1>6VOjDkm.jpg</boxart1>
	</game>
	<game name="Champion Boxing (Japan)">
		<description>Champion Boxing (Japan)</description>
		<rom crc="26F947D1" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Sega%20-%20SG-1000.zip/Sega%20-%20SG-1000%2FChampion%20Boxing%20%28Japan%29.zip" sha1="8CD55EE1EFCAB917087B80629CA18B4629EDC15D" size="18318" />
		<title_clean>Champion Boxing</title_clean>
		<plot>A straightforward championship boxing game from Sega. You can select several punches during a boxing match: straight, jab or upper. Don't get cornered and if you get hit then get up your defenses or step back. The matches can be played at four different levels of difficulty. In the game there is a referee, who counts when your opponent or you are down. The matches can be set at four difficulty levels.</plot>
		<releasedate>31/12/1983</releasedate>
		<year>1984</year>
		<genre>Action, Sports</genre>
		<studio>SEGA Enterprises</studio>
		<mobygames_url>https://www.mobygames.com/game/sg-1000/champion-boxing</mobygames_url>
		<giantbomb_url>https://www.giantbomb.com/champion-boxing/3030-19968/</giantbomb_url>
		<boxart1>iwbAHc6.jpg</boxart1>
		<boxart2>E1Eg6Wd.jpg</boxart2>
		<snapshot1>Jfj4iqu.png</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>5L8SQCa.png</snapshot2>
		<snapshot3>tlxARgB.png</snapshot3>
		<snapshot4>Ij0Q0kK.png</snapshot4>
		<snapshot5>klsjf6x.png</snapshot5>
		<snapshot6>PKAcFVK.png</snapshot6>
		<snapshot7>y5oC6Jq.png</snapshot7>
		<snapshot8>Z2pp8qu.png</snapshot8>
		<snapshot9>Jwvm4b1.png</snapshot9>
		<snapshot10>dm8wwF8.png</snapshot10>
	</game>
	<game name="Champion Golf (Japan)">
		<description>Champion Golf (Japan)</description>
		<rom crc="868419B5" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Sega%20-%20SG-1000.zip/Sega%20-%20SG-1000%2FChampion%20Golf%20%28Japan%29.zip" sha1="05DEB000F24B7D8625C6E9332DCC91416ED3258F" size="20061" />
		<title_clean>Champion Golf</title_clean>
		<giantbomb_url>https://www.giantbomb.com/champion-golf/3030-34936/</giantbomb_url>
		<boxart1>Z4AH0JI.jpg</boxart1>
	</game>
	<game name="Champion Ice Hockey (Japan)">
		<description>Champion Ice Hockey (Japan)</description>
		<rom crc="BDC05652" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Sega%20-%20SG-1000.zip/Sega%20-%20SG-1000%2FChampion%20Ice%20Hockey%20%28Japan%29.zip" sha1="FF6440FC7E5C5FAA0B9868D5CB5110D1D8635284" size="18304" />
		<title_clean>Champion Ice Hockey</title_clean>
		<releasedate>31/12/1985</releasedate>
		<giantbomb_url>https://www.giantbomb.com/champion-ice-hockey/3030-4697/</giantbomb_url>
		<boxart1>ojev78f.jpg</boxart1>
	</game>
	<game name="Champion Kendou (Japan)">
		<description>Champion Kendou (Japan)</description>
		<rom crc="10CDEBCE" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Sega%20-%20SG-1000.zip/Sega%20-%20SG-1000%2FChampion%20Kendou%20%28Japan%29.zip" sha1="8565FC398D0206100DA785D10E008F7F6A3C225E" size="19873" />
		<title_clean>Champion Kendou</title_clean>
		<releasedate>31/12/1986</releasedate>
		<giantbomb_url>https://www.giantbomb.com/champion-kendo/3030-41101/</giantbomb_url>
		<boxart1>SAIeKjO.jpg</boxart1>
	</game>
	<game name="Champion Pro Wrestling (Japan)">
		<description>Champion Pro Wrestling (Japan)</description>
		<rom crc="372FE6BC" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Sega%20-%20SG-1000.zip/Sega%20-%20SG-1000%2FChampion%20Pro%20Wrestling%20%28Japan%29.zip" sha1="3BDB1E9D8B1A04D8FCC242C47BE790C427A75403" size="18784" />
		<title_clean>Champion Pro Wrestling</title_clean>
		<plot>A straightforward Pro Wrestling game from Sega in the Champion sport series. You always start atrank C and have to fight your way up to rank B and A. To  play for a rank you 'll have to fight three matches. Winning two out of three matches promotes you to an higher rank.During a match several moves can be selected: chop, kick, pile driver, dropkick. The referee does a countdown when your opponent or you are down.</plot>
		<releasedate>31/12/1985</releasedate>
		<year>1985</year>
		<genre>Action, Sports</genre>
		<studio>SEGA Enterprises</studio>
		<mobygames_url>https://www.mobygames.com/game/sg-1000/champion-pro-wrestling</mobygames_url>
		<giantbomb_url>https://www.giantbomb.com/champion-pro-wrestling/3030-19484/</giantbomb_url>
		<boxart1>p1kPWyB.jpg</boxart1>
		<snapshot1>rHh1AQA.png</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>Qy1WQZc.png</snapshot2>
		<snapshot3>SXQm7zX.png</snapshot3>
		<snapshot4>MzFpXHl.png</snapshot4>
		<snapshot5>ak3jqYO.png</snapshot5>
		<snapshot6>8lzOXAd.png</snapshot6>
		<snapshot7>Q9c7Wwd.png</snapshot7>
		<snapshot8>r51ar82.jpg</snapshot8>
	</game>
	<game name="Champion Soccer (Japan)">
		<description>Champion Soccer (Japan)</description>
		<rom crc="6F39719E" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Sega%20-%20SG-1000.zip/Sega%20-%20SG-1000%2FChampion%20Soccer%20%28Japan%29.zip" sha1="0B3CF82F020AC9249EA52766FFBAD41515D0B8B4" size="8785" />
		<title_clean>Champion Soccer</title_clean>
		<plot>Champion Soccer (&#12481;&#12515;&#12531;&#12500;&#12458;&#12531;&#12469;&#12483;&#12459;&#12540;) is a simplistic football game built for the SG-1000. Pony Canyon later brought it to the MSX.</plot>
		<releasedate>31/12/1984</releasedate>
		<genre>Sports</genre>
		<thegamesdb_id>35135</thegamesdb_id>
		<giantbomb_url>https://www.giantbomb.com/champion-soccer/3030-4460/</giantbomb_url>
		<boxart1>obazlaZ.jpg</boxart1>
		<snapshot1>QXafAcd.png</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>EinIpFU.png</snapshot2>
		<snapshot3>IVINtqZ.png</snapshot3>
		<snapshot4>fhesRGz.png</snapshot4>
		<snapshot5>bKsRvTn.png</snapshot5>
	</game>
	<game name="Champion Tennis (Japan)">
		<description>Champion Tennis (Japan)</description>
		<rom crc="7C663316" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Sega%20-%20SG-1000.zip/Sega%20-%20SG-1000%2FChampion%20Tennis%20%28Japan%29.zip" sha1="8B90300DCABC2CF8D58EE4800DCE3084B739886B" size="5897" />
		<title_clean>Champion Tennis</title_clean>
		<releasedate>31/12/1984</releasedate>
		<giantbomb_url>https://www.giantbomb.com/champion-tennis/3030-51888/</giantbomb_url>
		<boxart1>L0PeFOv.jpg</boxart1>
	</game>
	<game name="Championship Lode Runner (Japan)">
		<description>Championship Lode Runner (Japan)</description>
		<rom crc="11DB4B1D" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Sega%20-%20SG-1000.zip/Sega%20-%20SG-1000%2FChampionship%20Lode%20Runner%20%28Japan%29.zip" sha1="A0DAD095489DA2BDF8EC03F1ACC83F809DB2371F" size="20602" />
		<title_clean>Championship Lode Runner</title_clean>
		<plot>[CR][B]Overview:[/B][CR]Championship Lode Runner is an expansion of sorts to the original Lode Runner. Intended for players who had already mastered the original, Championship Lode Runner starts off punishingly difficult and only gets more challenging from there.The Famicom version of the game was exclusive to Japan, as were the NEC PC and Sega SG-1000 versions. This is due to the series' popularity in Japan where, like Spelunker, it accrued a significantly larger fanbase than in its native country.The game is best known to modern Western audiences for its appearance in the GameCenter CX television show. It was part of a special segment where Arino called up various Japanese citizens for advice and guidance through the exceptionally tough stages.[CR]</plot>
		<releasedate>17/4/1985</releasedate>
		<giantbomb_url>https://www.giantbomb.com/championship-lode-runner/3030-3471/</giantbomb_url>
		<boxart1>eYNzSVS.jpg</boxart1>
		<snapshot1>LyJrtiC.jpg</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>4cSMO7J.jpg</snapshot2>
		<snapshot3>7AxArR3.jpg</snapshot3>
		<snapshot4>EwpeLM2.jpg</snapshot4>
	</game>
	<game name="Choplifter (Taiwan) (English Logo)">
		<description>Choplifter (Taiwan) (English Logo)</description>
		<rom crc="7C603987" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Sega%20-%20SG-1000.zip/Sega%20-%20SG-1000%2FChoplifter%20%28Taiwan%29%20%28English%20Logo%29.zip" sha1="61D1AFE62B2BE0DA26D8A185828387063DD4B06E" size="17566" />
		<title_clean>Choplifter</title_clean>
		<plot>[CR][B]Overview:[/B][CR]Choplifter is a side-scrolling action game in which the player controls a helicopter that must elude the various enemy military forces trying to shoot it down while rescuing prisoners. It debuted on the Apple-II home computer in 1982 before being ported or adapted for a number of other home computers and consoles throughout the 1980s. It also saw multiple sequels.One of the earliest video games to have an  exclaimed! title. While the original game and early licensed ports of Choplifter! have an exclamation point on the box art and/or title screen, later ports (notably Sega's) omitted it and subsequent games in the series followed suit.[CR]</plot>
		<releasedate>31/12/1982</releasedate>
		<year>1985</year>
		<genre>Action</genre>
		<studio>SEGA Enterprises</studio>
		<mobygames_url>https://www.mobygames.com/game/sg-1000/choplifter</mobygames_url>
		<giantbomb_url>https://www.giantbomb.com/choplifter/3030-18152/</giantbomb_url>
		<boxart1>SYJZRjs.jpg</boxart1>
		<boxart2>xHNPQro.jpg</boxart2>
		<snapshot1>g9aERZJ.png</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>OLRuRgo.png</snapshot2>
		<snapshot3>HNjw8N3.png</snapshot3>
		<snapshot4>eZ9MnHd.png</snapshot4>
		<snapshot5>S7fdzDQ.png</snapshot5>
		<snapshot6>zEFMB7Z.png</snapshot6>
		<snapshot7>ZpWlLdc.png</snapshot7>
		<snapshot8>IXxZLrr.png</snapshot8>
		<snapshot9>1sCu3gk.jpg</snapshot9>
		<snapshot10>XyL3hsZ.jpg</snapshot10>
	</game>
	<game name="Chuugaku Hisshuu Eibunpou (Chuugaku 2-Nen) (Japan) (SC-3000)">
		<description>Chuugaku Hisshuu Eibunpou (Chuugaku 2-Nen) (Japan) (SC-3000)</description>
		<rom crc="D4C473B2" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Sega%20-%20SG-1000.zip/Sega%20-%20SG-1000%2FChuugaku%20Hisshuu%20Eibunpou%20%28Chuugaku%202-Nen%29%20%28Japan%29%20%28SC-3000%29.zip" sha1="EFE8A2852344F094806039019314EBE9C49E53F9" size="5279" />
		<title_clean>Chuugaku Hisshuu Eibunpou</title_clean>
		<giantbomb_url>https://www.giantbomb.com/chuugaku-hisshuu-ei-bunpou-chuugaku-1-nensei-you/3030-35060/</giantbomb_url>
		<boxart1>dRjdoaY.jpg</boxart1>
	</game>
	<game name="Chuugaku Hisshuu Eisakubun (Chuugaku 2-Nen) (Japan) (40kB) (SC-3000)">
		<description>Chuugaku Hisshuu Eisakubun (Chuugaku 2-Nen) (Japan) (40kB) (SC-3000)</description>
		<rom crc="3657B285" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Sega%20-%20SG-1000.zip/Sega%20-%20SG-1000%2FChuugaku%20Hisshuu%20Eisakubun%20%28Chuugaku%202-Nen%29%20%28Japan%29%20%2840kB%29%20%28SC-3000%29.zip" sha1="312CE1B510A90A96BCA63D028E96ED732AB6A043" size="7574" />
		<title_clean>Chuugaku Hisshuu Eisakubun</title_clean>
		<giantbomb_url>https://www.giantbomb.com/chuugaku-hisshuu-ei-bunpou-chuugaku-1-nensei-you/3030-35060/</giantbomb_url>
		<boxart1>dRjdoaY.jpg</boxart1>
	</game>
	<game name="Chuugaku Hisshuu Eitango (Chuugaku 2-Nen) (Japan) (40kB) (SC-3000)">
		<description>Chuugaku Hisshuu Eitango (Chuugaku 2-Nen) (Japan) (40kB) (SC-3000)</description>
		<rom crc="4F599483" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Sega%20-%20SG-1000.zip/Sega%20-%20SG-1000%2FChuugaku%20Hisshuu%20Eitango%20%28Chuugaku%202-Nen%29%20%28Japan%29%20%2840kB%29%20%28SC-3000%29.zip" sha1="09515CE5C8B598020F4C6B97540A7020ABB6F596" size="9152" />
		<title_clean>Chuugaku Hisshuu Eitango</title_clean>
		<giantbomb_url>https://www.giantbomb.com/chuugaku-hisshuu-ei-bunpou-chuugaku-1-nensei-you/3030-35060/</giantbomb_url>
		<boxart1>dRjdoaY.jpg</boxart1>
	</game>
	<game name="Congo Bongo (Japan, Europe) (Rev 1)">
		<description>Congo Bongo (Japan, Europe) (Rev 1)</description>
		<rom crc="5A24C7CF" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Sega%20-%20SG-1000.zip/Sega%20-%20SG-1000%2FCongo%20Bongo%20%28Japan%2C%20Europe%29%20%28Rev%201%29.zip" sha1="47ABA6A295E5695DB4C3AAA1DEA8AD8AC961B5F9" size="12846" />
		<title_clean>Congo Bongo</title_clean>
		<plot>[CR][B]Overview:[/B][CR] One levels plays very much like Donkey KongCongo Bongo was first created by    Sega to compete with arcade games such as   Donkey Kong or  Frogger. It never found the success of Donkey Kong and Frogger, and it was very much a commercial failure. Despite its lack of success in the arcades, it was eventually ported to most home computers and game home consoles.     [CR][B]Story:[/B][CR] Bongo is a mischievous ape that sets the tent of safari hunter on fire. The safari hunter lost his tent and possessions, and he seeks revenge on the ape for his practical joke. The safari hunter chases Bongo and through the dangerous Congo to get his revenge. [CR][B]Gameplay:[/B] [CR] Rhinos, one of the many dangers in the CongoCongo Bongo takes place in an isometric perspective, and requires the player to move a safari hunter through for different levels. One level, that resembles Donkey Kong, has the hunter climbing a mountain while simultaneously avoiding coconuts that a gorilla is hurling its way. Two levels have that hunter moving through a level avoiding hippos and rhinos. The last level very much resembles frogger, and has the hunter crossing a river across logs and lily pads.  These four levels will loop until the player loses all their lives.[CR]</plot>
		<releasedate>28/2/1983</releasedate>
		<year>1983</year>
		<genre>Action</genre>
		<studio>SEGA Enterprises</studio>
		<mobygames_url>https://www.mobygames.com/game/sg-1000/congo-bongo</mobygames_url>
		<giantbomb_url>https://www.giantbomb.com/congo-bongo/3030-4169/</giantbomb_url>
		<boxart1>PG635XP.jpg</boxart1>
		<boxart2>gm7giDC.jpg</boxart2>
		<boxart3>q45m7Cr.jpg</boxart3>
		<snapshot1>NzELbMd.png</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>nZPF0wp.png</snapshot2>
		<snapshot3>Qf5NujA.jpg</snapshot3>
		<snapshot4>LlN6ciP.png</snapshot4>
		<snapshot5>OeeIp7I.jpg</snapshot5>
		<snapshot6>AdLZSAj.png</snapshot6>
		<snapshot7>VG5sYFF.png</snapshot7>
	</game>
	<game name="C_So! (Japan)">
		<description>C_So! (Japan)</description>
		<rom crc="BE7ED0EB" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Sega%20-%20SG-1000.zip/Sega%20-%20SG-1000%2FC_So%21%20%28Japan%29.zip" sha1="D45A230B3CBF2D2DCFE7B94691FC7F1A5D747625" size="24207" />
		<title_clean>C_So!</title_clean>
		<plot>C_So! (&#65315;-&#65331;&#65327;&#65281;) is a 1985 SG-1000 game developed by Compile and published by Sega. It is a port of an MSX game from the same year, which was published by Pony Canyon.[CR]The game has the player collect various items and defeat monsters by using see-saws. In order to progress, all items must be collected and all monsters must be destroyed. There is also an edit mode, allowing the player to create their own levels.[CR]The game was only released in Japan.[CR]A South Korean company Joy Soft redundantly produced their own unlicensed "port" of the MSX version to the SG-1000 as well.</plot>
		<releasedate>1/2/1985</releasedate>
		<year>1985</year>
		<genre>Action</genre>
		<studio>SEGA Enterprises</studio>
		<thegamesdb_id>35125</thegamesdb_id>
		<mobygames_url>https://www.mobygames.com/game/sg-1000/c-so</mobygames_url>
		<boxart1>iDc5XBO.jpg</boxart1>
		<snapshot1>U03zttJ.png</snapshot1>
	</game>
	<game name="Dokidoki Penguin Land (Japan)">
		<description>Dokidoki Penguin Land (Japan)</description>
		<rom crc="346556B9" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Sega%20-%20SG-1000.zip/Sega%20-%20SG-1000%2FDokidoki%20Penguin%20Land%20%28Japan%29.zip" sha1="F49C43B1F9A0B19EF5F30D9BF2B222AF7AEB9FBF" size="19427" />
		<title_clean>Dokidoki Penguin Land</title_clean>
		<plot>In Penguin Land, you must control a penguin trying to get his (her?) egg down to the bottom of the level, while tunneling through ice to get there. Special egg and penguin blocks may make things easier, while polar bears and falling rocks will almost certainly slow you down. </plot>
		<releasedate>31/12/1985</releasedate>
		<year>1985</year>
		<genre>Action</genre>
		<studio>SEGA Enterprises</studio>
		<mobygames_url>https://www.mobygames.com/game/sg-1000/doki-doki-penguin-land</mobygames_url>
		<giantbomb_url>https://www.giantbomb.com/doki-doki-penguin-land/3030-34968/</giantbomb_url>
		<boxart1>G9x4ZYb.jpg</boxart1>
	</game>
	<game name="Dragon Wang (Taiwan) (English Logo)">
		<description>Dragon Wang (Taiwan) (English Logo)</description>
		<rom crc="6F94E5C0" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Sega%20-%20SG-1000.zip/Sega%20-%20SG-1000%2FDragon%20Wang%20%28Taiwan%29%20%28English%20Logo%29.zip" sha1="B2A3C886677BA3926CB56A1A781E7926852499C7" size="19016" />
		<title_clean>Dragon Wang</title_clean>
		<plot>The game was inspired by the arcade classic Kung-Fu Master. It later received a sequel called Kung Fu Kid.The protagonist is Wang (inspired by Jackie Chan and/or his character Thomas), hence the unfortunate title Dragon Wang. Wang is Chinese for King. [CR]</plot>
		<releasedate>31/12/1985</releasedate>
		<genre>Action, Fighting</genre>
		<thegamesdb_id>35136</thegamesdb_id>
		<giantbomb_url>https://www.giantbomb.com/dragon-wang/3030-30815/</giantbomb_url>
		<boxart1>Ktl3dWi.jpg</boxart1>
	</game>
	<game name="Drol (Japan)">
		<description>Drol (Japan)</description>
		<rom crc="288940CB" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Sega%20-%20SG-1000.zip/Sega%20-%20SG-1000%2FDrol%20%28Japan%29.zip" sha1="607B2B9A946EAAEBB938800BD3B1DF7D9342388C" size="22715" />
		<title_clean>Drol</title_clean>
		<plot>Save the girl, avoid the bird Control a robot who is tasked with rescuing various people and cute animals from horrible monsters in a four story world. Drol could shoot, had a  jet pack, and could transition up and down the levels of the world through trap doors. Enemies include snakes, monsters, axes, and the dreaded robot eating plant. The children the robot had to rescue were chasing balloons, which could make them more difficult to catch. Similar to  Defender, Drol featured a mini-map at the top of the screen to see approaching enemies and locate the robot's rescue targets. Originally released on the Apple II, Drol was later ported to the Atari 400/800 and Commodore 64. Drol was published by  Broderbund in 1983 and retailed for $34.95.[CR]</plot>
		<releasedate>1/2/1985</releasedate>
		<year>1985</year>
		<genre>Action</genre>
		<studio>SEGA Enterprises</studio>
		<thegamesdb_id>35128</thegamesdb_id>
		<mobygames_url>https://www.mobygames.com/game/sg-1000/drol</mobygames_url>
		<giantbomb_url>https://www.giantbomb.com/drol/3030-19717/</giantbomb_url>
		<boxart1>kCNwhjk.jpg</boxart1>
		<snapshot1>fg5oS2J.png</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>7wPgNCB.png</snapshot2>
		<snapshot3>8PHDcn1.jpg</snapshot3>
		<snapshot4>iVJfWLQ.png</snapshot4>
		<snapshot5>gAVwEQ4.png</snapshot5>
		<snapshot6>uNkWbfw.jpg</snapshot6>
	</game>
	<game name="Elevator Action (Japan)">
		<description>Elevator Action (Japan)</description>
		<rom crc="5AF8F69D" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Sega%20-%20SG-1000.zip/Sega%20-%20SG-1000%2FElevator%20Action%20%28Japan%29.zip" sha1="F72B3E44309E7C2E447C46928CE795453102F717" size="18773" />
		<title_clean>Elevator Action</title_clean>
		<plot>[CR][B]Overview:[/B][CR]The player assumes the role of a spy codename: "Otto", who infiltrates buildings filled with elevators. The goal is to collect secret documents from the building, while moving from floor to floor using an increasingly complex series of elevators. Enemy agents appear from behind closed doors, and Otto must outwit them via force or evasion. Successful completion of a level involves collecting the secret documents and traversing the building from top to bottom. In the lower floors of the building, the elevator systems are so complex that some puzzle-solving skills are needed.[CR]Cabinet[CR]The arcade version's cabinet is a standard upright. The controls consist of a 4-way joystick and two buttons, one for "shoot" and the other for jumping and kicking.[CR]Scoring System[CR]Point SystemRetrieve secret documents --500 ptKnock out an agent by falling light -- 300 ptCrush an agent using elevator -- 300 ptKnock out an agent by jumping/kicking -- 150 ptEliminate an agent by gun -- 100 ptBonus points are given with completion of each round (1,000 pt per round; up to 10,000 pt per round)An extra life is earned when player reaches 10,000 points.G. Ben Carter, Jr. holds the official record for this game, with 143,450 points.[CR]Ports[CR]Like many arcade games of this era, Elevator Action was reworked for consoles and computers, including the ZX Spectrum, Amstrad CPC, MSX, Commodore 64, NES, and the Game Boy.A version for the Atari 2600 was being worked on, but was abandoned before completion as a result of the video game industry crash of 1983. Eventually a 90% complete prototype (missing all sound, and containing countless serious bugs and glitches including a trick that allowed the player to "fly") was circulated online, and in the end the game was actually released complete with period-appropriate Atari style packaging, in a limited run of about 200 at the Classic Games Expo 2001.[CR]</plot>
		<releasedate>31/7/1983</releasedate>
		<year>1985</year>
		<genre>Action</genre>
		<studio>SEGA Enterprises</studio>
		<mobygames_url>https://www.mobygames.com/game/sg-1000/elevator-action</mobygames_url>
		<giantbomb_url>https://www.giantbomb.com/elevator-action/3030-8179/</giantbomb_url>
		<boxart1>ASyfLSz.jpg</boxart1>
		<boxart2>k9ckil7.jpg</boxart2>
		<snapshot1>lpYlNgH.png</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>fRU3ajf.png</snapshot2>
		<snapshot3>C7LCrbW.png</snapshot3>
		<snapshot4>ihz5glI.png</snapshot4>
		<snapshot5>Cv90Zsf.png</snapshot5>
		<snapshot6>ZceMYcs.jpg</snapshot6>
		<snapshot7>3OshGtG.png</snapshot7>
		<snapshot8>r43jkdX.png</snapshot8>
		<snapshot9>9UFKrSJ.png</snapshot9>
		<snapshot10>oKyhtug.png</snapshot10>
	</game>
	<game name="Exerion (Japan, Europe)">
		<description>Exerion (Japan, Europe)</description>
		<rom crc="A2C45B61" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Sega%20-%20SG-1000.zip/Sega%20-%20SG-1000%2FExerion%20%28Japan%2C%20Europe%29.zip" sha1="839E19487B96D02222FF397B047CBC6A0FBC08FF" size="8674" />
		<title_clean>Exerion</title_clean>
		<plot>[CR][B]Overview:[/B][CR]Exerion is a vertical-scrolling shooter, where the player's ship would shoot upwards to take out waves of enemies. Though most of the screen was a static black, on the bottom half of the screen the player could see the horizon of whichever planet they were on rushing towards them, including various geographical fixtures whizzing past in a manner similar to parallax scrolling.The game is an example of an early shoot-em-up: There are no power-ups, just waves of enemies. Players had a limited number of lives and had to start over once they ran out. Enemies, rather than departing the screen upon passing the player's ship, would home in towards them in order to collide with and destroy them: The player had to circle back around and maneuver underneath the enemies in order to shoot them down.Exerion had four versions: The original 1983 arcade version, its initial MSX home version of the following year, a Sega SG-1000 version and an eventual Famicom version in 1985. The Famicom version would also be rereleased on the Wii Shop's Virtual Console decades later. The arcade version, though the best looking, was also the hardest to play as the ship had a strong sense of inertia and momentum to it, making it sluggish to move and difficult to control. The home versions were better regarded.[CR]</plot>
		<releasedate>11/2/1985</releasedate>
		<year>1983</year>
		<genre>Action</genre>
		<studio>SEGA Enterprises</studio>
		<mobygames_url>https://www.mobygames.com/game/sg-1000/exerion</mobygames_url>
		<giantbomb_url>https://www.giantbomb.com/exerion/3030-11700/</giantbomb_url>
		<boxart1>eehJ2bk.jpg</boxart1>
		<snapshot1>cXH6Zop.png</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>OIxUA3V.png</snapshot2>
		<snapshot3>VXQK9D5.png</snapshot3>
		<snapshot4>r1T4hxG.png</snapshot4>
		<snapshot5>LaDkpSK.png</snapshot5>
		<snapshot6>V6shxO9.png</snapshot6>
		<snapshot7>PGfsAlv.png</snapshot7>
		<snapshot8>thZso6P.png</snapshot8>
		<snapshot9>ZXeiGsB.png</snapshot9>
		<snapshot10>cnLZU3Z.png</snapshot10>
	</game>
	<game name="Flicky (Japan) (Rev 1)">
		<description>Flicky (Japan) (Rev 1)</description>
		<rom crc="26D2862C" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Sega%20-%20SG-1000.zip/Sega%20-%20SG-1000%2FFlicky%20%28Japan%29%20%28Rev%201%29.zip" sha1="51947FC0AE2BC3442B0FEE2CCCF2344B7A94A167" size="14346" />
		<title_clean>Flicky</title_clean>
		<plot>[CR][B]Overview:[/B][CR]Flicky is a action platformer developed by Sega. The title was first released for arcade in 1984 and Sega Genesis in 1991.The game has been re-released In the Sonic Mega Collection for the GameCube (2002), the Sonic Mega Collection Plus for the Xbox and PlayStation 2 (2005); Sega Genesis Collection for PSP and PlayStation 2 (2006); Sonic's Ultimate Genesis Collection for Xbox 360 and Playstation 3 (2009); and on PC via Steam (2010).[CR][B]Gameplay:[/B][CR]The player controls a bird named Flicky and the object of the game is to guide chicks to safety whilst avoiding a cat (Tiger) and a lizard (Iggy). Players can throw certain objects at Tiger and Iggy to kill them. There are 48 proper levels in the game and they are broken up with a mini-game in which Flicky must catch her chicks in a net as they are flung in the air by Tiger. Each main level wraps around.After finishing the 48 levels, it is possible to replay the game at a higher difficulty setting.[CR]Additional Information[CR]Flickies are a species of bird that have appeared in a number of Sonic games most notably Sonic 3D Blast and Tails Adventure.The game was designed by Yoji Shii before he went on to found Artoon.[CR]PC System Requirements[CR]MinimumOS: Windows&#174; XP or higherGraphics: 32MB or greater graphics cardDirectX&#174;: DirectX&#174; 9.0 or greaterHard Drive: 50MB free disc space[CR]</plot>
		<releasedate>31/12/1984</releasedate>
		<year>1984</year>
		<genre>Action</genre>
		<studio>SEGA Enterprises</studio>
		<mobygames_url>https://www.mobygames.com/game/sg-1000/flicky</mobygames_url>
		<giantbomb_url>https://www.giantbomb.com/flicky/3030-12914/</giantbomb_url>
		<boxart1>SPjsvcB.jpg</boxart1>
		<boxart2>6XLzC8s.jpg</boxart2>
		<boxart3>EYaO3yc.jpg</boxart3>
		<snapshot1>fpd8KZ0.png</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>MqNq80k.png</snapshot2>
		<snapshot3>nDWUmwT.jpg</snapshot3>
		<snapshot4>1HVfwIA.jpg</snapshot4>
		<snapshot5>0AcHXlH.jpg</snapshot5>
		<snapshot6>n5h83gT.png</snapshot6>
		<snapshot7>FKgtsTF.jpg</snapshot7>
		<snapshot8>3xWlEhF.jpg</snapshot8>
	</game>
	<game name="Flipper (Taiwan)">
		<description>Flipper (Taiwan)</description>
		<rom crc="042C36BA" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Sega%20-%20SG-1000.zip/Sega%20-%20SG-1000%2FFlipper%20%28Taiwan%29.zip" sha1="B7EB254A014772A83829E1991DCD32396E8DD9CC" size="8169" />
		<title_clean>Flipper</title_clean>
		<giantbomb_url>https://www.giantbomb.com/sega-flipper/3030-35119/</giantbomb_url>
		<boxart1>Odc5aVN.jpg</boxart1>
	</game>
	<game name="Galaga (Taiwan)">
		<description>Galaga (Taiwan)</description>
		<rom crc="845BBB22" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Sega%20-%20SG-1000.zip/Sega%20-%20SG-1000%2FGalaga%20%28Taiwan%29.zip" sha1="6C049DAA08AF7B1F08B98D6998BA52D7CF3CC4DE" size="8416" />
		<title_clean>Galaga</title_clean>
		<plot>[CR][B]Overview:[/B][CR]Released in 1981, Galaga has become one of the most popular arcade games of all time. Much more well received than its predecessor, Galaxian, Galaga features fast paced top-down shooting action. The player takes control of a small ship located at the bottom of the screen and is tasked with destroying the incoming waves of insect-like enemies.[CR][B]Gameplay:[/B][CR]Tractor-beamThe player controls a "fighter" spaceship whose movement is restricted to flying left or right. Upon the start of a level, waves of enemies fly in formation and complete a flight pattern before positioning themselves at the top of the screen. It is ideal to destroy the incoming ships before they complete their fly-in. Once in formation at the top of the screen, enemies will regularly break off to attack. Enemy ships attack by dropping bombs and/or attempting to collide with the player's ship.The most popular and effective strategy is for the player to sacrifice their own ship to a "Boss Galaga" ship. These ships hover above the player and emit a tractor-beam. Entering this beam will sacrifice the current ship and allow the player to use one of the reserves. Destroying the "Boss Galaga" will reclaim the captured ship. The player is then rewarded with dual ships which effectively doubles the player's firepower.Additionally, a bonus stage occurs every four levels, allowing the player to earn extra points without the risk of being destroyed. Upon destroying every fighter during a bonus stage, the player will then be rewarded with an extra life.[CR]Galaga in Mass Media[CR]1982 - Actor Matthew Broderick spent two months playing Galaga to prepare for his upcoming role in Wargames.2004 - The ABC television series Lost names a DHARMA Initiative submarine after the popular video game.2009 - Fans are able to purchase a Galaga arcade-style video game Christmas ornament (complete with audibles) thanks to Hallmark.2012 - In Marvel's The Avengers, Tony Stark catches a S.H.I.E.L.D. agent playing Galaga. The agent denies it but after the main characters leave the room he goes back to playing the game. The game footage shown on the computer screen is from the MSX port. [CR]</plot>
		<releasedate>30/9/1981</releasedate>
		<giantbomb_url>https://www.giantbomb.com/galaga/3030-15784/</giantbomb_url>
		<boxart1>CzQ7RPd.jpg</boxart1>
		<snapshot1>VzwyGu0.jpg</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>nsz1yL9.jpg</snapshot2>
		<snapshot3>OGYfW8A.jpg</snapshot3>
		<snapshot4>iLzgHMh.jpg</snapshot4>
		<snapshot5>qpq3QCq.jpg</snapshot5>
		<snapshot6>ChaS2JW.jpg</snapshot6>
		<snapshot7>16whF4V.jpg</snapshot7>
		<snapshot8>KG6TPTs.jpg</snapshot8>
		<snapshot9>Vd9MK64.jpg</snapshot9>
		<snapshot10>cRyed0F.jpg</snapshot10>
	</game>
	<game name="Girl's Garden (Japan)">
		<description>Girl's Garden (Japan)</description>
		<rom crc="1898F274" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Sega%20-%20SG-1000.zip/Sega%20-%20SG-1000%2FGirl%27s%20Garden%20%28Japan%29.zip" sha1="0E08786587FB76909B3F9806BA1F5D57EA17728C" size="19481" />
		<title_clean>Girl's Garden</title_clean>
		<plot>In order to prevent her boyfriend Minto from going to another little girl named Cocco, Papri must collect ten different flowers and return them to her boyfriend's house. Flowers must be caught in full bloom so that the number of flowers in her possession will increase; catching flowers too early will consider the flowers to be wasted and flowers caught too late will be wilted. Wilted flowers will ruin the bouquet, causing the player to lose half of the flowers.[CR]Bears have a taste for honey and cause the player to lose one of two hearts if one of them attacks the player. However, the honey can be dropped in order to render the bear temporarily harmless to the player. Bees appear as the player's ally, giving her bonus items occasionally and extra honey if the player catches it on a flower.</plot>
		<releasedate>13/4/1984</releasedate>
		<year>1984</year>
		<genre>Action</genre>
		<studio>SEGA Enterprises</studio>
		<nplayers>1</nplayers>
		<thegamesdb_id>33168</thegamesdb_id>
		<mobygames_url>https://www.mobygames.com/game/sg-1000/girls-garden</mobygames_url>
		<giantbomb_url>https://www.giantbomb.com/girls-garden/3030-36568/</giantbomb_url>
		<boxart1>HXd23SY.jpg</boxart1>
		<boxart2>bqreuxH.jpg</boxart2>
		<snapshot1>4dpw7hQ.png</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>vAAQBsf.png</snapshot2>
		<snapshot3>C2bsY02.png</snapshot3>
		<snapshot4>C2IUfRm.png</snapshot4>
		<snapshot5>Q0oD4Ku.png</snapshot5>
		<snapshot6>n6365aC.png</snapshot6>
		<snapshot7>zYlmESu.png</snapshot7>
	</game>
	<game name="Golgo 13 (Japan)">
		<description>Golgo 13 (Japan)</description>
		<rom crc="0D159ED0" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Sega%20-%20SG-1000.zip/Sega%20-%20SG-1000%2FGolgo%2013%20%28Japan%29.zip" sha1="BF27536C6AE71B333DA8B362479DA0A838D0715E" size="11636" />
		<title_clean>Golgo 13</title_clean>
		<plot>In this game players play Duke Togo, a.k.a. Golgo 13, who moves back and forth in a car at the bottom of the screen. Players must aim at the windows of a train and shoot them out to free captives behind each window. Initially a separate train appears to occasionally block shots, but in later rounds cars also appear to block shots and a helicopter flies in to attack the player's car.The gameplay was unique for its time, with sniping elements featured for the first time in gaming, a precursor of things to come in the more famous Golgo 13 games Top Secret Episode and The Mafat Conspiracy.  [CR]</plot>
		<releasedate>1/1/1984</releasedate>
		<year>1984</year>
		<genre>Action</genre>
		<studio>SEGA Enterprises</studio>
		<nplayers>1</nplayers>
		<thegamesdb_id>33246</thegamesdb_id>
		<mobygames_url>https://www.mobygames.com/game/sg-1000/golgo-13</mobygames_url>
		<giantbomb_url>https://www.giantbomb.com/golgo-13/3030-33478/</giantbomb_url>
		<boxart1>K68gWsP.jpg</boxart1>
		<snapshot1>nm56Sbu.png</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>2qhdCpF.png</snapshot2>
		<snapshot3>vphEoOV.png</snapshot3>
		<snapshot4>clao1eD.png</snapshot4>
		<snapshot5>xzTNjXQ.png</snapshot5>
	</game>
	<game name="GP World (Japan) (Rev 1)">
		<description>GP World (Japan) (Rev 1)</description>
		<rom crc="191FFE0A" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Sega%20-%20SG-1000.zip/Sega%20-%20SG-1000%2FGP%20World%20%28Japan%29%20%28Rev%201%29.zip" sha1="37AA4812D37445C9E86BC4E02F056FB50D19DC6A" size="18584" />
		<title_clean>GP World</title_clean>
		<plot>GP World (&#65319;&#65328;&#12527;&#12540;&#12523;&#12489;) for the SG-1000 and MSX, is a loose conversion of the 1984 LaserDisc-based arcade game, GP World. It was released in 1985 exclusively in Japan.</plot>
		<releasedate>1/2/1984</releasedate>
		<genre>Driving, Racing</genre>
		<thegamesdb_id>35146</thegamesdb_id>
		<boxart1>BFo4FJ0.jpg</boxart1>
	</game>
	<game name="Gulkave (Japan)">
		<description>Gulkave (Japan)</description>
		<rom crc="15A754A3" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Sega%20-%20SG-1000.zip/Sega%20-%20SG-1000%2FGulkave%20%28Japan%29.zip" sha1="3FB197D16B25BC128A2866C4B78B0535AB8DC412" size="20530" />
		<title_clean>Gulkave</title_clean>
		<plot>Gulkave horizontal shoot 'em up game developed by Compile and published by Sega in 1986.[CR]</plot>
		<releasedate>1/2/1986</releasedate>
		<year>1986</year>
		<genre>Action</genre>
		<studio>SEGA Enterprises</studio>
		<thegamesdb_id>35130</thegamesdb_id>
		<mobygames_url>https://www.mobygames.com/game/sg-1000/gulkave</mobygames_url>
		<giantbomb_url>https://www.giantbomb.com/gulkave/3030-18437/</giantbomb_url>
		<boxart1>Gj3jRcK.jpg</boxart1>
	</game>
	<game name="Guzzler (Japan) (Othello Multivision)">
		<description>Guzzler (Japan) (Othello Multivision)</description>
		<rom crc="61FA9EA0" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Sega%20-%20SG-1000.zip/Sega%20-%20SG-1000%2FGuzzler%20%28Japan%29%20%28Othello%20Multivision%29.zip" sha1="D42B2C5F1DA4E0FBD29FCEA91BFC092AE46DA4B8" size="5757" />
		<title_clean>Guzzler</title_clean>
		<plot>In Guzzler, you play a small transparent character trapped in a maze filled with walking flames, born from stationary fires. In order to survive, you must extinguish flames &#8212; and their mother fires &#8212; by filling up with water from a few puddles spread out around the screen (similar to the power pills of Pac-Man) and spit it out on the fires. However, once you are filled to the top, you move slower, making you a prone victim of the fires. One refill from a puddle is good enough for three cascades of water, making you lighter &#8212; and faster &#8212; each time you spit, but the range of your deluge will also be shorter. From time to time, an alcoholic beverage appears in the middle of the screen, the fires will momentarily freeze while you are fully recharged and may put them out at leisure.</plot>
		<year>1983</year>
		<genre>Action</genre>
		<studio>Tsukuda Original</studio>
		<mobygames_url>https://www.mobygames.com/game/sg-1000/guzzler_</mobygames_url>
		<snapshot1>w76w4yR.png</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>rt5MRL3.png</snapshot2>
		<snapshot3>maC54Z0.png</snapshot3>
		<snapshot4>fJRZBQk.png</snapshot4>
		<snapshot5>QckDiyY.png</snapshot5>
		<snapshot6>pqQOSCq.png</snapshot6>
		<snapshot7>WH0DOBo.png</snapshot7>
		<snapshot8>lvEeLiY.png</snapshot8>
		<snapshot9>mutqTqp.png</snapshot9>
		<snapshot10>BFSqOyZ.png</snapshot10>
	</game>
	<game name="H.E.R.O. (Japan)">
		<description>H.E.R.O. (Japan)</description>
		<rom crc="4587DE6E" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Sega%20-%20SG-1000.zip/Sega%20-%20SG-1000%2FH.E.R.O.%20%28Japan%29.zip" sha1="19ACB69B7B64DA5083349D8BC40A47BEACC88C41" size="19035" />
		<title_clean>H.E.R.O.</title_clean>
		<plot>[CR][B]Overview:[/B][CR]  H.E.R.O. is a platforming game published and developed by                     Activision in 1984. It was originally developed for the                    Atari 2600 but ported to many other consoles already listed on this page. The name is speculated to mean "Helicopter Emergency Rescue Operation".[CR][B]Gameplay:[/B][CR]   The main objective of the game is to rescue trapped miners. You're equipped with a       heli-pack  allowing you to          fly around the level, as well as a               laser-beam to defend yourself from the game's various enemies (             bats,             snakes,            spiders, etc). You're also equipped with           dynamite, which you can use to kill  enemies or to destroy various walls blocking your way. It's possible to use your laser beam to disintegrate the wall as well without the risk of killing yourself, although it takes longer. There are      magma walls later in the game that kill you if you touch them, making it slightly harder to plant dynamite next to, or navigate through the caverns. When you die, you're returned to the same screen as the one you were just on, costing a life. There is a        power meter on the bottom of the screen that slowly drains indicating a time limit, making later levels fairly difficult due to their length. When the power meter is drained, you lose a life. Later levels often feature a raft the player can use to float across the water unharmed.  [CR]H.E.R.O. for Xbox 360 Game Room[CR]H.E.R.O. was included in the June 23rd, 2010 Game Pack release of   Game Room for the  Xbox 360.[CR]</plot>
		<releasedate>1/1/1985</releasedate>
		<genre>Action</genre>
		<nplayers>1</nplayers>
		<thegamesdb_id>33244</thegamesdb_id>
		<giantbomb_url>https://www.giantbomb.com/hero/3030-4430/</giantbomb_url>
		<boxart1>izG1eHV.jpg</boxart1>
		<snapshot1>OJmigNl.png</snapshot1>
	</game>
	<game name="Hang-On II (Japan)">
		<description>Hang-On II (Japan)</description>
		<rom crc="9BE3C6BD" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Sega%20-%20SG-1000.zip/Sega%20-%20SG-1000%2FHang-On%20II%20%28Japan%29.zip" sha1="E636E889D4E81C024EE7DAE8943C2B8D9D4A5414" size="18095" />
		<title_clean>Hang-On II</title_clean>
		<plot>  [CR]</plot>
		<releasedate>31/12/1985</releasedate>
		<giantbomb_url>https://www.giantbomb.com/hang-on-ii/3030-41184/</giantbomb_url>
		<boxart1>dhrLSMv.jpg</boxart1>
	</game>
	<game name="Home Basic (Japan) (SC-3000)">
		<description>Home Basic (Japan) (SC-3000)</description>
		<rom crc="78A37CBC" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Sega%20-%20SG-1000.zip/Sega%20-%20SG-1000%2FHome%20Basic%20%28Japan%29%20%28SC-3000%29.zip" sha1="F1E1E7E9687CF4F9F498779A44134C2D70BB8D4B" size="22939" />
		<title_clean>Home Basic</title_clean>
	</game>
	<game name="Home Mahjong (Japan) (Rev 1)">
		<description>Home Mahjong (Japan) (Rev 1)</description>
		<rom crc="E7E0F0E3" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Sega%20-%20SG-1000.zip/Sega%20-%20SG-1000%2FHome%20Mahjong%20%28Japan%29%20%28Rev%201%29.zip" sha1="AC38A279F24E132ACF6AC9FD27B53D1B939D2E7E" size="25925" />
		<title_clean>Home Mahjong</title_clean>
		<giantbomb_url>https://www.giantbomb.com/home-mahjong/3030-34926/</giantbomb_url>
		<boxart1>NhaEGB2.jpg</boxart1>
	</game>
	<game name="Hustle Chumy (Japan)">
		<description>Hustle Chumy (Japan)</description>
		<rom crc="A627D440" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Sega%20-%20SG-1000.zip/Sega%20-%20SG-1000%2FHustle%20Chumy%20%28Japan%29.zip" sha1="1F1BAD94B2D869C10A2373CA40D4076D227CC302" size="9979" />
		<title_clean>Hustle Chumy</title_clean>
		<plot>Hustle Chumy (&#12495;&#12483;&#12473;&#12523;&#12481;&#12517;&#12540;&#12511;&#12540;) is an SG-1000 and MSX game developed by Compile and released in 1984.[CR]In Hustle Chumy players control a mouse named Chumy who needs to collect apples (and other food) in a sewer, avoiding other critters as he goes. As Chumy eats more food, his speed decreases, but his fireballs are given a longer range. Levels have varying layouts.[CR]There are several types of enemies in the game, most of which can be defeated with fireballs.</plot>
		<releasedate>1/2/1984</releasedate>
		<year>1984</year>
		<genre>Action</genre>
		<studio>SEGA Enterprises</studio>
		<thegamesdb_id>35132</thegamesdb_id>
		<mobygames_url>https://www.mobygames.com/game/sg-1000/hustle-chumy</mobygames_url>
		<giantbomb_url>https://www.giantbomb.com/hustle-chumy/3030-13431/</giantbomb_url>
		<boxart1>ZuCNBcX.jpg</boxart1>
	</game>
	<game name="Hyper Sports (Japan)">
		<description>Hyper Sports (Japan)</description>
		<rom crc="BA09A0FD" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Sega%20-%20SG-1000.zip/Sega%20-%20SG-1000%2FHyper%20Sports%20%28Japan%29.zip" sha1="8A13EE297F861F436B9529A5E2193CB697BAA56F" size="16074" />
		<title_clean>Hyper Sports</title_clean>
		<plot>[CR][B]Overview:[/B][CR]Hyper Sports is a competitive sports game that features seven events commonly seen in the Olympics. It was a tie-in game for the 1984 Summer Olympics in Los Angeles, and a sequel to Konami's earlier Track &amp; Field. As with Track &amp; Field, the player has to pass each of the game's events to move onto the next.The player, as various athletes, take part in the following seven events. In order to progress from one to the next, the player has to pass a minimal "qualification" score for each event. The events usually involve mashing buttons as quickly as possible, or some very specific timing. The events include:Skeet ShootingTriple JumpSwimmingLong HorseArcheryWeight LiftingPole Vault[CR]</plot>
		<releasedate>31/12/1984</releasedate>
		<year>1985</year>
		<genre>Action, Sports</genre>
		<studio>SEGA Enterprises</studio>
		<mobygames_url>https://www.mobygames.com/game/sg-1000/hyper-sports</mobygames_url>
		<giantbomb_url>https://www.giantbomb.com/hyper-sports/3030-5590/</giantbomb_url>
		<boxart1>xI94edH.jpg</boxart1>
		<boxart2>sTvBFj6.jpg</boxart2>
		<snapshot1>5Tc1v4J.jpg</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>ZtxUUBa.jpg</snapshot2>
		<snapshot3>bKiOQFM.jpg</snapshot3>
		<snapshot4>8pLqTIO.jpg</snapshot4>
		<snapshot5>gm6Z9kR.jpg</snapshot5>
		<snapshot6>kEAUHj0.png</snapshot6>
	</game>
	<game name="Kagaku (Gensokigou Master) (Japan) (SC-3000)">
		<description>Kagaku (Gensokigou Master) (Japan) (SC-3000)</description>
		<rom crc="F9C81FE1" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Sega%20-%20SG-1000.zip/Sega%20-%20SG-1000%2FKagaku%20%28Gensokigou%20Master%29%20%28Japan%29%20%28SC-3000%29.zip" sha1="6B35016742DB0A06947C679F41B8130C28D2DE7D" size="5316" />
		<title_clean>Kagaku</title_clean>
	</game>
	<game name="King's Valley (Taiwan)">
		<description>King's Valley (Taiwan)</description>
		<rom crc="223397A1" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Sega%20-%20SG-1000.zip/Sega%20-%20SG-1000%2FKing%27s%20Valley%20%28Taiwan%29.zip" sha1="922D23895C12707B2FC382EA5CB769C5CB9B5755" size="15133" />
		<title_clean>King's Valley</title_clean>
	</game>
	<game name="Knightmare (Taiwan)">
		<description>Knightmare (Taiwan)</description>
		<rom crc="281D2888" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Sega%20-%20SG-1000.zip/Sega%20-%20SG-1000%2FKnightmare%20%28Taiwan%29.zip" sha1="BABDB6B109B20E81C28CD892C2042723E9CBFF49" size="28125" />
		<title_clean>Knightmare</title_clean>
	</game>
	<game name="Legend of Kage, The (Taiwan)">
		<description>Legend of Kage, The (Taiwan)</description>
		<rom crc="2E7166D5" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Sega%20-%20SG-1000.zip/Sega%20-%20SG-1000%2FLegend%20of%20Kage%2C%20The%20%28Taiwan%29.zip" sha1="902DBB122BF0EFC76604A876C3FAE51C074BDC6A" size="24300" />
		<title_clean>Legend of Kage, The</title_clean>
	</game>
	<game name="Lode Runner (Japan, Europe)">
		<description>Lode Runner (Japan, Europe)</description>
		<rom crc="00ED3970" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Sega%20-%20SG-1000.zip/Sega%20-%20SG-1000%2FLode%20Runner%20%28Japan%2C%20Europe%29.zip" sha1="F14F216EDFDA7DFD113F5CB32375A27BE8A6409D" size="16792" />
		<title_clean>Lode Runner</title_clean>
		<plot>[CR][B]Overview:[/B][CR]This seminal early 1980s game started out as an Apple II prototype called 'Miner'. Lode Runner is a single screen 2D platform game developed by Douglas Smith. This original concept was rejected by Br&#248;derbund Software, which forced Smith to acquire extra equipment to make an enhanced version. This resulted in what was to become Lode Runner in its final form. Available on many platforms including the Apple II, Commodore 64, Sinclair Spectrum and the MSX.The most innovative feature of Lode Runner is the ability for the user to create their own levels. The game features a level editor tool similar to that used by the Smith, which can be used to add to the original 150 levels available with the game.The creator of Tetris, the most critically acclaimed puzzle game of all time, Alexey Pajitnov is claimed to have said the Lode Runner was his favourite game for many years.[CR][B]Gameplay:[/B][CR]Lode Runner on the Commodore 64The object is to collect all the gold in a level then get to the exit at the top of the level. The challenge lies in the level design and various enemies spread throughout. The only way to combat the enemy is to dig holes in the ground for them to fall into and get temporarily trapped, there was no jumping. The levels contain only brick 'ground', ladders and overhead bars.Even though it is a 2D platform game it is as many parts puzzle game. The level and enemies are designed to test a player mentally and physically, with problem solving and quick reactions needed to clear the more dastardly levels.[CR]</plot>
		<releasedate>20/7/1983</releasedate>
		<year>1984</year>
		<genre>Action</genre>
		<studio>SEGA Enterprises</studio>
		<mobygames_url>https://www.mobygames.com/game/sg-1000/lode-runner</mobygames_url>
		<giantbomb_url>https://www.giantbomb.com/lode-runner/3030-636/</giantbomb_url>
		<boxart1>f93Zn3d.jpg</boxart1>
		<boxart2>rH4Zdon.jpg</boxart2>
		<snapshot1>UajrzxD.jpg</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>s9AApr2.jpg</snapshot2>
		<snapshot3>Sw83RRP.png</snapshot3>
		<snapshot4>eLkMDiu.png</snapshot4>
		<snapshot5>0z1RJgb.png</snapshot5>
		<snapshot6>qD9HrKm.png</snapshot6>
		<snapshot7>u0ZPirB.png</snapshot7>
		<snapshot8>R3HKfYS.png</snapshot8>
		<snapshot9>8p0ZxeO.png</snapshot9>
	</game>
	<game name="Magical Kid Wiz (Taiwan)">
		<description>Magical Kid Wiz (Taiwan)</description>
		<rom crc="FFC4EE3F" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Sega%20-%20SG-1000.zip/Sega%20-%20SG-1000%2FMagical%20Kid%20Wiz%20%28Taiwan%29.zip" sha1="FD24B501046CF811B04386129BE0362A1EABF6B3" size="22295" />
		<title_clean>Magical Kid Wiz</title_clean>
	</game>
	<game name="Mahjong (Japan) (English Title)">
		<description>Mahjong (Japan) (English Title)</description>
		<rom crc="1C137CAB" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Sega%20-%20SG-1000.zip/Sega%20-%20SG-1000%2FMahjong%20%28Japan%29%20%28English%20Title%29.zip" sha1="81015CEA7E5FF08BD7D20953A702D47EFDB8C11C" size="14047" />
		<title_clean>Mahjong</title_clean>
		<giantbomb_url>https://www.giantbomb.com/home-mahjong/3030-34926/</giantbomb_url>
		<boxart1>NhaEGB2.jpg</boxart1>
	</game>
	<game name="Monaco GP (Japan) (Rev 2)">
		<description>Monaco GP (Japan) (Rev 2)</description>
		<rom crc="02E5D66A" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Sega%20-%20SG-1000.zip/Sega%20-%20SG-1000%2FMonaco%20GP%20%28Japan%29%20%28Rev%202%29.zip" sha1="694228631D09ED06C8850FD164C6D99B12FF173D" size="13488" />
		<title_clean>Monaco GP</title_clean>
		<plot>Monaco GP was also one of the last non-CPU video games, using earlier TTL logic technology (used in games prior to Gun Fight) instead of microprocessor technology.[CR]</plot>
		<releasedate>1/2/1983</releasedate>
		<genre>Driving, Racing</genre>
		<thegamesdb_id>35145</thegamesdb_id>
		<giantbomb_url>https://www.giantbomb.com/monaco-gp/3030-40782/</giantbomb_url>
		<boxart1>bFNRHzh.jpg</boxart1>
	</game>
	<game name="Music (Japan) (SC-3000)">
		<description>Music (Japan) (SC-3000)</description>
		<rom crc="2EC28526" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Sega%20-%20SG-1000.zip/Sega%20-%20SG-1000%2FMusic%20%28Japan%29%20%28SC-3000%29.zip" sha1="A2137E818242E8B361D5D5677797034C55FB1A2D" size="12040" />
		<title_clean>Music</title_clean>
	</game>
	<game name="N-Sub (Europe)">
		<description>N-Sub (Europe)</description>
		<rom crc="09196FC5" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Sega%20-%20SG-1000.zip/Sega%20-%20SG-1000%2FN-Sub%20%28Europe%29.zip" sha1="32A263110434288D3720E2370241D1E93B3F07A9" size="8176" />
		<title_clean>N-Sub</title_clean>
		<plot>N-Sub puts the player in control of a submarine in the Cobalt Blue Sea. The action takes place on one screen; the player-controlled submarine can move in all directions and must defend itself against an onslaught of enemy ships and submarines by firing torpedoes at them. Torpedoes can be fired vertically (which is the only way to hit ships)  and horizontally (to deal with enemy submarines), activated by two different buttons. Pressing the button down allows firing short bursts of three torpedoes each. A round is over after an enemy fleet of twelve ships and a destroyer has completed a fixed amount of loops. Subsequent rounds increase the difficulty by making enemy ships more aggressive.</plot>
		<year>1983</year>
		<genre>Action</genre>
		<studio>SEGA Enterprises</studio>
		<mobygames_url>https://www.mobygames.com/game/sg-1000/n-sub</mobygames_url>
		<boxart1>VRMIMSW.jpg</boxart1>
		<boxart2>rFt3BZS.jpg</boxart2>
		<boxart3>3amjdRK.jpg</boxart3>
		<snapshot1>xvj4FV7.png</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>Zv8RzzM.png</snapshot2>
		<snapshot3>izaINvk.png</snapshot3>
		<snapshot4>GWdhjMd.png</snapshot4>
		<snapshot5>tX40bhD.png</snapshot5>
	</game>
	<game name="Nihonshi Nenpyou (Japan) (SC-3000)">
		<description>Nihonshi Nenpyou (Japan) (SC-3000)</description>
		<rom crc="129D6359" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Sega%20-%20SG-1000.zip/Sega%20-%20SG-1000%2FNihonshi%20Nenpyou%20%28Japan%29%20%28SC-3000%29.zip" sha1="9A9363004D77037A0BBC9A8BCAE1BB05138FFC36" size="7648" />
		<title_clean>Nihonshi Nenpyou</title_clean>
	</game>
	<game name="Ninja Princess (Japan)">
		<description>Ninja Princess (Japan)</description>
		<rom crc="3B912408" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Sega%20-%20SG-1000.zip/Sega%20-%20SG-1000%2FNinja%20Princess%20%28Japan%29.zip" sha1="F142BB823CEBC4E31488E7A9A94644AF24186D99" size="20435" />
		<title_clean>Ninja Princess</title_clean>
		<plot>A ninja-themed run &amp; gun shooter arcade game released by Sega in 1985, also known as Sega Ninja. It was one of the first games to feature a strong human female protagonist, in this case a kunoichi, i.e. female ninja. The game was designed by female game designer Rieko Kodama; her later role-playing game Phantasy Star also had a strong, well-written, female protagonist, Alis Landale.It was soon ported to the MSX and Sega SG-1000 home platforms. The Sega Master System port was re-titled The Ninja and featured a male protagonist instead of a female lead. [CR]</plot>
		<releasedate>31/3/1985</releasedate>
		<year>1986</year>
		<genre>Action</genre>
		<studio>SEGA Enterprises</studio>
		<thegamesdb_id>35138</thegamesdb_id>
		<mobygames_url>https://www.mobygames.com/game/sg-1000/ninja-princess</mobygames_url>
		<giantbomb_url>https://www.giantbomb.com/ninja-princess/3030-34969/</giantbomb_url>
		<boxart1>j08Btmb.jpg</boxart1>
		<boxart2>ChXStqn.jpg</boxart2>
		<snapshot1>0Dtd26B.png</snapshot1>
	</game>
	<game name="Okamoto Ayako no Match Play Golf (Japan) (Rev 1) (Othello Multivision)">
		<description>Okamoto Ayako no Match Play Golf (Japan) (Rev 1) (Othello Multivision)</description>
		<rom crc="49D3DB2C" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Sega%20-%20SG-1000.zip/Sega%20-%20SG-1000%2FOkamoto%20Ayako%20no%20Match%20Play%20Golf%20%28Japan%29%20%28Rev%201%29%20%28Othello%20Multivision%29.zip" sha1="BCB03AFD3BBD5DADF00474EAC44BB66A5DF419CF" size="18830" />
		<title_clean>Okamoto Ayako no Match Play Golf</title_clean>
	</game>
	<game name="Orguss (Japan, Europe)">
		<description>Orguss (Japan, Europe)</description>
		<rom crc="F4F78B76" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Sega%20-%20SG-1000.zip/Sega%20-%20SG-1000%2FOrguss%20%28Japan%2C%20Europe%29.zip" sha1="C50B133DAC95718E3A92A7ED45B6C7E83927ABB0" size="17345" />
		<title_clean>Orguss</title_clean>
		<plot>Orguss (&#12458;&#12540;&#12460;&#12473;) is a shoot-'em-up game developed and published by Sega for the SG-1000. In the game, the player takes control of a robot which can transform into a starship. It is based on the science fiction anime series Super Dimension Century Orguss.[CR]The player can swap between robot and starship modes freely, though both come with their own set advantages and disadvantages. In robot mode, you are able to destroy ground targets and have greater freedom across the screen at the expense of being a bigger target for enemies. You can shoot rapidfire, but move slower. In starship mode you cannot destroy ground targets, but are less likely to be destroyed thanks to the smaller surface area of the ship. You can move faster, but cannot shoot rapidfire. 1 switches between the two forms and 2 shoots.[CR]Orguss had a spiritual sequel in the form of TransBot, released for the Sega Master System in 1985.</plot>
		<releasedate>1/2/1984</releasedate>
		<year>1984</year>
		<genre>Action</genre>
		<studio>SEGA Enterprises</studio>
		<thegamesdb_id>35139</thegamesdb_id>
		<mobygames_url>https://www.mobygames.com/game/sg-1000/orguss</mobygames_url>
		<giantbomb_url>https://www.giantbomb.com/orguss/3030-24740/</giantbomb_url>
		<boxart1>lFYXXhp.jpg</boxart1>
		<boxart2>wnLpO1l.jpg</boxart2>
		<snapshot1>xQhQTLw.png</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>QC73ebK.png</snapshot2>
		<snapshot3>TXxYqDQ.png</snapshot3>
		<snapshot4>v1MD8a8.png</snapshot4>
		<snapshot5>LsAt1Ra.png</snapshot5>
	</game>
	<game name="Othello (Japan)">
		<description>Othello (Japan)</description>
		<rom crc="AF4F14BC" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Sega%20-%20SG-1000.zip/Sega%20-%20SG-1000%2FOthello%20%28Japan%29.zip" sha1="D0CD594DDB321F707DDBA8A044FA3E9B906E720A" size="14547" />
		<title_clean>Othello</title_clean>
		<giantbomb_url>https://www.giantbomb.com/othello/3030-35063/</giantbomb_url>
		<boxart1>Na9SVDS.jpg</boxart1>
	</game>
	<game name="Pacar (Japan, Europe)">
		<description>Pacar (Japan, Europe)</description>
		<rom crc="30C52E5E" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Sega%20-%20SG-1000.zip/Sega%20-%20SG-1000%2FPacar%20%28Japan%2C%20Europe%29.zip" sha1="91FD213308B83BB1BDA1DFC7E971E576CAACE291" size="9318" />
		<title_clean>Pacar</title_clean>
	</game>
	<game name="Pachinko II (Japan)">
		<description>Pachinko II (Japan)</description>
		<rom crc="FD7CB50A" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Sega%20-%20SG-1000.zip/Sega%20-%20SG-1000%2FPachinko%20II%20%28Japan%29.zip" sha1="1DBC4BABBBB377A1FF59A11E550A9B1B5E742B02" size="8892" />
		<title_clean>Pachinko II</title_clean>
		<releasedate>31/12/1984</releasedate>
		<giantbomb_url>https://www.giantbomb.com/pachinko-ii/3030-52103/</giantbomb_url>
		<boxart1>O8srVMk.jpg</boxart1>
	</game>
	<game name="Pitfall II (Taiwan) (English Logo)">
		<description>Pitfall II (Taiwan) (English Logo)</description>
		<rom crc="4E93BC8E" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Sega%20-%20SG-1000.zip/Sega%20-%20SG-1000%2FPitfall%20II%20%28Taiwan%29%20%28English%20Logo%29.zip" sha1="C98A5BDB2F97E2E85D0A131D58E311544ADB416E" size="17879" />
		<title_clean>Pitfall II</title_clean>
		<plot>[CR][B]Overview:[/B][CR]Lost Caverns is the sequel to David Crane's  Pitfall. Both games were originally released for the Atari 2600 and later ported to multiple platforms. Pitfall II maintains much of the look and feel of the first game, but it opens the world up into a free-roaming adventure, rather than progressing on a linear path.  Pitfall Harry's quest in Pitfall II is to collect a diamond, find his niece Rhonda, and his cowardly lion companion, Quickclaw. Upon collecting all three, the quest ends. In most versions of the game, this is also the end of the game. On the Atari 8-bit versions of the game, Pitfall II contained a "second quest" with more difficult enemies, a more challenging level layout, and new items to collect.[CR]Significance[CR]Pitfall II is advanced for its time, and especially for the 2600 version of the game relative to the other games for that system.  It features save points, which allow you to continue again from the last cross symbol you stepped over.  When you die, sad music will play and your character will physically return to the save point while your score is deducted relative to the distance traveled back to the cross.The heroic music that runs through the game is fairly catchy, even by today's chip tune standards.  Not exactly an objective statement, but  give it a listen.  The music also changes to a slightly more downbeat version should you spend too much time not grabbing shiny loot.Among the game play modes there are the requisite running and jumping  found in the original Pitfall, along with swimming and ascending a chasm using a hot air balloon.  The enemies have also been increased to include bats (which also pop your balloons), poisonous frogs, and electric eels for the swimming portions. [CR]</plot>
		<releasedate>31/12/1984</releasedate>
		<year>1985</year>
		<genre>Action</genre>
		<studio>SEGA Enterprises</studio>
		<mobygames_url>https://www.mobygames.com/game/sg-1000/pitfall-ii-lost-caverns</mobygames_url>
		<giantbomb_url>https://www.giantbomb.com/pitfall-ii-lost-caverns/3030-12877/</giantbomb_url>
		<boxart1>flslETc.jpg</boxart1>
		<boxart2>2c1rhQN.jpg</boxart2>
		<snapshot1>oicthvE.png</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>0qfVKdO.png</snapshot2>
		<snapshot3>E2vZUgY.png</snapshot3>
		<snapshot4>lKL3kXG.png</snapshot4>
		<snapshot5>jD7Z0oJ.png</snapshot5>
		<snapshot6>I8Vs6jP.png</snapshot6>
		<snapshot7>tiBBVAo.png</snapshot7>
		<snapshot8>a0kzGdw.png</snapshot8>
		<snapshot9>VGMX76n.png</snapshot9>
		<snapshot10>DJ0LGCl.png</snapshot10>
	</game>
	<game name="Pop Flamer (Japan, Europe)">
		<description>Pop Flamer (Japan, Europe)</description>
		<rom crc="DB6404BA" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Sega%20-%20SG-1000.zip/Sega%20-%20SG-1000%2FPop%20Flamer%20%28Japan%2C%20Europe%29.zip" sha1="84B59A9F855EF5E953C43495D7A15DD78386D0A8" size="10439" />
		<title_clean>Pop Flamer</title_clean>
	</game>
	<game name="Q-bert (Japan) (Othello Multivision)">
		<description>Q-bert (Japan) (Othello Multivision)</description>
		<rom crc="77DB4704" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Sega%20-%20SG-1000.zip/Sega%20-%20SG-1000%2FQ-bert%20%28Japan%29%20%28Othello%20Multivision%29.zip" sha1="AE23FCE5DBBC1536275D57CA65D2AA9170D46EA4" size="6023" />
		<title_clean>Q-bert</title_clean>
		<plot>[CR][B]Gameplay:[/B][CR]The goal of Q*Bert is to navigate Q*Bert around an isometric pyramid structure. Each hop on a cube of the pyramid changes the color of its surface. The game will specify what color the entire pyramid must be changed to in order to advance. Multicolored discs alongside the pyramid allow for a quick getaway, but disappear once used.[CR]Arcade Cabinet[CR]The game designers wanted to add the sound of Q*Bert hitting the ground after falling off of the pyramid, so a pinball "knocker" (the solenoid that alerts the player that they've won a free game) was incorporated into the cabinet.[CR][B]Enemies:[/B][CR]The most common foe Q*Bert will encounter is Coily the snake, who hops down the pyramid structure. Once he reaches the bottom, he "uncoils" and chases after Q*Bert until he finishes the level or is killed. Red balls also bounce down the pyramid structure that Q*Bert must avoid. Slick and Sam are two more enemies that run around the structure changing the colors of the pyramid back to their original colors, slowing Q*Bert's progress. Unlike the other enemies in the game, Q*Bert can get rid of Slick and Sam by jumping on them.[CR]Other Versions[CR]Faster Harder More Challenging Q*Bert was to be the tougher successor to the original game. Changes, such as moving multicolored discs, lived up to the name, but the product was canceled before being released.[CR]</plot>
		<releasedate>30/11/1982</releasedate>
		<year>1983</year>
		<genre>Action</genre>
		<studio>Tsukuda Original</studio>
		<mobygames_url>https://www.mobygames.com/game/sg-1000/qbert</mobygames_url>
		<giantbomb_url>https://www.giantbomb.com/qbert/3030-20782/</giantbomb_url>
		<boxart1>7Dg2SdG.jpg</boxart1>
		<boxart2>pP95rC3.jpg</boxart2>
		<snapshot1>FeaTaXH.png</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>WD8oZi8.png</snapshot2>
	</game>
	<game name="Rally-X (Taiwan) (DahJee)">
		<description>Rally-X (Taiwan) (DahJee)</description>
		<rom crc="306D5F78" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Sega%20-%20SG-1000.zip/Sega%20-%20SG-1000%2FRally-X%20%28Taiwan%29%20%28DahJee%29.zip" sha1="21770691191B62BAFEC9099BBE0F9942F5480F83" size="11024" />
		<title_clean>Rally-X</title_clean>
	</game>
	<game name="Road Fighter (Taiwan) (Jumbo)">
		<description>Road Fighter (Taiwan) (Jumbo)</description>
		<rom crc="29E047CC" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Sega%20-%20SG-1000.zip/Sega%20-%20SG-1000%2FRoad%20Fighter%20%28Taiwan%29%20%28Jumbo%29.zip" sha1="4F1A139974E3DB27AF5973BC9572ED68ACD6EA68" size="15468" />
		<title_clean>Road Fighter</title_clean>
	</game>
	<game name="Rock n' Bolt (Japan)">
		<description>Rock n' Bolt (Japan)</description>
		<rom crc="0FFDD03D" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Sega%20-%20SG-1000.zip/Sega%20-%20SG-1000%2FRock%20n%27%20Bolt%20%28Japan%29.zip" sha1="D5E8E7CA7623521D4291AE5AB2740816FC674389" size="19296" />
		<title_clean>Rock n' Bolt</title_clean>
		<plot>Louie The constructor struts pieces to their location. The Girders are constantly moving back and forth. It is your job to lock them down, and then get back to where you started the level. There are 100 levels, and two types of levels. One is just locking down, the others you have to put them in a specific location. There are three levels of difficulty to choose from, you just get paid more the harder the level, and you have less time to complete the level.</plot>
		<year>1985</year>
		<genre>Action</genre>
		<studio>SEGA Enterprises</studio>
		<mobygames_url>https://www.mobygames.com/game/sg-1000/rock-n-bolt</mobygames_url>
		<snapshot1>wQWUiMV.png</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>F8eGBbi.png</snapshot2>
	</game>
	<game name="Safari Hunting (Taiwan)">
		<description>Safari Hunting (Taiwan)</description>
		<rom crc="6DC51C01" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Sega%20-%20SG-1000.zip/Sega%20-%20SG-1000%2FSafari%20Hunting%20%28Taiwan%29.zip" sha1="E3AA37F4C9F213A673E369F62561F3F80513E4F3" size="8010" />
		<title_clean>Safari Hunting</title_clean>
		<plot>Safari Hunting is a port of the 1980 arcade machine Tranquilizer Gun. The play area is sort of a maze-like jungle scene with walkable paths and impassible jungle, you can venture into the jungle on foot to hunt the animals and you can also shoot from your truck at any animals that venture out into the 4 edges around the play area where your truck travels. Your task is to tranquilize different animals (snakes, gorillas, lions and elephants). The larger the animal, the more number of tranquilizer darts it takes to put the animal down. As soon as you tranquilize an animal, a timer will begin to count down and you will have to slowly drag the animal back to your truck before the timer reaches zero or the animal will awaken and kill you. Not only do you need to consider the countdown timer for a tranquilized animal, but you also need to watch your trucks fuel gauge, which is basically a time limit counter for the game as you apparently leave your truck running while walking through the jungle.</plot>
		<releasedate>1/1/1983</releasedate>
		<year>1983</year>
		<genre>Action, Sports</genre>
		<studio>SEGA Enterprises</studio>
		<nplayers>1</nplayers>
		<thegamesdb_id>33247</thegamesdb_id>
		<mobygames_url>https://www.mobygames.com/game/sg-1000/safari-hunting</mobygames_url>
		<boxart1>kmchGDB.jpg</boxart1>
		<boxart2>GTnaq08.jpg</boxart2>
	</game>
	<game name="Safari Race (Europe)">
		<description>Safari Race (Europe)</description>
		<rom crc="619DD066" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Sega%20-%20SG-1000.zip/Sega%20-%20SG-1000%2FSafari%20Race%20%28Europe%29.zip" sha1="1D2CA62C894FC8AAB97605E65078E834BBBE3D8B" size="18842" />
		<title_clean>Safari Race</title_clean>
		<plot>Safari Race (&#12469;&#12501;&#12449;&#12522;&#12524;&#12540;&#12473;) is a racing game for the SG-1000, developed and published by Sega in 1984. The player must drive through various "sections", avoiding wildlife and other cars while making sure not to run out of fuel.[CR]The game is notable for using licensed cars, potentially the first video game to do so. The player controls a Lancia Stratos HF, and according to the box art, some of the rival cars are Audi Quattros. The Lancia Stratos would receive greater video game recognition in Sega's later creation Sega Rally Championship.</plot>
		<releasedate>1/2/1984</releasedate>
		<genre>Driving, Racing</genre>
		<thegamesdb_id>35141</thegamesdb_id>
		<boxart1>xOCA358.jpg</boxart1>
	</game>
	<game name="San-nin Mahjong (Taiwan)">
		<description>San-nin Mahjong (Taiwan)</description>
		<rom crc="6FD17655" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Sega%20-%20SG-1000.zip/Sega%20-%20SG-1000%2FSan-nin%20Mahjong%20%28Taiwan%29.zip" sha1="245E9ADF0FDB33849F1E6EF872C1B204CBED5754" size="11028" />
		<title_clean>San-nin Mahjong</title_clean>
	</game>
	<game name="Sega Flipper (Japan, Europe)">
		<description>Sega Flipper (Japan, Europe)</description>
		<rom crc="8EFC77BC" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Sega%20-%20SG-1000.zip/Sega%20-%20SG-1000%2FSega%20Flipper%20%28Japan%2C%20Europe%29.zip" sha1="E0605E23D80B8B975743D3417F548B28810E0BA3" size="8237" />
		<title_clean>Sega Flipper</title_clean>
		<giantbomb_url>https://www.giantbomb.com/sega-flipper/3030-35119/</giantbomb_url>
		<boxart1>Odc5aVN.jpg</boxart1>
	</game>
	<game name="Sega-Galaga (Japan) (40kB)">
		<description>Sega-Galaga (Japan) (40kB)</description>
		<rom crc="31283003" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Sega%20-%20SG-1000.zip/Sega%20-%20SG-1000%2FSega-Galaga%20%28Japan%29%20%2840kB%29.zip" sha1="9B093878F92CE8B918BEAA44DCC8A41282F9F267" size="8878" />
		<title_clean>Sega-Galaga</title_clean>
		<plot>[CR][B]Overview:[/B][CR]Released in 1981, Galaga has become one of the most popular arcade games of all time. Much more well received than its predecessor, Galaxian, Galaga features fast paced top-down shooting action. The player takes control of a small ship located at the bottom of the screen and is tasked with destroying the incoming waves of insect-like enemies.[CR][B]Gameplay:[/B][CR]Tractor-beamThe player controls a "fighter" spaceship whose movement is restricted to flying left or right. Upon the start of a level, waves of enemies fly in formation and complete a flight pattern before positioning themselves at the top of the screen. It is ideal to destroy the incoming ships before they complete their fly-in. Once in formation at the top of the screen, enemies will regularly break off to attack. Enemy ships attack by dropping bombs and/or attempting to collide with the player's ship.The most popular and effective strategy is for the player to sacrifice their own ship to a "Boss Galaga" ship. These ships hover above the player and emit a tractor-beam. Entering this beam will sacrifice the current ship and allow the player to use one of the reserves. Destroying the "Boss Galaga" will reclaim the captured ship. The player is then rewarded with dual ships which effectively doubles the player's firepower.Additionally, a bonus stage occurs every four levels, allowing the player to earn extra points without the risk of being destroyed. Upon destroying every fighter during a bonus stage, the player will then be rewarded with an extra life.[CR]Galaga in Mass Media[CR]1982 - Actor Matthew Broderick spent two months playing Galaga to prepare for his upcoming role in Wargames.2004 - The ABC television series Lost names a DHARMA Initiative submarine after the popular video game.2009 - Fans are able to purchase a Galaga arcade-style video game Christmas ornament (complete with audibles) thanks to Hallmark.2012 - In Marvel's The Avengers, Tony Stark catches a S.H.I.E.L.D. agent playing Galaga. The agent denies it but after the main characters leave the room he goes back to playing the game. The game footage shown on the computer screen is from the MSX port. [CR]</plot>
		<releasedate>30/9/1981</releasedate>
		<genre>Shooter</genre>
		<thegamesdb_id>35142</thegamesdb_id>
		<giantbomb_url>https://www.giantbomb.com/galaga/3030-15784/</giantbomb_url>
		<boxart1>CzQ7RPd.jpg</boxart1>
		<snapshot1>VzwyGu0.jpg</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>nsz1yL9.jpg</snapshot2>
		<snapshot3>OGYfW8A.jpg</snapshot3>
		<snapshot4>iLzgHMh.jpg</snapshot4>
		<snapshot5>qpq3QCq.jpg</snapshot5>
		<snapshot6>ChaS2JW.jpg</snapshot6>
		<snapshot7>16whF4V.jpg</snapshot7>
		<snapshot8>KG6TPTs.jpg</snapshot8>
		<snapshot9>Vd9MK64.jpg</snapshot9>
		<snapshot10>cRyed0F.jpg</snapshot10>
	</game>
	<game name="Sekaishi Nenpyou (Japan) (SC-3000)">
		<description>Sekaishi Nenpyou (Japan) (SC-3000)</description>
		<rom crc="3274EE48" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Sega%20-%20SG-1000.zip/Sega%20-%20SG-1000%2FSekaishi%20Nenpyou%20%28Japan%29%20%28SC-3000%29.zip" sha1="388FDFF0CF2AD276E07A419239710632C376E1DB" size="7527" />
		<title_clean>Sekaishi Nenpyou</title_clean>
	</game>
	<game name="Serizawa Hachidan no Tsumeshougi (Japan)">
		<description>Serizawa Hachidan no Tsumeshougi (Japan)</description>
		<rom crc="545FC9BB" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Sega%20-%20SG-1000.zip/Sega%20-%20SG-1000%2FSerizawa%20Hachidan%20no%20Tsumeshougi%20%28Japan%29.zip" sha1="C2D3882874A5A9B79A5DC9FDEB7AF750BC52CA21" size="9272" />
		<title_clean>Serizawa Hachidan no Tsumeshougi</title_clean>
	</game>
	<game name="Shinnyushain Tooru Kun (Japan)">
		<description>Shinnyushain Tooru Kun (Japan)</description>
		<rom crc="5A917E06" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Sega%20-%20SG-1000.zip/Sega%20-%20SG-1000%2FShinnyushain%20Tooru%20Kun%20%28Japan%29.zip" sha1="83784E8248E2367546115382DAC157CA8E6FE3AB" size="19860" />
		<title_clean>Shinnyushain Tooru Kun</title_clean>
		<plot>[CR][B]Overview:[/B][CR]Mikie is a 1984 Konami action game, where the player must guide Mikie through various school-themed stages. A variety of obstacles and nemesis try to prevent him from collecting a number of hearts which spell out love-notes left by his girlfriend, as he moves through the five stages of gameplay. The title was more popular on the various home computer ports than at arcades.[CR][B]Gameplay:[/B][CR]Mikie is controlled using a joystick in eight directions. The fire button controls various abilities depending on the stage and situation. The player must collect hearts which spell out a different love note left by Mandy, Mikie's girlfriend.Stage one: ClassroomMikie must hipcheck students off of their chairs in order to collect hearts. Meanwhile, Mikie must avoid the teacher. Once all of the hearts are collected, Mikie may exit the classroom into the Corridor.Corridor:While not a distinct stage, all stages are connected by a corridor, which has a number of doors. One door flashes, alerting the player to the location of the next stage. Opening a different door may result in a boxing glove knocking Mikie over, or various bonus opportunities. A janitor chases Mikie in the corridor.Stage two: LockerroomMikie must gather hearts by headbutting (or yelling at on the home versions) the lockers until they break, revealing a heart. Meanwhile, the teacher, a janitor, and a chef chase Mikie. The player may grab basketballs from one of three bins, and stun the pursuing enemies briefly.Stage three: CafeteriaMikie must gather hearts while avoiding the chef. The cafeteria tables hold entire chickens, which Mikie may throw at the chef to stun him temporarily.Stage four: Dance StudioThere are hearts between a number of ballet girls, which Mikie must grab, while avoiding the dancers. He must also avoid the teacher and dance instructor.Stage five: Football FieldMikie has to grab hearts while avoiding football players as he finally reaches Mandy. Completing the game sends the player back to the beginning of stage one, with an increased difficulty level.[CR][B]Music:[/B][CR]The game is notable for its licensed use of the Beatles' "A Hard Day's Night", along with original music. [CR]</plot>
		<releasedate>31/12/1984</releasedate>
		<thegamesdb_id>35143</thegamesdb_id>
		<giantbomb_url>https://www.giantbomb.com/mikie/3030-18968/</giantbomb_url>
		<boxart1>2rFhXF2.jpg</boxart1>
		<snapshot1>dA2hgxv.jpg</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>wPDbea4.png</snapshot2>
		<snapshot3>ggLh6Pk.png</snapshot3>
		<snapshot4>tKOtl1z.png</snapshot4>
		<snapshot5>7gySbPd.png</snapshot5>
		<snapshot6>HoGn8oX.png</snapshot6>
		<snapshot7>XBhA8dY.png</snapshot7>
		<snapshot8>QR5SD0z.png</snapshot8>
		<snapshot9>qRcOA3v.png</snapshot9>
		<snapshot10>PfmcIHA.png</snapshot10>
	</game>
	<game name="Sindbad Mystery (Japan, Europe)">
		<description>Sindbad Mystery (Japan, Europe)</description>
		<rom crc="01932DF9" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Sega%20-%20SG-1000.zip/Sega%20-%20SG-1000%2FSindbad%20Mystery%20%28Japan%2C%20Europe%29.zip" sha1="90BB8B8337866339F32B3FD48B4D25D78D682B55" size="14540" />
		<title_clean>Sindbad Mystery</title_clean>
	</game>
	<game name="Soukoban (Taiwan)">
		<description>Soukoban (Taiwan)</description>
		<rom crc="A2C3FC97" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Sega%20-%20SG-1000.zip/Sega%20-%20SG-1000%2FSoukoban%20%28Taiwan%29.zip" sha1="4216770EFBAF49F832FF7A78FBC9CD2C8300F52C" size="19078" />
		<title_clean>Soukoban</title_clean>
		<plot>[CR][B]Overview:[/B][CR]Soko-Ban (meaning Warehouse Keeper) is a simple puzzle game which has the player pushing boxes onto chosen locations in the level. Players can only push one box at a time and they cannot pull them in any direction. Using this simple rule, the difficulty of the game increases by having larger and more complex level designs. The game is always viewed from a  top-down perspective.[CR]</plot>
		<releasedate>31/12/1982</releasedate>
		<year>1985</year>
		<genre>Puzzle</genre>
		<studio>SEGA Enterprises</studio>
		<mobygames_url>https://www.mobygames.com/game/sg-1000/soko-ban</mobygames_url>
		<giantbomb_url>https://www.giantbomb.com/sokoban/3030-17545/</giantbomb_url>
		<boxart1>yOuQfGK.jpg</boxart1>
		<snapshot1>Axw4FHY.png</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>YKk1IuD.png</snapshot2>
		<snapshot3>7LPuBiT.png</snapshot3>
		<snapshot4>Jd9OV9W.png</snapshot4>
		<snapshot5>hxumr35.png</snapshot5>
		<snapshot6>aaeuiVj.png</snapshot6>
		<snapshot7>k3zausJ.png</snapshot7>
		<snapshot8>I3vmOCu.png</snapshot8>
		<snapshot9>je1oFNL.png</snapshot9>
		<snapshot10>WlgF70o.png</snapshot10>
	</game>
	<game name="Space Armor (Japan) (v2.0) (Newer) (Othello Multivision)">
		<description>Space Armor (Japan) (v2.0) (Newer) (Othello Multivision)</description>
		<rom crc="AC4F0A5C" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Sega%20-%20SG-1000.zip/Sega%20-%20SG-1000%2FSpace%20Armor%20%28Japan%29%20%28v2.0%29%20%28Newer%29%20%28Othello%20Multivision%29.zip" sha1="A968B1DEBB39909CD83203244CC60DA1E0003F71" size="11375" />
		<title_clean>Space Armor</title_clean>
	</game>
	<game name="Space Invaders (Taiwan)">
		<description>Space Invaders (Taiwan)</description>
		<rom crc="0760EA93" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Sega%20-%20SG-1000.zip/Sega%20-%20SG-1000%2FSpace%20Invaders%20%28Taiwan%29.zip" sha1="5A7904697EA8A360066EA8403793227021735969" size="7590" />
		<title_clean>Space Invaders</title_clean>
		<plot>[CR][B]Overview:[/B][CR]One of the earliest shooting games, Space Invaders was released by Taito in Japan on June 19, 1978. Gameplay involves attempting to defeat waves of aliens cascading down from the top of the screen with a laser cannon that moves along a fixed horizontal axis. The only goal is to earn as many points as possible. Designer Tomohiro Nishikado was in charge of planning, graphic design, and programming for the game and drew creative inspiration from such diverse sources as Gun Fight, Breakout, The War of the Worlds, and Star Wars. The game&#8217;s development cycle lasted for one year, during which Nishikado created custom hardware and software. The game achieved massive popularity upon its release (leading to a temporary shortage of one hundred yen coins in Japan), and helped usher in the golden age of arcade video games (circa 1978-1984).Space Invaders sold over 400,000 arcade cabinets worldwide and grossed around $3.8 billion in revenue by 1982, equivalent to over $13 billion in 2014, making it the highest-grossing video game of all time.[CR][B]Gameplay:[/B][CR]Arcade (cabaret/cocktail) versionGameplay in Space Invaders is relatively simple. The player controls a small ship that can only move laterally across the bottom of the screen and fires vertically. Five rows of eleven aliens each advance slowly from one side of the screen to the other, dropping down one space and reversing direction when they reach either side. The player&#8217;s task is to acquire points by eliminating enemies and to destroy all of the aliens before they reach the bottom of the screen and complete their &#8220;invasion.&#8221; As aliens are destroyed, the speed of the remaining enemies increases, as does the tempo of the music. Once all of the enemies are destroyed, the wave resets and the difficulty increases (a cycle that can continue indefinitely).The Invaders constantly shoot back at the player as they advance from side to side across the screen. To help avoid their attacks, the player can hide behind a number of destructible barriers or &#8220;bunkers&#8221; near the bottom of the screen (four in the original version). Occasionally a &#8220;mystery ship&#8221; will appear near the top of the screen and move quickly from one side to the other while making a distinctive klaxon noise. Destroying it rewards the player with a sizeable point bonus.[CR]Development[CR]While working for the Taito Corporation, designer Nishikado was inspired to create Space Invaders by an early Taito electro-mechanical game called Space Monsters, and by the Atari arcade game Breakout. The game was planned to have tanks, planes, and battleships as enemies, but Nishikado was not happy with their onscreen movements. He considered making the enemies human (which would have been easier to animate), but scrapped the idea since he thought it would be immoral for players to shoot them. After he saw a magazine featuring the 1977 film Star Wars, he decided to use a space theme, and based his alien enemies on the squid-like antagonists from the 1953 movie version of The War of the Worlds.Upright cabinetDue to the limitations of 1970s microprocessors, Nishikado was forced to design and build his own hardware and development tools. The arcade board he put together contained a variety of both Japanese and American components. It used an Intel 8080 central processing unit (designed by American and Japanese engineers), which could output raster graphics on a CRT monitor, but was slow when it came to drawing sprite graphics, so a dedicated Fujitsu MB14241 video shifter (an early example of a graphics chip) was used to accelerate the drawing of sprite graphics to a bitmap framebuffer. Monaural sound was hosted by a combination of analogue circuitry and a Texas Instruments SN76477 sound chip. The system that he put together is now known as the Taito 8080 arcade system board.In spite of his efforts, Nishikado was unable to program the game exactly as he wanted. The hardware that he had assembled was not powerful enough to display graphics in color and the enemies moved slower than he had intended. Fortunately he discovered that the more enemies that were removed from play, the faster the processor could render those that remained. Rather than attempt to design the game to compensate for the speed increase, he opted to leave it in as a challenging gameplay mechanic.It was originally released in Japan by Taito as a cocktail cabinet, with monochrome graphics enhanced by a rainbow-colored cellophane overlay to simulate color graphics. Taito and American licence-holder Bally/Midway then created an upright cabinet that used strips of orange and green cellophane applied to the screen to simulate color graphics, though this version only simulated several colors (compared to Taito's original cocktail version simulating a wider range of colors). Both the Japanese and American upright cabinets also included a painted backdrop of a lunar surface and a starscape, and cabinet art featuring large humanoid creatures that bore little resemblance to the in-game enemies. Nishikado claims that this was due to the artist basing his interpretation on the game&#8217;s original title, Space Monsters.[CR]Impact and Legacy[CR]Soon after its release in Japan, Space Invaders became a huge success, completely taking over certain arcades and earning Taito a tidy profit. By the end of 1978, Taito had installed 100,000 machines across the country and grossed over $600 million dollars. An oft-quoted urban legend states that there was a shortage of 100-yen coins&#8212;and subsequent production increase&#8212;in Japan attributed to the game. By 1980, 300,000 cabinets had been sold in Japan and an additional 60,000 in the United States. By 1981, Space Invaders had made Taito more than $1 billion, and continued to gross an average of $600 million per year, through to 1982, by which time it had grossed $2 billion in quarters (equivalent to $4.6 billion in 2011). This made it the best-selling video game and highest-grossing entertainment product of its time, surpassing the then highest-grossing film Star Wars, which had grossed $486 million in movie tickets.Atari 2600 versionThe 1980 Atari 2600 version represented the first official licensed port of an arcade game to a home console, and and became the first "killer app" for video game consoles by quadrupling sales of the 2600. It sold over two million units in its first year on sale as a home console game, becoming the first title to sell over a million cartridges. Ports were also released for the Atari 8-bit computer line and the Atari 5200, as well as the Nintendo Entertainment System, Game Boy and SNES. Numerous unofficial clones were made as well, such as the popular computer games Super Invader (1979) and TI Invaders (1981).Game designer Shigeru Miyamoto considered Space Invaders a game that revolutionized the video game industry; he was never interested in video games before seeing it. Hideo Kojima also described it as the first video game that impressed him and got him interested in video games. Several publications ascribed the expansion of the video game industry from a novelty into a global industry to the success of the game. Edge magazine attributed the shift of video games from bars and arcades to more mainstream locations like restaurants and department stores to Space Invaders. Its popularity was such that it was the first game where an arcade machine's owner could make up for the cost of the machine in under one month, or in some places within one week.Technology journalist Jason Whittaker credited the game's success to ending the video game crash of 1977, which had earlier been caused by Pong clones flooding the market, and beginning the golden age of video arcade games.According to The Observer, the home console versions were popular and encouraged users to learn programming; many who later became industry leaders. 1UP stated that Space Invaders showed that video games could compete against the major entertainment media at the time: movies, music, and television IGN attributed the launch of the arcade phenomenon in North America in part to Space Invaders. Electronic Games credited the game's success as the impetus behind video gaming becoming a rapidly growing hobby and as "the single most popular coin-operated attraction of all time." Game Informer considered it, along with Pac-Man, one of the most popular arcade games that tapped into popular culture and generated excitement during the golden age of arcades.IGN listed it as one of the "Top 10 Most Influential Games" in 2007, citing the source of inspiration to video game designers and the impact it had on the shooting genre. 1UP ranked it at No. 3 in its list of "The 60 Most Influential Games of All Time," stating that, in contrast to earlier arcade games which "were attempts to simulate already-existing things," Space Invaders was "the first video game as a video game, instead of merely a playable electronic representation of something else." In 2008, Guinness World Records listed it as the top-rated arcade game in technical, creative, and cultural impact.As one of the earliest shooting games, it set precedents and helped pave the way for future titles and for the shooting genre. Space Invaders popularized a more interactive style of gameplay with the enemies responding to the player controlled cannon's movement, and was the first video game to popularize the concept of achieving a high score, being the first to save the player's score. While earlier shooting games allowed the player to shoot at targets, Space Invaders was the first in which targets could fire back at the player. It was also the first game where players were given multiple lives, had to repel hordes of enemies, could take cover from enemy fire, and use destructible barriers,in addition to being the first game to use a continuous background soundtrack, with four simple diatonic descending bass notes repeating in a loop, which was dynamic and changed pace during stages, like a heartbeat sound that increases pace as enemies approached.It also introduced the concept of a difficulty curve, with the aliens moving faster as the player kills more of them, making the game more difficult as it progresses. The game's concept of scaling difficulty became the basis for modern single-player video gaming.Cited by influential creators like Shigeru Miyamoto and Hideo Kojima as a major inspiration, Space Invaders revolutionized the industry following the video game crash of 1977 (brought on by a glut of Pong clones on the market and the departure of manufacturers like RCA and Fairchild). Proving that video games were capable of competing with movies, music and television, Space Invaders has since become recognized as one of the most influential games ever released. It was one of the first games to utilize the concept of a &#8220;high score,&#8221; and was the first to save the player&#8217;s score. It was the first shooter that allowed enemies to shoot back at the player, the first to give the player multiple lives and provide destructible cover against enemy fire. Its success effectively launched an entire genre of space shooters, including Atari&#8217;s Asteroids, Williams&#8217; Defender, and Namco&#8217;s Galaxian series.It moved the gaming industry away from Pong-inspired sports games grounded in real-world situations towards action games involving fantastical situations. Whittaker commented that Space Invaders helped action games become the most dominant genre on both arcades and consoles, through to contemporary times. Guinness World Records considered Space Invaders one of the most successful arcade shooting games by 2008. In describing it as a "seminal arcade classic", IGN listed it as the number eight "classic shoot 'em up". Space Invaders set the template for the shoot 'em up genre. Its worldwide success created a demand for a wide variety of science fiction games, inspiring the development of arcade games, such as Atari's Asteroids, Williams Electronic's Defender, and Namco's Galaxian and Galaga, which were modeled after Space Invaders' gameplay and design. This influence extends to most shooting games released to the present day, including first-person shooters such as Wolfenstein, Doom, Halo, and Call of Duty. Space Invaders also had an influence on early computer dungeon crawl games such as Dungeons of Daggorath, which used similar heartbeat sounds to indicate player health. Space Invaders' concept of a gradually increasing difficulty level also revolutionized the gaming industry.Remakes and sequelsSpace Invaders '95, one of many sequelsRecent ports and remakes include Space Invaders Anniversary, released in 2003 for the PlayStation 2 and including nine variants of the core game. Space Invaders, Space Invaders Part II and Return of the Invaders were featured in the arcade compilation Taito Legends (released in 2005), and Space Invaders '91, Space Invaders '95, and Space Invaders DX were featured in Taito Legends 2 (released in 2006). A remake of the game called Space Invaders Extreme was released for the PSP and Nintendo DS in 2008 and on Xbox Live Arcade in 2009. A second remake, Space Invaders Infinity Gene, was released in 2009 on PlayStation Network, Xbox Live Arcade, and iOS devices. [CR]</plot>
		<releasedate>31/5/1978</releasedate>
		<year>1985</year>
		<genre>Action</genre>
		<studio>SEGA Enterprises</studio>
		<mobygames_url>https://www.mobygames.com/game/sg-1000/space-invaders-</mobygames_url>
		<giantbomb_url>https://www.giantbomb.com/space-invaders/3030-5099/</giantbomb_url>
		<boxart1>4Mm1BX8.jpg</boxart1>
		<snapshot1>CxwVkNy.png</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>k47ncVC.png</snapshot2>
		<snapshot3>jV50Lhk.jpg</snapshot3>
		<snapshot4>PFAV9y7.jpg</snapshot4>
		<snapshot5>Y7CwWzv.jpg</snapshot5>
		<snapshot6>9lsjQIg.jpg</snapshot6>
		<snapshot7>XVvFxWP.jpg</snapshot7>
		<snapshot8>qWkmHUc.jpg</snapshot8>
		<snapshot9>sj3afgu.jpg</snapshot9>
		<snapshot10>HazxtxA.jpg</snapshot10>
	</game>
	<game name="Space Mountain (Japan) (Othello Multivision)">
		<description>Space Mountain (Japan) (Othello Multivision)</description>
		<rom crc="BBD87D8F" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Sega%20-%20SG-1000.zip/Sega%20-%20SG-1000%2FSpace%20Mountain%20%28Japan%29%20%28Othello%20Multivision%29.zip" sha1="08D9360D6E92B081D99B7629F91D4FE482383A18" size="6082" />
		<title_clean>Space Mountain</title_clean>
	</game>
	<game name="Space Slalom (Japan)">
		<description>Space Slalom (Japan)</description>
		<rom crc="B8B58B30" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Sega%20-%20SG-1000.zip/Sega%20-%20SG-1000%2FSpace%20Slalom%20%28Japan%29.zip" sha1="798B5F3742CB3F95FD5977D9A2CB48BA2DC804E6" size="6023" />
		<title_clean>Space Slalom</title_clean>
	</game>
	<game name="Star Force (Taiwan)">
		<description>Star Force (Taiwan)</description>
		<rom crc="1F736931" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Sega%20-%20SG-1000.zip/Sega%20-%20SG-1000%2FStar%20Force%20%28Taiwan%29.zip" sha1="F3DDF97DDF0E40289E38D9105300F15EC7EAB78C" size="18183" />
		<title_clean>Star Force</title_clean>
		<plot>[CR][B]Overview:[/B][CR]Star Force first entered the scene on the arcades. It was later released for the Nintendo Entertainment System. It's a vertical shoot em up game where each stage in the game is named after a letter of the Greek alphabet.[CR][B]Story:[/B][CR]The story of the game is that the year is 2010 of Dimension Almanac, there was a mysterious planet named Gordess which was moving in the darkness of the cosmos for the purpose of mass murder and plunder. Everyone gave up fighting against Gordess because of its awesome power. One day a brave soldier riding a space patroller challenged Gordess to fight. People called this space patroller "Final Star", wishing to be saved. You must bring an end to the murders which have committed for the past 2000 years.[CR]Other Mediums[CR]In episode #8 of the Tecmo-Koei produced Rio - Rainbow Gate anime series, the character Jack Mighty must hack into a computer terminal in order to regain control of an automated system. Rather use a text based interface, he programs a game to visually represent the process. That game is Star Force.[CR]</plot>
		<releasedate>2/8/1985</releasedate>
		<year>1985</year>
		<genre>Action</genre>
		<studio>SEGA Enterprises</studio>
		<mobygames_url>https://www.mobygames.com/game/sg-1000/star-force</mobygames_url>
		<giantbomb_url>https://www.giantbomb.com/star-force/3030-3329/</giantbomb_url>
		<boxart1>8pFYVJb.jpg</boxart1>
		<snapshot1>9L7Gwmy.jpg</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>7T9fRvY.jpg</snapshot2>
		<snapshot3>RxQ5cbC.jpg</snapshot3>
		<snapshot4>TQkow1J.jpg</snapshot4>
		<snapshot5>NV9j4yv.jpg</snapshot5>
		<snapshot6>VGmPimD.jpg</snapshot6>
		<snapshot7>gi3gtRj.jpg</snapshot7>
		<snapshot8>xLj0hAT.jpg</snapshot8>
		<snapshot9>gkbLviY.jpg</snapshot9>
		<snapshot10>JB7hURm.jpg</snapshot10>
	</game>
	<game name="Star Jacker (Japan, Europe) (Rev 2)">
		<description>Star Jacker (Japan, Europe) (Rev 2)</description>
		<rom crc="3FE59505" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Sega%20-%20SG-1000.zip/Sega%20-%20SG-1000%2FStar%20Jacker%20%28Japan%2C%20Europe%29%20%28Rev%202%29.zip" sha1="A2A06E7545CA1E0D522D0EB75A72B5B520F42330" size="14551" />
		<title_clean>Star Jacker</title_clean>
		<plot>Star Jacker (&#12473;&#12479;&#12540;&#12472;&#12515;&#12483;&#12459;&#12540;) is a shoot 'em up video game released for Sega System 1 arcade hardware in 1983. Unlike most shoot 'em ups, the player initially controls three space ships, losing one each time the player dies. This means on the first life you will have three times the amount of firepower than on your last.[CR]Like Xevious there are two types of weapon - forward lasers for flying enemies and bombs for bases.[CR]Star Jacker was ported to the SG-1000 in the same year. Due to the limitations of the console there are fewer variations in backgrounds and the graphics are far simpler overall. The player in this version starts with four ships rather than three, however.</plot>
		<releasedate>1/2/1983</releasedate>
		<year>1983</year>
		<genre>Action</genre>
		<studio>SEGA Enterprises</studio>
		<thegamesdb_id>35137</thegamesdb_id>
		<mobygames_url>https://www.mobygames.com/game/sg-1000/star-jacker</mobygames_url>
		<boxart1>0AK9KxD.jpg</boxart1>
	</game>
	<game name="Super Tank (Taiwan)">
		<description>Super Tank (Taiwan)</description>
		<rom crc="D0C3DF3F" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Sega%20-%20SG-1000.zip/Sega%20-%20SG-1000%2FSuper%20Tank%20%28Taiwan%29.zip" sha1="0D014FC9DB775B62FF55196B85B8E91C5E3249F3" size="23436" />
		<title_clean>Super Tank</title_clean>
	</game>
	<game name="Tank Battalion (Taiwan)">
		<description>Tank Battalion (Taiwan)</description>
		<rom crc="5CBD1163" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Sega%20-%20SG-1000.zip/Sega%20-%20SG-1000%2FTank%20Battalion%20%28Taiwan%29.zip" sha1="0CA3B740B28266A2A606127ED8967C684B67CB44" size="10693" />
		<title_clean>Tank Battalion</title_clean>
	</game>
	<game name="Tanoshii Sansuu (Shougaku 6-Nen Jou) (Japan) (SC-3000)">
		<description>Tanoshii Sansuu (Shougaku 6-Nen Jou) (Japan) (SC-3000)</description>
		<rom crc="8B5E6E1B" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Sega%20-%20SG-1000.zip/Sega%20-%20SG-1000%2FTanoshii%20Sansuu%20%28Shougaku%206-Nen%20Jou%29%20%28Japan%29%20%28SC-3000%29.zip" sha1="103FCB058B6F9671E5CA969A5CBD4BD171CADDC3" size="10974" />
		<title_clean>Tanoshii Sansuu</title_clean>
	</game>
	<game name="Terebi Oekaki (Japan)">
		<description>Terebi Oekaki (Japan)</description>
		<rom crc="DD4A661B" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Sega%20-%20SG-1000.zip/Sega%20-%20SG-1000%2FTerebi%20Oekaki%20%28Japan%29.zip" sha1="12296F2BB57D80D1774749D3002A039E0940C6FA" size="2742" />
		<title_clean>Terebi Oekaki</title_clean>
		<plot>It required the use of the Sega Graphic Board tablet, along with a stylus pen that came with it. [CR]</plot>
		<releasedate>31/12/1985</releasedate>
		<giantbomb_url>https://www.giantbomb.com/terebi-oekaki/3030-44069/</giantbomb_url>
		<boxart1>O3X69Xq.jpg</boxart1>
	</game>
	<game name="TwinBee (Taiwan)">
		<description>TwinBee (Taiwan)</description>
		<rom crc="C550B4F0" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Sega%20-%20SG-1000.zip/Sega%20-%20SG-1000%2FTwinBee%20%28Taiwan%29.zip" sha1="A8C30043C145E63F79A3265DDE167529F0E08D49" size="24877" />
		<title_clean>TwinBee</title_clean>
	</game>
	<game name="Uranai Angel Cutie (Japan) (SC-3000)">
		<description>Uranai Angel Cutie (Japan) (SC-3000)</description>
		<rom crc="AE4F92CF" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Sega%20-%20SG-1000.zip/Sega%20-%20SG-1000%2FUranai%20Angel%20Cutie%20%28Japan%29%20%28SC-3000%29.zip" sha1="90E32471B68CB60449B30E5D5A19D3A88F9829D3" size="19914" />
		<title_clean>Uranai Angel Cutie</title_clean>
	</game>
	<game name="Wonder Boy (Japan) (Rev 1)">
		<description>Wonder Boy (Japan) (Rev 1)</description>
		<rom crc="E8F0344D" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Sega%20-%20SG-1000.zip/Sega%20-%20SG-1000%2FWonder%20Boy%20%28Japan%29%20%28Rev%201%29.zip" sha1="240600A0DDA16809F49B173F731C7FDAF921466A" size="20522" />
		<title_clean>Wonder Boy</title_clean>
		<plot>[CR][B]Gameplay:[/B][CR]The gameplay in Wonder Boy is traditional platforming fare, tasking players with navigating their way to the end of each level which would entail correctly timing jumps and either defeating enemies using throwing axes or avoiding them entirely. Wonder Boy can collect items, such as fruit, which were scattered throughout the levels to increase their score. Whilst Wonder Boy begins his journey on foot, players could often navigate them on via a skateboard, should the correct item be collected.Adventure Island and Wonder Boy share the same engine and are essentially the same game, with minor differences. Each of these games would spin out into their own completely separate franchises.[CR]</plot>
		<releasedate>31/12/1986</releasedate>
		<year>1986</year>
		<genre>Action</genre>
		<studio>SEGA Enterprises</studio>
		<mobygames_url>https://www.mobygames.com/game/sg-1000/wonder-boy</mobygames_url>
		<giantbomb_url>https://www.giantbomb.com/wonder-boy/3030-5220/</giantbomb_url>
		<boxart1>isXTEHZ.jpg</boxart1>
		<snapshot1>LXmNRnR.jpg</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>1sBn9Qr.jpg</snapshot2>
		<snapshot3>7VSEpPn.jpg</snapshot3>
		<snapshot4>7MEnfbs.jpg</snapshot4>
		<snapshot5>Jt8xNTJ.jpg</snapshot5>
		<snapshot6>ucqDT3F.jpg</snapshot6>
		<snapshot7>IvKm1L3.jpg</snapshot7>
		<snapshot8>wewxjoQ.jpg</snapshot8>
		<snapshot9>4wVswJw.jpg</snapshot9>
		<snapshot10>C5w3dye.jpg</snapshot10>
	</game>
	<game name="Yamato (Japan, Europe)">
		<description>Yamato (Japan, Europe)</description>
		<rom crc="E2FD5201" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Sega%20-%20SG-1000.zip/Sega%20-%20SG-1000%2FYamato%20%28Japan%2C%20Europe%29.zip" sha1="4D746558FB699C5CB480BA26130518105B2E2031" size="6423" />
		<title_clean>Yamato</title_clean>
		<plot>Yamato is a shooter were you sit behind the front of a ship and its guns at the bottom of the screen while the enemy ships and planes are ahead in the distance. The aim is to keep destroying the enemies ships and planes until it is game over but the more you destroy then the higher the round you play on. You take control of two cross-hairs, one for firing bullets and the other for missiles and they both move together when you move them left or right which also moves your ship. When you move them up or down, then they move at different speeds and the bullets are for shooting down the planes and the missiles for the boats which has a short delay between firing. As the boats move across the screen from left to right they will fire missiles and torpedoes at you and these can be shot or avoided and if you are hit by one then you lose one of three lives. Two players can play and each player takes it in turns to play when the other player has been killed.</plot>
		<year>1983</year>
		<genre>Action</genre>
		<studio>SEGA Enterprises</studio>
		<mobygames_url>https://www.mobygames.com/game/sg-1000/yamato</mobygames_url>
	</game>
	<game name="Yie Ar Kung-Fu II (Taiwan)">
		<description>Yie Ar Kung-Fu II (Taiwan)</description>
		<rom crc="FC87463C" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Sega%20-%20SG-1000.zip/Sega%20-%20SG-1000%2FYie%20Ar%20Kung-Fu%20II%20%28Taiwan%29.zip" sha1="44FB2DCA3774F859F0AE0AD4D809A67F760CF9AE" size="28144" />
		<title_clean>Yie Ar Kung-Fu II</title_clean>
	</game>
	<game name="Zaxxon (Taiwan)">
		<description>Zaxxon (Taiwan)</description>
		<rom crc="49CAE925" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Sega%20-%20SG-1000.zip/Sega%20-%20SG-1000%2FZaxxon%20%28Taiwan%29.zip" sha1="172A8FF1A574D7920906C5CF60E1D39F31B9B639" size="15380" />
		<title_clean>Zaxxon</title_clean>
		<plot>[CR][B]Overview:[/B][CR]Zaxxon is an arcade title that was originally released in 1981 and later ported to a multitude of home platforms over the years. Developed by Sega, the game is a space shooter viewed from an isometric perspective. This perspective made the game stand out from other space shooters of the era, as most at the time were strictly either top-down shooters or side-scrollers. [CR]</plot>
		<releasedate>31/12/1981</releasedate>
		<year>1985</year>
		<genre>Action</genre>
		<studio>SEGA Enterprises</studio>
		<mobygames_url>https://www.mobygames.com/game/sg-1000/zaxxon</mobygames_url>
		<giantbomb_url>https://www.giantbomb.com/zaxxon/3030-9547/</giantbomb_url>
		<boxart1>E3QdjXW.jpg</boxart1>
		<snapshot1>nVX9IS6.png</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>5HJb3O0.png</snapshot2>
		<snapshot3>AiM425M.png</snapshot3>
		<snapshot4>jSslrjp.png</snapshot4>
		<snapshot5>bNIgQnA.png</snapshot5>
		<snapshot6>2hxVfds.png</snapshot6>
		<snapshot7>FIx7OPL.png</snapshot7>
		<snapshot8>mVanOIA.png</snapshot8>
		<snapshot9>iSDJVnC.png</snapshot9>
		<snapshot10>cvZh21t.png</snapshot10>
	</game>
	<game name="Zippy Race (Taiwan)">
		<description>Zippy Race (Taiwan)</description>
		<rom crc="BCF441A5" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Sega%20-%20SG-1000.zip/Sega%20-%20SG-1000%2FZippy%20Race%20%28Taiwan%29.zip" sha1="F6926D0C3C654A038CD5EEC9AAA6876BCE86FDAA" size="15794" />
		<title_clean>Zippy Race</title_clean>
		<plot>[CR][B]Overview:[/B][CR]MotoRace USA is a vertically-scrolling top-down motorcycle racing game that alternates to a behind-the-bike view for the latter half of each of its races. It was first released in the Arcades in Japan as Zippy Race. The game was ported to the Sega SG-1000, a predecessor of the Master System, and was also Irem's first game for the Nintendo Famicom - both of these ports are Japan-exclusive. It would also be included in the Irem Arcade Classics compilation for the Sega Saturn and Sony PlayStation.The goal of the game is to reach the end of each stage of the player character's coast-to-coast motorcycle race from LA to New York before their fuel supply runs out. Along the way, the racer has to avoid car traffic and take into account forks in the road, collecting extra fuel and score bonuses when they appear.[CR]</plot>
		<releasedate>31/12/1983</releasedate>
		<giantbomb_url>https://www.giantbomb.com/motorace-usa/3030-27193/</giantbomb_url>
		<boxart1>BbalOuH.jpg</boxart1>
		<snapshot1>I7qhZWB.jpg</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>ULaDHxl.png</snapshot2>
		<snapshot3>x3Rn5LJ.png</snapshot3>
		<snapshot4>GwyUbuc.png</snapshot4>
	</game>
	<game name="Zoom 909 (Taiwan)">
		<description>Zoom 909 (Taiwan)</description>
		<rom crc="9943FC2B" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Sega%20-%20SG-1000.zip/Sega%20-%20SG-1000%2FZoom%20909%20%28Taiwan%29.zip" sha1="7A998A0DA19471F7E3E5BD82A9FBAF82A966EE40" size="20027" />
		<title_clean>Zoom 909</title_clean>
	</game>
</datafile>