<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<datafile>
	<header>
		<emu_name>Sharp X1</emu_name>
		<emu_description>Sharp X1</emu_description>
		<emu_category>PC, Sharp, 1980s</emu_category>
		<emu_version>010622</emu_version>
		<emu_date>11/4/21</emu_date>
		<emu_author>Zach Morris</emu_author>
		<emu_visibility>visible</emu_visibility>
		<emu_homepage>https://archive.org</emu_homepage>
		<emu_baseurl>https://archive.org/download/</emu_baseurl>
		<emu_launcher>retroplayer</emu_launcher>
		<emu_default_addon>none</emu_default_addon>
		<emu_ext_launch_cmd>none</emu_ext_launch_cmd>
		<emu_downloadpath>default</emu_downloadpath>
		<emu_postdlaction>none</emu_postdlaction>
		<emu_comment>The X1, sometimes called the Sharp X1, is a series of home computers released by Sharp Corporation from 1982 to 1988. It is based on a Zilog Z80 CPU.[CR]Despite the fact that the Computer Division of Sharp Corporation had released the MZ series, suddenly the Television Division released a new computer series called the X1. At the time the original X1 was released, all other home computers generally had a BASIC language in ROM. However the X1 did not have a BASIC ROM, and it had to load the Hu-BASIC interpreter from a cassette tape. On the plus side however, this concept meant that a free RAM area was available that was as big as possible when not using BASIC. This policy was originally copied from the Sharp MZ series, and they were called clean computers in Japan. The cabinet shape of X1 was also much more stylish than others at that time and a range of cabinet colors (including Red) was selectable.[CR]Developer:  Sharp Corporation[CR]Manufacturer:  Sharp Corporation[CR]CPU:  Sharp Z80 A 8MHz[CR]Memory:  64 KB[CR]Graphics:  320 × 200, 640 × 200[CR]Sound:  Yamaha YM2149, General Instrument AY-3-8910[CR]Media:  Cassette, Floppy[CR]Max Controllers:  2</emu_comment>
		<emu_thumb>fvHHvOv.jpg</emu_thumb>
		<emu_banner>UEaGpP3.jpg</emu_banner>
		<emu_fanart>0LUCeHG.jpg</emu_fanart>
		<emu_logo>fI5Gwnf.png</emu_logo>
		<emu_trailer>Nexw9T0u5Do</emu_trailer>
	</header>
	<game name="100 Yen Disk">
		<description>100 Yen Disk</description>
		<rom name="sharp-x-1/Sharp_X1.zip/Sharp_X1%2F100%20Yen%20Disk%20%28ver.%202.50%29.d88" size="348848"/>
		<plot>100 Yen Disk is a Miscellaneous game, developed and published by Onion Soft, which was released in Japan in 1986.</plot>
		<snapshot1>HYyPnDn.jpg</snapshot1>
		<videoid>8Fowr-IA8j8</videoid>
	</game>
	<game name="1942">
		<description>1942</description>
		<rom name="sharp-x-1/Sharp_X1.zip/Sharp_X1%2F1942.d88" size="348848"/>
		<plot>[I]1942[/I] is a vertically scrolling shooter for one or two players. The year is 1942, and you are a daring fighter pilot "Super Ace". You begin and end each of the numerous levels on an aircraft carrier and then fly your plane into battle against the enemy over both sea and land. After destroying certain plane formations you can collect several different power ups to increase your fire power and chances of survival. You can also make your plane roll to avoid enemy attacks 3 times per life. There are 24 levels, the first being Midway and the last The Final Area.</plot>
		<year>1987</year>
		<boxart1>http://www.mobygames.com/images/covers/l/17048-1942-nes-front-cover.jpg</boxart1>
		<genre>Shoot Em Up</genre>
		<groups>194x series,Aircraft: P-38 Lightning,Genre: Scrolling shoot 'em up</groups>
	</game>
	<game name="A Train">
		<description>A Train</description>
		<rom name="sharp-x-1/Sharp_X1.zip/Sharp_X1%2FA-Train%20%28A%20Ressha%20de%20Ikou%29%20%28X1turbo%29.d88" size="348848"/>
		<plot>A-Train is a series of business simulation video games that were originally developed and published by Japanese game developer Artdink in Japan. The first game in the series was published in 1985.  The first release in the United States was Take the A-Train II, published in 1988 by the Seika Corporation under the title Railroad Empire. However, the most well known U.S. release is Take the A-Train III, published in 1992 by Maxis as simply A-Train</plot>
		<boxart1>https://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/5/50/Atraincover.jpg</boxart1>
	</game>
	<game name="Advanced Fantasian">
		<description>Advanced Fantasian</description>
		<rom name="sharp-x-1/Sharp_X1.zip/Sharp_X1%2FAdvanced%20Fantasian%20%28X1turbo%29%20%28Main%20disk%29.d88" size="348848"/>
		<rom name="sharp-x-1/Sharp_X1.zip/Sharp_X1%2FAdvanced%20Fantasian%20%28X1turbo%29%20%28Scenario%20disk%29.d88" size="348848"/>
		<rom name="sharp-x-1/Sharp_X1.zip/Sharp_X1%2FAdvanced%20Fantasian%20%28demo%29.d88" size="348848"/>
		<plot>Long ago, humans and other creatures lived peacefully in a magical paradise. However, one day a new star appeared nearby. A meteorite fell onto the Earth, turning it into a realm of perpetual darkness and misery. Humans managed to restore the land to its original state. But orcs, trolls, and other hostile races refused to give up their territory. Thus, the second age of peace quickly turned into an age of a new battle...[CR][I]Advanced Fantasian[/I] is a follow-up to Fantasian. Like its predecessor, it is a Western-style (despite its Japanese origins) role-playing game most closely resembling Wizardry games. Compared to the first game, it has enhanced visuals - graphical locations in the town as well as in the dungeon, as opposed to menus and vector graphics of the original. Gameplay system is more refined: the player can customize the characters' weapon proficiencies and a few skills. Turn-based combat takes place on separate screens and is more tactical than in the previous game: each character has action points that determine his or her mobility and attack range; characters can also face different directions, which influences their attacks and defense.</plot>
		<groups>Fantasian series</groups>
	</game>
	<game name="Albatross">
		<description>Albatross</description>
		<rom name="sharp-x-1/Sharp_X1.zip/Sharp_X1%2FAlbatross%20%28Disk%201%20-%20System%20disk%29.d88" size="348848"/>
		<rom name="sharp-x-1/Sharp_X1.zip/Sharp_X1%2FAlbatross%20%28Disk%202%29.d88" size="348848"/>
		<rom name="sharp-x-1/Sharp_X1.zip/Sharp_X1%2FAlbatross%20%28Disk%203%29.d88" size="348848"/>
		<plot>[I]Albatross[/I] is a top view golf game that consists of an 18 holes course. You can select your own clubs from 14 drivers, irons and a putter. Further you can adjust your stance, how you hit the ball and your swing. It features a split screen with two views, an overhead view of the entire hole and a more detailed zoom of your ball's current position. The screen also contains a status bar with all necessary information.[CR]The gameplay options include single player stroke play, multi player stroke play, or multi player match play.</plot>
		<boxart1>http://www.mobygames.com/images/covers/l/306763-albatross-msx-front-cover.jpg</boxart1>
		<genre>Sports,Golf</genre>
	</game>
	<game name="Albatross Expert Course">
		<description>Albatross Expert Course</description>
		<rom name="sharp-x-1/Sharp_X1.zip/Sharp_X1%2FAlbatross%20-%20Expert%20Course%20%28Disk%201%29.d88" size="322736"/>
		<rom name="sharp-x-1/Sharp_X1.zip/Sharp_X1%2FAlbatross%20-%20Expert%20Course%20%28Disk%202%29.d88" size="322736"/>
		<plot>[I]Albatross[/I] is a top view golf game that consists of an 18 holes course. You can select your own clubs from 14 drivers, irons and a putter. Further you can adjust your stance, how you hit the ball and your swing. It features a split screen with two views, an overhead view of the entire hole and a more detailed zoom of your ball's current position. The screen also contains a status bar with all necessary information.[CR]The gameplay options include single player stroke play, multi player stroke play, or multi player match play.</plot>
		<boxart1>http://www.mobygames.com/images/covers/l/306763-albatross-msx-front-cover.jpg</boxart1>
		<genre>Sports,Golf</genre>
	</game>
	<game name="Albatross Jun Classic Country Club">
		<description>Albatross Jun Classic Country Club</description>
		<rom name="sharp-x-1/Sharp_X1.zip/Sharp_X1%2FAlbatross%20-%20Jun%20Classic%20Country%20Club%20%28Disk%201%29.d88" size="348848"/>
		<rom name="sharp-x-1/Sharp_X1.zip/Sharp_X1%2FAlbatross%20-%20Jun%20Classic%20Country%20Club%20%28Disk%202%29.d88" size="348848"/>
		<plot>Golf course add-on for Albatross featuring the Jun Classic Country Club in Japan.</plot>
		<boxart1>http://www.mobygames.com/images/covers/l/306763-albatross-msx-front-cover.jpg</boxart1>
		<genre>Sports,Golf</genre>
	</game>
	<game name="Albatross Visual Course">
		<description>Albatross Visual Course</description>
		<rom name="sharp-x-1/Sharp_X1.zip/Sharp_X1%2FAlbatross%20-%20Visual%20Course%20%28Disk%201%29.d88" size="322736"/>
		<rom name="sharp-x-1/Sharp_X1.zip/Sharp_X1%2FAlbatross%20-%20Visual%20Course%20%28Disk%202%29.d88" size="322464"/>
		<plot>[I]Albatross[/I] is a top view golf game that consists of an 18 holes course. You can select your own clubs from 14 drivers, irons and a putter. Further you can adjust your stance, how you hit the ball and your swing. It features a split screen with two views, an overhead view of the entire hole and a more detailed zoom of your ball's current position. The screen also contains a status bar with all necessary information.[CR]The gameplay options include single player stroke play, multi player stroke play, or multi player match play.</plot>
		<boxart1>http://www.mobygames.com/images/covers/l/306763-albatross-msx-front-cover.jpg</boxart1>
		<genre>Sports,Golf</genre>
	</game>
	<game name="Albatross World Course">
		<description>Albatross World Course</description>
		<rom name="sharp-x-1/Sharp_X1.zip/Sharp_X1%2FAlbatross%20-%20World%20Course%20%28Disk%201%29.d88" size="322736"/>
		<rom name="sharp-x-1/Sharp_X1.zip/Sharp_X1%2FAlbatross%20-%20World%20Course%20%28Disk%202%29.d88" size="322736"/>
		<plot>[I]Albatross[/I] is a top view golf game that consists of an 18 holes course. You can select your own clubs from 14 drivers, irons and a putter. Further you can adjust your stance, how you hit the ball and your swing. It features a split screen with two views, an overhead view of the entire hole and a more detailed zoom of your ball's current position. The screen also contains a status bar with all necessary information.[CR]The gameplay options include single player stroke play, multi player stroke play, or multi player match play.</plot>
		<boxart1>http://www.mobygames.com/images/covers/l/306763-albatross-msx-front-cover.jpg</boxart1>
		<genre>Sports,Golf</genre>
	</game>
	<game name="Algarna">
		<description>Algarna</description>
		<rom name="sharp-x-1/Sharp_X1.zip/Sharp_X1%2FAlgarna%20%28Program%20disk%29.d88" size="348576"/>
		<rom name="sharp-x-1/Sharp_X1.zip/Sharp_X1%2FAlgarna%20%28Disk%20A%29.d88" size="348848"/>
		<rom name="sharp-x-1/Sharp_X1.zip/Sharp_X1%2FAlgarna%20%28Disk%20B%29.d88" size="348848"/>
		<snapshot1>http://adb.arcadeitalia.net/media/mess.current/titles/x1_flop/algarna.png</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>https://i.ytimg.com/vi/4fVGiJdzUx0/maxresdefault.jpg</snapshot2>
	</game>
	<game name="American Truck">
		<description>American Truck</description>
		<rom name="sharp-x-1/Sharp_X1.zip/Sharp_X1%2FAmerican%20Truck.d88" size="348848"/>
		<plot>American Truck is a top view race and driving game. In each stage you 'll have to reach the finish line before you run out of gasoline or time. Additional gasoline can be acquired by picking up the gasoline items that do appear randomly on the road, but be careful, bombs appear randomly too. Further, you have to avoid crashes with other traffic like cars and trucks and don't get off the road or crash into walls.</plot>
		<studio>Telenet Japan</studio>
		<boxart1>http://www.mobygames.com/images/covers/l/306765-american-truck-msx-front-cover.jpg</boxart1>
		<snapshot2>https://images.launchbox-app.com/5e4054b9-2e09-4b67-8209-fdb53a808b97.jpg</snapshot2>
		<genre>Driving,Racing</genre>
		<groups>Genre: Truck racing / driving</groups>
	</game>
	<game name="Aoki Ookami to Shiroki Mejika">
		<description>Aoki Ookami to Shiroki Mejika</description>
		<rom name="sharp-x-1/Sharp_X1.zip/Sharp_X1%2FAoki%20Ookami%20to%20Shiroki%20Mejika%20%28X1turbo%2C%20hi-res%29.d88" size="348848"/>
		<boxart1>http://www.mobygames.com/images/covers/l/547184-aoki-okami-to-shiroki-mejika-pc-98-front-cover.png</boxart1>
		<groups>Genghis Khan series,KOEI Historical Simulation series</groups>
	</game>
	<game name="Arctic">
		<description>Arctic</description>
		<rom name="sharp-x-1/Sharp_X1.zip/Sharp_X1%2FArctic%20%28X1turbo%29.d88" size="348848"/>
		<plot>[I]Arctic[/I] is an action puzzle game that describes itself as "active rail playing". Each of more than two-dozen stages consists of a set of rails in various arrangements, often looping around each other and splitting in various directions. Each stage contains a number of colored balls which begin in corresponding slots, and after launching them the goal is to return the balls to the matching-colored slots. The only interaction the player has with the board is switching two sets of splits; there are yellow and blue splits, which will redirect any balls moving through them, and the player can only turn all of one color as a group. Many stages also contain bumpers and gates which will affect the speed and direction of the balls. Completing a puzzle often requires strategic use of the stage's features to bounce balls onto the correct paths.</plot>
		<year>1988</year>
		<genre>Puzzle</genre>
		<boxart1>https://gamefaqs.gamespot.com/a/box/6/8/2/683682_front.jpg</boxart1>
	</game>
	<game name="Arcus">
		<description>Arcus</description>
		<rom name="sharp-x-1/Sharp_X1.zip/Sharp_X1%2FArcus%20%28X1turbo%29%20%28Disk%201%29.d88" size="454272"/>
		<rom name="sharp-x-1/Sharp_X1.zip/Sharp_X1%2FArcus%20%28X1turbo%29%20%28Disk%202%29.d88" size="458928"/>
		<rom name="sharp-x-1/Sharp_X1.zip/Sharp_X1%2FArcus%20%28X1turbo%29%20%28Disk%203%29.d88" size="458928"/>
		<rom name="sharp-x-1/Sharp_X1.zip/Sharp_X1%2FArcus%20%28X1turbo%29%20%28Disk%204%29.d88" size="458928"/>
		<rom name="sharp-x-1/Sharp_X1.zip/Sharp_X1%2FArcus%20%28X1turbo%29%20%28Disk%205%29.d88" size="458928"/>
		<plot>The people of the kingdom Arkases have mastered the ways of magic, thanks to their connection to the world of spirits. However, the humans used their magical powers to wage war on each other and to disrupt the harmony. Finally, the Golden Dragon told the king of Arkases that his country will be punished for the deeds of the humans. Enter Jedah Chaf, a young man who has left his home village to fulfill his dream of becoming a knight. Will Jedah be able to save his country and to restore peace in the world?[CR][I]Arcus[/I] is a RPG that is played entirely from first-person perspective. You navigate your hero by choosing a location from a menu. Once in dungeons, you have a separate menu whenever you encounter enemies. You fight them in turn-based combat, attacking physically or casting magic. The game is more close to Western RPG style than to Japanese one, and utilizes AD&amp;D; terminology for character stats.</plot>
		<boxart1>http://www.mobygames.com/images/covers/l/80282-arcus-msx-front-cover.jpg</boxart1>
		<groups>Arcus series</groups>
	</game>
	<game name="Argo">
		<description>Argo</description>
		<rom name="sharp-x-1/Sharp_X1.zip/Sharp_X1%2FArgo%20%28Disk%20A%29.d88" size="348848"/>
		<rom name="sharp-x-1/Sharp_X1.zip/Sharp_X1%2FArgo%20%28Disk%20B%29.d88" size="348576"/>
		<plot>Loosely based on the Greek myth of the Argonauts, [I]Argo[/I] focuses on its central protagonist Iason (Jason), narrating a simple story that does not quite correspond to the known myth: Iason's father has been poisoned, and his native city Iolkos overrun by monsters known as Pontos. Iason must single-handedly eliminate them and save his homeland.[CR][I]Argo[/I] is a role-playing game set in a pseudo-3D continuous world. The player explores the environments from a first-person view. It is possible to try to talk to any encountered character, as well as attack anyone. Most battles take place within the exploration area and involve a fairly simple turn-based exchange of attacks. However, occasional fights against larger monsters take place on a separate screen, have an over-the-shoulder third-person perspective, and require the player to move and attack in real time. Experience points and gold are awarded for defeating enemies. It is necessary to feed the protagonist; when his condition is "hungry" food also restores a portion of his hit points.</plot>
		<groups>Mythology: Greek</groups>
		<snapshot1>https://gamefaqs.gamespot.com/a/screen/full/2/2/5/435225.jpg</snapshot1>
	</game>
	<game name="Asteka">
		<description>Asteka</description>
		<rom name="sharp-x-1/Sharp_X1.zip/Sharp_X1%2FAsteka%20%28X1turbo%29.d88" size="436912"/>
		<plot>[I]Asteka[/I] might be a misspelling of [I]Azteca[/I], but it deals with the legacy of the Maya culture rather than the Aztecs. The player takes control of a nameless adventurer who travels to the town of Palenque in South Mexico. There, he has to visit various locations and talk to the local inhabitants in order to gain entrance to the ruins of an ancient Mayan temple, which supposedly harbors the deepest secrets of their civilization.[CR]The game is a text adventure with graphics. The player switches between locations by typing words for "North", "South", etc., or simply by using the numeric arrow keys. The interaction with the environment is performed entirely by typing verb-object (or, rather, as the rules of Japanese grammar dictate, object-verb) command combinations. Text input and output are both in katakana only.</plot>
		<groups>Asteka / Tombs &amp; Treasure series</groups>
		<snapshot1>https://www.mobygames.com/images/shots/l/509226-asteka-pc-88-screenshot-title-screen.gif</snapshot1>
	</game>
	<game name="Aztec">
		<description>Aztec</description>
		<rom name="sharp-x-1/Sharp_X1.zip/Sharp_X1%2FAztec.d88" size="392368"/>
		<plot>[I]Aztec[/I] is an Indiana Jones-type action game with adventure elements, featuring our hero's quest to recover a valuable Jade Idol from a maze. Armed with only three sticks of dynamite and a pistol, the hero must get by traps, animals (lots of snakes and panthers), and natives, and find a way to make it out alive.[CR]The value of the Idol is set on the level of difficulty and declines as the game progresses. Thus, the player is awarded with the speed of which a successful recovery can be made. Multiple commands allow for freedom of movement, and expand the adventuring side of the game. The animation used several frames for each creature.[CR]Although the game is somewhat easy on the lower levels of difficulty, the game appears impossible on the highest of the 8 skill levels. The creatures in the maze increase in number and speed, and tend to want to follow you around more. This is difficult however if you want to go to the lower level and there's a hungry jaguar waiting for you.[CR]You walk around exploring boxes and "trash piles". Sometimes a box contains something useful such as a machete, pistol, bullets, dynamite, a health potion, or the idol. Sometimes it contains skulls or bones, or even nothing at all. [CR]The game features some unusual traps. You can walk into a room and the walls start moving in on you, or the ceiling starts dropping on your head. When you die, you have the option of restarting using the maze you just died in. That way, all of your exploring is not wasted.</plot>
		<year>1982</year>
		<boxart1>http://www.mobygames.com/images/covers/l/534843-aztec-apple-ii-front-cover.png</boxart1>
		<genre>Platform</genre>
		<groups>Games with randomly generated environments,Genre: Explorable platformer / Metroidvania,Setting: Aztec</groups>
	</game>
	<game name="Balloon Fight">
		<description>Balloon Fight</description>
		<rom name="sharp-x-1/Sharp_X1.zip/Sharp_X1%2FBalloon%20Fight.d88" size="43360"/>
		<plot>In [I]Balloon Fight[/I] you need to fly around with the aid of two balloons and try to pop your opponent's balloons before they pop yours. Landing on top of your opponents will cause their balloons to pop and they will use a parachute to fall to safety. You then have to destroy the fallen opponents by running into them before they can blow a new balloon and rejoin the battle. Should both of your balloons get popped, you will fall into the water below and lose a life. There is also a second game variation called "balloon trip" where you need to collect as many balloons as possible while avoiding the ocean floor and lightnings that form maze-like walls.</plot>
		<year>1985</year>
		<boxart1>http://www.mobygames.com/images/covers/l/18585-balloon-fight-nes-front-cover.jpg</boxart1>
		<genre>Action</genre>
		<groups>Classic NES / Famicom Mini / NES Classics releases,Joust variants,Nintendo's Action series,e-Reader series</groups>
	</game>
	<game name="Bastard Special">
		<description>Bastard Special</description>
		<rom name="sharp-x-1/Sharp_X1.zip/Sharp_X1%2FBastard%20Special.d88" size="348848"/>
		<plot>Bastard Special is an action RPG, somewhat similar to The Legend of Zelda (even though that one is an action adventure), based on the manga and anime [I]Bastard[/I].[CR]You fight monsters and humanoid beings in a very huge dungeon, eventually getting gold and experience points. Gold can be used to spend outside the dungeons in shops where you can buy better weapons, armor and shields, items for healing or other purposes, spells or in a temple to heal your status.</plot>
		<boxart1>https://images.launchbox-app.com/379b6cc5-3488-4951-9105-e3a6aaa1cf19.jpg</boxart1>
		<snapshot1>https://images.launchbox-app.com/702675aa-6d03-4baa-8122-304db46257ce.png</snapshot1>
	</game>
	<game name="Batten Tanuki no Daibouken">
		<description>Batten Tanuki no Daibouken</description>
		<rom name="sharp-x-1/Sharp_X1.zip/Sharp_X1%2FBatten%20Tanuki%20no%20Daibouken.d88" size="346080"/>
		<plot>The cover of Technosofts Batten Tanuki no Daibouken (Batten Tanuki’s Great Adventure) has a photograph of an adorable raccoon dog just hanging out. ([I]batten[/I] is a conjunctive word unique to the Kyushu dialect that means something like however, and gives the title a folksy charm.) Its cute, but it greatly undersells the kind of insane, frustrating action within.[CR]The story takes place in a forest, where the evil Count Wolf has kidnapped all of the creatures, save for an elderly rabbit. A tanuki warrior from outside the land, trained in kung-fu just happens to be passing through, so the rabbit granny begs him to use his strength to find Wolf Castle and rescue all of the villagers.</plot>
		<genre>Beat Em Up</genre>
		<boxart1>http://www.hardcoregaming101.net/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/cover2.jpg</boxart1>
		<snapshot1>http://www.hardcoregaming101.net/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/Batten-Tanuki-no-Daibouken-1985-Tecno-Soft-J-a1_0001.png</snapshot1>
	</game>
	<game name="Battle Gorilla">
		<description>Battle Gorilla</description>
		<rom name="sharp-x-1/Sharp_X1.zip/Sharp_X1%2FBattle%20Gorilla%20%28X1turbo%29%20%28Disk%201%29.d88" size="348848"/>
		<rom name="sharp-x-1/Sharp_X1.zip/Sharp_X1%2FBattle%20Gorilla%20%28X1turbo%29%20%28Disk%202%29.d88" size="348848"/>
		<plot>Despite its title, Combat Simulator: Battle Gorilla has nothing to do with the well-known large African primates, but rather with guerrilla combat. It is a top-down action game that has certain similarities with Commando, but with a much more tactical approach and extended simulation</plot>
		<boxart1>en2VoKh.jpg</boxart1>
		<snapshot1>http://adb.arcadeitalia.net/media/mess.current/ingames/x1_flop/bgorilla.png</snapshot1>
		<videoid>i4da0LJsNyk</videoid>
	</game>
	<game name="Bosconian">
		<description>Bosconian</description>
		<rom name="sharp-x-1/Sharp_X1.zip/Sharp_X1%2FBosconian.d88" size="348848"/>
		<plot>[I]Bosconian[/I] is a space shooter. It's your job to destroy enormous enemy battle stations scattered throughout the galaxy, which is filled with meteors and space mines. You can either do this by destroying one by one their outer structures or with a single shot in their core. They are heavily defended however by guns, fighters and (in later levels) missiles. Destroying all battle stations, with the help of your radar, will bring you to the next level. [CR]Often the enemy will try to destroy you by launching attack waves. Keep your eyes out for the enemy spy ship, if it escapes your fire, you are really in for it. </plot>
		<genre>Shoot Em Up</genre>
		<groups>Bosconian games,Video games turned into board / card games</groups>
		<boxart1>http://adb.arcadeitalia.net/media/mame.archive/flyers/1/bosco.png</boxart1>
		<snapshot1>http://adb.arcadeitalia.net/media/mame.current/titles/bosco.png</snapshot1>
	</game>
	<game name="Byakuya Monogatari">
		<description>Byakuya Monogatari</description>
		<rom name="sharp-x-1/Sharp_X1.zip/Sharp_X1%2FByakuya%20Monogatari%20%28Disk%201%29.d88" size="349392"/>
		<rom name="sharp-x-1/Sharp_X1.zip/Sharp_X1%2FByakuya%20Monogatari%20%28Disk%202%29.d88" size="348848"/>
		<rom name="sharp-x-1/Sharp_X1.zip/Sharp_X1%2FByakuya%20Monogatari%20%28Disk%203%29.d88" size="348848"/>
		<boxart1>https://images.launchbox-app.com/a11b16ab-a418-41da-86a7-5fa6c4f6181e.jpg</boxart1>
		<snapshot1>https://images.launchbox-app.com/a25060cc-cc19-41b4-b90e-3a5464757597.png</snapshot1>
		<plot>College student Hiroyuki Sato came to a hot spring resort and was shocked by western type mansion known as witch's house and decided to sneak in. This is a museum horror game inside a mansion, but also with comedy elements. It's command selection with verbs selected from vertical row with 2 and 8 keys and nouns selected from horizontal rows with 4 and 6 keys. I tried to bruteforce commands as usual, but I spent over 10 minutes on the 2nd scene and was not able to move on... this game is the hell for bruteforcing. The game is reported to feature battles inside the mansion and multiple endings, especially bad endings.</plot>
	</game>
	<game name="Carmine">
		<description>Carmine</description>
		<rom name="sharp-x-1/Sharp_X1.zip/Sharp_X1%2FCarmine%20%28Disk%20A%29.d88" size="374048"/>
		<rom name="sharp-x-1/Sharp_X1.zip/Sharp_X1%2FCarmine%20%28Disk%20B%29.d88" size="380848"/>
		<plot>CARMINE is basically an adventure game that tries to look like a first-person view mech simulator. The player has to navigate around a 3D maze looking for events to advance the story, all whilst getting constantly harrassed by random enemy encounters that are way too frequent and way too dangerous for their own good.</plot>
		<snapshot1>https://blog-imgs-62-origin.fc2.com/r/e/t/retrogamedaisuki/carmine_title.png</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>https://blog-imgs-62-origin.fc2.com/r/e/t/retrogamedaisuki/carmine_98_gameover.png</snapshot2>
		<genre>RPG</genre>
	</game>
	<game name="Casablanca ni Ai o">
		<description>Casablanca ni Ai o</description>
		<rom name="sharp-x-1/Sharp_X1.zip/Sharp_X1%2FCasablanca%20ni%20Ai%20o%20%28X1turbo%29%20%28Disk%20A%29.d88" size="413296"/>
		<rom name="sharp-x-1/Sharp_X1.zip/Sharp_X1%2FCasablanca%20ni%20Ai%20o%20%28X1turbo%29%20%28Disk%20B%29.d88" size="416688"/>
		<plot>The year is 1945. Jerry Randolph, a female reporter working for the Chicago newspaper "Daily Casablanca", finds a diary belonging to her high school friend May Elgar, who has disappeared several years ago under mysterious circumstances. Jerry discovers that May's father was working on a groundbreaking scientific project. Too late to save Dr. Elgar from untimely death, Jerry uses a time machine constructed by him to travel to 1916, following the traces left by the criminals.[CR]In spite of its title, the game has little to do with the famous movie [I]Casablanca[/I] beyond a few loose references. It is a text adventure with graphics, in which the player types text commands to interact with the environment. Several useful commands (including Look, Search, Take and Knock) can be accessed directly through function keys. Limited navigation between screens can be performed with directional arrows. English text input is supported to a certain degree, though text descriptions are in Japanese only.</plot>
		<boxart1>https://www.giantbomb.com/a/uploads/scale_medium/16/164924/3008727-2277969506-44874.jpg</boxart1>
		<snapshot1>https://i.ytimg.com/vi/vkIiUoLBN0o/maxresdefault.jpg</snapshot1>
	</game>
	<game name="Castle Excellent">
		<description>Castle Excellent</description>
		<rom name="sharp-x-1/Sharp_X1.zip/Sharp_X1%2FCastle%20Excellent.d88" size="348848"/>
		<plot>The puzzle and platform game Castle Excellent (Castlequest) is a sequel to The Castle. In Castle Excellent you control a prince that has to save the princess again. The main difference with the original The Castle game is that the castle rooms are completely redesigned and contain many new challenges. The game play has not changed.[CR]To find your princess you have to explore the castle, which has 100 different rooms. Each room is a puzzle on its own as you have to avoid enemy knights, fat Tiroler men, hazardous objects and have to use objects to get to the next door. In each room you have to collect keys and items like rings and gold bars. The keys may have different colors and only opens doors with the corresponding key color.</plot>
		<boxart1>https://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/3/34/CastlequestNESBoxart.jpg</boxart1>
		<genre>Platform</genre>
		<videoid>oM2upeGlakk</videoid>
	</game>
	<game name="Chackn Pop load Chackn Popr">
		<description>Chackn Pop load Chackn Popr</description>
		<rom name="sharp-x-1/Sharp_X1.zip/Sharp_X1%2FChack%27n%20Pop%20%7Bload%20Chack%27n%20Pop%2Cr%7D.d88" size="348848"/>
		<plot>[I]Chack'n Pop[/I] is considered a predecessor of Bubble Bobble. It is a platform game where a roundish yellow creature, named Chack'n, must fight against Monstas and Mightas in order to reclaim hearts that were stolen during a romantic encounter with Miss Chack'n.[CR]The Monstas themselves hatch from eggs hanging from the ceilings and the Mightas push a rock that is used as the game's timer. The Monsta eggs have three phases: if it's blue, it's completely harmless, if it's yellow it will pop within 10 seconds and if an egg turns red it will pop almost immediately.[CR]Chack'n uses bombs to blow up the Monstas and their eggs and he also uses them to release the captured hearts from their cages. When the heart is released, it will fly up and destroy the separator block and reveal the exit to the level.[CR]Most versions of the game contain 14 levels to play through, however the Famicom version only includes 9.</plot>
		<boxart1>http://www.mobygames.com/images/covers/l/545896-chack-n-pop-pc-6001-front-cover.png</boxart1>
	</game>
	<game name="Champion ProWres Special">
		<description>Champion ProWres Special</description>
		<rom name="sharp-x-1/Sharp_X1.zip/Sharp_X1%2FChampion%20ProWres%20Special.d88" size="348288"/>
		<plot>Appoooh (Champion ProWres Special) is an arcade wrestling game for one or two player simultaneously. There is a choice of eight wrestlers, each with a different look and a different set of moves.</plot>
		<genre>Wrestling</genre>
		<boxart1>https://segaretro.org/images/5/53/CPWS_SharpX1_JP_Box.jpg</boxart1>
		<snapshot1>https://retrocdn.net/images/b/bf/ChampionProwresSpecial_PC88_JP_SSTitle.png</snapshot1>
	</game>
	<game name="Columns X1">
		<description>Columns X1</description>
		<rom name="sharp-x-1/Sharp_X1.zip/Sharp_X1%2FColumns%20X1.d88" size="348848"/>
		<genre>Puzzle</genre>
		<plot>Columns is a match-three puzzle video game released by Sega</plot>
		<boxart1>1pONrOq.jpg</boxart1>
		<videoid>GzVViOrCQEA</videoid>
	</game>
	<game name="Cosmic Soldier">
		<description>Cosmic Soldier</description>
		<rom name="sharp-x-1/Sharp_X1.zip/Sharp_X1%2FCosmic%20Soldier%20%28X1turbo%29.d88" size="376928"/>
		<plot>The year is 3530 AD. The KGD (an obvious nod to the developer Kogado) Star System has fallen into the clutches of the evil Quila Empire. The hero of the game is a soldier of the Galactic Alliance who receives a mission to infiltrate a Quila base with his companion, a beautiful female android, and eventually defeat the enemy. [CR][I]Cosmic Soldier[/I] is an early Japan-made RPG, which still mostly follows the Wizardry template, being a dungeon crawler with first-person navigation. Random enemy encounters lead to simple turn-based battles, graphically displayed at the top of the screen. The player cannot assign individual commands to the party members, but is able to choose various types of elemental attacks, which have different effects on different enemies.[CR]An original gameplay element is the ability to have short conversation with some enemies. It is possible to convince the enemy to join the party; this feature predates the famous demon conversations from Megaten games.</plot>
		<boxart1>http://www.mobygames.com/images/covers/l/542828-cosmic-soldier-pc-98-front-cover.png</boxart1>
		<genre>Adventure</genre>
		<groups>Cosmic Soldier series</groups>
	</game>
	<game name="Cream Lemon Star Trap">
		<description>Cream Lemon Star Trap</description>
		<rom name="sharp-x-1/Sharp_X1.zip/Sharp_X1%2FCream%20Lemon%20-%20Star%20Trap%20%28Disk%20A%29.d88" size="414128"/>
		<rom name="sharp-x-1/Sharp_X1.zip/Sharp_X1%2FCream%20Lemon%20-%20Star%20Trap%20%28Disk%20B%29.d88" size="414128"/>
		<plot>The game faithfully follows the part 10 [I]Start Trap[/I] of anime series Cream Lemon with some insignificant for the plot additional scenes.</plot>
		<boxart1>https://s2.vndb.org/cv/41/11941.jpg</boxart1>
		<snapshot1>https://s2.vndb.org/sf/87/121787.jpg</snapshot1>
	</game>
	<game name="Crimson">
		<description>Crimson</description>
		<rom name="sharp-x-1/Sharp_X1.zip/Sharp_X1%2FCrimson%20%28Program%20disk%29.d88" size="348848"/>
		<rom name="sharp-x-1/Sharp_X1.zip/Sharp_X1%2FCrimson%20%28Scenario%20disk%29.d88" size="348848"/>
		<rom name="sharp-x-1/Sharp_X1.zip/Sharp_X1%2FCrimson%20%28User%20disk%29.d88" size="348848"/>
		<plot>[I]Crimson[/I] is a medieval-themed role-playing game similar to Dragon Quest. The player controls a lone character, a young man whose father sent him on a mission to defeat the evil monster Crimson before passing away. Exploration is done in an overhead fashion, and is divided into world map and hostile areas, which are usually maze-like and contain one or more dungeons each. In towns the hero can buy weapons, armor, and items, as well as rest in inns.[CR]Enemies appear randomly, and the battles are turn-based. The player character can either attack, defend, or use an item. Combat is viewed from a first-person perspective. Unlike [I]Dragon Quest[/I], there are no random encounters on the world map. Exploration is non-linear, i.e. the player has access to many areas of the map from the beginning of the game.</plot>
		<boxart1>http://www.mobygames.com/images/covers/l/545909-crimson-msx-front-cover.jpg</boxart1>
		<groups>Crimson series</groups>
	</game>
	<game name="Cruise Chaser Blassty">
		<description>Cruise Chaser Blassty</description>
		<rom name="sharp-x-1/Sharp_X1.zip/Sharp_X1%2FCruise%20Chaser%20Blassty%20%28Disk%20A%29.d88" size="413296"/>
		<rom name="sharp-x-1/Sharp_X1.zip/Sharp_X1%2FCruise%20Chaser%20Blassty%20%28Disk%20B%29.d88" size="413296"/>
		<plot>In the future, humans have finally reached the surfaces of the other planets in the solar system. Eventually, a group called the Commune, based on a gigantic space station named Ondina, began to dominate the expansion of human colonies. A rebel group from Mars called the Inverse is trying to overthrow the Commune, using for that purpose the Cruise Chasers, space fighters that can transform into giant robots called with the help of a system known as Blassty.[CR][I]Cruise Chaser Blassty[/I] is a sci-fi role-playing game. The player controls an unnamed mercenary from Earth who eventually can choose to join either the Commune or the Inverse. The player navigates the protagonist in a mecha through pseudo-3D dungeon-like areas, fighting other robots in turn-based combat and gaining credits and experience. Missions can be received in populated areas, and the player-controlled robot can be customized.</plot>
		<boxart1>http://www.mobygames.com/images/covers/l/543029-cruise-chaser-blassty-pc-88-front-cover.png</boxart1>
		<genre>Driving</genre>
	</game>
	<game name="Daisenryaku X1">
		<description>Daisenryaku X1</description>
		<rom name="sharp-x-1/Sharp_X1.zip/Sharp_X1%2FDaisenryaku%20X1%20%28Disk%20A%29.d88" size="348848"/>
		<plot>[I]Super Daisenryaku[/I] is one of the many titles in SystemSoft's long-running war strategy series. The game mechanics are based on Daisenryaku II, but many of the included maps are unique to this release, including several based on Phantasy Star in Sega's console version. There is no campaign mode, and any of the included maps can be played. Some maps are for two players, some for four, and any map can be played with any combination of human and computer players. The computer versions also feature an editor.[CR]The game is played on a large map made up of hexagonal spaces, each of which consists of one of the included terrain types. Each player controls a number of units (bought with money), which each take up one space on the grid. The unit types are for the most part based on real-life military equipment from around the time the game was released, what is available to the player depends on the chosen faction. The choices range from single nations, such as China or the USA (the CD port by Microcabin in particular adds a lot of smaller ones, like Sweden and Libya), to alliances and blocs, for example NATO, which uses a mixture of equipment of it's members. [CR]Different units have different strengths and weaknesses, which affect their performance in combat and their general role on the battlefield. The cheap infantry units for example are not very strong and mobile, but may capture facilities and cities, unlike battle tanks. Terrain also affects the outcome of battles. The goal of each game is to capture the other players' capitals.</plot>
		<boxart1>http://www.mobygames.com/images/covers/l/549365-super-daisenryaku-genesis-front-cover.jpg</boxart1>
		<genre>Strategy</genre>
		<groups>Daisenryaku series</groups>
	</game>
	<game name="Daiva Story 3 Trial of Nirvana">
		<description>Daiva Story 3 Trial of Nirvana</description>
		<rom name="sharp-x-1/Sharp_X1.zip/Sharp_X1%2FDaiva%20Story%203%20-%20Trial%20of%20Nirvana%20%28Disk%201%29.d88" size="348848"/>
		<rom name="sharp-x-1/Sharp_X1.zip/Sharp_X1%2FDaiva%20Story%203%20-%20Trial%20of%20Nirvana%20%28Disk%202%29.d88" size="348848"/>
		<videoid>KMoa88dnMSk</videoid>
		<plot>Daiva Story 3: Trial of Nirvana is a Strategy game, developed and published by T and E Soft, which was released in Japan in 1987.</plot>
		<boxart1>https://gamefaqs.gamespot.com/a/box/4/7/7/154477_front.jpg</boxart1>
	</game>
	<game name="Dezeni Land">
		<description>Dezeni Land</description>
		<rom name="sharp-x-1/Sharp_X1.zip/Sharp_X1%2FDezeni%20Land.d88" size="284752"/>
		<plot>[I]Dezeni Land[/I] is a text adventure with graphics. The game's nameless protagonist must visit six attractions parodying well-known areas of Tokyo Disneyland of the early 1980's, find the treasures within and escape. The title itself is a pun involving Disney and a Japanese expression referring showing off one's wealth. The gameplay largely follows the standards of interactive fiction, including simple verb-noun combinations as well as directions (forward, back, left, and right) for navigation. The areas are accessed in a linear fashion; items needed to advance to the next attraction can only be founded in an earlier explored location.</plot>
		<boxart1>http://www.mobygames.com/images/covers/l/545913-dezeni-land-pc-6001-front-cover.png</boxart1>
		<groups>Dezeni series</groups>
	</game>
	<game name="Dezeni World">
		<description>Dezeni World</description>
		<rom name="sharp-x-1/Sharp_X1.zip/Sharp_X1%2FDezeni%20World.d88" size="271824"/>
		<plot>[I]Dezeni World[/I] is a sequel to Dezeni Land. Like its predecessor, it is set in a theme park, this time with a broader range of parodies. Featuring a warning "For Crazy People Only" on the cover, the game casts the player into the role of one Dezeni-Man, a rather unremarkably-looking character who nevertheless must defeat the nefarious supercomputer HAL3. On his way he encounters various eccentric people, including popular comic book characters such as Superman, a robot bearing a strong resemblance to C-3PO from Star Wars, etc. [CR]Gameplay-wise, it is very similar to the previous title. The player moves from screen to screen with key abbreviations representing the four directions, and interacts with the environment by typing combinations of verbs and nouns. The game is fairly simple and develops in a comparatively linear fashion, with only a few items needed to access the next area, and puzzles mostly involving talking to people or using the right item at the right place.</plot>
		<groups>Dezeni series</groups>
		<boxart1>https://www.giantbomb.com/a/uploads/scale_tiny/5/59247/1173580-dezeni_world_pc88.jpg</boxart1>
	</game>
	<game name="Diable de Laplace">
		<description>Diable de Laplace</description>
		<rom name="sharp-x-1/Sharp_X1.zip/Sharp_X1%2FDiable%20de%20Laplace%20%28Laplace%20no%20Ma%29%20%28Disk%201%29.d88" size="421040"/>
		<rom name="sharp-x-1/Sharp_X1.zip/Sharp_X1%2FDiable%20de%20Laplace%20%28Laplace%20no%20Ma%29%20%28Disk%202%29.d88" size="415840"/>
		<rom name="sharp-x-1/Sharp_X1.zip/Sharp_X1%2FDiable%20de%20Laplace%20%28Laplace%20no%20Ma%29%20%28Disk%203%20-%20User%20disk%29.d88" size="416688"/>
		<plot>The town Newcam, Massachusetts, 1924. On the outskirts of the town stands the Weathertop mansion. It was just an ordinary place until the last owner, Benedict Weathertop, started practicing black magic. He killed his parents and populated the mansion with all kinds of undead. Since then, nobody dared to approach the mansion. But a short while ago, two boys were found dead near this horrible place. Apparently, the boys had tried to enter the mansion. Another evidence pointed out that a girl followed them - but her body hasn't been found yet, and there is a slight hope she might be alive. This is where you, the hero of the game, decide to investigate the mystery, and to venture into the mansion...</plot>
		<boxart1>https://images.launchbox-app.com/62f96047-0c45-4c3d-8dc5-9c6738c8549d.jpg</boxart1>
		<snapshot1>https://images.launchbox-app.com/f0680577-7788-42e0-85f2-596d2d97e786.png</snapshot1>
	</game>
	<game name="Diablo">
		<description>Diablo</description>
		<rom name="sharp-x-1/Sharp_X1.zip/Sharp_X1%2FDiablo.d88" size="348848"/>
		<plot>[I]Diablo[/I] is a puzzle game with similarities to sliding block puzzles. Each level is composed of a number of tiles and every one has a part of a pipe (straight or angular) on it - except one which is just a black hole. In one tile a red ball starts rolling and all tiles it rolls through become blank. [CR]The goal of each level is to let the ball roll through all pipe parts without meeting the hole or a blank tile. [CR]To ensure this, the player can move the parts while using the hole as buffer. So, as example, if the player clicks on a tile which is a few tiles away from the hole, all tiles between the clicked tile and the hole are moved by one towards the hole. Then the hole is at the place where the player clicked on. At the start of a puzzle, rolling out of the level boundaries is also deadly, but after a certain amount of tiles are cleared the ball comes out at the opposite side of the playfield.</plot>
		<snapshot1>https://www.mobygames.com/images/shots/l/564250-diablo-sharp-x1-screenshot-title-screen.png</snapshot1>
		<genre>Puzzle</genre>
		<groups>Genre: Sliding block / tile puzzle</groups>
		<videoid>Rzp2nXzVikU</videoid>
	</game>
	<game name="Digital Devil Story Megami Tensei">
		<description>Digital Devil Story Megami Tensei</description>
		<rom name="sharp-x-1/Sharp_X1.zip/Sharp_X1%2FDigital%20Devil%20Story%20-%20Megami%20Tensei%20%28Disk%20A%29.d88" size="414992"/>
		<rom name="sharp-x-1/Sharp_X1.zip/Sharp_X1%2FDigital%20Devil%20Story%20-%20Megami%20Tensei%20%28Disk%20B%29.d88" size="415840"/>
		<plot>You are Akineki Nakashima, a 17-year-old Japanese student and computer freak. You developed a program that allows you to communicate with demons via your computer and to summon them. To test your new program, you summon the Norse god Loki. Unfortunately, the newly summoned god kidnaps Yumiko, a girl who studies together with Nakashima. Japan becomes infested with demons, and now it's up to you to traverse the mazes of the demon realm and to rescue Yumiko.[CR]This version of [I]Megami Tensei[/I] has little to do with the Famicom (NES) version (and with [I]Megaten[/I] RPGs in general) gameplay-wise. It is an action game with RPG elements, in which you must fight your way through a series of mazes infested with demons, whom you must defeat in real time combat. You find many items and become stronger as the game progresses, but the emphasis of the game is not on character development but on action-oriented combat and exploration of the dungeons.</plot>
		<boxart1>https://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/0/0a/Digital_Devil_Story_Megami_Tensei.png</boxart1>
		<genre>RPG</genre>
		<groups>Megami Tensei / Megaten universe</groups>
	</game>
	<game name="Dione">
		<description>Dione</description>
		<rom name="sharp-x-1/Sharp_X1.zip/Sharp_X1%2FDione%20%28Disk%201%29.d88" size="348848"/>
		<rom name="sharp-x-1/Sharp_X1.zip/Sharp_X1%2FDione%20%28Disk%202%29.d88" size="348848"/>
		<plo>Dione is a turn-based sci-fi strategy game where the player controls the mobile base "Dione" that can carry aircraft, amphibious craft and mechas. The player can choose to let the computer pick the units for him or choose by their own. The units all have different costs though.</plo>
		<genre>Strategy</genre>
		<boxart1>https://images.launchbox-app.com/f9c050c5-162c-4d32-b57e-f671601df040.jpg</boxart1>
		<snapshot1>https://i.ytimg.com/vi/gEYD3PCVDdk/hqdefault.jpg</snapshot1>
		<videoid>gEYD3PCVDdk</videoid>
	</game>
	<game name="Dome">
		<description>Dome</description>
		<rom name="sharp-x-1/Sharp_X1.zip/Sharp_X1%2FDome%20%28Disk%201%29.d88" size="415840"/>
		<rom name="sharp-x-1/Sharp_X1.zip/Sharp_X1%2FDome%20%28Disk%202%29.d88" size="415840"/>
		<rom name="sharp-x-1/Sharp_X1.zip/Sharp_X1%2FDome%20%28Disk%203%29.d88" size="415840"/>
		<rom name="sharp-x-1/Sharp_X1.zip/Sharp_X1%2FDome%20%28Disk%204%29.d88" size="415840"/>
		<rom name="sharp-x-1/Sharp_X1.zip/Sharp_X1%2FDome%20%28Disk%205%29.d88" size="415840"/>
		<plot>DOME is based on Shizuko Natsukis novel of the same name. The original work as well as the games plot focus on the construction of a nuclear shelter called "The Dome", capable of protecting humans from an impending atomic war. The player takes the role of an employee in an advertisement company, whose job is to raise peoples awareness of the shelters importance, and donate money to the project.[CR]The game opens System Sacoms Novel Ware series, demonstrating its concept. Though its basic gameplay is that of a puzzle-less Japanese-style adventure, the game has extended dialogue and text descriptions that either do not contain any interaction or occasionally prompt the player to make a choice. Despite this visual novel-like feature, the game still retains considerable portions of interactivity, with verb-object commands, reviewing information concerning recent events and characters in the game, and even the possibility to take and examine objects. The game's graphics consist of digitized photos of people and objects, and are rather sparse.</plot>
		<snapshot1>https://i.ytimg.com/vi/8dEWVGEN5Ys/hqdefault.jpg</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>https://www.mobygames.com/images/shots/l/1076949-dome-pc-98-screenshot-graphics-consist-of-digitized-photos.png</snapshot2>
	</game>
	<game name="Don Juan">
		<description>Don Juan</description>
		<rom name="sharp-x-1/Sharp_X1.zip/Sharp_X1%2FDon%20Juan.d88" size="348848"/>
		<plot>Don Juan is a strategy game, set in a turn-based theme.</plot>
		<boxart1>https://images.launchbox-app.com/9c4318c3-a5a2-462d-aa5b-df32791cf892.jpg</boxart1>
		<snapshot1>https://images.launchbox-app.com/d5aa83e2-afa4-4d82-9d59-1a0112f7b4f0.png</snapshot1>
	</game>
	<game name="Dragon Slayer">
		<description>Dragon Slayer</description>
		<rom name="sharp-x-1/Sharp_X1.zip/Sharp_X1%2FDragon%20Slayer%20%28LOGiN-ban%29.d88" size="415840"/>
		<plot>[I]Dragon Slayer[/I] is commonly considered one of the progenitors of the action RPG genre. The premise is similar to Roguelikes: the player takes control of a knight who must fight his way through large overhead maze-like dungeons. Unlike roguelikes, the combat in the game is fully action-oriented: the player must approach the monster and "bump" into it in order to inflict damage, at the same time trying to avoid its blows. Combat takes place on the same screen as the exploration; monsters will also sometimes pursue the knight if he attempts to escape. Also contrary to roguelikes, none of the locations or items in the game is randomized.[CR]The player can collect power stones and coins during the journey; the power stones increase the hero's strength, while the coins increase his hit points (health). Defeating enemies also yields experience points, which determine the amount of maximum HP the hero is able to receive. The knight is able to cast magic spells, though they are mostly used outside of combat, for example breaking walls, teleporting, or creating a map of the area.</plot>
		<boxart1>http://www.mobygames.com/images/covers/l/408559-dragon-slayer-game-boy-front-cover.jpg</boxart1>
		<genre>RPG</genre>
		<groups>Dragon Slayer universe</groups>
	</game>
	<game name="Eggy">
		<description>Eggy</description>
		<rom name="sharp-x-1/Sharp_X1.zip/Sharp_X1%2FEggy%20%28demo%29.d88" size="348848"/>
		<plot>EGGY is an action game that won the Excellence Award at Bothtec's first programming contest and was inspired by Choplifter. In this game players take the role of Ena, a robot which has to collect goods that are dropped from the sky with parachutes.[CR]The robot has a limited fuel supply that decreases with time and every time the robot takes damage from the enemies. The fuel supply can be replenished by saving humans that were transformed into killer cyborgs.[CR]35 years after its initial release, the game was ported to IOS.</plot>
		<releasedate>07/06/1985</releasedate>
		<year>1985</year>
		<studio>Bothtec</studio>
		<boxart1>http://www.mobygames.com/images/covers/l/538009-eggy-iphone-front-cover.jpg</boxart1>
		<snapshot1>https://images.launchbox-app.com/40f422dd-1a7e-4895-9452-eb43be09d78c.PNG</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>https://images.launchbox-app.com/0ee62dfc-cfc5-42f1-b0ac-e54453b0d0a8.PNG</snapshot2>
		<genre>Action,Driving,Shooter</genre>
	</game>
	<game name="Elthlead">
		<description>Elthlead</description>
		<rom name="sharp-x-1/Sharp_X1.zip/Sharp_X1%2FElthlead.d88" size="348848"/>
		<plot>On the continent of Gaia, Boser, the King of the East, is raising an army of dark creatures. King Sieghart of Elthlead, champion of light, must muster his own troops in order to stop him from ruling the world.[CR]After booting up the game, you are given the option to load a previous save. If you don't, you are immediately faced with the world map, where Boser starts moving his troops from his castle to any adjacent province. Once he is done, it is your turn. You first get to buy a unit or two that you can place on your castle. You then move any unit you want to a neighbouring province. After that comes the magic phase, where you can cast spells to give your troops an advantage, like summoning a mighty white dragon that will participate in one fight before disappearing, or hinder those of your AI opponent, even forcibly moving one of his units to another province. The number of magic points available to you depends on the number of ruins you control. Of course, Böser can also cast spells of his own.[CR]This turn order goes on until one of the lords has managed to take the other's castle.</plot>
		<snapshot1>https://www.mobygames.com/images/shots/l/1038461-elthlead-sharp-x1-screenshot-title-screen.png</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>https://www.mobygames.com/images/shots/l/1038465-elthlead-sharp-x1-screenshot-sending-my-initial-set-of-troops.png</snapshot2>
	</game>
	<game name="Euphory">
		<description>Euphory</description>
		<rom name="sharp-x-1/Sharp_X1.zip/Sharp_X1%2FEuphory%20%28X1turbo%2C%20hi-res%29.d88" size="382448"/>
		<plot>[I]Euphory[/I] is a medieval-themed action game with light role-playing elements. The protagonists of the game are the brother and sister Rafael and Falram. Their mother became gravely ill, and they have to travel to her homeland in order to find the rare medicine. The game can be played controlling either of the characters, or in a two-player mode where both are controlled cooperatively.[CR]The game world consists of towns, where the player characters can buy weapons and equipment, and hostile areas. There is no experience points system, but defeated enemies award the player gold and healing items. Some areas also require the protagonist to jump and swim.</plot>
		<boxart1>https://www.giantbomb.com/a/uploads/scale_small/13/139866/2726061-4084750899-29013.jpg</boxart1>
		<snapshot1>https://i.ytimg.com/vi/Tkk8qndrvrQ/maxresdefault.jpg</snapshot1>
		<videoid>Tkk8qndrvrQ</videoid>
	</game>
	<game name="Fantasian">
		<description>Fantasian</description>
		<rom name="sharp-x-1/Sharp_X1.zip/Sharp_X1%2FFantasian.d88" size="347984"/>
		<rom name="sharp-x-1/Sharp_X1.zip/Sharp_X1%2FFantasian%20%28User%20disk%29.d88" size="380048"/>
		<plot>The magical country of Luizard has been recently terrorized by the minions of the demon king Billades. The king of the country recruits a party of brave warriors, asking them to do the impossible: venture into the depths of Billades' lair, defeat the demon king, and release the Elven Seed that would restore the country to its glory.[CR][I]Fantasian[/I] is a role-playing game that mostly relies on the Wizardry template. The player creates characters (up to five in the active party), choosing between traditional fantasy races (elf, half-orc, etc.) and classes. The latter are divided into four disciplines (thief, fighter, monk, and magician), each containing two classes, of which the less powerful one may evolve into a stronger form by meeting certain conditions during gameplay.[CR]The player then takes these characters to explore an abstract maze, fighting randomly appearing enemies. Combat takes place on a top-down screen and is similar in concept to that of Ultima games.</plot>
		<boxart1>https://gamefaqs.gamespot.com/a/box/4/4/4/621444_front.jpg</boxart1>
		<snapshot1>https://www.mobygames.com/images/shots/l/525023-fantasian-pc-88-screenshot-title-screen.png</snapshot1>
		<groups>Fantasian series</groups>
	</game>
	<game name="Final Zone">
		<description>Final Zone</description>
		<rom name="sharp-x-1/Sharp_X1.zip/Sharp_X1%2FFinal%20Zone%20%28Disk%20A%29.d88" size="420192"/>
		<rom name="sharp-x-1/Sharp_X1.zip/Sharp_X1%2FFinal%20Zone%20%28Disk%20B%29.d88" size="436640"/>
		<plot>Final Zone Wolf is a overhead game where your in command of a small military commando team, and you move down the streets shooting. The goal of the game seems to be to stop some kind of missile attack. At the beginning of the game you need to select two members of your team, out of five options available. Statistics of these members are presented during the opening credits of the game.[CR]The gameplay is sluggish, and your team members take a fixed formation which is actually a hindrance to get past obstacles as they will not get out of formation and prevent you from moving forward. The enemies seem to be being spawned at random, as such it is critical to keep moving forward as fast as possible avoiding them as much as you can.</plot>
		<boxart1>http://www.mobygames.com/images/covers/l/327710-final-zone-wolf-msx-front-cover.jpg</boxart1>
		<groups>Final Zone series</groups>
	</game>
	<game name="Front Line">
		<description>Front Line</description>
		<rom name="sharp-x-1/Sharp_X1.zip/Sharp_X1%2FFront%20Line.d88" size="305872"/>
		<plot>[I]Front Line[/I] is a vertically scrolling action game. Your mission is to infiltrate enemy territory and destroy their fortress. To reach the fortress, you will have to make your way through varied and dangerous terrain. Jungles, deserts, brush, and rocks all slow your progress, plus each area has numerous enemy fighters and tanks trying to stop you. To help get past these obstacles, you are armed with a machine gun and grenades; at some points in the game you may even come across an abandoned tank which you can control to increase your odds of survival. When you reach the end of the level and successfully destroy the fortress, the game will repeat at a higher level of difficulty. Gameplay is for one or two players, and four different skill levels are available.</plot>
		<boxart1>http://www.mobygames.com/images/covers/l/545902-front-line-pc-6001-front-cover.png</boxart1>
		<genre>Shooter</genre>
		<groups>Arcade Archives series</groups>
	</game>
	<game name="Gaia no Kiba">
		<description>Gaia no Kiba</description>
		<rom name="sharp-x-1/Sharp_X1.zip/Sharp_X1%2FGaia%20no%20Kiba%20%28hi-res%29%20%28Disk%20A%29.d88" size="422160"/>
		<rom name="sharp-x-1/Sharp_X1.zip/Sharp_X1%2FGaia%20no%20Kiba%20%28hi-res%29%20%28Disk%20B%29.d88" size="422160"/>
		<plot>Gaia no Kiba is a doujin Japanese-style adventure game.  The player picks from various commands, such as look, talk and even kiss, to progress in the game's story.</plot>
		<snapshot1>https://i.ytimg.com/vi/HVPNke6sASo/maxresdefault.jpg</snapshot1>
		<videoid>HVPNke6sASo</videoid>
	</game>
	<game name="Gaiflame">
		<description>Gaiflame</description>
		<rom name="sharp-x-1/Sharp_X1.zip/Sharp_X1%2FGaiflame%20%28Disk%20A%29.d88" size="348848"/>
		<rom name="sharp-x-1/Sharp_X1.zip/Sharp_X1%2FGaiflame%20%28Disk%20B%29.d88" size="348848"/>
		<plot>[I]Gaiflame[/I] (or [I]Gai Flame[/I]) is sci-fi, turn-based strategy, with giant, heavy armed humanoid robots. The player controls an army of giant robots and try to destroy enemies.[CR]The game starts with macro-level view of the world (player can move units from battlefield to battlefield - each battlefield has 6 slot for troops), and battle mode - player commands several robots on a "fake-hexes" based map (squares with 6 neighbors) and tries to defeat the enemy's army. Fight between robots are animated on special, small screen - like in Advance War.</plot>
		<boxart1>http://www.mobygames.com/images/covers/l/457122-gaiflame-turbografx-16-front-cover.jpg</boxart1>
		<genre>Driving</genre>
	</game>
	<game name="Gall Force">
		<description>Gall Force</description>
		<rom name="sharp-x-1/Sharp_X1.zip/Sharp_X1%2FGall%20Force%20%28Disk%201%29.d88" size="414992"/>
		<rom name="sharp-x-1/Sharp_X1.zip/Sharp_X1%2FGall%20Force%20%28Disk%202%29.d88" size="416688"/>
		<rom name="sharp-x-1/Sharp_X1.zip/Sharp_X1%2FGall%20Force%20%28Disk%203%29.d88" size="414608"/>
		<plot>This is based on an anime movie whit the same name, after there came both more movies and shows, some more games. Gal Force first started as a 3D comic.</plot>
		<boxart1>https://images.launchbox-app.com/e406d840-6ff0-459c-bf1b-d23e3c2bcf87.jpg</boxart1>
		<snapshot1>https://s.uvlist.net/l/y2010/09/74862.jpg</snapshot1>
	</game>
	<game name="Gambler Jikochuushinha">
		<description>Gambler Jikochuushinha</description>
		<rom name="sharp-x-1/Sharp_X1.zip/Sharp_X1%2FGambler%20Jikochuushinha.d88" size="348848"/>
		<plot>Gambler Jiko Chuushinha is a mahjong game based upon a manga license of the same name that was developed by Game Arts X and published in Japan by Asmik towards the end of 1988. Being based on a manga, it has a large cast of characters from the comics that the player can choose to compete against. Beyond the manga license, it is very much still a mahjong game, focusing mostly on playing the tile-based board game, though using a difficult variation on the usual rules of the game, known as Reach Mahjong.</plot>
		<boxart1>https://www.retroplace.com/pics/gamegear/packshots/98149--gambler-jiko-chuushinha.png</boxart1>
		<snapshot1>https://cdn.wikimg.net/en/strategywiki/images/5/53/Gambler_Jiko_Chuushinha_FC_title.png</snapshot1>
	</game>
	<game name="Gambler Jikochuushinha 2">
		<description>Gambler Jikochuushinha 2</description>
		<rom name="sharp-x-1/Sharp_X1.zip/Sharp_X1%2FGambler%20Jikochuushinha%202.d88" size="348848"/>
		<plot>Gambler Jiko Chuushinha 2: Dorapon Quest is a 1994 mahjong game and one based on Katayama Masayuki's manga Gambler Jiko Chuushinha. Dorapon Quest frames its various mahjong games as battles in an RPG</plot>
		<boxart1>https://www.giantbomb.com/a/uploads/scale_small/2/23093/2737752-2112722361-31257.jpg</boxart1>
	</game>
	<game name="Gandhara">
		<description>Gandhara</description>
		<rom name="sharp-x-1/Sharp_X1.zip/Sharp_X1%2FGandhara%20%28Disk%20A%29.d88" size="348848"/>
		<rom name="sharp-x-1/Sharp_X1.zip/Sharp_X1%2FGandhara%20%28Disk%20B%29.d88" size="348848"/>
		<plot>One of Enixs works that were unreleased outside of Japan, Gandhara is an action RPG with rather simple gameplay mechanics. The player navigates the hero through hostile top-down areas, fighting constantly respawning enemies with sword or magical spells. Rations must be bought in order to keep the hero alive. Defeated enemies grant the protagonist experience points; once a certain amount of those is accumulated, the hero levels up and grows stronger</plot>
		<boxart1>https://www.retroplace.com/pics/pc88/packshots/7085--gandhara-buddha-no-seisen.png</boxart1>
		<snapshot1>https://i.ytimg.com/vi/621Cr-Z_YuY/maxresdefault.jpg</snapshot1>
		<genre>RPG</genre>
		<videoid>621Cr-Z_YuY</videoid>
	</game>
	<game name="Golques">
		<description>Golques</description>
		<rom name="sharp-x-1/Sharp_X1.zip/Sharp_X1%2FGolques%20%28Disk%201%29.d88" size="348848"/>
		<rom name="sharp-x-1/Sharp_X1.zip/Sharp_X1%2FGolques%20%28Disk%202%29.d88" size="348848"/>
		<plot>Adventure game created by DataWest in 1987</plot>
		<boxart1>https://www.giantbomb.com/a/uploads/scale_small/5/59247/1156071-golques.png</boxart1>
		<snapshot1>https://www.giantbomb.com/a/uploads/square_medium/5/59247/1156104-title.png</snapshot1>
	</game>
	<game name="Gradius">
		<description>Gradius</description>
		<rom name="sharp-x-1/Sharp_X1.zip/Sharp_X1%2FGradius%20%28OPM%20hack%29.d88" size="348848"/>
		<rom name="sharp-x-1/Sharp_X1.zip/Sharp_X1%2FGradius.d88" size="348848"/>
		<plot>The people of Gradius are in trouble. The ameoboid Bacterions have launched an all out attack against the planet, and it's up to you to fly into battle and save them. Along the way you'll be able to power up your ship with hyper speed, force fields, lasers, missiles, double beam cannons and more to help you battle. [CR][I]Gradius[/I] is a side-scrolling shooter. Shooting certain enemies will leave a power up pod behind which can be collected to add more power to your ship. Each level features a wide variety of enemies trying to stop you, with a large boss at the end. Gameplay is for one player or two players alternating.</plot>
		<boxart1>http://www.mobygames.com/images/covers/l/79855-gradius-msx-front-cover.jpg</boxart1>
		<genre>Driving,Shoot Em Up</genre>
		<groups>Arcade Archives series,Game Center CX challenge games,Genre: Scrolling shoot 'em up,Gradius series,Video games turned into board / card games</groups>
	</game>
	<game name="Gruppe">
		<description>Gruppe</description>
		<rom name="sharp-x-1/Sharp_X1.zip/Sharp_X1%2FGruppe.d88" size="348848"/>
		<snapshot1>https://i.ytimg.com/vi/q3Hra1WSeXQ/maxresdefault.jpg</snapshot1>
		<genre>Platform</genre>
		<videoid>q3Hra1WSeXQ</videoid>
	</game>
	<game name="Gyrodine">
		<description>Gyrodine</description>
		<rom name="sharp-x-1/Sharp_X1.zip/Sharp_X1%2FGyrodine.d88" size="349648"/>
		<plot>[I]Gyrodine[/I] is a basic vertical scrolling shooter. You pilot a helicopter and have to shoot as many enemies as you can. You will fight against enemy helicopters, bunkers, tanks and fighter jets above different terrains like water, desserts and military camps. There is no background story and there are no levels.</plot>
		<boxart1>http://www.mobygames.com/images/covers/l/471481-gyrodine-nes-front-cover.jpg</boxart1>
		<genre>Driving,Shoot Em Up</genre>
	</game>
	<game name="Haja no Fuuin">
		<description>Haja no Fuuin</description>
		<rom name="sharp-x-1/Sharp_X1.zip/Sharp_X1%2FHaja%20no%20Fuuin%20%28User%20disk%29.d88" size="348848"/>
		<plot>Fate calls thee to bar evils way! The Dark Lord Terarin has removed the Golden Seal from the Pandora Passage to let monstrous creatures roam the Five Lands. An ancient prophecy foretells of four brave warriors destined to battle Terarin and return the Seal to its rightful place. Art thou the one fated to lead the Miracle Warriors? Dost noble blood flow in thy veins? Join now in a fantasy role-playing quest across time to a world of swords and sorcery.</plot>
		<boxart1>https://gamefaqs.gamespot.com/a/box/3/4/3/88343_front.jpg</boxart1>
		<snapshot1>https://s.uvlist.net/l/y2014/02/124329.jpg</snapshot1>
	</game>
	<game name="Hang On">
		<description>Hang On</description>
		<rom name="sharp-x-1/Sharp_X1.zip/Sharp_X1%2FHang-On.d88" size="348848"/>
		<plot>A motorcycle game very much inspired by Sega's [I]Hang-On[/I], right down to the title. In a chase-view 3D mode, you ride a motor cycle at speeds up to 250 km/h, making sure not to slide out of the corners or collide with fellow competitors. The game runs over several courses, beginning with a series of test courses. A course editor is also included.</plot>
		<genre>Driving,Motorcycle</genre>
		<boxart1>https://www.mobygames.com/images/covers/l/45372-hang-on-sega-master-system-front-cover.jpg</boxart1>
		<snapshot1>https://www.mobygames.com/images/shots/s/723439-hang-on-sharp-x1-screenshot-title-screen.jpg</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>https://www.mobygames.com/images/shots/l/723415-hang-on-sharp-x1-screenshot-slid-off-the-track.png</snapshot2>
		<videoid>3Jxn_ur2Jmk</videoid>
	</game>
	<game name="Harajuku After Dark">
		<description>Harajuku After Dark</description>
		<rom name="sharp-x-1/Sharp_X1.zip/Sharp_X1%2FHarajuku%20After%20Dark%20%28Disk%201%29.d88" size="348848"/>
		<rom name="sharp-x-1/Sharp_X1.zip/Sharp_X1%2FHarajuku%20After%20Dark%20%28Disk%202%29.d88" size="348848"/>
		<rom name="sharp-x-1/Sharp_X1.zip/Sharp_X1%2FHarajuku%20After%20Dark%20%28Disk%203%29.d88" size="348848"/>
		<rom name="sharp-x-1/Sharp_X1.zip/Sharp_X1%2FHarajuku%20After%20Dark%20%28User%20disk%29.d88" size="348848"/>
		<plot>An adventure game developed by Kogado Studio for Japanese computers</plot>
		<boxart1>https://www.giantbomb.com/a/uploads/scale_small/9/97089/3200265-126000601.jpg</boxart1>
		<snapshot1>https://www.giantbomb.com/a/uploads/square_medium/9/97089/3200274-eksk1010_3.jpg</snapshot1>
	</game>
	<game name="Hayato">
		<description>Hayato</description>
		<rom name="sharp-x-1/Sharp_X1.zip/Sharp_X1%2FHayato%20%28Disk%20A%29.d88" size="348848"/>
		<rom name="sharp-x-1/Sharp_X1.zip/Sharp_X1%2FHayato%20%28Disk%20B%29.d88" size="348848"/>
		<plot>Hayato is an RPG where the player, as Hayato, travels from the future to the past to save Leaza, his girlfriend...and later on the world.  The game has 4 different chapters.</plot>
		<genre>RPG</genre>
		<snapshot1>https://i.ytimg.com/vi/HMGdOxfHes0/maxresdefault.jpg</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>https://jrkrpg.pl/media/game_imgs/pc_88/hayato_j/wal.png</snapshot2>
		<videoid>HMGdOxfHes0</videoid>
	</game>
	<game name="Herzog">
		<description>Herzog</description>
		<rom name="sharp-x-1/Sharp_X1.zip/Sharp_X1%2FHerzog.d88" size="415840"/>
		<plot>The first, obscure instalment in the Herzog series is also one of the early precursors of the modern-day RTS (real-time strategy game) genre that was popularised by Dune 2. Unlike the common RTS game, the playfield is a long vertical stretch instead of the well-known map stretching in both X and Y axes. [CR]Another now unique trait is that there is little emphasis on building up a base to produce units which are then directly commanded into action. Instead, a base is already located at each end of the path, and the player is given control over a hovering battlemech. New units are bought using funds accumulated during play. These units, ranging from single foot soldiers to tanks and AA batteries, advance from the home base towards the enemy base. The player may pick up a single unit (or five soldiers) and move them closer to the enemy base in order to speed up the attack. A radar on the top of the screen gives an overlook of the battlefield.[CR]The opposing faction has got the same resources, and the enemy battlemech will make raids towards your base, forcing you into mech-on-mech battle. This element turns Herzog into a rather unique blend of strategy and shoot'em up.[CR]The game takes place in a balkanised region, where the last war has given birth to a new state, called Ruth. A military coup d'état in the now-independent state leads to a new war, which the peace-loving Mercies must win.</plot>
		<snapshot1>https://www.mobygames.com/images/shots/l/508993-herzog-pc-88-screenshot-title-screen.gif</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>https://www.mobygames.com/images/shots/l/508995-herzog-pc-88-screenshot-this-is-your-base.gif</snapshot2>
		<genre>Driving,Shooter</genre>
		<groups>Herzog series</groups>
		<videoid>PzWJ7GDA7do</videoid>
	</game>
	<game name="Hot Dog">
		<description>Hot Dog</description>
		<rom name="sharp-x-1/Sharp_X1.zip/Sharp_X1%2FHot%20Dog.d88" size="348848"/>
		<plot>Hot Dog is a 3D skiing simulator, undoubtedly a daunting task for early-80s computers. For what it is, the graphics are reasonably nice. Gameplay is choppy, but that improves as you go faster.</plot>
		<snapshot1>https://i.ytimg.com/vi/Kx8CFJT1Fd8/hqdefault.jpg</snapshot1>
		<genre>Skiing</genre>
		<videoid>quzgTLG_9UE</videoid>
	</game>
	<game name="Hover Attack">
		<description>Hover Attack</description>
		<rom name="sharp-x-1/Sharp_X1.zip/Sharp_X1%2FHover%20Attack%20%28Kai%20hack%29%20%28bgm%20version%29.d88" size="348848"/>
		<plot>[I]Hover Attack[/I] is a multi-directional shooter in which the player has to transfer a mobile base through a hostile level towards the exit. The base itself can fire an unlimited amount of short-ranged missiles, but has limited manoeuvrability. In order to be able to withstand the constant enemy onslaught, the player must release the pilot from time to time, and have him explore the location on his own, leaving the base behind. [CR]The pilot is equipped with a jetpack and can therefore jump much higher than the base, and generally move faster and more efficiently. He can fire independently of his movement, and his missiles are long-ranged. Three different shot angles are bound to three keys on the keyboard: up, straight, and down. The pilot, however, can fire only a limited amount of missiles, and will also run out of fuel for his jetpack. He will have to return to the base to recharge his ammo and to refuel.</plot>
		<snapshot1>https://www.mobygames.com/images/shots/l/519635-hover-attack-pc-88-screenshot-title-screen.png</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>https://www.mobygames.com/images/shots/l/519640-hover-attack-pc-88-screenshot-the-base-is-under-attack.png</snapshot2>
		<genre>Action</genre>
	</game>
	<game name="Hurry Fox Yuki no Maou hen">
		<description>Hurry Fox Yuki no Maou hen</description>
		<rom name="sharp-x-1/Sharp_X1.zip/Sharp_X1%2FHurry%20Fox%20-%20Yuki%20no%20Maou-hen%20%28Disk%20A%29.d88" size="348848"/>
		<rom name="sharp-x-1/Sharp_X1.zip/Sharp_X1%2FHurry%20Fox%20-%20Yuki%20no%20Maou-hen%20%28Disk%20B%29.d88" size="348848"/>
		<plot>Winter has come and now the land is filled with snow.  Mama fox has been kidnapped by an evil demon. It is up to the little fox and the human girl Mari to save mama fox.</plot>
		<boxart1>https://www.giantbomb.com/a/uploads/square_medium/9/97089/3156944-0ecac5060bfd3a13fb4c7c7378705e36.jpg</boxart1>
		<snapshot1>https://www.giantbomb.com/a/uploads/square_medium/9/97089/2174456-2.png</snapshot1>
		<videoid>beInliGJQ4k</videoid>
	</game>
	<game name="Hurry Fox">
		<description>Hurry Fox</description>
		<rom name="sharp-x-1/Sharp_X1.zip/Sharp_X1%2FHurry%20Fox.d88" size="348848"/>
		<plot>A mother fox and her child live together in peace in Romulus Forest. One day, though, the child contracts the rare Romulus disease and the distraught mother wracks her brain to figure out how to save them. She remembers hearing the story that it can be cured by traveling to a certain shrine and eating the abura-age (deep-fried tofu) that can be found there, so she sets out on a journey to save her child.[CR]This interactive fiction game with artwork is inspired by classics like Mystery House. Players guide the mother fox through her journey using a text parser via commands typed in katakana, with responses provided to the player in simple katakana text. Events are also illustrated through simple static 2D illustrations which take up a large portion of the screen.</plot>
		<snapshot1>https://www.mobygames.com/images/shots/l/1044685-hurry-fox-sharp-x1-screenshot-intro-a-long-time-ago-there.png</snapshot1>
		<genre>Adventure</genre>
	</game>
	<game name="Hydlide 2">
		<description>Hydlide 2</description>
		<rom name="sharp-x-1/Sharp_X1.zip/Sharp_X1%2FHydlide%20II.d88" size="348848"/>
		<rom name="sharp-x-1/Sharp_X1.zip/Sharp_X1%2FHydlide%20II%20%28Data%20disk%29.d88" size="348848"/>
		<plot>A long time ago, evil descended upon the peaceful people of Hydlide. Old legends tell of a lone brave hero who saved Hydlide from the imminent threat of doom - the evil demon Varalys. Since then, the people of Hydlide have lived through centuries of peace. But one dark evening, a huge column of fire exploded out of the depths of Hydlide. The next morning, strange doors began to appear from nowhere. Many who were curious entered these doors, but were never seen again. From that day on, unusual events and disasters began to take place. Huge cracks opened in the ground, scarring the beautiful lands, floods wiped out entire villages. And then the monsters came. The Hydlide council feared that the same evil in the legends was back again. A wise old oracle predicted the second coming of evil. He also spoke of a young man who could save Hydlide from the grave danger. This young man is you...[CR][I]Super Hydlide[/I] (originally entitled [I]Hydlide 3: The Space Memories[/I]) is the third entry in the Hydlide series, continuing its action RPG legacy. Character creation allows the player to choose one of the four character classes: Warrior, Thief, Priest, and Monk. In combat, the protagonist uses melee or long-ranged weapons or casts magic spells. Unlike the previous games in the series, the player is required to press the attack button during melee combat, instead of simply "bumping" into the enemies. There is an internal clock in the game, which makes it necessary for the protagonist to sleep periodically and regain his strength. The main character also has to eat from time to time, otherwise his hit points will gradually decrease. The morality system from the previous game returns: killing friendly creatures will reduce the player's morality level, which will eventually have an effect on one of the game's most decisive battles.</plot>
		<boxart1>http://www.mobygames.com/images/covers/l/79857-super-hydlide-msx-front-cover.jpg</boxart1>
		<groups>Hydlide series</groups>
	</game>
	<game name="Hydlide 3">
		<description>Hydlide 3</description>
		<rom name="sharp-x-1/Sharp_X1.zip/Sharp_X1%2FHydlide%203%20%28Disk%20A%29.d88" size="392368"/>
		<rom name="sharp-x-1/Sharp_X1.zip/Sharp_X1%2FHydlide%203%20%28Disk%20B%29.d88" size="392368"/>
		<rom name="sharp-x-1/Sharp_X1.zip/Sharp_X1%2FHydlide%203%20%28User%20disk%29.d88" size="392368"/>
		<plot>The [I]Special Version[/I] of Hydlide 3: The Space Memories offers improved graphics, new areas and characters, some arranged music tracks, plus character portraits during dialogues.</plot>
		<snapshot1>https://www.mobygames.com/images/shots/l/985449-hydlide-3-special-version-sharp-x68000-screenshot-title-screen.png</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>https://www.mobygames.com/images/shots/l/985450-hydlide-3-special-version-sharp-x68000-screenshot-intro.png</snapshot2>
		<groups>Hydlide series</groups>
		<videoid>vNzZU50Kmzs</videoid>
	</game>
	<game name="Irowanioedo">
		<description>Irowanioedo</description>
		<rom name="sharp-x-1/Sharp_X1.zip/Sharp_X1%2FIrowanioedo%20%28Disk%20A%29.d88" size="413296"/>
		<rom name="sharp-x-1/Sharp_X1.zip/Sharp_X1%2FIrowanioedo%20%28Disk%20B%29.d88" size="416688"/>
		<plot>Main character is a normal school student. He sleeps during the history class and gives the wrong answer on the question. In the night he slips into the school to correct the mistake, but the answer is already input in the computer. When he messes with the computer he arrives to 1169 year, the events before the Genpei War. If he can't fix the answer, he will change history instead to fit the answer!</plot>
		<boxart1>https://s2.vndb.org/cv/50/11250.jpg</boxart1>
	</game>
	<game name="Ishin no Arashi">
		<description>Ishin no Arashi</description>
		<rom name="sharp-x-1/Sharp_X1.zip/Sharp_X1%2FIshin%20no%20Arashi%20%28Disk%20A%29.d88" size="380864"/>
		<rom name="sharp-x-1/Sharp_X1.zip/Sharp_X1%2FIshin%20no%20Arashi%20%28Disk%20B%29.d88" size="380848"/>
		<rom name="sharp-x-1/Sharp_X1.zip/Sharp_X1%2FIshin%20no%20Arashi%20%28Disk%20C%29.d88" size="380848"/>
		<plot>[I]Ishin no Arashi[/I] is set during Bakumatsu period (around 1850 until the Meiji Restoration of 1867), the final stretch of the Japanese Edo period, which was a turbulent time, a time of great struggle between the supporters of the feudal shoguns, the rulers of the country, and the adherents of the Emperor, which eventually won and carried through the Meiji Restoration, turning Japan into a modern, powerful state. In [I]Ishin no Arashi[/I] the player can choose one of the three major battles of Bakumastu period, and decide which leader will eventually propel Japan towards the Meiji era.[CR]This strategy game is somewhat similar to the better-known Romance of the Three Kingdoms series and other historical simulation games by the same company, but also differs from them by having much less complex diplomacy options and focusing the gameplay on navigation and individual encounters. Before beginning, the player chooses a general and customizes his parameters (stamina, attack power, charisma, knowledge). The player then controls the general with soldiers of his choice, navigating him on grids representing towns and countryside of Japan in turn-based fashion. The grids can be occupied by shops, schools (to train the general), friendly and hostile characters and groups. Battles, as well as negotiations and diplomatic procedures, are carried out automatically, and their outcome depends on the characters' statistics.</plot>
		<boxart1>http://www.mobygames.com/images/covers/l/466067-ishin-no-arashi-windows-front-cover.jpg</boxart1>
	</game>
	<game name="Jesus">
		<description>Jesus</description>
		<rom name="sharp-x-1/Sharp_X1.zip/Sharp_X1%2FJesus%20%28Disk%201%29.d88" size="367616"/>
		<rom name="sharp-x-1/Sharp_X1.zip/Sharp_X1%2FJesus%20%28Disk%202%29.d88" size="348848"/>
		<rom name="sharp-x-1/Sharp_X1.zip/Sharp_X1%2FJesus%20%28Disk%203%29.d88" size="348848"/>
		<plot>It is the year 2061, and Halley's Comet is coming towards Earth. A crew has been gathered from eight different countries to man a pair of space probes sent to investigate the comet. The two probes, Comet and Corona, are to launch from Space Lab Jesus and collect a sample of the gases in the tail of the comet, and determine if life on Earth was brought by this comet as some have speculated. However, communication has been lost with the probe Comet; what could be going on?[CR]Jesus is a Japanese-style adventure game. Each area is shown with an image, and you have the option of several commands. The player takes the role of Japanese pilot Hayao Musou, a member of the crew, and attempts to solve the mystery surrounding Comet and Halley's Comet.</plot>
		<studio>Enix Corporation</studio>
		<nplayers>1</nplayers>
		<snapshot1>https://images.launchbox-app.com/b7b765ef-7f9a-45cf-a95c-57493c3ca078.png</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>https://images.launchbox-app.com/9f97deea-2d5f-49eb-bfa0-550918fd83ac.png</snapshot2>
		<snapshot3>https://images.launchbox-app.com/c786ba4c-833a-45c7-bac3-aa5924ef05c1.png</snapshot3>
		<genre>Adventure</genre>
	</game>
	<game name="Jotuun">
		<description>Jotuun</description>
		<rom name="sharp-x-1/Sharp_X1.zip/Sharp_X1%2FJotuun%20%28Disk%20A%29.d88" size="348848"/>
		<rom name="sharp-x-1/Sharp_X1.zip/Sharp_X1%2FJotuun%20%28Disk%20B%29.d88" size="348848"/>
		<plot>Jotunn is a Role-Playing game, developed and published by XAIN, which was released in Japan in 1988.</plot>
		<genre>RPG</genre>
		<videoid>BBn0VwGt0nA</videoid>
		<snapshot1>https://i.ytimg.com/vi/BBn0VwGt0nA/maxresdefault.jpg</snapshot1>
		<boxart1>https://gamefaqs.gamespot.com/a/box/7/1/7/595717_front.jpg</boxart1>
	</game>
	<game name="Kage no Densetsu">
		<description>Kage no Densetsu</description>
		<rom name="sharp-x-1/Sharp_X1.zip/Sharp_X1%2FKage%20no%20Densetsu.d88" size="348848"/>
		<boxart1>https://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/1/13/Kageflyer.jpg</boxart1>
		<snapshot1>https://www.mobygames.com/images/shots/l/131958-the-legend-of-kage-msx-screenshot-title-screen.png</snapshot1>
		<plot>You play Kage, a skillful ninja in search of rescuing Princess Kiri from the hands of the warlord Yoshi. Armed only with a sword and star knives, you must fight your way through countless henchmen and the occasional boss to complete your task. Levels include the forest, moat, inside and outside of the castle. These levels repeat as the seasons change. The gameplay is side scrolling. Kage's moves include the ability jump extremely high in the air, grab and climb trees, block and attack with his sword, and throw shuriken. The game can be challenging at times though because the player dies in one hit. 2-players are supported, but must take turns.</plot>
		<genre>Beat Em Up</genre>
	</game>
	<game name="Kaleidoscope">
		<description>Kaleidoscope</description>
		<rom name="sharp-x-1/Sharp_X1.zip/Sharp_X1%2FKaleidoscope%20%28Loader%20disk%29.d88" size="392368"/>
		<rom name="sharp-x-1/Sharp_X1.zip/Sharp_X1%2FKaleidoscope%20%28Scenario%20%231%20-%207-man%20Kounen%20no%20Houshi-tachi%29.d88" size="392368"/>
		<boxart1>https://www.giantbomb.com/a/uploads/scale_small/5/59247/1672995-kaleidoscopefm7.jpg</boxart1>
		<plot>Kaleidoscope: 7 Man Kounen no Houshi-tachi is an RPG developed by Hot-B in 1986</plot>
	</game>
	<game name="Kings Knight">
		<description>Kings Knight</description>
		<rom name="sharp-x-1/Sharp_X1.zip/Sharp_X1%2FKing%27s%20Knight%20%28Disk%201%29.d88" size="348848"/>
		<rom name="sharp-x-1/Sharp_X1.zip/Sharp_X1%2FKing%27s%20Knight%20%28Disk%202%29.d88" size="348848"/>
		<plot> _King's Knight_ is a fantasy-themed top-down shooter where four heroes have to unite to defeat a dragon and rescue a princess in despair. It was one of the first games published by Square Soft (now one-half of Square Enix). _King's Knight_ is a variation on Konami's Knightmare which sold extremely well.[CR]The first four stages involve you powering up your characters as far as they can go, picking up shields (to increase defense), boots (to increase speed), swords (to increase attack power), and spell icons (which will be required to be held by everyone for the final storm on the castle), defeating monsters along the way. The power-ups are hidden underneath mountains, rocks, and houses. Nearly everything can be shot at and destroyed. The heroes are, in order:[CR]Ray Jack, the Knight, who possesses strong attacking power;[CR]Kaliva, the Wizard, who is good with magic and jumping;[CR]Barusa, the Monster, who has a strong defense; and[CR]Toby, the Thief, who can move swiftly.[CR]It is necessary to keep all four heroes alive for the fifth and final stage, because there are certain points that the group cannot get past if one of the party members has died.</plot>
		<boxart1>http://www.mobygames.com/images/covers/l/109483-king-s-knight-nes-front-cover.jpg</boxart1>
		<genre>RPG,Shooter</genre>
		<groups>Knightmare variants</groups>
	</game>
	<game name="Kiss of Murder">
		<description>Kiss of Murder</description>
		<rom name="sharp-x-1/Sharp_X1.zip/Sharp_X1%2FKiss%20of%20Murder.d88" size="415840"/>
		<plot>[I]Kiss of Murder[/I] is an adventure game set in a parallel world to Manhattan Requiem. While it features the same graphics and set of characters as that title, it has a completely different story. In Manhattan a large blue sapphire has been stolen and a young woman named Sarah Shields who worked at a jewelry store has been murdered. Insurance investigator Judd Gregory has contacted the private detective J.B. Harold and asked him for help with the case. Gameplay involves going to various locations in New York, talking to people, interrogating suspects, finding clues and gathering evidence.[CR]Early releases of the game (PC-88, X68000, FM-7, X1 and PC-98) are add-ons and require Manhattan Requiem to play. Later iterations became stand-alone.</plot>
		<boxart1>http://www.mobygames.com/images/covers/l/481472-kiss-of-murder-nintendo-switch-front-cover.jpg</boxart1>
		<genre>Extra Content</genre>
		<groups>J.B. Harold series,Protagonist: P.I. (Private Investigator)</groups>
	</game>
	<game name="Konya mo Asa made Powerful Mahjong">
		<description>Konya mo Asa made Powerful Mahjong</description>
		<rom name="sharp-x-1/Sharp_X1.zip/Sharp_X1%2FKonya%20mo%20Asa%20made%20Powerful%20Mahjong%20%28Disk%20A%29.d88" size="348848"/>
		<rom name="sharp-x-1/Sharp_X1.zip/Sharp_X1%2FKonya%20mo%20Asa%20made%20Powerful%20Mahjong%20%28Disk%20B%29.d88" size="348848"/>
	</game>
	<game name="Ku Gyoku Den">
		<description>Ku Gyoku Den</description>
		<rom name="sharp-x-1/Sharp_X1.zip/Sharp_X1%2FKugyokuden%20%28Disk%201%20-%20Joukan%29.d88" size="348848"/>
		<rom name="sharp-x-1/Sharp_X1.zip/Sharp_X1%2FKugyokuden%20%28Disk%202%20-%20Gekan%29.d88" size="348576"/>
		<plot>Ku Gyoku Den a.k.a. Legendly Nine Gems, is an overhead multi-directional shooter with RPG elements, which was developed and published by Tecno Soft in 1987 for the MSX2, Sharp X1, FM-77 and PC-8801. The MSX version allows two-player support, which is not available for the other ones. Contrary to what is outlined in the original instruction manual, the game was never ported to the PC-98, Sharp X68000 and MZ-2500.</plot>
		<boxart1>https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/japanese-pc-games/images/2/2c/Ku_Gyoku_Den_%28Boxart%29.png</boxart1>
		<snapshot1>https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/japanese-pc-games/images/4/49/Ku_Gyoku_Den_%28Screen_01%29.png</snapshot1>
		<genre>Action,RPG</genre>
		<videoid>FfwOY_Iir4s</videoid>
	</game>
	<game name="Labyrinth">
		<description>Labyrinth</description>
		<rom name="sharp-x-1/Sharp_X1.zip/Sharp_X1%2FLabyrinth%20%28Disk%20A%29.d88" size="348848"/>
		<rom name="sharp-x-1/Sharp_X1.zip/Sharp_X1%2FLabyrinth%20%28Disk%20B%29.d88" size="348848"/>
		<plot>The player starts this game off controlling the actions of an ordinary citizen on their way to a movie theater. In the south cinema, the player chats with two teenagers about the actual movie at which point a hush descends upon the room and the in-game film begins...where the player learns that they have been chosen to be the thrall of Jareth the Goblin King, who must be overcome to finish the game. A clock ticks down 13 meager hours to complete this task, lest the player's character end up lost in the labyrinth forever.</plot>
		<studio>Pack-In Video</studio>
		<nplayers>1</nplayers>
		<snapshot1>https://images.launchbox-app.com/288d80ac-af95-4d4b-a709-9eb0367e2ea8.jpg</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>https://images.launchbox-app.com/e6a51185-8f1c-4323-9730-60783b632722.jpg</snapshot2>
		<genre>Adventure</genre>
	</game>
	<game name="Lagrange L 2 Part 1">
		<description>Lagrange L 2 Part 1</description>
		<rom name="sharp-x-1/Sharp_X1.zip/Sharp_X1%2FLagrange%20L-2%20Part%201.d88" size="349120"/>
		<plot>The Federal Army research vessel Gaul 201 was destroyed by a mysterious missile attack in Area L-2 on its way back from Mars to Earth. Lyle, the only correspondent who was saved, wore a normal suit and succeeded in escaping. However, the air in the suit was limited. With no hope of being saved, Lyle was swept away in space. However, something came into view in front of Lyle.  Only a little oxygen is sent from the air hose...[CR]Lagrange L-2 is a text adventure with graphics. The player types in commands (in katakana) to tell Lyle what to do. Movement, however, is done with the arrow keys.</plot>
		<genre>Adventure</genre>
		<boxart1>https://images.launchbox-app.com/774f1c41-d289-4e7c-b36d-d9c358265c9d.jpg</boxart1>
		<snapshot1>https://i.ytimg.com/vi/Gz7zHIzG6Kk/hqdefault.jpg</snapshot1>
		<videoid>Gz7zHIzG6Kk</videoid>
	</game>
	<game name="Lagrange L 2 Part 2: D Side">
		<description>Lagrange L 2 Part 2: D Side</description>
		<rom name="sharp-x-1/Sharp_X1.zip/Sharp_X1%2FD-Side%20-%20Lagrange%20L-2%20Part%202.d88" size="392368"/>
		<plot>Game starts in the shuttle right after the end of Lagrange L2. The breath is relieved now but the first challenge is already there - the need to escape from missiles of approaching Zera enemy.</plot>
		<boxart1>https://s2.vndb.org/cv/20/11920.jpg</boxart1>
		<genre>Adventure</genre>
		<videoid>8d6ni4flvOw</videoid>
	</game>
	<game name="Laptick">
		<description>Laptick</description>
		<rom name="sharp-x-1/Sharp_X1.zip/Sharp_X1%2FLaptick.d88" size="349136"/>
		<plot>[I]Laptick[/I] is an action puzzle game. You play as Vickey and the goal is to step on all the question mark tiles in a stage while avoiding enemies. If you step on a blinking question mark tile you'll get either a points bonus, movement speed or jumping ability increase, 1up or turn into Super Vickey. In this form the player becomes invulnerable for a short time and can take out enemies, although they will respawn in a while. The game features 100 stages.</plot>
		<boxart1>https://gamefaqs.gamespot.com/a/box/7/4/4/363744_front.jpg</boxart1>
		<snapshot1>https://i.ytimg.com/vi/Rab6Zw93JvA/hqdefault.jpg</snapshot1>
		<genre>Action</genre>
		<videoid>zhOuf5Nd8Vg</videoid>
	</game>
	<game name="Las Vegas">
		<description>Las Vegas</description>
		<rom name="sharp-x-1/Sharp_X1.zip/Sharp_X1%2FLas%20Vegas%20%28Disk%201%29.d88" size="348848"/>
		<rom name="sharp-x-1/Sharp_X1.zip/Sharp_X1%2FLas%20Vegas%20%28Disk%202%29.d88" size="348848"/>
		<rom name="sharp-x-1/Sharp_X1.zip/Sharp_X1%2FLas%20Vegas%20%28Disk%203%29.d88" size="348848"/>
		<plot>[I]Las Vegas[/I] is a Japan-exclusive graphical variant of Softporn Adventure, and hence can be seen as an earlier version of Leisure Suit Larry, which was released a few months later. The gameplay is, by and large, identical to the original text-only version, with the exception of a few adjustments made to the monetary system and a few commands handled slightly differently. Like before, the player types text commands consisting of combinations of verbs and objects. The game recognizes both Japanese and English inputs.[CR]The major difference is the inclusion of graphics. Each location is represented by an anime-style image. With the exception of flashing lights and alike, there is no animation, though a few actions lead to separate zoomed-in scenes appearing on top of the main image. The game's visuals are sexually more explicit than [I]Leisure Suit Larry[/I]. For example, the hooker is partially nude, and there are also visible obscene drawings on the bathroom walls.</plot>
		<boxart1>http://www.mobygames.com/images/covers/l/533506-las-vegas-pc-98-front-cover.png</boxart1>
		<groups>Leisure Suit Larry series</groups>
	</game>
	<game name="Last Armageddon">
		<description>Last Armageddon</description>
		<rom name="sharp-x-1/Sharp_X1.zip/Sharp_X1%2FLast%20Armageddon%20%28Disk%20A%29.d88" size="425392"/>
		<rom name="sharp-x-1/Sharp_X1.zip/Sharp_X1%2FLast%20Armageddon%20%28Disk%20B%29.d88" size="425392"/>
		<rom name="sharp-x-1/Sharp_X1.zip/Sharp_X1%2FLast%20Armageddon%20%28Disk%20C%29.d88" size="425392"/>
		<rom name="sharp-x-1/Sharp_X1.zip/Sharp_X1%2FLast%20Armageddon%20%28Disk%20D%29.d88" size="425392"/>
		<rom name="sharp-x-1/Sharp_X1.zip/Sharp_X1%2FLast%20Armageddon%20%28Disk%20E%29.d88" size="425392"/>
		<rom name="sharp-x-1/Sharp_X1.zip/Sharp_X1%2FLast%20Armageddon%20%28Disk%20F%29.d88" size="425392"/>
		<rom name="sharp-x-1/Sharp_X1.zip/Sharp_X1%2FLast%20Armageddon%20%28Disk%20G%29.d88" size="425392"/>
		<plot>The Earth has changed. We don't know yet what happened to humanity, but we know it was eradicated. The new Earth is called Makai - the Demon World. Generations of mythological creatures dwell upon the planet, from which the human being has mysteriously disappeared. One day, a wave of energy hits the Earth. The leaders of the demons realize that a robotic alien race from outer space threatens their existence. The explosion turns earth into a wasteland. Many demons die in the chaos of destruction. It is now up to the remaining demons to fend off the alien invaders, to bring back peace to the demonic race, and perhaps to find out more about the tragic fate of humanity.[CR][I]Last Armageddon[/I] can be described as a post-apocalyptic Final Fantasy. Instead of a party of four light warriors who fight hordes of demons, you have a party of four demons who fight... no, not hordes of light warriors, but mysterious robot-like aliens. The turn-based fights are viewed from third-person perspective and are very similar to the battles of early NES Final Fantasies. The demons can attack, cast offensive and defensive magic, and use special skills. Once they reach a high enough level, they morph into stronger forms with more powerful skills.[CR]Dungeon areas are done in pseudo-3D and are viewed from first-person perspective. The player is able to set and use multiple parties of demons, some of which have unique skills. For example, a flying demon can take the party quicker to some locations, avoiding random encounters.</plot>
		<boxart1>http://www.mobygames.com/images/covers/l/259267-last-armageddon-msx-front-cover.jpg</boxart1>
		<groups>Last Armageddon series,Protagonist: Demon</groups>
	</game>
	<game name="Last War">
		<description>Last War</description>
		<rom name="sharp-x-1/Sharp_X1.zip/Sharp_X1%2FLast%20War.d88" size="349888"/>
		<plot>Starting with the last war in 2013 when food runs out or the main character, Fondi, dies.</plot>
		<snapshot1>VbCjHT6.png</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>4kNLoRe.png</snapshot2>
		<genre>Strategy</genre>
		<videoid>oAL0ZEpZnw4</videoid>
	</game>
	<game name="Legend">
		<description>Legend</description>
		<rom name="sharp-x-1/Sharp_X1.zip/Sharp_X1%2FLegend%20%28Disk%20A%29.d88" size="348848"/>
		<rom name="sharp-x-1/Sharp_X1.zip/Sharp_X1%2FLegend%20%28Disk%20B%29.d88" size="348848"/>
		<plot>Once upon a time, a fairy accidentally dropped a magic crystal that governs good and evil. Unfortunately, it lands in the hands of the demon Great Maou Gaudius (also known as "Gaudius the Great Satan"), who uses the power of the crystal to kill most of the population and further devastate their cities; even going so far as to turn the plants and soil into poison. It is up to the lord Aros di Gran to save the land, by collecting four "Fire Crystals" and challenging Gaudius for control over the more powerful crystal.[CR]Action takes place from a side view, action platforming perspective. Your character's primary means of attack are projectiles, with some additional items to be picked up over the course of your adventure serving to expand your character's arsenal. Flip-screen transitions cause enemies to respawn immediately upon exiting / re-entering certain screens, making some of the vertical platforming particularly challenging. While the game does boast above-average sprite work for the platform, the stilted animation and movements can often render the game difficult to visually parse.</plot>
		<snapshot1>https://i.ytimg.com/vi/nGghGobDupk/maxresdefault.jpg</snapshot1>
		<genre>Platform</genre>
		<videoid>nGghGobDupk</videoid>
	</game>
	<game name="Lizard">
		<description>Lizard</description>
		<rom name="sharp-x-1/Sharp_X1.zip/Sharp_X1%2FLizard.d88" size="346032"/>
		<plot>[I]Lizard[/I] is a simple first-person dungeon crawler in Wizardry style, though with a single player character rather than a party. The goal is to explore a maze-like pseudo-3D tower and locate a magical book that would help the hero to rescue a captured princess. The player can choose between the classes of Fighter, Thief, and Merchant when creating the protagonist. Town menu is wholly text-based. Battles are random and allow the player to either attack or use items.</plot>
		<boxart1>http://www.mobygames.com/images/covers/l/533362-lizard-pc-6001-front-cover.png</boxart1>
		<genre>RPG</genre>
	</game>
	<game name="Lode Runner">
		<description>Lode Runner</description>
		<rom name="sharp-x-1/Sharp_X1.zip/Sharp_X1%2FLode%20Runner.d88" size="405664"/>
		<plot>The Bungeling Empire has stolen a huge cache of gold from its rightful owners, and your mission is to infiltrate its treasury and recapture it. This entails progressing through 150 screens of platforms, ladders and ropes.[CR]The Empire has sent robotic guards down to protect the gold, and contact with any of these will cost you a life. Your method of escaping them is to press fire to dig a hole in their line of movement, thus causing them to fall in briefly, allowing you to move across the gap safely. Once all the gold has been collected, a ladder allowing you to move onto the next screen is added. Completing these screens often requires forward planning and precision.[CR]This was one of the earliest games to include a level editor, allowing the creation of new level designs with no programming skill.</plot>
		<boxart1>http://www.mobygames.com/images/covers/l/1534-lode-runner-pc-booter-front-cover.jpg</boxart1>
		<genre>Platform</genre>
		<groups>Lode Runner games,Panic variants,Video games turned into board / card games</groups>
	</game>
	<game name="Love Chaser">
		<description>Love Chaser</description>
		<rom name="sharp-x-1/Sharp_X1.zip/Sharp_X1%2FLove%20Chaser%20%28Disk%201%29.d88" size="348848"/>
		<rom name="sharp-x-1/Sharp_X1.zip/Sharp_X1%2FLove%20Chaser%20%28Disk%202%29.d88" size="348848"/>
		<boxart1>https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/alicesoft/images/7/75/Love_Chaser_box.jpg</boxart1>
		<plot>Love Chaser is an adventure game by Champion Soft.  It uses a hybrid system with a menu for verbs and text for objects. You have an HP system and your starting HP is decided by the puzzle. 360 is apparently the smallest amount you can get away with.</plot>
	</game>
	<game name="Luna City Satsujin Jiken">
		<description>Luna City Satsujin Jiken</description>
		<rom name="sharp-x-1/Sharp_X1.zip/Sharp_X1%2FLuna%20City%20Satsujin%20Jiken.d88" size="396336"/>
		<plot>You play as detective in charge of investigation of Luna city mayor murder in 2216 AD. You have both male and female body with a single personality and can switch them on will.</plot>
		<boxart1>https://s2.vndb.org/cv/62/11962.jpg</boxart1>
	</game>
	<game name="Lupin Sansei Cagliostro no Shiro">
		<description>Lupin Sansei Cagliostro no Shiro</description>
		<rom name="sharp-x-1/Sharp_X1.zip/Sharp_X1%2FLupin%20Sansei%20-%20Cagliostro%20no%20Shiro%20%28Disk%20A%29.d88" size="348848"/>
		<rom name="sharp-x-1/Sharp_X1.zip/Sharp_X1%2FLupin%20Sansei%20-%20Cagliostro%20no%20Shiro%20%28Disk%20B%29.d88" size="348576"/>
		<plot>Lupin Sansei Cagliostro no Shiro is a video game adaption of Hayao Miyazaki's Lupin III anime film of the same name.</plot>
		<boxart1>https://www.giantbomb.com/a/uploads/original/5/59247/1663524-_____________.jpg</boxart1>
	</game>
	<game name="Luxsor">
		<description>Luxsor</description>
		<rom name="sharp-x-1/Sharp_X1.zip/Sharp_X1%2FLuxsor%20%28Disk%201%29.d88" size="415840"/>
		<rom name="sharp-x-1/Sharp_X1.zip/Sharp_X1%2FLuxsor%20%28Disk%202%29.d88" size="415840"/>
		<plot>Luxsor Night Over Egypt is an top down shooter, developed and published by Telenet, which was released in Japan in 1987.</plot>
		<boxart1>https://images.launchbox-app.com/8dc69df0-ad0f-4468-81ed-399d255590dd.jpg</boxart1>
		<snapshot1>https://i.ytimg.com/vi/LJPtHEkuMbA/hqdefault.jpg</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>https://i.ytimg.com/vi/KBJDM5_VOcE/maxresdefault.jpg</snapshot2>
		<genre>Shoot Em Up</genre>
		<videoid>KBJDM5_VOcE</videoid>
	</game>
	<game name="MULE">
		<description>MULE</description>
		<rom name="sharp-x-1/Sharp_X1.zip/Sharp_X1%2FM.U.L.E..d88" size="348576"/>
		<plot>[I]M.U.L.E.[/I] is about four hopeful explorers trying to make a fortune on a virgin planet. This is done by producing various goods (Food, Energy, Smithore, Crystite). Each of these goods have their uses: if you don't have enough food, you will have less time during your turn. If you don't have enough energy, your output will be lower. If enough smithore isn't produced, there will be a shortage of M.U.L.E.s. Crystite is the big earner that can make or break your game.[CR]You start the game by selecting your race. Some are easier to play, some harder. There are three levels of difficulty, in the easiest the game only lasts 6 turns, but the real game is 12 turns. Crystite is not available at the easiest level.[CR]Each turn starts with land claim. Each player gets to choose a spot of land for themselves from the map. If two players choose the same spot, the player with less money wins. The map consists of different landscape. River is best for producing food, plains for energy, mountains for smithore. Crystite is hidden and must be first found by taking a land sample to the town.[CR]After the land claim each player takes turns in cultivating their land and do other tasks. They can buy M.U.L.E.s to start production on their land, sabotage other players by buying M.U.L.E.s and letting them loose, try to catch the Wumpus for cash and try to find crystite veins. The time to do these things depends on if the player has enough food. Finally the player goes to the casino and wins a small amount of money, depending on how much time was left.[CR]After the cultivation phase is the production phase where each land produces an amount of goods depending on a number of factors such as if the player has enough energy in storage, what type of land is used, and some random events such as sunspots that increase energy output. Also, if the same player has plots producing the same goods next to each other, they gain a bonus. Three plots of same production type anywhere on the map by the same player also gives a bonus.[CR]Third phase is the auction. Here the players buy and sell their goods on open market. Players negotiate the price by moving up and down on the screen. The shop also has prices that depend on how abundant or scarce the goods is. So if there is a shortage of food, the price goes up and vice versa. This allows for various tactics, especially if one player manages to monopolize food, energy or smithore production. If there is no food, others don't have time to change their production types, if there is a shortage of energy, their land won't produce and if there are no M.U.L.E.s they can't change production type on their plot. Hoarding goods also has a drawback in the form of surplus where each turn a percentage of goods is wasted. [CR]There are a number of random events in the game. Some affect one player, usually the one winning gets small penalties and the losing player(s) get small rewards. The big events that happen randomly are: [CR]- M.U.L.E. goes crazy - the M.U.L.E. on one of the plots runs away losing production for that round plus the money to replace it. [CR]- Planetquake - production of smithore and crystite is much lower.[CR]- Fire in store - all stock in the shops are destroyed (which means prices will skyrocket, but if you needed to buy something, you are at the mercy of other players).[CR]- Pirate attack - pirates steal all crystite from stores and players (in the easiest level they steal smithore). Nasty if you happened to have a lot of them waiting for better prices.[CR]- Acid rain storm - affects the plot under the storm and below it by boosting food production and decreasing energy production.[CR]- Sunspot activity - increases energy production.[CR]- Pest attack - eats all food on one plot.[CR]- Meteor strike - destroys the M.U.L.E on the plot it strikes but creates a very rich crystite plot.[CR]The game always has four players, with 1-4 human players possible and the rest played by the AI. Because the players only need two buttons at most (up/down in auction) in auction, it's easy to play with four people around the computer. </plot>
		<boxart1>http://www.mobygames.com/images/covers/l/22824-m-u-l-e-commodore-64-front-cover.jpg</boxart1>
		<genre>Simulation</genre>
		<groups>M.U.L.E. games</groups>
	</game>
	<game name="Madeleine">
		<description>Madeleine</description>
		<rom name="sharp-x-1/Sharp_X1.zip/Sharp_X1%2FMadeleine%20%28Disk%201%29.d88" size="410944"/>
		<rom name="sharp-x-1/Sharp_X1.zip/Sharp_X1%2FMadeleine%20%28Disk%202%29.d88" size="416688"/>
		<boxart1>https://64.media.tumblr.com/12363d58b65e58d7e4c148cdb5949975/tumblr_p32ug96oCv1ulp8mfo4_500.jpg</boxart1>
		<plot>Madeleine: Naki Oujo no Tame no Pavane was a visual novel made by Thinking Rabbit in 1987</plot>
	</game>
	<game name="Mahjong Kyou Jidai Special">
		<description>Mahjong Kyou Jidai Special</description>
		<rom name="sharp-x-1/Sharp_X1.zip/Sharp_X1%2FMahjong%20Kyou%20Jidai%20Special%20%28Disk%20A%29.d88" size="414144"/>
		<rom name="sharp-x-1/Sharp_X1.zip/Sharp_X1%2FMahjong%20Kyou%20Jidai%20Special%20%28Disk%20B%29.d88" size="416688"/>
		<plot>Mahjong Kyou Jidai Special is a Miscellaneous game, developed and published by Micronet, which was released in Japan in 1988.</plot>
		<boxart1>https://gamefaqs.gamespot.com/a/box/1/6/2/217162_front.jpg</boxart1>
	</game>
	<game name="Maison Ikkoku Omoide no Photograph">
		<description>Maison Ikkoku Omoide no Photograph</description>
		<rom name="sharp-x-1/Sharp_X1.zip/Sharp_X1%2FMaison%20Ikkoku%20-%20Omoide%20no%20Photograph%20%28Disk%201%29.d88" size="378448"/>
		<rom name="sharp-x-1/Sharp_X1.zip/Sharp_X1%2FMaison%20Ikkoku%20-%20Omoide%20no%20Photograph%20%28Disk%202%29.d88" size="380848"/>
		<rom name="sharp-x-1/Sharp_X1.zip/Sharp_X1%2FMaison%20Ikkoku%20-%20Omoide%20no%20Photograph%20%28Disk%203%29.d88" size="350448"/>
		<plot>[I]Maison Ikkoku: Omoide no Photograph[/I] is a Japanese menu-based graphical adventure game based on the anime and manga series. Players control Yusaku Godai and will need to help him find a secret photograph that's been hidden away by the manager. Godai will need to bribe the inhabitants, which constantly move around the house in order to get access to Kyoko's room. But even if Godai makes it into the manager's room and tries to look at the framed photo, something will always happen which will force Godai to leave the room. Thus, after multiple attempts, Godai makes the (il)logical decision to gather photos of all the inhabitants of the boarding house to make Kyoko show him the photo. The game has the player move between locations in the boarding house and the town, constantly running out of money, and meeting all the cast from the original comic book, including Nikaido who did not appear in the anime.</plot>
		<boxart1>https://s2.vndb.org/cv/82/1482.jpg</boxart1>
		<snapshot1>https://www.mobygames.com/images/shots/l/955119-maison-ikkoku-omoide-no-photograph-turbografx-16-screenshot.png</snapshot1>
		<groups>Maison Ikkoku licensees</groups>
	</game>
	<game name="Maison Ikkoku Kanketsu hen">
		<description>Maison Ikkoku Kanketsu hen</description>
		<rom name="sharp-x-1/Sharp_X1.zip/Sharp_X1%2FMaison%20Ikkoku%20Kanketsu-hen%20%28Disk%201%29.d88" size="377936"/>
		<rom name="sharp-x-1/Sharp_X1.zip/Sharp_X1%2FMaison%20Ikkoku%20Kanketsu-hen%20%28Disk%202%29.d88" size="380848"/>
		<rom name="sharp-x-1/Sharp_X1.zip/Sharp_X1%2FMaison%20Ikkoku%20Kanketsu-hen%20%28Disk%203%29.d88" size="380848"/>
		<rom name="sharp-x-1/Sharp_X1.zip/Sharp_X1%2FMaison%20Ikkoku%20Kanketsu-hen%20%28Disk%204%29.d88" size="380848"/>
		<plot>The game is based on the manga [I]Maison Ikkoku[/I] by Rumiko Takahashi.[CR]Set in Tokyo of the 80-ies, the story can be described as a romantic tale with a touch of comedy. It centers on a boarding house which is managed by the young and lovely widow Kyoko Otonashi. The protagonist is a college student named Yusaki Godai, and his relationship with Kyoko is the main plot line. The game's story approximately corresponds to the middle volumes of the manga until the conclusion.[CR]The game is a "puzzle-less" adventure, the gameplay mostly focusing on simply depleting all the verb commands at every given screen and moving between locations. The commands include the usual "Look", "Talk", and Move" typical for Japanese adventures (no "Think" command), but also context-sensitive commands "Eat", "Drink", etc., as well as the possibility to use certain inventory items.</plot>
		<groups>Maison Ikkoku licensees</groups>
		<boxart1>https://m.media-amazon.com/images/M/MV5BNWZiZmQxNGEtN2ExNC00YTYzLThiM2ItNzU1NGM3NGUyMDdjXkEyXkFqcGdeQXVyMTA3NTQwNDU4._V1_.jpg</boxart1>
	</game>
	<game name="Majaventure Negi Mahjong">
		<description>Majaventure Negi Mahjong</description>
		<rom name="sharp-x-1/Sharp_X1.zip/Sharp_X1%2FMajaventure%20-%20Negi%20Mahjong%20%28Disk%201%29.d88" size="348848"/>
		<rom name="sharp-x-1/Sharp_X1.zip/Sharp_X1%2FMajaventure%20-%20Negi%20Mahjong%20%28Disk%202%29.d88" size="348848"/>
		<snapshot1>gej29Xr.jpg</snapshot1>
	</game>
	<game name="Makai Fukkatsu">
		<description>Makai Fukkatsu</description>
		<rom name="sharp-x-1/Sharp_X1.zip/Sharp_X1%2FMakai%20Fukkatsu%20%28Disk%20A%29.d88" size="344496"/>
		<rom name="sharp-x-1/Sharp_X1.zip/Sharp_X1%2FMakai%20Fukkatsu%20%28Disk%20B%29.d88" size="348848"/>
		<plot>Makai Fukkatsu is a text-based adventure game developed by Soft Studio Wing released only in Japan.</plot>
		<videoid>pUE-Dq9lG5c</videoid>
		<boxart1>https://www.giantbomb.com/a/uploads/scale_small/16/165036/2974847-makai.jpg</boxart1>
	</game>
	<game name="Manhattan Requiem">
		<description>Manhattan Requiem</description>
		<rom name="sharp-x-1/Sharp_X1.zip/Sharp_X1%2FManhattan%20Requiem%20%28Disk%20A%29.d88" size="415840"/>
		<rom name="sharp-x-1/Sharp_X1.zip/Sharp_X1%2FManhattan%20Requiem%20%28Disk%20B%29.d88" size="416688"/>
		<plot>A 24-year-old woman was found dead in her flat in Manhattan, New York. Her skull was crushed - it was clear that she was murdered. Further investigation showed that she was working as a pianist. The police can find no clues, so it's time for the private detective J.B. Harold to investigate the murder and to bring the killer to justice.[CR]Despite its Japanese origins, [I]Manhattan Requiem[/I] has realistic graphic design without any manga/anime influences. As an adventure game, it has Japanese influences (no inventory, no puzzles), as well as Western ones (relative freedom in navigation, detailed dialogue system, no "trigger commands" to advance the plot). The game plays similarly to a real investigation: the player has to question suspects, collect evidence, find new leads, after which new locations become accessible. It is also possible to review all the data collected during the investigation in-game, by going to a bar at any time.</plot>
		<boxart1>http://www.mobygames.com/images/covers/l/506771-manhattan-requiem-laseractive-front-cover.jpg</boxart1>
		<groups>J.B. Harold series,Protagonist: P.I. (Private Investigator)</groups>
	</game>
	<game name="Milky Way">
		<description>Milky Way</description>
		<rom name="sharp-x-1/Sharp_X1.zip/Sharp_X1%2FMilky%20Way.d88" size="348848"/>
		<boxart1>https://images.launchbox-app.com/46069482-6be9-4a93-a4ef-cc1faaaa1e2d.jpg</boxart1>
		<snapshot1>https://i.ytimg.com/vi/X3pa5jCO46Y/hqdefault.jpg</snapshot1>
		<genre>Shoot Em Up</genre>
		<videoid>X3pa5jCO46Y</videoid>
	</game>
	<game name="Mobile Suit Zeta Gundam">
		<description>Mobile Suit Zeta Gundam</description>
		<rom name="sharp-x-1/Sharp_X1.zip/Sharp_X1%2FMobile%20Suit%20Zeta%20Gundam.d88" size="348848"/>
		<genre>Shoot Em Up</genre>
		<videoid>OfWOXCnz-tg</videoid>
		<snapshot1>https://i.ytimg.com/vi/YRMgYk0Kdng/maxresdefault.jpg</snapshot1>
		<boxart1>https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/gundam/images/b/bf/Zk1_1_M.jpg</boxart1>
	</game>
	<game name="Tetris - Moscow">
		<description>Tetris - Moscow</description>
		<rom name="sharp-x-1/Sharp_X1.zip/Sharp_X1%2FMoscow.d88" size="348848"/>
		<snapshot1>https://i.ytimg.com/vi/DnRbpOupgxI/maxresdefault.jpg</snapshot1>
		<videoid>DnRbpOupgxI</videoid>
		<genre>Puzzle</genre>
	</game>
	<game name="Mr Pro Yakyuu">
		<description>Mr Pro Yakyuu</description>
		<rom name="sharp-x-1/Sharp_X1.zip/Sharp_X1%2FMr.%20Pro%20Yakyuu%20%28Senshu%20Data%20%2788%29.d88" size="348848"/>
		<plot>Mr. Pro Yakyuu is a Sports game, developed and published by XTALSOFT, which was released in Japan in 1988.</plot>
		<boxart1>https://images.launchbox-app.com/5f49143a-de53-43d7-b1f7-e50b7db31aa1.jpg</boxart1>
		<snapshot1>https://images.launchbox-app.com/a0fc915c-387c-4add-aa91-fd8adbba62ac.png</snapshot1>
	</game>
	<game name="Mugen Senshi Valis">
		<description>Mugen Senshi Valis</description>
		<rom name="sharp-x-1/Sharp_X1.zip/Sharp_X1%2FMugen%20Senshi%20Valis%20%28Disk%20A%29.d88" size="415840"/>
		<rom name="sharp-x-1/Sharp_X1.zip/Sharp_X1%2FMugen%20Senshi%20Valis%20%28Disk%20B%29.d88" size="415840"/>
		<plot>Rogles, the tyrant who wanted to gain control over the three worlds in the universe, was defeated by Yuko, an ordinary Japanese teenager who was chosen to become the heroic Valis Soldier. The dream world Vecanti fell into the hands of Emperor Megas. Driven by intense hatred to Rogles and his followers, Megas became an even more dangerous fanatic, imposing an iron rule on his realm. Yuko must now travel to the dream world and defeat the new tyrant and his minions.[CR]Like its predecessor, [I]Mugen Senshi Valis II[/I] is an action platformer. Yuko fights and jumps her way through enemies and platform structures, acquiring various power-ups during the course of the game. Various weapons and armor can be found in the stages and equipped on a separate screen. Weapons have their own unique ranged patterns and are always attached to Yuko's default sword attack. Different types of armor may increase Yuko's hit points, offense, and defense ratings. [CR]Yuko can also acquire and execute special attacks and techniques, such as for example an ability that freezes all the enemies on screen for a limited amount of time. These deplete a separate bar that can be filled by collecting colored orbs left by enemies. Two of the six stages control like side-scrolling shoot-em-ups, allowing Yuko to fly in any direction.[CR]The Sharp X68000 version features improved graphics, voice acting during the intro, reduced difficulty level (particularly for boss battles), and allows the player to save the game between the stages.</plot>
		<releasedate>01/12/1986</releasedate>
		<year>1986</year>
		<studio>Wolf Team</studio>
		<snapshot2>https://images.launchbox-app.com/1a0a9a5b-28ab-4e6b-95eb-ba5ddbc38d47.png</snapshot2>
		<clearlogo1>https://images.launchbox-app.com/3fb76520-3fe7-416c-8548-69f34bc3b7fa.png</clearlogo1>
		<genre>Action,Beat Em Up</genre>
		<groups>Gameplay feature: Time manipulation,Valis games,Valis series</groups>
	</game>
	<game name="Murder Club">
		<description>Murder Club</description>
		<rom name="sharp-x-1/Sharp_X1.zip/Sharp_X1%2FMurder%20Club%20%28Disk%20A%29.d88" size="415840"/>
		<rom name="sharp-x-1/Sharp_X1.zip/Sharp_X1%2FMurder%20Club%20%28Disk%20B%29.d88" size="416688"/>
		<plot>Murder Club is an adventure game with simulation elements. The player controls the private detective J.B. Harold, who must investigate the murder of a wealthy businessman named Bill Robbins and bring the murderer to court. The player has to do all the work a real detective would do: find clues, gather evidence, interrogate suspects, establish the motive for the crime — and in the end, make sure the case will stand up in the court.</plot>
		<studio>Riverhill Soft Inc.</studio>
		<nplayers>1</nplayers>
		<boxart1>http://www.mobygames.com/images/covers/l/535725-murder-club-pc-98-front-cover.png</boxart1>
		<boxart3>https://images.launchbox-app.com/a2cf5ae7-3371-4dca-b0b3-1a944ef20702.jpg</boxart3>
		<snapshot1>https://images.launchbox-app.com/2895453d-ab9b-4e67-93eb-e47fcf200ed2.png</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>https://images.launchbox-app.com/b4fee390-9eb2-4f6a-b50d-c193aff2eff1.png</snapshot2>
		<snapshot3>https://images.launchbox-app.com/d20ed3db-0c38-49d2-9611-df4f6e52c337.png</snapshot3>
		<banner1>https://images.launchbox-app.com/3cede5bb-308f-40c0-8b7b-e1d2da43f17b.jpg</banner1>
		<genre>Adventure</genre>
		<groups>J.B. Harold series</groups>
	</game>
	<game name="Nobunaga no Yabou">
		<description>Nobunaga no Yabou</description>
		<rom name="sharp-x-1/Sharp_X1.zip/Sharp_X1%2FNobunaga%20no%20Yabou.d88" size="348848"/>
		<boxart1>http://www.mobygames.com/images/covers/l/546135-nobunaga-no-yabo-pc-6001-front-cover.png</boxart1>
		<groups>KOEI Historical Simulation series,Nobunaga's Ambition series,Setting: Japanese Sengoku Period</groups>
	</game>
	<game name="Nukenin Densetsu">
		<description>Nukenin Densetsu</description>
		<rom name="sharp-x-1/Sharp_X1.zip/Sharp_X1%2FNukenin%20Densetsu%20%28Opening%20disk%29.d88" size="425392"/>[]
		<rom name="sharp-x-1/Sharp_X1.zip/Sharp_X1%2FNukenin%20Densetsu%20%28Common%20disk%29.d88" size="425392"/>
		<rom name="sharp-x-1/Sharp_X1.zip/Sharp_X1%2FNukenin%20Densetsu%20%28Genyousai%29.d88" size="425392"/>
		<rom name="sharp-x-1/Sharp_X1.zip/Sharp_X1%2FNukenin%20Densetsu%20%28Jakimaru%29.d88" size="425392"/>
		<rom name="sharp-x-1/Sharp_X1.zip/Sharp_X1%2FNukenin%20Densetsu%20%28Kogenta%29.d88" size="425392"/>
		<plot>Nukenin Densetsu is an Action game, developed and published by Brain Grey, which was released in Japan in 1987.</plot>
		<boxart1>https://gamefaqs.gamespot.com/a/box/7/4/6/659746_front.jpg</boxart1>
		<snapshot1>https://i.ytimg.com/vi/oSSJv0vbeNI/maxresdefault.jpg</snapshot1>
		<videoid>oSSJv0vbeNI</videoid>
	</game>
	<game name="Oji Bin Bin Story">
		<description>Oji Bin Bin Story</description>
		<rom name="sharp-x-1/Sharp_X1.zip/Sharp_X1%2FOji%20Bin%20Bin%20Story%20%28Disk%20A%29.d88" size="348848"/>
		<rom name="sharp-x-1/Sharp_X1.zip/Sharp_X1%2FOji%20Bin%20Bin%20Story%20%28Disk%20B%29.d88" size="348848"/>
		<plot>Oji Bin Bin Story is a Dragon Quest-style RPG. It has all the typical elements of a solid RPG, from (slightly) customizable stats that grow as your character levels up, upgradeable equipment, and an open world with a good assortment of fantasy creatures.</plot>
		<videoid>AEWwaf0emGo</videoid>
		<snapshot1>https://monochromeeffect.org/JVCC/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/oujibinbin01.jpg</snapshot1>
	</game>
	<game name="Original Tetris">
		<description>Original Tetris</description>
		<rom name="sharp-x-1/Sharp_X1.zip/Sharp_X1%2FOriginal%20Tetris.d88" size="348848"/>
		<plot>This version of [I]Tetris[/I] is one of many conversions of the famous block-stacking game. The goal is to place pieces made up of four tiles in a ten-by-twenty well, organizing them into complete rows, which then disappear. The goal of each round is to clear 25 lines, after which the player moves on to the next round. If the stack reaches the top of the field, the player loses a life, and if all three lives are lost, the game is over.[CR]The game lets the player choose the starting stage and round, as well as one of three background tunes. Difficulty is increased throughout the stages by an increase in speed and the addition of garbage blocks in the well.</plot>
		<boxart1>http://www.mobygames.com/images/covers/l/152593-tetris-msx-front-cover.jpg</boxart1>
		<groups>Tetris licensees,Tetris variants</groups>
	</game>
	<game name="Orrbit 3">
		<description>Orrbit 3</description>
		<rom name="sharp-x-1/Sharp_X1.zip/Sharp_X1%2FOrrbit%20III.d88" size="350384"/>
		<genre>Shooter</genre>
		<plot>Orrbit 3 is a space based vector shooter by Tecno Soft</plot>
		<videoid>dKwzZBtDiWQ</videoid>
		<boxart1>https://images.launchbox-app.com/50205a7d-bc2f-456a-9d66-480e8b16974f.jpg</boxart1>
		<snapshot1>https://i.ytimg.com/vi/dKwzZBtDiWQ/mqdefault.jpg</snapshot1>
	</game>
	<game name="Outroyd">
		<description>Outroyd</description>
		<rom name="sharp-x-1/Sharp_X1.zip/Sharp_X1%2FOutroyd.d88" size="348848"/>
		<plot>In the year 2108, the world of Quorn was almost destroyed by a battle between the central computers of the East and West factions. While the West faction won, its computer no longer recognised the interests of its human creators. Instead, it started the creation of a robot society, Outroyd, and started to wage war against the human survivors of the first battle. But one of the humans, Ramon Okudaira, has decided to take a stand against the robots. Armed only with his XX-85 Armoured suit, he will try to win back Quorn in the name of humanity.[CR]The game is played on an 8x8 overworld map showing a birds-eye view of the armoured player. The overworld is tiled with various sort of terrain such as grass and concrete, impenetrable walls, as well as traps of various sort which may zap the player with electricity, blast them with lasers or send them falling into an endless abyss. There are also squares with water, magnetic plates and aerial rails, which may only be traversed once you have found the appropriate upgrades for your armoured suit.</plot>
		<genre>RPG</genre>
		<videoid>TSDsSmh7w94</videoid>
		<snapshot1>https://www.mobygames.com/images/shots/l/1028797-outroyd-msx-screenshot-title-screen.png</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>https://www.mobygames.com/images/shots/l/1028802-outroyd-msx-screenshot-a-droid-guarding-a-base-and-an-item.png</snapshot2>
	</game>
	<game name="Penguin kun Wars">
		<description>Penguin kun Wars</description>
		<rom name="sharp-x-1/Sharp_X1.zip/Sharp_X1%2FPenguin-kun%20Wars.d88" size="348848"/>
		<plot>A penguin rolls spheres across a table attempting to knock its opponent out for points. The character with the fewest spheres on its side of the table at the end of the timed match is the winner.</plot>
		<boxart1>http://www.mobygames.com/images/covers/l/382889-penguin-kun-wars-msx-front-cover.jpg</boxart1>
		<genre>Sports</genre>
		<groups>Animals: Penguins,Penguin-Kun Wars series</groups>
		<videoid>EvQZBW8-dNU</videoid>
	</game>
	<game name="Phantasie">
		<description>Phantasie</description>
		<rom name="sharp-x-1/Sharp_X1.zip/Sharp_X1%2FPhantasie%20%28Disk%201%20-%20Program%20disk%29.d88" size="348848"/>
		<rom name="sharp-x-1/Sharp_X1.zip/Sharp_X1%2FPhantasie%20%28Disk%202%20-%20Player%20disk%29.d88" size="348848"/>
		<plot>The island of Gelnor has been taken over by The Black Knights, who demand sacrifices and homage as they travel from town to town. Defeat them and their master, Nikademus![CR][I]Phantasie[/I] is a classic role-playing game, and one of the first to introduce a "bank" for storing money in addition to expanding on the classic Wizardry-style gameplay of building your own adventuring party with traveling from town to town via the countryside, overhead views of dungeons, and multiple styles of attack.</plot>
		<boxart1>http://www.mobygames.com/images/covers/l/4481-phantasie-commodore-64-front-cover.jpg</boxart1>
		<groups>Fantasy Creatures: Dwarves,Fantasy Creatures: Elves,Phantasie series</groups>
	</game>
	<game name="Produce">
		<description>Produce</description>
		<rom name="sharp-x-1/Sharp_X1.zip/Sharp_X1%2FProduce.d88" size="348848"/>
		<plot>Four classmates of international ESP Institute - Gilbert, Toshio, Tina and Sayaka decide to spend their summer vacation together. Toshio is secretly in love with Sayaka but all his dreams are shattered when it turns out that Sayaka actually likes Gilbert. [CR]Toshio is overcome by envy and hatred and then suddenly fate offers him an excellent opportunity to take revenge on his former friend and get his beloved. Taking a walk around the neighborhood, he accidentally stumbles upon an abandoned building, as he goes inside he begins to hear voices in his head. As it turns out, an evil entity who can communicate with people through telepathy lives in this building and he offers Toshio a deal: if he can lure his "friends" here, the monster will help him deal with Gilbert and reunite him with Sayaka. [CR]The objective is to scare the former friends to death and drive them to the top floor of the building, right in the clutches of the monster. There's 30 specter types and they effect each of the 3 characters differently. The game takes place in real time, events start at 19:00 in the evening and it's game over if you don't deal with them until dawn (5:00 AM the next day).</plot>
		<boxart1>http://www.mobygames.com/images/covers/l/539582-produce-pc-98-front-cover.png</boxart1>
		<genre>RPG</genre>
	</game>
	<game name="Psy O Blade">
		<description>Psy O Blade</description>
		<rom name="sharp-x-1/Sharp_X1.zip/Sharp_X1%2FPsy-O-Blade%20%28Disk%201%20-%20Program%29.d88" size="392368"/>
		<rom name="sharp-x-1/Sharp_X1.zip/Sharp_X1%2FPsy-O-Blade%20%28Disk%202%20-%20A%29.d88" size="392368"/>
		<rom name="sharp-x-1/Sharp_X1.zip/Sharp_X1%2FPsy-O-Blade%20%28Disk%203%20-%20B%29.d88" size="392368"/>
		<rom name="sharp-x-1/Sharp_X1.zip/Sharp_X1%2FPsy-O-Blade%20%28Disk%204%20-%20C%29.d88" size="392368"/>
		<rom name="sharp-x-1/Sharp_X1.zip/Sharp_X1%2FPsy-O-Blade%20%28Disk%205%20-%20D%29.d88" size="392368"/>
		<rom name="sharp-x-1/Sharp_X1.zip/Sharp_X1%2FPsy-O-Blade%20%28User%20disk%29.d88" size="392368"/>
		<plot>In 21th century, there are three main powers on the Earth. The free world and the communist block carried over from the 20th century; the third power is the New Communist Federation. Since a program of denuclearizing was supported by all those powers, the New Communist Federation developed a devastating non-nuclear weapon: the satellite "Raiden". The two other powers competed with the New Communist Federation, developing their own killer satellites, and the danger of total annihilation became once again an issue. Seeing no future for the Earth, humans started to colonize other planets. In 22th century, they sent an experimental ship "Septemius 1" to a star six light years far away from the Solar System. The ship's main computer, "Racoon", sent a strange message before stopping any communication. Keith McDonnell, a seventeen-year-old crew member of the ship "Septemius 2", was sent to investigate the strange disappearance. [CR][I]Psy-O-Blade[/I] is a Japanese adventure in anime style. The player interacts with the game world by moving a cursor and clicking on objects to examine or use them, and people to talk to them, or by choosing options ("Move" and "Scroll") from a menu. There are no puzzles to solve; the player advances in the game by talking to characters, visiting different locations, as well as examining and using objects.</plot>
		<boxart1>http://www.mobygames.com/images/covers/l/92116-psy-o-blade-genesis-front-cover.jpg</boxart1>
	</game>
	<game name="Punch Ball Mario Bros">
		<description>Punch Ball Mario Bros</description>
		<rom name="sharp-x-1/Sharp_X1.zip/Sharp_X1%2FPunch%20Ball%20Mario%20Bros..d88" size="348848"/>
		<plot>Punch Ball Mario Bros. is a single-screen action game adapted from the 1983 arcade game Mario Bros.. Visually and structurally, the game is quite similar: enemies emerge from pipes at the top of the screen, and must be knocked over and kicked off the stage. Enemies that reach the bottom will enter a pipe and return to the top. The last remaining enemy on the stage, as well as any enemy left knocked over for too long, will change color and move faster. However, unlike the original game where Mario must flip enemies by hitting the platform they're on from underneath, in Punch Ball, Mario (and optionally a second player as Luigi) carries a red ball which can be thrown at enemies to knock them over. The ball must be picked back up after being thrown.[CR]Every few stages, there is a bonus coin round with no enemies. Most stages also feature a POW block in the center, which can be hit a limited number of times to flip every enemy on the screen. There is also a small pit in the center of the screen at the bottom, into which Mario can fall if he isn't careful. One or two players can play the game simultaneously.</plot>
		<releasedate>26/08/1984</releasedate>
		<year>1984</year>
		<studio>Hudson Soft Company</studio>
		<nplayers>1-2 Co-Op</nplayers>
		<ESRB>Not Rated</ESRB>
		<videoid>27aPBx-g3_w</videoid>
		<boxart1>http://www.mobygames.com/images/covers/l/545926-punch-ball-mario-bros-pc-6001-front-cover.png</boxart1>
		<snapshot1>https://images.launchbox-app.com/cf73c833-0914-46e0-8ca1-b641fe8f1d9f.png</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>https://images.launchbox-app.com/d702a6a2-7280-48f9-b9ee-b8e41c1d4eac.png</snapshot2>
		<snapshot3>https://images.launchbox-app.com/916568b4-509d-4d6f-a619-86021e21ebb9.png</snapshot3>
		<snapshot4>https://images.launchbox-app.com/e96d4379-1f9f-47ec-aa2c-a0fe2d83f465.png</snapshot4>
		<clearlogo1>https://images.launchbox-app.com/b942f1d0-b32e-4c15-87a9-33bcc605225b.png</clearlogo1>
		<genre>Platform</genre>
	</game>
	<game name="Puzzle Game">
		<description>Puzzle Game</description>
		<rom name="sharp-x-1/Sharp_X1.zip/Sharp_X1%2FPuzzle%20Game%20%28System%20disk%29.d88" size="348848"/>
		<rom name="sharp-x-1/Sharp_X1.zip/Sharp_X1%2FPuzzle%20Game%20%28Data%201%29.d88" size="416688"/>
		<rom name="sharp-x-1/Sharp_X1.zip/Sharp_X1%2FPuzzle%20Game%20%28Data%202%29.d88" size="416688"/>
	</game>
	<game name="R">
		<description>R</description>
		<rom name="sharp-x-1/Sharp_X1.zip/Sharp_X1%2FR%20%28Disk%20A%29.d88" size="144304"/>
		<rom name="sharp-x-1/Sharp_X1.zip/Sharp_X1%2FR%20%28Disk%20B%29.d88" size="335792"/>
		<genre>Miscellaneous</genre>
	</game>
	<game name="ReBirth">
		<description>ReBirth</description>
		<rom name="sharp-x-1/Sharp_X1.zip/Sharp_X1%2FReBirth%20%28Disk%201%29.d88" size="416112"/>
		<rom name="sharp-x-1/Sharp_X1.zip/Sharp_X1%2FReBirth%20%28Disk%202%29.d88" size="416960"/>
		<rom name="sharp-x-1/Sharp_X1.zip/Sharp_X1%2FReBirth%20%28Disk%203%29.d88" size="416960"/>
		<rom name="sharp-x-1/Sharp_X1.zip/Sharp_X1%2FReBirth%20%28Disk%204%29.d88" size="416960"/>
		<snapshot1>QkPSA5q.png</snapshot1>
	</game>
	<game name="Relics">
		<description>Relics</description>
		<rom name="sharp-x-1/Sharp_X1.zip/Sharp_X1%2FRelics%20%28Disk%20A%29.d88" size="348848"/>
		<rom name="sharp-x-1/Sharp_X1.zip/Sharp_X1%2FRelics%20%28Disk%20B%29.d88" size="348848"/>
		<plot>Relics is an action-adventure game where players take the role of a spirit who can possess different characters. The spirit appears at underwater ruins with no explanation why it became a spirit and what it needs to do. In fact, one will only find out about the story of the game when seeing the real ending. The graphic style of the game is compared to the works of H. R. Giger.[CR]Players can possess other bodies after killing their owners, but to get the real ending, they must explore the ruins while avoiding unnecessary combat by running away or ignoring the characters they meet on their way. There is no music in the game apart from the opening and the real ending and, depending on the body possessed, players will acquire different skills and attacks.</plot>
		<boxart1>http://www.mobygames.com/images/covers/l/539628-relics-pc-98-front-cover.png</boxart1>
		<genre>Action</genre>
		<groups>Game feature: Possession,Relics series</groups>
	</game>
	<game name="Reviver">
		<description>Reviver</description>
		<rom name="sharp-x-1/Sharp_X1.zip/Sharp_X1%2FReviver%20%28Disk%20A%20-%20Master%20disk%29.d88" size="414992"/>
		<rom name="sharp-x-1/Sharp_X1.zip/Sharp_X1%2FReviver%20%28Disk%20B%20-%20Data%20disk%29.d88" size="414992"/>
		<rom name="sharp-x-1/Sharp_X1.zip/Sharp_X1%2FReviver%20%28User%20disk%29.d88" size="414992"/>
		<plot>Reviver: The Real-Time Adventure is an adventure game designed by Katsunori Yoshimura and released by Arsys Software in July 1987. The sub-title, The Real-Time Adventure, is a reference to the games real-time, persistent, open world, where time continues to elapse, day-night cycles adjust the brightness of the screen to indicate the time of day, and certain stores and non-player characters would only be available at certain times of the day. The game also gives players direct control over the player character. The game also features a fantasy story, full-colour 2D overhead scrolling graphics, and RPG elements. It won the 1987 Game of the Year award from Japanese gaming magazine Oh!X</plot>
		<videoid>egorX582_G4</videoid>
		<boxart1>https://www.giantbomb.com/a/uploads/original/13/139866/2424204-reviver88.gif</boxart1>
		<snapshot1>https://i.ytimg.com/vi/egorX582_G4/maxresdefault.jpg</snapshot1>
	</game>
	<game name="Revolty 2">
		<description>Revolty 2</description>
		<rom name="sharp-x-1/Sharp_X1.zip/Sharp_X1%2FRevolty%20II%20%28Disk%200%29.d88" size="348848"/>
		<rom name="sharp-x-1/Sharp_X1.zip/Sharp_X1%2FRevolty%20II%20%28Disk%201%29.d88" size="348848"/>
		<rom name="sharp-x-1/Sharp_X1.zip/Sharp_X1%2FRevolty%20II%20%28Disk%202%29.d88" size="348848"/>
		<rom name="sharp-x-1/Sharp_X1.zip/Sharp_X1%2FRevolty%20II%20%28Disk%203%29.d88" size="348848"/>
		<plot>Revolty 2 was developed by Fuga System and released in 1989</plot>
		<snapshot1>https://i.ytimg.com/vi/Rywn0vAAXR0/maxresdefault.jpg</snapshot1>
		<videoid>Rywn0vAAXR0</videoid>
	</game>
	<game name="Riglas">
		<description>Riglas</description>
		<rom name="sharp-x-1/Sharp_X1.zip/Sharp_X1%2FRiglas.d88" size="379920"/>
		<plot>The continent of Riglas is inhabited by two races: Miria and Galt. For years they have been fighting each other for dominance. Caught in the struggle between the two is the nearly forgotten Osborn race, discriminated and enslaved. Mei is a young man belonging to that races, who leaves his home village in order to free his people.[CR][I]Riglas[/I] is an action role-playing game. The game is set in a vast seamless world that consists of interconnected yet varied urban, wilderness, and dungeon-like locations. The principal view is third-person with a side-scrolling flavor, similar to Western adventure games of the time. The player is free to explore most of the locations from the onset.[CR]The game world is populated by many different types of friendly and hostile characters. Killing hostile characters increases the player's score and eventually makes the main character stronger. Killing friendly NPCs, on the other hand, may lower the score. Combat system is simple and involves approaching a character and pressing the attack button, which results in the protagonist swinging the sword.</plot>
		<snapshot1>https://www.mobygames.com/images/shots/l/557722-riglas-sharp-x1-screenshot-lovely-view.png</snapshot1>
		<genre>Beat Em Up</genre>
		<videoid>-DcyXHmPhfk</videoid>
	</game>
	<game name="Robo Wres 2001">
		<description>Robo Wres 2001</description>
		<rom name="sharp-x-1/Sharp_X1.zip/Sharp_X1%2FRobo%20Wres%202001.d88" size="366352"/>
		<plot>As the name implies, [I]Robo Wres 2001[/I] is a game about robots that wrestle in (what then was) the future. Six robots from six countries fight in a tournament that, apart from the robot element, is closer to American, Mexican or Japanese wrestling than the classic kind of wrestling. Each player uses three keys or buttons to execute various attacks in the classic "button masher" beat'em'up manner, with different button combinations triggering different techniques according to the proximity between the combatants. Each robot has its own arsenal of special moves. The ring is viewed from an elevated position and allows movement in two dimensions. The losing robot is turned into scrap ready for recycling, with the winner going on the next round.</plot>
		<boxart1>https://m.media-amazon.com/images/M/MV5BNjM5NWJlNTUtZWE2OC00NWY1LWJmMGUtMmRhZGVhMTA1MThlXkEyXkFqcGdeQXVyNzg5OTk2OA@@._V1_.jpg</boxart1>
		<snapshot1>https://segaretro.org/images/9/9e/RoboWres2001_title.png</snapshot1>
		<genre>Driving,Sports,Wrestling</genre>
	</game>
	<game name="Romancia">
		<description>Romancia</description>
		<rom name="sharp-x-1/Sharp_X1.zip/Sharp_X1%2FRomancia.d88" size="379680"/>
		<genre>RPG</genre>
		<plot>Romancia, also known as Dragon Slayer Jr, is an action-adventure game developed by Nihon Falcom. It is the third installment in the Dragon Slayer series, preceded by Xanadu and followed by Dragon Slayer IV.[CR]Romancia is a simpler and brightly colored game in comparison to the other Dragon Slayer titles, hence the name Dragon Slayer Jr</plot>
		<boxart1>https://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/8/87/Romancia_Box.jpg</boxart1>
		<snapshot1>https://www.mobygames.com/images/shots/l/688381-romancia-dragon-slayer-jr-sharp-x1-screenshot-the-king-despises.png</snapshot1>
		<videoid>iBcvtfxqqT0</videoid>
	</game>
	<game name="SF3D Original Operation 5">
		<description>SF3D Original Operation 5</description>
		<rom name="sharp-x-1/Sharp_X1.zip/Sharp_X1%2FS.F.3.D%20Original%20-%20Operation%20V.d88" size="354288"/>
		<genre>Strategy</genre>
		<boxart1>https://pds.exblog.jp/pds/1/201506/13/69/e0296069_94288.jpg</boxart1>
		<plot>SF3D Original Operation 5 is a strategy game. SF3D Original: Operation V was released by Crossmedia Soft in 1985, with SF3D Original: Operation Thanksgiving released the following year. Both of these games are extremely rare.</plot>
	</game>
	<game name="Sangokushi 2">
		<description>Sangokushi 2</description>
		<rom name="sharp-x-1/Sharp_X1.zip/Sharp_X1%2FSangokushi%20II%20%28Disk%20A%29.d88" size="380864"/>
		<rom name="sharp-x-1/Sharp_X1.zip/Sharp_X1%2FSangokushi%20II%20%28Disk%20B%29.d88" size="380848"/>
		<rom name="sharp-x-1/Sharp_X1.zip/Sharp_X1%2FSangokushi%20II%20%28Disk%20C%29.d88" size="380848"/>
		<plot>Romance of the Three Kingdoms II is the second in the Romance of the Three Kingdoms series of turn-based strategy games produced by Koei and based on the historical novel Romance of the Three Kingdoms.</plot>
		<boxart1>https://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/thumb/9/94/Romance_of_the_Three_Kingdoms_II.jpg/220px-Romance_of_the_Three_Kingdoms_II.jpg</boxart1>
		<snapshot1>https://s.uvlist.net/n/y2018/12/189151.jpg</snapshot1>
	</game>
	<game name="Sangokushi Turbo">
		<description>Sangokushi Turbo</description>
		<rom name="sharp-x-1/Sharp_X1.zip/Sharp_X1%2FSangokushi%20Turbo%20%28Disk%20A%29.d88" size="380864"/>
		<rom name="sharp-x-1/Sharp_X1.zip/Sharp_X1%2FSangokushi%20Turbo%20%28Disk%20B%29.d88" size="380848"/>
		<rom name="sharp-x-1/Sharp_X1.zip/Sharp_X1%2FSangokushi%20Turbo%20%28Disk%20C%29.d88" size="380848"/>
		<snapshot1>https://s.uvlist.net/n/y2016/03/142541.jpg</snapshot1>
	</game>
	<game name="Satsujin wa Tegami ni Notte">
		<description>Satsujin wa Tegami ni Notte</description>
		<rom name="sharp-x-1/Sharp_X1.zip/Sharp_X1%2FSatsujin%20wa%20Tegami%20ni%20Notte%20%28Disk%20A%29.d88" size="344496"/>
		<rom name="sharp-x-1/Sharp_X1.zip/Sharp_X1%2FSatsujin%20wa%20Tegami%20ni%20Notte%20%28Disk%20B%29.d88" size="348848"/>
		<rom name="sharp-x-1/Sharp_X1.zip/Sharp_X1%2FSatsujin%20wa%20Tegami%20ni%20Notte%20%28Disk%20C%29.d88" size="348848"/>
		<plot>This is a Japanese-style adventure game, where the player talks to people, asks them and goes to various places.  The main character is a high school student who hears that his friend was hit and killed by a train. He has 7 days remaining until school starts and he intends to find out the truth behind this incident before then.</plot>
		<snapshot1>https://i.ytimg.com/vi/A0vuGiBmcWk/maxresdefault.jpg</snapshot1>
		<videoid>A0vuGiBmcWk</videoid>
	</game>
	<game name="Saziri">
		<description>Saziri</description>
		<rom name="sharp-x-1/Sharp_X1.zip/Sharp_X1%2FSaziri%20%28Disk%20A%29.d88" size="423312"/>
		<rom name="sharp-x-1/Sharp_X1.zip/Sharp_X1%2FSaziri%20%28Disk%20B%29.d88" size="415840"/>
		<plot>Saziri is a manga role-play video game for Sharp X1, created and published by Telenet Japan / Renovation Game in 1988</plot>
		<boxart1>https://images.launchbox-app.com/bfcce32d-dd25-4328-ae17-37e80ad9333f.jpg</boxart1>
		<snapshot1>https://i.ytimg.com/vi/rsgUbEhv6eo/maxresdefault.jpg</snapshot1>
		<genre>Beat Em Up</genre>
	</game>
	<game name="Scramble Fighter">
		<description>Scramble Fighter</description>
		<rom name="sharp-x-1/Sharp_X1.zip/Sharp_X1%2FScramble%20Fighter.d88" size="348848"/>
		<snapshot1>https://i.ytimg.com/vi/tfSBQmdbVxM/maxresdefault.jpg</snapshot1>
		<videoid>tfSBQmdbVxM</videoid>
		<genre>Shoot Em Up</genre>
	</game>
	<game name="Shin Taketori Monogatari">
		<description>Shin Taketori Monogatari</description>
		<rom name="sharp-x-1/Sharp_X1.zip/Sharp_X1%2FShin%20Taketori%20Monogatari%20%28Disk%200%29.d88" size="363536"/>
		<plot>Shin Taketori Monogatari is an adventure game developed by Cross Media Soft in 1984</plot>
		<boxart1>https://www.giantbomb.com/a/uploads/scale_small/5/59247/1173576-shin______.jpg</boxart1>
	</game>
	<game name="Silver Ghost">
		<description>Silver Ghost</description>
		<rom name="sharp-x-1/Sharp_X1.zip/Sharp_X1%2FSilver%20Ghost%20%28Disk%20A%20-%20Game%20disk%29.d88" size="348848"/>
		<rom name="sharp-x-1/Sharp_X1.zip/Sharp_X1%2FSilver%20Ghost%20%28Disk%20B%29.d88" size="348848"/>
		<rom name="sharp-x-1/Sharp_X1.zip/Sharp_X1%2FSilver%20Ghost%20%28Disk%20C%29.d88" size="348848"/>
		<rom name="sharp-x-1/Sharp_X1.zip/Sharp_X1%2FSilver%20Ghost%20%28User%20disk%29.d88" size="348848"/>
		<plot>[I]Silver Ghost[/I] is very loosely based on the Camelot cycle of legends, starring the legendary Lancelot - who, in this game, is a prince rather than a knight. Lancelot's father was killed by a demonic magician and his country overrun by his minions. The young prince must assemble a capable army and lead it to the enemy's stronghold.[CR]The game marks the first implementation of Kure Software Koubou's trademark "gocha-kyara" ("mixed-up characters") system. Essentially it is a hybrid of a role-playing and a real-time strategy game. Initially the player controls only Lancelot himself, but soon thereafter he becomes the leader of the first team, and eventually the player is put in control of several teams containing a dozen or more soldiers each. It is possible to switch between teams at almost any time and explore different areas. [CR]The player physically controls only the team leader, navigating him or her through interconnected overhead areas. Battles flow in real time and are automatized for everyone except the leader, which must be controlled manually. In order to prevail, however, it is necessary to assemble and outfit teams properly, judging the nature of upcoming battles in advance. Each team member has his or her own statistics and grows up in levels as they vanquish enemies.</plot>
		<snapshot1>https://www.mobygames.com/images/shots/l/724781-silver-ghost-sharp-x1-screenshot-title-screen.png</snapshot1>
	</game>
	<game name="Sirius 1">
		<description>Sirius 1</description>
		<rom name="sharp-x-1/Sharp_X1.zip/Sharp_X1%2FSirius-1.d88" size="348848"/>
		<snapshot1>https://i.ytimg.com/vi/PDLxSAS3Mwg/hqdefault.jpg</snapshot1>
		<videoid>PDLxSAS3Mwg</videoid>
	</game>
	<game name="Soft Jump">
		<description>Soft Jump</description>
		<rom name="sharp-x-1/Sharp_X1.zip/Sharp_X1%2FSoft%20Jump.d88" size="348848"/>
		<genre>Adventure</genre>
		<videoid>5i4kiGocq0A</videoid>
		<snapshot1>https://i.ytimg.com/vi/5i4kiGocq0A/sddefault.jpg</snapshot1>
	</game>
	<game name="Sorcerian">
		<description>Sorcerian</description>
		<rom name="sharp-x-1/Sharp_X1.zip/Sharp_X1%2FSorcerian%20%28Program%20disk%29.d88" size="426240"/>
		<rom name="sharp-x-1/Sharp_X1.zip/Sharp_X1%2FSorcerian%20%28Scenario%201%29.d88" size="426240"/>
		<rom name="sharp-x-1/Sharp_X1.zip/Sharp_X1%2FSorcerian%20%28Scenario%202%29.d88" size="436640"/>
		<rom name="sharp-x-1/Sharp_X1.zip/Sharp_X1%2FSorcerian%20%28Scenario%203%29.d88" size="426240"/>
		<rom name="sharp-x-1/Sharp_X1.zip/Sharp_X1%2FSorcerian%20%28User%20disk%29.d88" size="426240"/>
		<plot>[I]Sorcerian[/I] is the fifth game in the Dragon Slayer series. It is set in the fantasy land known as Pentawa, whose inhabitants are in constant need of protection from ferocious creatures roaming the wilderness. The king of Pentawa hires a party of adventurers, and their first assignment is to retrieve a precious sceptre from a dungeon, where it is guarded by the evil demonic lord Ouks.[CR]The game is an RPG with an unusual side-scrolling perspective and action-based combat, somewhat of a cross between Wizardry and platform games. Despite being a Japanese game, [I]Sorcerian[/I] resembles Western RPGs of its time, focusing more on character development than story. In the beginning, the player creates a party of four characters, choosing between fighter, wizard, elf, and dwarf (races and classes are not distinguished). Beside the usual inns and shops, there are many things that can be done in the towns of the game, including complex development of magical spells (up to 120 spells of different disciplines), training to raise personal skills (strength, intelligence, etc.), enchanting weapons with elemental magic, as well as looking for part-time jobs.[CR]The view switches to side-scrolling when the party ventures into a hostile area. Combat is performed in real time, with the player controlling the entire party at once. The lead character can be changed at any time, and battle actions will be carried out by whoever is in front. Melee attacks and magic spells are unleashed by pressing corresponding buttons. The characters can also jump and interact with objects by bumping into them. Dungeons are usually maze-like, and some contain simple puzzles such as finding and activating hidden switches to open doors.</plot>
		<boxart1>http://www.mobygames.com/images/covers/l/26962-sorcerian-dos-front-cover.jpg</boxart1>
		<groups>Dragon Slayer universe,Sorcerian series</groups>
	</game>
	<game name="Space Harrier">
		<description>Space Harrier</description>
		<rom name="sharp-x-1/Sharp_X1.zip/Sharp_X1%2FSpace%20Harrier%20%28Disk%20A%29.d88" size="348848"/>
		<rom name="sharp-x-1/Sharp_X1.zip/Sharp_X1%2FSpace%20Harrier%20%28Disk%20B%29.d88" size="348848"/>
		<rom name="sharp-x-1/Sharp_X1.zip/Sharp_X1%2FSpace%20Harrier%20%28unofficial%29.d88" size="348848"/>
		<plot>Run... fly... dodge those obstacles, but return fire on wave after wave of attacking aliens. Armed with a really big gun, you have to defend yourself against the alien hordes using your wits to navigate around the screen. But watch out for those end of level bosses![CR]Originating in the arcades, Space Harrier is a third-person rail shooter with pseudo-3D graphics, set in the same world as Fantasy Zone. The lone titular hero fights aliens with a fireball-launching cannon, which can also be used to transform the hero into a flying rocket. The protagonist is constantly in motion, but the speed of his movement can be regulated by the player.</plot>
		<releasedate>01/09/1987</releasedate>
		<year>1987</year>
		<studio>AM R&amp;D Dept. #2</studio>
		<nplayers>1</nplayers>
		<ESRB>E - Everyone</ESRB>
		<videoid>vyRNgbeaA0s</videoid>
		<boxart1>http://www.mobygames.com/images/covers/l/40231-space-harrier-commodore-64-front-cover.jpg</boxart1>
		<boxart3>https://images.launchbox-app.com/9f2003ec-03a9-4f47-b1cd-914ef550aba3.jpg</boxart3>
		<snapshot1>https://images.launchbox-app.com/d4aa6d60-7a19-4324-9d42-3523cbe17223.png</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>https://images.launchbox-app.com/598dc188-7160-4b19-961c-92af14ef36cd.png</snapshot2>
		<clearlogo1>https://images.launchbox-app.com/2528060e-4be3-4b46-ad97-74b257a2c51d.png</clearlogo1>
		<genre>Action,Shooter</genre>
		<groups>Genre: Chase-view / Space Harrier-style shooter,Space Harrier series</groups>
	</game>
	<game name="Spare Change">
		<description>Spare Change</description>
		<rom name="sharp-x-1/Sharp_X1.zip/Sharp_X1%2FSpare%20Change.d88" size="349616"/>
		<plot>In [I]Spare Change[/I], you are the owner and operator of the Spare Change Arcade, dedicated to making your place of business run as smoothly as possible. Inside the arcade are Token machines, jukeboxes, telephones, movie booths, popcorn machines, and so on. The token machines need to be restocked with money from the cash register when they are out of tokens, but eventually, the register must be replenished with cash from the safe. You must drop the tokens in one of your two storage bins. When you have stored at least ten tokens, the movie booth opens, and you can go inside to proceed to the next level. You are also awarded one bag of money, but if you store more than ten tokens, then more than one bag of money is awarded for each extra token collected. If nine bags of money are obtained, you proceed to the next level.[CR]But the Zerks, two aliens that run around the screen, can steal tokens either from the machines or from the storage bins. Sometimes, a Zerk will toss a token to the other nearest the "piggy bank". You must touch them in order to get the token back, before they throw it in their piggy bank. Alternatively, you can throw a token into the jukebox, telephone, popcorn machine, etc. and the Zerks will get distracted from their goal, giving you enough time to continue filling the storage bins. If the Zerks insert five tokens in the piggy bank, the game is over.[CR]Between levels, an intermission plays, which are similar to those in Pac-Man. Later in the game, you have the ability to access these intermissions. As you proceed through the levels, the game gets quite difficult.</plot>
		<boxart1>http://www.mobygames.com/images/covers/l/538148-spare-change-apple-ii-front-cover.png</boxart1>
		<genre>Miscellaneous</genre>
	</game>
	<game name="Spy vs Spy">
		<description>Spy vs Spy</description>
		<rom name="sharp-x-1/Sharp_X1.zip/Sharp_X1%2FSpy%20vs.%20Spy.d88" size="366256"/>
		<plot>[I]MAD[/I] magazine’s comic strip of the same name comes to life in this game which was designed for one or two players. The split-screen shows both spies at the same time. Play with a friend or against the machine.[CR]The black spy and the white spy are out to outsmart each other before the time bell rings. Find the needed objects (money, passport, secret plans and airport door key) by searching rooms in the embassy, which include desks, file cabinets and other furniture. Foil your opponent by setting creative booby traps in the various rooms (a bomb in a dresser drawer, for instance). Traps can be disarmed with objects found in rooms (a water bucket from a firebox on the wall will disarm the bomb in the prior example). When all the items are together in the secret briefcase, head for the airport door.[CR]Fights ensue when both spies enter the same room and are armed with clubs.</plot>
		<boxart1>http://www.mobygames.com/images/covers/l/26616-spy-vs-spy-commodore-64-front-cover.jpg</boxart1>
		<genre>Miscellaneous</genre>
		<groups>Inspiration: Comics,Spy vs. Spy licensees</groups>
	</game>
	<game name="Star Cruiser">
		<description>Star Cruiser</description>
		<rom name="sharp-x-1/Sharp_X1.zip/Sharp_X1%2FStar%20Cruiser%20%28Disk%20A%29.d88" size="415840"/>
		<rom name="sharp-x-1/Sharp_X1.zip/Sharp_X1%2FStar%20Cruiser%20%28Disk%20B%29.d88" size="415840"/>
		<plot>In the 25th century, a new age of space exploration has taken humanity throughout the galaxy. In that expansion, by random chance humanity encountered an alien kingdom, the Galaxy Alliance. The human Federation wished to develop peaceful relations, but there were those who did not trust the Galaxy Alliance, and mounted a fierce rebellion. The rebellion was quickly put down, but its leader, Geist Needman, went missing. Having expanded too quickly, the Federation was unable to maintain control over its territories, and more remote regions quickly soon to rebel in great numbers.[CR]In the middle of this, an unknown group called VOID began to amass power at a frightening rate, and unafraid of involving civilians, they became known as the "dark destroyers". It appears that a dark age in space is about to begin. However, there were those brave few still willing to stand up against such evil: Hunters. This is the story of Brian Light, one of those hunters.[CR][I]Star Cruiser[/I] is a 3D action game with light RPG elements from the creators of Wibarm. The player explores various labyrinthine locations on foot, interacting with NPCs and shops and fighting various alien and robotic enemies. Combat takes place in real-time, consisting of basic first-person shooting. Additionally, there are also space-flight battle and exploration segments where the player controls Brian's ship.</plot>
		<boxart1>http://www.mobygames.com/images/covers/l/275508-star-cruiser-genesis-front-cover.jpg</boxart1>
		<genre>Driving</genre>
		<groups>Star Cruiser series</groups>
	</game>
	<game name="State 2">
		<description>State 2</description>
		<rom name="sharp-x-1/Sharp_X1.zip/Sharp_X1%2FState%20II.d88" size="348848"/>
		<genre>Shoot Em Up</genre>
	</game>
	<game name="Super Laydock">
		<description>Super Laydock</description>
		<rom name="sharp-x-1/Sharp_X1.zip/Sharp_X1%2FSuper%20Laydock%20%28Disk%20A%29.d88" size="348848"/>
		<rom name="sharp-x-1/Sharp_X1.zip/Sharp_X1%2FSuper%20Laydock%20%28Disk%20B%29.d88" size="348848"/>
		<plot>A shoot 'em up game in the Laydock series that fits in perfectly between Laydock (Laydock 1) and Laydock 2. It's again a game that can be played by two players though a single player game is also a possibility. If played by two players they can cooperate by docking the jets together, docked side-by-side or end-to-end for greater fire and fighting power. When docked one player is the pilot and the other is the weapons officer.</plot>
		<boxart1>http://www.mobygames.com/images/covers/l/327789-super-laydock-mission-striker-msx-front-cover.jpg</boxart1>
		<genre>Driving,Shoot Em Up</genre>
		<groups>Laydock series</groups>
	</game>
	<game name="Super Mario Bros Special">
		<description>Super Mario Bros Special</description>
		<rom name="sharp-x-1/Sharp_X1.zip/Sharp_X1%2FSuper%20Mario%20Bros.%20Special.d88" size="348848"/>
		<plot>Super Mario Bros. Special (スーパーマリオブラザーズ スペシャル) was developed by Hudson Soft and released in 1986 for the Sharp X1. Special was the first Nintendo-licensed follow-up to Super Mario Bros., released shortly before Super Mario Bros.: The Lost Levels.[CR]Although it has similar controls and graphics, there are new level layouts and the game scrolls in a different manner than the original game (differing based on the computer). In addition, many new enemies are included, including enemies from Mario Bros. and Donkey Kong.</plot>
		<studio>Hudson Soft</studio>
		<boxart1>https://mario.wiki.gallery/images/3/34/SMBSpecial.jpg</boxart1>
		<videoid>J-a3cJfgG5A</videoid>
		<nplayers>1</nplayers>
		<videoid>txcEMPakkPg</videoid>
		<genre>Adventure,Platform</genre>
		<groups>Super Mario series</groups>
	</game>
	<game name="Super Rambo">
		<description>Super Rambo</description>
		<rom name="sharp-x-1/Sharp_X1.zip/Sharp_X1%2FSuper%20Rambo.d88" size="348848"/>
		<plot>Super Rambo Special is a stealth-action-RPG based on the movie Rambo: First Blood Part 2. It was released in 1986 and featured some early stealth elements anticipating Metal Gear</plot>
		<genre>Shooter</genre>
		<boxart1>https://www.giantbomb.com/a/uploads/scale_small/16/164924/2492446-godslylookssoyounghere.jpg</boxart1>
		<snapshot1>https://tcrf.net/images/thumb/c/c1/Superrambo_x1_title.png/320px-Superrambo_x1_title.png</snapshot1>
		<videoid>pU9eWzoY_Xc</videoid>
	</game>
	<game name="TO-KY-O">
		<description>TO-KY-O</description>
		<rom name="sharp-x-1/Sharp_X1.zip/Sharp_X1%2FTO-KY-O%20%28Disk%20A%29.d88" size="348848"/>
		<rom name="sharp-x-1/Sharp_X1.zip/Sharp_X1%2FTO-KY-O%20%28Disk%20B%29.d88" size="348848"/>
		<plot>TO-KY-O is a Role-Playing game, developed and published by Starcraft, which was released in Japan in 1987.</plot>
		<boxart1>https://www.legendra.com/media/covers/x1/to_ky_o_japon.jpg</boxart1>
		<snapshot1>https://images.launchbox-app.com/bdfb5df3-a79c-4891-90ce-21cba5c601ca.jpg</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>https://images.launchbox-app.com/e82950e7-f2d2-44e3-ab56-28ad76be5bda.jpg</snapshot2>
		<genre>RPG</genre>
		<videoid>xZ5yXV5zIGg</videoid>
	</game>
	<game name="Take Out Vol 5">
		<description>Take Out Vol 5</description>
		<rom name="sharp-x-1/Sharp_X1.zip/Sharp_X1%2FTake%20Out%20Vol.%205%20%28v1.62%29.d88" size="366256"/>
	</game>
	<game name="Take Out Vol 6">
		<description>Take Out Vol 6</description>
		<rom name="sharp-x-1/Sharp_X1.zip/Sharp_X1%2FTake%20Out%20Vol.%206%20%28v1.60%29.d88" size="348848"/>
	</game>
	<game name="Take Out Vol 7">
		<description>Take Out Vol 7</description>
		<rom name="sharp-x-1/Sharp_X1.zip/Sharp_X1%2FTake%20Out%20Vol.%207%20%28Disk%20A%29.d88" size="348848"/>
		<rom name="sharp-x-1/Sharp_X1.zip/Sharp_X1%2FTake%20Out%20Vol.%207%20%28Disk%20B%29.d88" size="348848"/>
	</game>
	<game name="Templo del Sol Asteka 2">
		<description>Templo del Sol Asteka 2</description>
		<rom name="sharp-x-1/Sharp_X1.zip/Sharp_X1%2FTemplo%20del%20Sol%20-%20Asteka%20II%20%28Disk%201%29.d88" size="415840"/>
		<rom name="sharp-x-1/Sharp_X1.zip/Sharp_X1%2FTemplo%20del%20Sol%20-%20Asteka%20II%20%28Disk%202%29.d88" size="415840"/>
		<rom name="sharp-x-1/Sharp_X1.zip/Sharp_X1%2FTemplo%20del%20Sol%20-%20Asteka%20II%20%28User%20disk%29.d88" size="348848"/>
		<plot>Deep in the jungles of Mexico lie the ancient Mayan tombs of Chichen Itza. Eternal resting place of kings - and the vast treasure that was buried with them, including the legendary Sun Key. Now a famous archaeologist has vanished there, leaving behind only a tattered notebook that speaks not just of treasure, but of the bloodthirsty demons that guard it. And with the notebook, the legacy of treasure and terror has passed to you... Can you penetrate the heart of the mystery, and find the mythical Sun Key? Or will the tombs of Chichen Itza claim you among the dead</plot>
		<boxart1>https://gamefaqs.gamespot.com/a/box/3/8/1/108381_front.jpg</boxart1>
		<genre>RPG</genre>
	</game>
	<game name="The Screamer">
		<description>The Screamer</description>
		<rom name="sharp-x-1/Sharp_X1.zip/Sharp_X1%2FThe%20Screamer%20%28System%20disk%29.d88" size="415792"/>
		<rom name="sharp-x-1/Sharp_X1.zip/Sharp_X1%2FThe%20Screamer%20%28Data%20disk%201%29.d88" size="415840"/>
		<rom name="sharp-x-1/Sharp_X1.zip/Sharp_X1%2FThe%20Screamer%20%28Data%20disk%202%29.d88" size="415840"/>
		<plot>The Screamer is set in a dark futuristic environment. The existence of a megalopolis called Beast City depends on a huge complex known as "Biological Intelligence in Artificial System" (sic), usually referred to as simply "BIAS". But recently, disturbances within BIAS have been reported. Apparently, dangerous creatures have gone rampant. Nobody dares to venture inside - except, naturally, the protagonist of this game...[CR]The game is a somewhat unusual mixture of first-person dungeon crawler and side-scrolling action. Following a simple character creation, the player is taken to the Beast City, where it is possible to rest, buy equipment for the hero, and hear the latest gossip. Afterwards, the player can venture into the depths of BIAS, which is a huge maze-like dungeon. Enemies attack randomly; however, instead of the usual turn-based battle screen, the hero and the enemy are taken to a small side-scrolling area. [CR]At that point, the game plays similarly to a side-scrolling shooter: the hero can jump, duck, and shoot at the enemies in real time. Due to the RPG nature of the game, the outcome of the battle depends on the hero's level as well as the player's dexterity.</plot>
		<releasedate>25/05/1985</releasedate>
		<year>1985</year>
		<studio>MagicalZoo</studio>
		<nplayers>1</nplayers>
		<snapshot2>https://images.launchbox-app.com/e75f7ffe-1501-427e-aabf-f6aa26decca8.png</snapshot2>
		<genre>RPG,Shooter</genre>
	</game>
	<game name="Thexder">
		<description>Thexder</description>
		<rom name="sharp-x-1/Sharp_X1.zip/Sharp_X1%2FThexder.d88" size="349920"/>
		<plot>A platform shooter from Japan, Thexder offers many levels and diverse enemies that gradually increase in difficulty. You pilot a Battletech-style robot capable of switching from a mech into a jet at any time. Your weapon auto-aims, but uses up a fixed amount of rechargeable energy; if you run out of this energy, you'll have to wait a few seconds before you can fire again. Your mech also contains a shield that can be activated to protect you from harm, but this lasts for a few seconds and uses up some of your life energy.</plot>
		<releasedate>01/04/1985</releasedate>
		<year>1985</year>
		<studio>Game Arts</studio>
		<nplayers>1</nplayers>
		<ESRB>Not Rated</ESRB>
		<videoid>QVfRGsfnI_c</videoid>
		<boxart1>http://www.mobygames.com/images/covers/l/296145-thexder-nes-front-cover.jpg</boxart1>
		<snapshot1>https://images.launchbox-app.com/04b7d37a-9dcd-49a4-a192-cdb462b994f1.png</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>https://images.launchbox-app.com/54c7092c-476b-4cf0-8209-9821c34be99a.jpg</snapshot2>
		<clearlogo1>https://images.launchbox-app.com/166028c6-a8ab-424b-91c6-7b22b7091729.png</clearlogo1>
		<genre>Driving,Shooter</genre>
		<groups>Thexder series</groups>
	</game>
	<game name="Thunder Force">
		<description>Thunder Force</description>
		<rom name="sharp-x-1/Sharp_X1.zip/Sharp_X1%2FThunder%20Force%20%281984%20version%29.d88" size="348816"/>
		<plot>Control a lone fighter ship, destroying enemies, weapons, and bases of the evil alien Orn Empire. The player's ship can shoot both air and land targets, and there are many targets of both types to destroy. The goal of each stage is to destroy all of the shield bases, enter the area base, and destroy the core. After shooting the core, the player moves on to the next stage to destroy more bases.</plot>
		<releasedate>26/10/1984</releasedate>
		<year>1984</year>
		<studio>Tecno Soft</studio>
		<nplayers>1</nplayers>
		<ESRB>Not Rated</ESRB>
		<boxart1>http://www.mobygames.com/images/covers/l/545880-thunder-force-pc-6001-front-cover.png</boxart1>
		<snapshot2>https://images.launchbox-app.com/09a0d5d4-4bb8-46d8-b7a6-f6d28d9672b5.png</snapshot2>
		<snapshot3>https://images.launchbox-app.com/47fcab70-565b-49ef-a725-f1cebb890428.png</snapshot3>
		<clearlogo1>https://images.launchbox-app.com/bf1e874c-afbb-47c5-b3db-74f8e25df735.png</clearlogo1>
		<genre>Shooter</genre>
		<groups>Thunder Force series</groups>
	</game>
	<game name="Time Secret">
		<description>Time Secret</description>
		<rom name="sharp-x-1/Sharp_X1.zip/Sharp_X1%2FTime%20Secret.d88" size="348848"/>
		<plot>Time Secret is an adventure game created by Bond Soft in 1984.</plot>
		<boxart1>https://www.giantbomb.com/a/uploads/square_medium/5/59247/1671948-times.png</boxart1>
	</game>
	<game name="Time Tunnel">
		<description>Time Tunnel</description>
		<rom name="sharp-x-1/Sharp_X1.zip/Sharp_X1%2FTime%20Tunnel.d88" size="348848"/>
		<plot>This is the second of the "Time Series" trilogy, and a true hidden gem in the history of Japanese adventures. Though it had been planned as trilogy, the third game was cancelled and so it ended with this game.</plot>
		<boxart1>https://images.launchbox-app.com/f977a4a0-c4f8-42e3-9803-e08cf527124c.jpg</boxart1>
	</game>
	<game name="Topple Zip">
		<description>Topple Zip</description>
		<rom name="sharp-x-1/Sharp_X1.zip/Sharp_X1%2FTopple%20Zip.d88" size="348848"/>
		<plot>Topple Zip is a vertically scrolling shooter that is marketed as a racing game. The basic premise is that you control an aircraft and fly in competition against several other, computer controlled crafts. In addition to shooting at your opponents, you may ram into them, and they into you. Doing so may dislodge a pill shaped power-up from them which you can then shoot and collect. [CR]Power-ups exist in various types, including defensive and offensive such as giving you better weapons. There are eight different levels, each of which contain a number of warps which link to other levels. How the levels connect is random each time you play the game. [CR]The goal of the game is to locate a key which is necessary to access the warp which leads to the eight and final level. Collect it from whichever level it is hidden inside of, and access the eighth level before any of your competitors.</plot>
		<boxart1>http://www.mobygames.com/images/covers/l/328090-topple-zip-msx-front-cover.jpg</boxart1>
		<genre>Shoot Em Up</genre>
	</game>
	<game name="Tritorn">
		<description>Tritorn</description>
		<rom name="sharp-x-1/Sharp_X1.zip/Sharp_X1%2FTritorn.d88" size="339328"/>
		<plot>Everything was peaceful on the island of Rwanda, until the evil demon lord Pay Valusa invaded it, sending hordes of monsters to do his bidding. A lone warrior named Tritorn is the only one who can defeat the demon and restore peace.[CR][I]Tritorn[/I] is, together with Dragon Slayer and Hydlide, an early progenitor of the action role-playing genre. Similarly to Xanadu, exploration is performed from a side view, with jumping and vertical areas, but no true platforming. Unlike the aforementioned games, it is necessary to press the action key to hit enemies rather than simply "bumping" into them.[CR]The gameplay system is very simple, having no weapon or equipment management, monetary system, or friendly areas. The protagonist either attacks enemies with his sword or throws magic balls at them, which come in limited supply. Experience points are awarded for slaying enemies; though there is no clear indicator as to when the player character levels up, he gradually becomes stronger, tougher, and learns new abilities (e.g. walking faster).</plot>
		<boxart1>http://www.mobygames.com/images/covers/l/539324-tritorn-pc-6001-front-cover.png</boxart1>
		<genre>Action,RPG</genre>
		<groups>Tritorn series</groups>
	</game>
	<game name="Trivia Q">
		<description>Trivia Q</description>
		<rom name="sharp-x-1/Sharp_X1.zip/Sharp_X1%2FTrivia%20Q.d88" size="396176"/>
		<plot>Trivia Q was developed by Cross Media Soft and released in 1985</plot>
		<snapshot1>https://www.sockscap64.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/100063687_86158_2.png</snapshot1>
	</game>
	<game name="Ultima 4">
		<description>Ultima 4</description>
		<rom name="sharp-x-1/Sharp_X1.zip/Sharp_X1%2FUltima%20IV%20%28Disk%20A%29.d88" size="359248"/>
		<rom name="sharp-x-1/Sharp_X1.zip/Sharp_X1%2FUltima%20IV%20%28Brittania%20disk%29.d88" size="359248"/>
		<rom name="sharp-x-1/Sharp_X1.zip/Sharp_X1%2FUltima%20IV%20%28Dungeon%20disk%29.d88" size="369648"/>
		<rom name="sharp-x-1/Sharp_X1.zip/Sharp_X1%2FUltima%20IV%20%28Town%20disk%29.d88" size="359248"/>
		<plot>Following the defeat of the evil triad in the previous three Ultima games, the world of Sosaria changed beyond recognition: continents rose and sank, and new cities were built, heralding the advent of a different civilization. Unified by the reign of the benevolent monarch Lord British, the new world was renamed Britannia. Lord British wished to base people's well-being on the ethical principles of Truth, Love, and Courage, proclaiming the Eight Virtues (Honesty, Compassion, Valor, Justice, Sacrifice, Honor, Spirituality, and Humility) as the ideal everyone should strive for. The person who could accomplish full understanding and realization of these virtues would serve as a spiritual leader and a moral example for the inhabitants of Britannia; he alone would be able to obtain holy artifacts, descend into the Stygian Abyss, and access the Codex of Ultimate Wisdom. This person is the Avatar.</plot>
		<boxart1>https://www.mobygames.com/images/covers/l/91366-ultima-iv-quest-of-the-avatar-msx-front-cover.jpg</boxart1>
	</game>
	<game name="Ultra Monogatari">
		<description>Ultra Monogatari</description>
		<rom name="sharp-x-1/Sharp_X1.zip/Sharp_X1%2FUltra%20Monogatari.d88" size="348848"/>
		<genre>Platform</genre>
		<videoid>QDgTOpPJ0Oc</videoid>
		<snapshot1>https://i.ytimg.com/vi/OTD5jTh16NE/hqdefault.jpg</snapshot1>
	</game>
	<game name="Uootoy">
		<description>Uootoy</description>
		<rom name="sharp-x-1/Sharp_X1.zip/Sharp_X1%2FUootoy.d88" size="348848"/>
		<videoid>lo8Fc-djhjE</videoid>
		<boxart1>https://images.launchbox-app.com/eb5d80c4-285c-4bb6-b73c-7d4debdc28e7.jpg</boxart1>
		<snapshot1>https://i.ytimg.com/vi/lo8Fc-djhjE/maxresdefault.jpg</snapshot1>
		<genre>Platform</genre>
	</game>
	<game name="Urusei Yatsura Koi no Survival Birthday">
		<description>Urusei Yatsura Koi no Survival Birthday</description>
		<rom name="sharp-x-1/Sharp_X1.zip/Sharp_X1%2FUrusei%20Yatsura%20-%20Koi%20no%20Survival%20Birthday%20%28Disk%201%29.d88" size="380064"/>
		<rom name="sharp-x-1/Sharp_X1.zip/Sharp_X1%2FUrusei%20Yatsura%20-%20Koi%20no%20Survival%20Birthday%20%28Disk%202%29.d88" size="380848"/>
		<rom name="sharp-x-1/Sharp_X1.zip/Sharp_X1%2FUrusei%20Yatsura%20-%20Koi%20no%20Survival%20Birthday%20%28Disk%203%29.d88" size="380848"/>
		<plot>Scenario is original from the anime. We get and invitation to Okiko birthday party. The person who finds her first is going to get a kiss, so a fierce competition among the invited guests ensues.</plot>
		<nplayers>1</nplayers>
		<boxart1>https://s2.vndb.org/cv/77/11577.jpg</boxart1>
		<snapshot1>https://images.launchbox-app.com/f92d2f2a-1d12-4b76-bf23-7563ff3c1ed9.jpg</snapshot1>
		<genre>Adventure</genre>
	</game>
	<game name="Wibarm">
		<description>Wibarm</description>
		<rom name="sharp-x-1/Sharp_X1.zip/Sharp_X1%2FWibarm%20%28User%20disk%29.d88" size="414992"/>
		<rom name="sharp-x-1/Sharp_X1.zip/Sharp_X1%2FWibarm.d88" size="414992"/>
		<plot>Wibarm, stylized as WiBArM, is an early role-playing shooter released by Arsys Software for the NEC PC-88 computer in Japan. It combines run and gun shooter gameplay with role-playing video game elements, and was also the first action role-playing game to feature 3D polygonal graphics. In Wibarm, the player controls a transformable mecha robot that can shift between walking mode, a tank, and a flying jet. The viewpoint switches between several different perspectives: a 2D top-down perspective while flying, a side-scrolling view during on-foot outdoor exploration, a fully 3D polygonal third-person perspective inside buildings, and arena-style 2D shoot 'em up battles during boss encounters.[CR]The game features a variety of weapons and equipment as well as an automap, and the player can upgrade equipment and earn experience to raise stats. In contrast to first-person RPGs at the time that were restricted to 90-degree movements, Wibarm's use of 3D polygons allows full 360-degree movement.</plot>
		<releasedate>01/08/1986</releasedate>
		<year>1986</year>
		<studio>Arsys Software</studio>
		<nplayers>1</nplayers>
		<boxart1>http://www.mobygames.com/images/covers/l/533763-wibarm-pc-98-front-cover.jpg</boxart1>
		<snapshot1>https://images.launchbox-app.com/4caf9bc1-d69b-462e-8ce9-47fbb1669d30.jpg</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>https://images.launchbox-app.com/86ae39ea-0683-4805-9809-bd76f109f8f9.jpg</snapshot2>
		<snapshot3>https://images.launchbox-app.com/3e236d9c-2f89-4f34-81f8-a3398787460d.jpg</snapshot3>
		<clearlogo1>https://images.launchbox-app.com/dde4183c-fd65-4a3a-a2d8-1b676bad2230.png</clearlogo1>
		<genre>Action,Driving,RPG,Shooter</genre>
	</game>
	<game name="Will The Death Trap 2">
		<description>Will The Death Trap 2</description>
		<rom name="sharp-x-1/Sharp_X1.zip/Sharp_X1%2FWill%20-%20The%20Death%20Trap%20II.d88" size="350432"/>
		<plot>President of the United States of America receives a letter with simple, but blood-chilling words: within the next twenty-four hours, the entire life on Earth will be annihilated. Specialists track the sender of the letter to a small island named Torinia somewhere in the Pacific Ocean. Special agent Benson is sent there with the ultimate mission: find out who sent the letter, or prepare for the destruction of the world...[CR]Will is a sequel to The Death Trap, the first game made by Square. As in the previous game, the locations are represented by graphical images, but the interaction is performed by typing commands. It is now possible to move between locations using the directional keys.</plot>
		<studio>Square</studio>
		<nplayers>1</nplayers>
		<snapshot1>https://images.launchbox-app.com/10c43874-44ad-4067-901e-b6fed70b2931.png</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>https://images.launchbox-app.com/eedd01b0-c5e5-4033-ad69-d62906037b88.png</snapshot2>
		<snapshot3>https://images.launchbox-app.com/4a62790d-6419-483a-a3bd-e019880b2faf.png</snapshot3>
		<genre>Adventure</genre>
		<groups>The Death Trap series</groups>
	</game>
	<game name="Wizardry">
		<description>Wizardry</description>
		<rom name="sharp-x-1/Sharp_X1.zip/Sharp_X1%2FWizardry.d88" size="380048"/>
		<plot>Are you ready to step into the world of Wizardry? Unmatched by any other fantasy role-playing game, the Wizardry Gaming System allows for unlimited combinations of strategies and tactics, so that each quest into the Maze is always fresh and interesting.</plot>
		<boxart1>https://gamefaqs.gamespot.com/a/box/3/8/4/399384_front.jpg</boxart1>
		<genre>RPG</genre>
	</game>
	<game name="Wizardry 2">
		<description>Wizardry 2</description>
		<rom name="sharp-x-1/Sharp_X1.zip/Sharp_X1%2FWizardry%20II.d88" size="380048"/>
		<plot>Wizardry II is a first-person, grid-based,  RPG that is part of a series that had helped to set many standards within the PC-RPG genre with its graphical interface and gameplay mechanics. At the time, the series graphical capabilities and gameplay mechanics were considered revolutionary and innovative for PCs. Wizardry II continues the story begun with the first game and allows players to import characters in from Wizardry I to continue the quest in a new scenario. It is an early example of an expansion pack, requiring the player to have the original Wizardry installed to play. It uses the same engine and spells, but is scaled for importing existing characters rather than creating a new party.</plot>
		<boxart1>https://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/6/6d/Wizardry_II_-_The_Knight_of_Diamonds_Coverart.png</boxart1>
		<snapshot1>https://dungeoncrawlers.org/images/2020/09/5f74d9c2199bd.jpg</snapshot1>
		<genre>RPG</genre>
	</game>
	<game name="Wizardry 3">
		<description>Wizardry 3</description>
		<rom name="sharp-x-1/Sharp_X1.zip/Sharp_X1%2FWizardry%20III.d88" size="380048"/>
		<plot>A generation has passed since your band of adventurers reclaimed the Staff of Gnilda and the armor of the Knight of Diamonds, and the land has been at peace. But now nature itself seems to be attacking the land of Llylgamyn, as earthquakes and tidal waves ravage the land. The Sages believe the Orb of Scrying is the city's salvation, but it is guarded by the dragon L'kbreth. A band of explorers must once again venture forth in search of the Orb. Legacy of Llylgamyn is the third entry in the Wizardry series. Like its predecessors, it is a first-person dungeon-crawling role-playing game in which the player assembles a party of up to six characters and explores a large maze-like dungeon, fighting randomly appearing enemies in turn-based combat and occasionally returning to the game's only town to rest, buy supplies, and outfit the characters. Characters must be imported from either the first or the second game. Character classes, combat system, and overall gameplay mechanics are very similar to those of the two previous games. Good, evil and neutral alignment, however, plays a larger role. While the first level of the dungeon is accessible to everyone, the other five levels impose alignment restrictions, requiring the party either to have at least one good or bad character, or contain no neutral characters.</plot>
		<boxart1>https://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/1/1b/Wizardry_3_cover.jpg</boxart1>
		<snapshot1>https://dungeoncrawlers.org/images/2020/09/5f74d9c2205c1.jpg</snapshot1>
		<genre>RPG</genre>
	</game>
	<game name="Woody Poco">
		<description>Woody Poco</description>
		<rom name="sharp-x-1/Sharp_X1.zip/Sharp_X1%2FWoody%20Poco.d88" size="348848"/>
		<rom name="sharp-x-1/Sharp_X1.zip/Sharp_X1%2FWoody%20Poco%20%28User%20disk%29.d88" size="348848"/>
		<plot>Poco is a wooden boy (or girl, depending on the game version) who was magically given life. Unfortunately, something has happened in the land which has caused them to revert to their original doll form. Wishing once again to be truly alive, they set off an adventure through the kingdom to regain their humanity.</plot>
		<boxart1>http://www.hardcoregaming101.net/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/woodypoco-msx.jpg</boxart1>
		<snapshot1>http://www.hardcoregaming101.net/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/woody-poko-j-a10001.png</snapshot1>
		<genre>Beat Em Up</genre>
		<videoid>aJTcEOy85f4</videoid>
	</game>
	<game name="World Golf 2">
		<description>World Golf 2</description>
		<rom name="sharp-x-1/Sharp_X1.zip/Sharp_X1%2FWorld%20Golf%20II%20%28Disk%20A%29.d88" size="348848"/>
		<rom name="sharp-x-1/Sharp_X1.zip/Sharp_X1%2FWorld%20Golf%20II%20%28Disk%20B%29.d88" size="348848"/>
		<plot>World Golf II is a Sports game, developed and published by Enix Corporation, which was released in Japan in 1988</plot>
		<boxart1>https://gamefaqs.gamespot.com/a/box/7/6/2/459762_front.jpg</boxart1>
		<snapshot1>https://gamefaqs.gamespot.com/a/screen/full/7/4/0/450740.jpg</snapshot1>
		<videoid>3zlWeS0uXDk</videoid>
		<genre>Golf</genre>
	</game>
	<game name="Xanadu">
		<description>Xanadu</description>
		<rom name="sharp-x-1/Sharp_X1.zip/Sharp_X1%2FXanadu%20%28Disk%20A%29.d88" size="415840"/>
		<rom name="sharp-x-1/Sharp_X1.zip/Sharp_X1%2FXanadu%20%28Disk%20B%29.d88" size="415840"/>
		<rom name="sharp-x-1/Sharp_X1.zip/Sharp_X1%2FXanadu%20%28Disk%20C%20-%20User%20disk%29.d88" size="416384"/>
		<plot>Xanadu, also known as Xanadu: Dragon Slayer II, is an action role-playing game developed by Nihon Falcom and released in 1985. It is the second entry in the Dragon Slayer series, preceded by Dragon Slayer and followed by Dragon Slayer Jr: Romancia, which, as most games in the Dragon Slayer series, have very little relation with each other.</plot>
		<boxart1>https://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/8/84/Xanadu_MSX_Cover.jpg</boxart1>
		<snapshot1>https://gamefaqs.gamespot.com/a/screen/full/4/7/3/433473.jpg</snapshot1>
		<genre>RPG</genre>
		<videoid>dJiWB9BrAK8</videoid>
	</game>
	<game name="Xanadu Scenario 2">
		<description>Xanadu Scenario 2</description>
		<rom name="sharp-x-1/Sharp_X1.zip/Sharp_X1%2FXanadu%20Scenario%20II%20%28Recon%20hack%29%20%28OPM%29.d88" size="415840"/>
		<rom name="sharp-x-1/Sharp_X1.zip/Sharp_X1%2FXanadu%20Scenario%20II%20%28Recon%20hack%29%20%28OPM%20MagicKai%29.d88" size="415840"/>
		<plot>[I]Xanadu: Scenario 2[/I] is an expansion pack to Xanadu: Dragon Slayer II. Just like the original game, it is not particularly story-driven; once again, the player is thrown into the medieval fantasy world as a lone nameless hero, who must explore the maze-like environments and stay alive in the process. [CR]This add-on scenario features new, more complex maps, new enemies (including bosses), and a trading system which allows purchasing items in one shop and selling them for profit in another. Otherwise, the gameplay system remains identical to that of the predecessor; with side-scrolling exploration, separate top-down battle screens, "bumping" action-based combat, and role-playing system with levelling up, equipment, etc.[CR]The game requires the original [I]Xanadu[/I] to play; character creation must be done with the original game discs inserted, after which the player can directly access this scenario.</plot>
		<groups>Dragon Slayer universe,Xanadu games</groups>
		<boxart1>https://images.igdb.com/igdb/image/upload/t_cover_big_2x/v1entstok6vmvxotet5m.jpg</boxart1>
		<snapshot1>https://www.mobygames.com/images/shots/l/689707-xanadu-scenario-ii-sharp-x1-screenshot-fighting-orcs.png</snapshot1>
	</game>
	<game name="Xevious">
		<description>Xevious</description>
		<rom name="sharp-x-1/Sharp_X1.zip/Sharp_X1%2FXevious.d88" size="344768"/>
		<plot>A hundred thousand years ago, an ancient civilization prospered on our Earth, their product being GAMP (General Artificial Matrix Producer). In order to survive the Ice Age, most of the Earth's inhabitants have decided to leave it, finally settling on a planet called Xevious. A group of humans remained, becoming our own ancestors. Many years have passed, and the Xevians are now planning a massive comeback to their long-lost homeland. The pilot Mu, his android companion Eve, and Mio, a Xevian who opposes the GAMP regime, are back from a space travel just in time to warn the Earth of the upcoming invasion. The prototype fighter craft Solvalou is going to be used as the main weapon against the Xevian attack.[CR]Xevious is a vertically-scrolling shooter which is notable for being the first game of that type to feature an aircraft flying over the Earth (as opposed to the outer space in other games), displaying views of South American nature. It also introduced, for the first time, two types of enemies to fight: aerial and ground-based (the menacing SOL towers invoked by GAMP to aid their planes). The player-controlled ship, Solvalou, is equipped with two weapons, each assigned to a button: the Zapper for air enemies, and the Blaster, which drops bombs on ground targets with the aid of a lock-on. The aerial enemies are divided into sub-categories distinguished by their attack and behavior patterns. Certain enemy types are immune to Solvalou's weapons, and must be avoided.</plot>
		<studio>Namco Limited</studio>
		<nplayers>1</nplayers>
		<videoid>-XnSqVPh2I4</videoid>
		<boxart1>http://www.mobygames.com/images/covers/l/533819-xevious-pc-6001-front-cover.png</boxart1>
		<snapshot1>https://images.launchbox-app.com/9f241fc8-9219-4ff7-9752-b2ae1d225a82.png</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>https://images.launchbox-app.com/f278103e-fcb4-44bf-be62-91f6d2d0f536.png</snapshot2>
		<clearlogo1>https://images.launchbox-app.com/a8c365fd-0829-4773-b49e-136b36ccf396.png</clearlogo1>
		<genre>Shoot Em Up,Shooter</genre>
		<groups>Classic NES / Famicom Mini / NES Classics releases,Genre: Scrolling shoot 'em up,Xevious series</groups>
	</game>
	<game name="Yaksa">
		<description>Yaksa</description>
		<rom name="sharp-x-1/Sharp_X1.zip/Sharp_X1%2FYaksa%20%28demo%29.d88" size="416416"/>
		<plot>Yaksa is a Role-Playing game, developed and published by Wolf Team, which was released in Japan in 1987.</plot>
		<videoid>7m9JwZyUI4E</videoid>
		<boxart1>https://images.generation-msx.nl/cover/973b7f30.jpg</boxart1>
		<snapshot1>https://i.ytimg.com/vi/7m9JwZyUI4E/maxresdefault.jpg</snapshot1>
	</game>
	<game name="Yoshies Cookie X1">
		<description>Yoshies Cookie X1</description>
		<rom name="sharp-x-1/Sharp_X1.zip/Sharp_X1%2FYoshie%27s%20Cookie%20X1.d88" size="348848"/>
		<genre>Puzzle</genre>
		<videoid>UFhMZEtT-v8</videoid>
		<snapshot1>https://i.ytimg.com/vi/UFhMZEtT-v8/sddefault.jpg</snapshot1>
	</game>
	<game name="Youkai Tantei Chima Chima">
		<description>Youkai Tantei Chima Chima</description>
		<rom name="sharp-x-1/Sharp_X1.zip/Sharp_X1%2FYoukai%20Tantei%20Chima%20Chima.d88" size="348576"/>
		<plot>Another winner of Bothtec's first programming contest, [I]Youkai Tantei Chima Chima[/I] is an arcade game similar to Pac-Man. In this game players will control a cyclops called Chima Chima who will fight against ghosts. In order to defeat the ghosts, Chima Chima shoots bouncing fireballs. These fireballs move together with the protagonist and can kill him so players will need to avoid enemies and have the fireballs explode next to them. Players can receive a bonus score for having blown up more enemies using one fireball. There are 9 stages in total in the game.</plot>
		<boxart1>http://www.mobygames.com/images/covers/l/539288-yokai-tantei-chima-chima-pc-6001-front-cover.png</boxart1>
		<genre>Action</genre>
	</game>
	<game name="Ys">
		<description>Ys</description>
		<rom name="sharp-x-1/Sharp_X1.zip/Sharp_X1%2FYs%20%28Disk%20A%29.d88" size="415840"/>
		<rom name="sharp-x-1/Sharp_X1.zip/Sharp_X1%2FYs%20%28Disk%20B%29.d88" size="415840"/>
		<rom name="sharp-x-1/Sharp_X1.zip/Sharp_X1%2FYs%20%28User%20disk%29.d88" size="348848"/>
		<plot>In this game, the player takes the role of Adol (Aron in the English-language Sega Master System version) Christin, a red-haired adventurer and expert swordsman. One day he encounters a fortune teller who sends him on a quest to find information about the six books of Ys. It appears that there was once an ancient land called Ys, whose secret was sealed in those six books. Before long Adol learns that the six books were all stolen by the evil wizard Dark Fact (Dulk Dekt in the Sega Master System version, Malificus in the English-language computer versions). It is Adol's task to defeat the villain and discover the secret of Ys!</plot>
		<boxart1>https://www.mobygames.com/images/covers/l/310-ys-the-vanished-omens-dos-front-cover.jpg</boxart1>
		<snapshot1>https://www.mobygames.com/images/shots/l/257835-ys-the-vanished-omens-apple-iigs-screenshot-adol-starts-out.png</snapshot1>
	</game>
	<game name="Ys 2">
		<description>Ys 2</description>
		<rom name="sharp-x-1/Sharp_X1.zip/Sharp_X1%2FYs%20II%20%28Disk%201%20-%20Program%20disk%29.d88" size="415840"/>
		<rom name="sharp-x-1/Sharp_X1.zip/Sharp_X1%2FYs%20II%20%28Disk%203%20-%20Disk%20A%29.d88" size="415840"/>
		<rom name="sharp-x-1/Sharp_X1.zip/Sharp_X1%2FYs%20II%20%28Disk%204%20-%20Disk%20B%29.d88" size="415840"/>
		<rom name="sharp-x-1/Sharp_X1.zip/Sharp_X1%2FYs%20II%20%28Disk%202%20-%20User%20disk%29.d88" size="33952"/>
		<plot>A bright light shot up from Darm Tower in the end of the first Ys, and Adol Christin is awakened by a young girl who finds him lying on the ground. She introduces herself as Lilia and tells Adol he is in the land of Ys. Finally he was able to establish a connection between his world and this mysterious land! But finding the gateway to Ys is not enough: Adol must stop an evil entity that his archenemy Dark Fact served. And his foes already know where he is.</plot>
		<boxart1>https://www.mobygames.com/images/covers/l/84394-ys-ii-ancient-ys-vanished-the-final-chapter-msx-front-cover.jpg</boxart1>
		<snapshot1>https://www.mobygames.com/images/shots/l/566688-ys-ii-ancient-ys-vanished-the-final-chapter-fm-7-screenshot.png</snapshot1>
	</game>
	<game name="Ys III Wanderers from Ys">
		<description>Ys III Wanderers from Ys</description>
		<rom name="sharp-x-1/Sharp_X1.zip/Sharp_X1%2FYs%20III%20-%20Wanderers%20from%20Ys%20%28Disk%201%20-%20Program%20disk%29.d88" size="415840"/>
		<rom name="sharp-x-1/Sharp_X1.zip/Sharp_X1%2FYs%20III%20-%20Wanderers%20from%20Ys%20%28Disk%202%20-%20Scenario%20disk%29.d88" size="415840"/>
		<rom name="sharp-x-1/Sharp_X1.zip/Sharp_X1%2FYs%20III%20-%20Wanderers%20from%20Ys%20%28Disk%203%20-%20Data%201%29.d88" size="415840"/>
		<rom name="sharp-x-1/Sharp_X1.zip/Sharp_X1%2FYs%20III%20-%20Wanderers%20from%20Ys%20%28Disk%204%20-%20Data%202%29.d88" size="415840"/>
		<plot>Adol Christin's long-time friend, Dogi, wishes to return to his home town of Redmont after hearing about strange disturbances that are happening there. Always looking for an adventure, Adol joins him and soon finds out the cause of this new evil.[CR]Ys III: Wanderers from Ys breaks away from the "bumping into enemies" battle system of the first two games, allowing Adol to control his sword in a variety of directions. Beside changing the battle system, the game's perspective switches to a side-scrolling view, as opposed to the top-down one of the previous games. Adol also has the ability to jump now. New to the series is the use of magical rings, which give Adol different powering-up abilities such as healing and shielding. The game also uses various key items found along the way to solve minor puzzles and progress the story.</plot>
		<releasedate>24/03/1990</releasedate>
		<year>1990</year>
		<studio>Nihon Falcom Corp.</studio>
		<nplayers>1</nplayers>
		<videoid>PGVkHMWC-1o</videoid>
		<boxart1>http://www.mobygames.com/images/covers/l/84392-ys-iii-wanderers-from-ys-msx-front-cover.jpg</boxart1>
		<boxart3>https://images.launchbox-app.com/2fdbcf0f-7854-46bd-84f2-4ec789c48f4f.jpg</boxart3>
		<snapshot1>https://images.launchbox-app.com/0b3f4f94-42d0-45dc-96e9-e78eecf19469.png</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>https://images.launchbox-app.com/ca4e6575-5e70-4313-b86d-3a5398a2a514.png</snapshot2>
		<snapshot3>https://images.launchbox-app.com/91ef819a-a76a-49e4-9168-88490a340c8f.jpg</snapshot3>
		<snapshot4>https://images.launchbox-app.com/8b2df0ee-0cfa-4563-8665-7643d2df781b.jpg</snapshot4>
		<fanart1>https://images.launchbox-app.com/b348661d-6627-40f9-902c-489b83ef8315.jpg</fanart1>
		<fanart2>https://images.launchbox-app.com/64373f4c-8195-402c-ac22-43e95699fc9d.jpg</fanart2>
		<genre>RPG</genre>
		<groups>Ys series</groups>
	</game>
	<game name="Zeliard">
		<description>Zeliard</description>
		<rom name="sharp-x-1/Sharp_X1.zip/Sharp_X1%2FZeliard%20%28Disk%201%29.d88" size="392368"/>
		<rom name="sharp-x-1/Sharp_X1.zip/Sharp_X1%2FZeliard%20%28Disk%202%29.d88" size="392368"/>
		<rom name="sharp-x-1/Sharp_X1.zip/Sharp_X1%2FZeliard%20%28Disk%203%29.d88" size="392368"/>
		<rom name="sharp-x-1/Sharp_X1.zip/Sharp_X1%2FZeliard%20%28User%20disk%29.d88" size="392368"/>
		<plot>The ancient demon Jashiin has slept for two thousand years. When he awakens, he directs his wrath towards the kingdom of Zeliard, whose rulers of yore have allegedly harmed him. For 115 days, a sand rain devastates the kingdom, turning it into a desert. To complete his cruel revenge, Jashiin turns Felicia, the princess of Zeliard, into a stone. The valiant Duke Garland sets out on a quest to vanquish the demon and restore the princess to her true form. To do that, he must collect the Nine Tears of Esmesanti, which alone can reverse the terrible curse.[CR]Zeliard is a side-scrolling action game with platforming and role-playing elements. The game world is divided into hostile labyrinths, which occupy its largest portion and contain maze-like passages for Duke Garland to traverse, as well as enemies that must be dealt with. Crests and keys must often be collected in order to ensure the progress to the next area. Garland takes damage from enemy attacks as well as the environment (hidden spikes, high temperature, etc.), but suffers no damage should he fall off a platform.[CR]The hero uses his sword to combat the enemies, and shield to defend himself. He can also learn and cast projectile offensive magic. Special items can restore his health, increase the damage inflicted with the sword, grant additional protection, etc. Various types of clothes can be equipped; these can bestow the hero with further enhancements and immunities, such as prevent him from slipping on ice, allow him to jump higher, etc.[CR]The Duke will visit different towns during his journey. In these towns, he can rest, replenishing his health, purchase and repair weapons and armor, acquire potions, and learn magic spells. Currency is obtained by exchanging enemy spirits for gold in banks. These spirits (called "almas") also serve as experience points: after the player has obtained a sufficient amount of them, the protagonist receives upgrades to his health and magic points from a local town sage.</plot>
		<studio>Game Arts</studio>
		<nplayers>1</nplayers>
		<boxart1>http://www.mobygames.com/images/covers/l/9461-zeliard-dos-front-cover.jpg</boxart1>
		<snapshot1>https://images.launchbox-app.com/fdf45b87-365c-470b-aa6b-0764dc14196b.png</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>https://images.launchbox-app.com/5addd725-3e0c-4364-b314-b6268d06019b.png</snapshot2>
		<snapshot3>https://images.launchbox-app.com/94a9172f-1071-477b-80d7-5265096a3452.png</snapshot3>
		<genre>Action,RPG</genre>
	</game>
</datafile>