<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<datafile>
	<header>
		<emu_name>Wolfenstein 3D</emu_name>
		<emu_description>Standalone Game</emu_description>
		<emu_category>Port</emu_category>
		<emu_version>02242020</emu_version>
		<emu_date>4/24/2020</emu_date>
		<emu_author>Zach Morris</emu_author>
		<emu_visibility>visible</emu_visibility>
		<emu_homepage>https://archive.org</emu_homepage>
		<emu_baseurl>https://archive.org/download/</emu_baseurl>
		<emu_launcher>retroplayer</emu_launcher>
		<emu_default_addon>none</emu_default_addon>
		<emu_ext_launch_cmd>none</emu_ext_launch_cmd>
		<emu_downloadpath>default</emu_downloadpath>
		<emu_postdlaction>unzip_and_launch_file</emu_postdlaction>
		<emu_comment>Wolfenstein 3D and supported Wolfenstein engine games for use with ECWolf.[CR]Wolfenstein 3D is a first-person shooter video game developed by id Software and published by Apogee Software and FormGen. Originally released on May 5, 1992 for MS-DOS, it was inspired by the 1981 Muse Software video game Castle Wolfenstein, and is the third installment in the Wolfenstein series. In Wolfenstein 3D, the player assumes the role of Allied spy William B.J. Blazkowicz during World War II as he escapes from the Nazi German prison Castle Wolfenstein and carries out a series of crucial missions against the Nazis. The player traverses each of the game's levels to find an elevator to the next level or kill a final boss, fighting Nazi soldiers, dogs, and other enemies with knives and a variety of guns.</emu_comment>
		<emu_thumb>CQCGGLR.jpg</emu_thumb>
		<emu_banner>VvxROoS.jpg</emu_banner>
		<emu_fanart>3tJcoeI.jpg</emu_fanart>
		<emu_logo>JdSuV2i.png</emu_logo>
		<emu_trailer>7P_dic-pSKo</emu_trailer>
	</header>
	<game name="Super Noahs Ark 3D">
		<description>Super Noahs Ark 3D</description>
		<rom name="ECWolf/Super_Noahs_Ark_3D.zip" size="550700" />
		<plot>Super Noah's Ark 3-D is a First Person Shooter based on the Wolfenstein engine with a biblical twist.[CR]As Noah, the player travels around the Ark feeding the restless animals in order to put them to sleep; this is achieved by firing feed (ammo) at them using a variety of hand catapults.[CR]The SNES version is largely a reskin of the SNES version of Wolfenstein 3D, the only notable difference being slightly altered behaviour for a couple of bad guys. Even your weapons are reskins that behave exactly like the guns from Wolf3D; Noah must be very skilled to operate a catapult at the speed of a machine gun![CR]The PC version however, while still a reskin of Wolf3D in gameplay has some more advanced features; higher resolution graphics (along the lines of the Jaguar and 3DO versions of the game, albeit with all 8 directions like the original PC version), midi music support, floor textures (like Blake Stone) and a new game play feature in the form of a question mark pickup; picking one up pauses the game and brings up a random multiple choice question about content in the bible. Answer the question correctly and you get a bunch of ammo and points.</plot>
		<year>1994</year>
		<genre>FPS,Action,Educational</genre>
		<nplayers>1</nplayers>
		<videoid>luwFRUhmJ18</videoid>
		<boxart1>yOK4q2u.jpg</boxart1>
		<snapshot1>iLVxCwG.png</snapshot1>
		<clearlogo1>E2sqiC2.png</clearlogo1>
		<emu_command>Super_Noahs_Ark_3D.N3D</emu_command>
	</game>
	<game name="Wolfenstein 3D">
		<description>Wolfenstein 3D</description>
		<rom name="ECWolf/Wolfenstein_3D_Full.zip" size="1000000" />
		<plot>Wolfenstein 3D is an episodic first-person shooter and a follow-up to the top-down infiltration game Castle Wolfenstein. The game puts the player in the boots of B.J. Blazkowicz, an allied spy. There are six episodes: the first distributed complete as shareware; the second and the third available after registration; and the three final missions (which happen before the events of the first episode) available in the Nocturnal Missions pack.[CR]In the first episode (Escape from Wolfenstein), B.J. is captured, but overpowers a guard with the help of a concealed knife and manages to get out of his cell. Throughout the next nine levels the player guides B.J. searching for an escape from Wolfenstein, guarded by Hans Grosse. After returning to Allied territory, B.J. is given the instructions to Operation: Eisenfaust, where he has to stop Dr. Schabbs and his army of mutant prototypes before they are released into the battlefields. The final mission (Die, Führer, Die!) has a simple goal: infiltrate the bunker under the Reichstag, and terminate Hitler (in a robotic suit) himself.[CR]The Nocturnal Missions are focused on the Nazi plans for chemical warfare, and start with Dark Secret, where B.J. hunts for lead researcher Dr. Otto Giftmacher. It's followed by Trail of the Madman, where the goal is capturing the war plans guarded by Gretel Grosse, and the final episode Confrontation, where B.J. meets General Fettgesicht, the planner for the chemical assault.[CR]Each episode has nine levels (eight regular and a final boss level), plus a secret level activated by an hidden switch somewhere in the eight first levels. Regular levels often feature a maze-like appearance or large areas with many enemies (the number of them on each area depends on the difficulty level), where the player must reach the exit elevator. To do so, he must kill the enemies (while it's possible to move behind the guards' backs and even there's a slight bonus in attacking them from behind, most enemies have to be dealt with by fire power), and depending on the level, activate "push walls" and/or get silver and golden keys to open certain doors.[CR]Many objects can be found in a level, from medikits, chicken meals, and even dog food (to restore health), ammo and treasures, which solely exist for points. There are four weapons (knife, pistol, machine gun and Gatling), all of them using the same bullets except the knife. The knife and the pistol are given at the start of the level, while the machine gun is either found (usually in secret areas) or picked up from SS troopers, and the Gatling is always dropped somewhere in the level. There are five kinds of enemies (excluding bosses) - Dogs (fast, but more a nuisance than life-threatening), Army Soldiers (dressed in regular brown outfit, not very powerful but usually found in large groups), Officers (dressed in white, armed with a very accurate pistol and tough to kill), SS Troopers (blue attire, armed with a machine gun and tough to kill), and Mutants (the rarest and toughest of regular enemies, pale-skinned troopers with green clothes and a machine gun stuck in their chest).[CR]The player character has a number of lives; once he loses the last life, the game ends. To win extra lives, the player has to either find the 1-up item in the level or get 20,000 points (by killing enemies and capturing treasures or completing a level below the 'par' time while killing all enemies, finding all secrets by pushing walls, and collecting all treasure points).</plot>
		<year>1992</year>
		<genre>FPS,Action,Shooter</genre>
		<nplayers>1</nplayers>
		<videoid>x8o0a5ntxfc</videoid>
		<boxart1>8UplnAH.jpg</boxart1>
		<boxart2>CXTpTsv.jpg</boxart2>
		<snapshot1>bupE5XG.png</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>m5lNGkC.gif</snapshot2>
		<fanart1>3tJcoeI.jpg</fanart1>
		<clearlogo1>D6tdXHq.png</clearlogo1>
		<emu_command>Wolfenstein_3D_Full.WL6</emu_command>
	</game>
	<game name="Mission 2: Return to Danger">
		<description>Mission 2: Return to Danger</description>
		<rom name="ECWolf/Wolfenstein_3D_Return_to_Danger.zip" size="1600000" />
		<plot>Mission 2: Return to Danger is an accessory pack to Spear of Destiny released by FormGen Corporation in May 1994, which, along with the similar Mission 3: Ultimate Challenge have been called the Mission packs of Spear of Destiny.[CR]Six weeks after the Spear of Destiny has been brought out of enemy hands, the Axis mounts a successful commando raid to recover it! After a bloody battle and narrow escape, it's taken to the Nazis' Secret Scandinavian Base, excavated from the solid rock of a fjord. The fortress is said to be impregnable![CR]The Nazis have recaptured the Spear of Destiny and taken it deep in the heart of their Secret Scandinavian Base. The base was built to carry out top secret scientific research, with the ultimate goal of creating an atomic bomb. B.J. Blazkowicz is once again called upon to infiltrate the heavily guarded base and retrieve the Spear.</plot>
		<year>1994</year>
		<genre>FPS,Action,Shooter</genre>
		<nplayers>1</nplayers>
		<videoid>0cuJfaFM7dI</videoid>
		<boxart1>gTbrz0b.jpg</boxart1>
		<boxart2>MmR3VHg.jpg</boxart2>
		<fanart1>rGlVHoq.jpg</fanart1>
		<snapshot1>DSHjXCK.png</snapshot1>
		<clearlogo1>qZt0jbW.png</clearlogo1>
		<emu_command>Wolfenstein_3D_Return_to_Danger.SOD</emu_command>
	</game>
	<game name="Mission 3: Ultimate Challenge">
		<description>Mission 3: Ultimate Challenge</description>
		<rom name="ECWolf/Wolfenstein_3D_Ultimate_Challenge.zip" size="1600000" />
		<plot>Mission 3: Ultimate Challenge is an "accessory pack" to Spear of Destiny released by FormGen Corporation in May 1994, which, along with the similar Mission 2: Return to Danger has been called the Mission packs of Spear of Destiny.[CR]As the Allies' top agent, you face your toughest challenge yet! Learning from his past mistakes, Hitler has expanded his subterranean command bunker beneath the chancellery in Berlin so that he can keep the Spear of Destiny nearby and well-guarded![CR]Calling upon the dark forces of the occult, Hitler can see into the future and obtain the plans to future weapon systems![CR]Having recaptured the Spear once again, Hitler has made a blood pact with the demon Abigor and has gained knowledge of future weapons systems. He has started developing them in his subterranean bunker. B.J. Blazkowicz is tasked to yet again retrieve the Spear and put an end to the Nazis' mad plans.</plot>
		<year>1994</year>
		<genre>FPS,Action,Shooter</genre>
		<nplayers>1</nplayers>
		<videoid>CHSixrXQ9Og</videoid>
		<boxart1>oWC3rIc.jpg</boxart1>
		<boxart2>ceBFsmJ.jpg</boxart2>
		<snapshot1>PqHrxjA.png</snapshot1>
		<fanart1>rGlVHoq.jpg</fanart1>
		<clearlogo1>qZt0jbW.png</clearlogo1>
		<emu_command>Wolfenstein_3D_Ultimate_Challenge.SOD</emu_command>
	</game>
	<game name="Spear of Destiny">
		<description>Spear of Destiny</description>
		<rom name="ECWolf/Wolfenstein_3D_Spear_of_Destiny.zip" size="1400000" />
		<plot>It's World War II and you are B.J. Blazkowicz, the Allies' most valuable agent. In the midst of the German Blitzkrieg, the Spear that pierced the side of Christ is taken from Versailles by the Nazis and secured in the impregnable Castle Wolfenstein. According to legend, no man can be defeated when he has the Spear. Hitler believes himself to be invincible with the power of the Spear as his brutal army sweeps across Europe.[CR]Your mission is to infiltrate the heavily guarded Nazi stronghold and recapture the Spear from an already unbalanced Hitler. The loss of his most coveted weapon could push him over the edge. It could also get you ripped to pieces.[CR]Spear of Destiny is a prequel to Wolfenstein 3-D. It is a first-person shooter that uses the same engine and has the same gameplay, however the game is not divided into 6 separate episodes - all the levels are one long episode.[CR]The enemies and weapons are pretty much the same as in Wolfenstein 3-D. Only new additions include: new bosses, a new type of enemy, and a new pickup (a large box of ammo).</plot>
		<year>1992</year>
		<genre>FPS,Action,Shooter</genre>
		<nplayers>1</nplayers>
		<videoid>gYfSJQ9mjww</videoid>
		<boxart1>UCu13oY.jpg</boxart1>
		<boxart2>EtFBaf0.jpg</boxart2>
		<snapshot1>nFCoMN8.gif</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>qEXZRiy.gif</snapshot2>
		<fanart1>rGlVHoq.jpg</fanart1>
		<clearlogo1>qZt0jbW.png</clearlogo1>
		<emu_command>Wolfenstein_3D_Spear_of_Destiny.SOD</emu_command>
	</game>
</datafile>