<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<datafile>
	<header>
		<emu_name>WonderSwan</emu_name>
		<emu_description>WonderSwan</emu_description>
		<emu_category>Handheld, Bandai, 16 Bit, 1990s</emu_category>
		<emu_version>04012018</emu_version>
		<emu_date>03/03/2015</emu_date>
		<emu_author>Zach Morris</emu_author>
		<emu_visibility>visible</emu_visibility>
		<emu_homepage>http://www.no-intro.org</emu_homepage>
		<emu_baseurl>https://archive.org/download/</emu_baseurl>
		<emu_launcher>retroplayer</emu_launcher>
		<emu_default_addon>none</emu_default_addon>
		<emu_ext_launch_cmd>none</emu_ext_launch_cmd>
		<emu_downloadpath>default</emu_downloadpath>
		<emu_postdlaction>unzip_rom</emu_postdlaction>
		<emu_comment>The WonderSwan was a line of handheld game consoles produced in Japan by Bandai. It was developed by Gunpei Yokois company Koto and Bandai. The WonderSwan was made to compete with the Neo Geo Pocket Color and the market leader Nintendos Game Boy Color (even though the developer for the WonderSwan, Gunpei Yokoi, developed the original Nintendo Game Boy). The original WonderSwan was later replaced by the WonderSwan Color, although some WonderSwan Color games are compatible with the original WonderSwan, many are designed exclusively for the WonderSwan Color and show a message such as "This cartridge is for WonderSwan Color only" when run on the original WonderSwan. The WonderSwan is playable both vertically and horizontally, and feature a fairly large library of games, including numerous first-party titles based on licensed anime properties, with significant third-party support from Square and Capcom. As it was a console designed essentially for the Japanese market, most of the games are in Japanese, with only a few featuring English text.[CR]Developer:Bandai[CR]Manufacturer:Bandai[CR]CPU:  16-bit NEC V30 MZ processor at 3.072 MHz[CR]Memory:  Built-in EEPROM and 1Kbit RAM[CR]Sound: 4 digital audio channels[CR]Display:  224 x 144[CR]Media:  Cartridge[CR]Max Controllers:  1</emu_comment>
		<emu_thumb>d8gMqxx.jpg</emu_thumb>
		<emu_banner>lsatiUJ.jpg</emu_banner>
		<emu_fanart>jhXsAUo.jpg</emu_fanart>
		<emu_logo>cXmTkkp.png</emu_logo>
		<emu_trailer>YEpnxE5zPos</emu_trailer>
	</header>
	<game name="Anchorz Field (Japan)">
		<description>Anchorz Field (Japan)</description>
		<rom crc="425EB893" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan.zip/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan%2FAnchorz%20Field%20%28Japan%29.zip" sha1="06447C248AFCE04C4F4A1C3B5F7A4AB6F383C94B" size="417023" />
		<title_clean>Anchorz Field</title_clean>
		<plot>Anchorz Field is a Strategy game, developed and published by Sammy Studios, which was released in Japan in 1999.</plot>
		<releasedate>24/6/1999</releasedate>
		<year>1999</year>
		<genre>Strategy</genre>
		<nplayers>1-2 Alt</nplayers>
		<rating>10</rating>
		<thegamesdb_id>27587</thegamesdb_id>
		<giantbomb_url>https://www.giantbomb.com/anchor-field-z/3030-31031/</giantbomb_url>
		<boxart1>FhPuR7Y.jpg</boxart1>
		<snapshot1>OAZTCwh.png</snapshot1>
	</game>
	<game name="Armored Unit (Japan)">
		<description>Armored Unit (Japan)</description>
		<rom crc="C11639AF" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan.zip/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan%2FArmored%20Unit%20%28Japan%29.zip" sha1="AE5E4F06F07FE13A48F414A1CD437A816E9AD2E7" size="166733" />
		<title_clean>Armored Unit</title_clean>
		<plot>Armored Unit is a Strategy game, published by Sammy Studios, which was released in Japan in 1999.</plot>
		<releasedate>18/11/1999</releasedate>
		<year>1999</year>
		<genre>Strategy</genre>
		<studio>Sammy Corporation</studio>
		<nplayers>1-2 Alt</nplayers>
		<thegamesdb_id>27588</thegamesdb_id>
		<mobygames_url>https://www.mobygames.com/game/wonderswan/armored-unit</mobygames_url>
		<giantbomb_url>https://www.giantbomb.com/armored-unit/3030-31077/</giantbomb_url>
		<boxart1>33M5DjJ.jpg</boxart1>
		<boxart2>Asj6RmC.jpg</boxart2>
		<boxart3>DzcNFGd.jpg</boxart3>
		<snapshot1>1LWaPN4.png</snapshot1>
	</game>
	<game name="Bakusou Dekotora Densetsu for WonderSwan (Japan)">
		<description>Bakusou Dekotora Densetsu for WonderSwan (Japan)</description>
		<rom crc="392DD813" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan.zip/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan%2FBakusou%20Dekotora%20Densetsu%20for%20WonderSwan%20%28Japan%29.zip" sha1="821BB81917445B63AC663C706AB4CE27DE28543F" size="1544152" />
		<title_clean>Bakusou Dekotora Densetsu for WonderSwan</title_clean>
		<plot>You are a young man who lives in Japan and likes driving trucks. There is a competition of truck drivers who deliver goods all across the country. Willing to impress your girlfriend Yukie, you decide to participate in the races and to win the title of the best trucker in Japan.[CR]Dekotora is short for "decorated truck", and this racing game consists not only of driving your truck through the highway, trying to be faster than your rivals, but also of buying various stuff for your truck and decorating it. Depending on your results in the races, you can buy truck parts and customize it the way you wish.</plot>
		<releasedate>29/12/1999</releasedate>
		<year>1999</year>
		<genre>Driving, Racing, Simulation</genre>
		<studio>Naxat Soft</studio>
		<nplayers>1-2 Sim</nplayers>
		<perspective>Top-Down</perspective>
		<mobygames_url>https://www.mobygames.com/game/wonderswan/bakus-dekotora-densetsu-for-wonderswan</mobygames_url>
		<giantbomb_url>https://www.giantbomb.com/bakusou-dekotara-densetsu-for-wonderswan/3030-9483/</giantbomb_url>
		<boxart1>9nSVoFJ.jpg</boxart1>
		<boxart2>1wV92TH.jpg</boxart2>
		<boxart3>plALfLm.jpg</boxart3>
		<snapshot1>J2d4rYw.png</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>3cHRf2K.gif</snapshot2>
		<snapshot3>xqpR46G.gif</snapshot3>
		<snapshot4>XJvEKsX.gif</snapshot4>
		<snapshot5>N48jJ7Q.gif</snapshot5>
		<snapshot6>5LeHpUz.gif</snapshot6>
		<snapshot7>ju7hMxM.gif</snapshot7>
		<snapshot8>MEX0X24.gif</snapshot8>
		<snapshot9>NTWbwc4.gif</snapshot9>
		<snapshot10>DsDFLey.gif</snapshot10>
	</game>
	<game name="Beatmania for WonderSwan (Japan)">
		<description>Beatmania for WonderSwan (Japan)</description>
		<rom crc="324622C9" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan.zip/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan%2FBeatmania%20for%20WonderSwan%20%28Japan%29.zip" sha1="544E76133FA53FC0AE5E00E3465B9CF634F14FD0" size="11795455" />
		<title_clean>Beatmania for WonderSwan</title_clean>
		<plot>This is a portable version of beatmania and as such it contains everything one could hope for in such a game, a series of music track (with reproduced vocals!), a lot of buttons to press, and a lot of vinyl to scratch.[CR]After you select the music you want to play you'll have a vertical scroll which will indicate when you should hit one of the left directional buttons along with the music. The game also indicates when you should 'scratch' which should be be familiar to anyone who has played a beatmania arcade game. This refers to the scratching of a record, one might think that the WonderSwan is ill-equiped for such a for of input, well think again! beatmania for WonderSwan included in its packaging a miniature record that could be fitted over the right directional keys to  make scratching more realistic.[CR]As you finish songs you'll on lock more difficult and interesting(?) tunes. The game plays vertically.</plot>
		<releasedate>28/4/1999</releasedate>
		<year>1999</year>
		<studio>Konami Co.</studio>
		<nplayers>1-2 Sim</nplayers>
		<mobygames_url>https://www.mobygames.com/game/wonderswan/beatmania-for-wonderswan</mobygames_url>
		<giantbomb_url>https://www.giantbomb.com/beatmania/3030-31083/</giantbomb_url>
		<boxart1>p4sHYcb.jpg</boxart1>
		<boxart3>VFwPl2r.jpg</boxart3>
		<snapshot1>9gJcQYi.png</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>HPidZ7J.png</snapshot2>
		<snapshot3>VmsdJPx.png</snapshot3>
		<snapshot4>FF7tWVa.png</snapshot4>
		<snapshot5>vUbfkgJ.png</snapshot5>
		<snapshot6>SGjgGFL.png</snapshot6>
		<snapshot7>Z9azsRw.png</snapshot7>
		<snapshot8>SuzcRbc.png</snapshot8>
		<snapshot9>TGT66t6.png</snapshot9>
		<snapshot10>B2FCeWv.png</snapshot10>
	</game>
	<game name="Buffers Evolution (Japan)">
		<description>Buffers Evolution (Japan)</description>
		<rom crc="B25A0635" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan.zip/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan%2FBuffers%20Evolution%20%28Japan%29.zip" sha1="35EEA568F756BACF533BB9AAAD7E3239BA00E411" size="879351" />
		<title_clean>Buffers Evolution</title_clean>
		<plot>In a post-apocalyptic future a gambling syndicate seeks to make a quick buck in the gritty remains of earth. By fusing the best of animal and mechanical traits they create three bestial androids from a bird, a lion, and a rhinoceros. Bets are taken and then the robots are loosed into hostile mazes of scrap metal on old earth. Maybe they'll even make it back alive...[CR]The goal of BUFFERS EVOLUTION is to run through a course while collecting ten parts in the best time possible. The courses are large and vary between jungle scenes, deserts, old factories, and general mechanical wastes. These areas are cased in by electricity to stop the contests from escaping and thereby ruining the entertainment of the masses. This will keep you in the bounds of the course. With the press of a button your character will momentarily turn into a 'buffer', a sharp pisiform metallic object, while being a buffer you can destroy enemies by slamming into them, this will often bounce you in a given direction, which is useful for reaching high ledges. [CR]Although you do not need to get all the parts to clear an area special items can be accrued by collection parts, while on the course proper these parts will heal any damage you may have taken. Perhaps if you collect all the part in all nine areas you'll have the means to escape you captors? [CR][B]Gameplay:[/B] is reminiscent of Sonic the Hedghog[CR] although in those games you race against a countdown while here you are merely trying to get good times.</plot>
		<releasedate>9/12/1999</releasedate>
		<year>1999</year>
		<genre>Action, Driving, Racing</genre>
		<studio>Bandai Co.</studio>
		<nplayers>1</nplayers>
		<perspective>Platform</perspective>
		<thegamesdb_id>19613</thegamesdb_id>
		<mobygames_url>https://www.mobygames.com/game/wonderswan/buffers-evolution</mobygames_url>
		<giantbomb_url>https://www.giantbomb.com/buffers-evolution/3030-31085/</giantbomb_url>
		<boxart1>ZKLRgqP.jpg</boxart1>
		<boxart2>Vbaj0OG.jpg</boxart2>
		<boxart3>m3XLzml.jpg</boxart3>
		<snapshot1>FkDa5I7.png</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>2VgNCG3.png</snapshot2>
		<snapshot3>4uus8SO.png</snapshot3>
		<snapshot4>ozmQBFr.png</snapshot4>
		<snapshot5>vlW90gg.png</snapshot5>
		<snapshot6>kzeNhR3.png</snapshot6>
		<snapshot7>zURL6YN.png</snapshot7>
		<snapshot8>e2O45ed.png</snapshot8>
		<snapshot9>HEc57Ft.png</snapshot9>
		<snapshot10>JDT3uzN.png</snapshot10>
	</game>
	<game name="Cardcaptor Sakura - Sakura to Fushigi na Clow Card (Japan)">
		<description>Cardcaptor Sakura - Sakura to Fushigi na Clow Card (Japan)</description>
		<rom crc="7F3A14C0" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan.zip/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan%2FCardcaptor%20Sakura%20-%20Sakura%20to%20Fushigi%20na%20Clow%20Card%20%28Japan%29.zip" sha1="39E9A897B681B2C326B052827D7C534F22290286" size="846097" />
		<title_clean>Cardcaptor Sakura - Sakura to Fushigi na Clow Card</title_clean>
		<plot>Card Captor Sakura: Sakura to Fushigi na Clow Card is a Role-Playing game, developed by Sims and published by Bandai, which was released in Japan in 1999.</plot>
		<releasedate>2/12/1999</releasedate>
		<genre>RPG</genre>
		<nplayers>1-2 Alt</nplayers>
		<thegamesdb_id>27590</thegamesdb_id>
		<giantbomb_url>https://www.giantbomb.com/cardcaptor-sakura-sakura-to-fushigi-na-clow-cards/3030-33561/</giantbomb_url>
		<boxart1>8wmQtSo.jpg</boxart1>
		<snapshot1>ZZ5Egng.png</snapshot1>
	</game>
	<game name="Chaos Gear - Michibikareshi Mono (Japan)">
		<description>Chaos Gear - Michibikareshi Mono (Japan)</description>
		<rom crc="27B3CC18" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan.zip/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan%2FChaos%20Gear%20-%20Michibikareshi%20Mono%20%28Japan%29.zip" sha1="E212BBA4FAC51BBFCF440966DA0E67B1686DCFC5" size="1134699" />
		<title_clean>Chaos Gear - Michibikareshi Mono</title_clean>
		<plot>Chaos Gear: Michibi Kareshi Mono is a Strategy game, developed by Lay-Up and published by Bandai, which was released in Japan in 1999.</plot>
		<releasedate>10/6/1999</releasedate>
		<genre>Strategy</genre>
		<nplayers>1-2 Alt</nplayers>
		<thegamesdb_id>19546</thegamesdb_id>
		<giantbomb_url>https://www.giantbomb.com/chaos-gear-michibi-kareshi-mono/3030-51280/</giantbomb_url>
		<boxart1>1LDBgMw.jpg</boxart1>
		<boxart2>7NwuLbM.jpg</boxart2>
		<snapshot1>DZwQGp9.png</snapshot1>
	</game>
	<game name="Chocobo no Fushigi na Dungeon for WonderSwan (Japan)">
		<description>Chocobo no Fushigi na Dungeon for WonderSwan (Japan)</description>
		<rom crc="CCAA4853" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan.zip/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan%2FChocobo%20no%20Fushigi%20na%20Dungeon%20for%20WonderSwan%20%28Japan%29.zip" sha1="3B62FD2841602F1077270848AB7A3AAD58712EE9" size="1033565" />
		<title_clean>Chocobo no Fushigi na Dungeon for WonderSwan</title_clean>
		<releasedate>23/12/1997</releasedate>
		<giantbomb_url>https://www.giantbomb.com/chocobo-no-fushigina-dungeon/3030-21782/</giantbomb_url>
		<boxart1>C61UU52.jpg</boxart1>
		<snapshot1>DEwQJBa.png</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>fX1NhQR.jpg</snapshot2>
		<snapshot3>xk2GYHp.jpg</snapshot3>
		<snapshot4>xJPZcVB.jpg</snapshot4>
		<snapshot5>EPLvwmb.jpg</snapshot5>
		<snapshot6>XMFxJr2.jpg</snapshot6>
		<snapshot7>DDHy5kW.jpg</snapshot7>
		<snapshot8>jM2x2XB.jpg</snapshot8>
		<snapshot9>8yztRGv.jpg</snapshot9>
		<snapshot10>HRYQ6de.jpg</snapshot10>
	</game>
	<game name="Chou Aniki - Otoko no Tamafuda (Japan)">
		<description>Chou Aniki - Otoko no Tamafuda (Japan)</description>
		<rom crc="7FFF2520" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan.zip/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan%2FChou%20Aniki%20-%20Otoko%20no%20Tamafuda%20%28Japan%29.zip" sha1="EB538B82C5516FAE8CE38778E41FB118AA5C830F" size="466990" />
		<title_clean>Chou Aniki - Otoko no Tamafuda</title_clean>
		<plot>Cho Aniki makes it's first appearance in a handheld console with Cho Aniki: Otoko no Tamafuda, only this time the game isn't a 2D shooter developed by Masaya, but instead a card-fighting RPG.[CR]You select your character from a roster of Cho Aniki characters and set out to explore it's funky body-building universe and challenge the many npcs for a few rounds of card combat. Win and you get to increase your collection. Special cards can be unlocked by defeating another player in the vs. mode.</plot>
		<releasedate>10/12/2000</releasedate>
		<year>2000</year>
		<genre>RPG</genre>
		<studio>Bandai Co.</studio>
		<nplayers>1</nplayers>
		<perspective>Isometric</perspective>
		<thegamesdb_id>27592</thegamesdb_id>
		<mobygames_url>https://www.mobygames.com/game/wonderswan/ch-aniki-otoko-no-tamafuda-</mobygames_url>
		<giantbomb_url>https://www.giantbomb.com/cho-aniki-otoko-no-tamafuda/3030-5809/</giantbomb_url>
		<boxart1>1MNLp6t.jpg</boxart1>
		<snapshot1>nVoJL5Z.png</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>0j93yJz.png</snapshot2>
		<snapshot3>CssWj7q.png</snapshot3>
		<snapshot4>VWsknU3.png</snapshot4>
		<snapshot5>6zZX6WL.png</snapshot5>
		<snapshot6>HGfu01m.png</snapshot6>
		<snapshot7>4a7Ow7K.png</snapshot7>
		<snapshot8>5xxVILs.png</snapshot8>
		<snapshot9>4UQhVWY.png</snapshot9>
		<snapshot10>v8NW1Gh.png</snapshot10>
	</game>
	<game name="Chou Denki Card Battle - Youfu Makai (Japan)">
		<description>Chou Denki Card Battle - Youfu Makai (Japan)</description>
		<rom crc="56E2C069" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan.zip/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan%2FChou%20Denki%20Card%20Battle%20-%20Youfu%20Makai%20%28Japan%29.zip" sha1="C4436A59FD830BA6AF2D63462F71E1AB1CFA3212" size="737804" />
		<title_clean>Chou Denki Card Battle - Youfu Makai</title_clean>
		<snapshot1>sV0aRl8.png</snapshot1>
	</game>
	<game name="Clock Tower for WonderSwan (Japan)">
		<description>Clock Tower for WonderSwan (Japan)</description>
		<rom crc="A9936941" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan.zip/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan%2FClock%20Tower%20for%20WonderSwan%20%28Japan%29.zip" sha1="4BA44F23D3B43EE730CE34D56F4CADAF429B6D1B" size="1015670" />
		<title_clean>Clock Tower for WonderSwan</title_clean>
		<plot>[CR][B]Overview:[/B][CR]Clock Tower is a survival horror point-and-click adventure game developed by Human Entertainment for the Super Famicom that was released in Japan on September 24, 1995. Players must guide Jennifer Simpson through a secluded mansion, known as the "Clock Tower," while being hunted by the mysterious Scissorman.Clock Tower was ported to the PlayStation in 1997, retitled to Clock Tower: The First Fear, to the PC in the same year and to the WonderSwan in 1999. The original Super Famicom version was made available on the Nintendo Wii's Virtual Console in 2010 by Sunsoft, who also released the PlayStation Clock Tower games on PSN. All the ports and re-releases of Clock Tower never left Japan but an unofficial English translation patch was created for the Super Famicom version by Aeon Genesis on September 8, 2001. Since then fans have also created translation patches for the Windows and PlayStation ports of The First Fear.Clock Tower would spawn an entire franchise with three sequels that would all see worldwide releases.[CR][B]Story:[/B][CR]The Clock Tower itself!Jennifer Simpson is an orphan from the Granite Orphanage in Romsdalen, Norway. She and her fellow orphans, Laura, Ann, and Lotte, have been adopted by a wealthy man named Simon Barrows, who lives in a secluded mansion known as the Clock Tower. The girl's guardian, Mary, brings the orphans to the Clock Tower and leaves them in the Lobby to find Mr. Barrows. This seemingly-normal event soon turns bad when Mary and the other girls go missing. Things get even worse when a disfigured boy with giant scissors named Bobby begins chasing Jennifer throughout the mansion and the bodies of her friends begin to stack up. Jennifer has to save as many of her friends as she can and get out of the Clock Tower alive.Clock Tower has 9 different endings depending on Jennifer's actions in the game. The endings are categorized as endings A, B, C, D, E, F, G, and H (A is the best and H is the worst). There is also a secret ending which is called ending S. According to the events in the sequel, the only canonical endings are A, B, and C.[CR][B]Gameplay:[/B][CR]Clock Tower is a 2D point and click adventure, where Jennifer is controlled by moving a cursor across the screen. Throughout the game Jennifer is being stalked by Bobby, who randomly appears throughout the mansion and cannot be killed. When Bobby begins to chase Jennifer the player must either hide or attack Bobby with objects in the room. If Bobby attacks Jennifer she will go into panic mode, where the player must mash the panic button to escape. Jennifer can be killed in panic mode if the player does not mash the button fast enough or if her health is too low.Health colorsJennifer's health bar is not based on her physical state, like most games, but is instead based on her psychological state of mind. The more frightened or tired Jennifer becomes the lower her "health" is.This is indicated by the color of the Jennifer's portrait in the bottom left of the screen. The color begins in blue, which is full health, and moves down to the color red, which is low health. When Jennifer's health is low the chances of Bobby finding you increase, as do the chances that Jennifer will trip while running away, so it is important to make Jennifer rest to refill her health.[CR][B]Characters:[/B][CR]Jennifer Simpson: The 14 year old protagonist.Dr. Walter Simpson: Jennifer's father.Anne, Laura, and Lotte: Jennifer's friends and fellow orphans.Mary: The girls' guardian.Simon Barrows: The owner of the Clock Tower mansion.Bobby Barrows: A 9 year old boy with a giant pair of scissors.Dan Barrows: Bobby's mutated brother.[CR][B]Trivia:[/B][CR]Japanese Phenomena PosterThe story of Clock Tower is said to be inspired by the ending of Dario Aregento's film Phenomena (released in an edited form as Creepers in the US). The main character, Jennifer Simpson, even looks very similar to Jennifer Connelly in Phenomena.On July 21, 2011 the Clock Tower episode of Retro Game Master aired on Kotaku. Shinya Arino, the host, originally played through Clock Tower on the 53rd episode of Game Center CX and acquired the S ending. The episode is no longer available on Kotaku but it is included on Discotek's DVD release of Retro Game Master.[CR]</plot>
		<releasedate>14/9/1995</releasedate>
		<giantbomb_url>https://www.giantbomb.com/clock-tower-the-first-fear/3030-31949/</giantbomb_url>
		<boxart1>y3FQGml.jpg</boxart1>
		<snapshot1>wUnNUb9.png</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>7tDsrX7.jpg</snapshot2>
		<snapshot3>FKiZn8z.jpg</snapshot3>
		<snapshot4>c2OoLgn.jpg</snapshot4>
		<snapshot5>l8epdbD.jpg</snapshot5>
		<snapshot6>jvNBDsG.jpg</snapshot6>
		<snapshot7>i5AHv2W.jpg</snapshot7>
		<snapshot8>w5W8buK.jpg</snapshot8>
		<snapshot9>y5FJOpd.jpg</snapshot9>
		<snapshot10>ZwvxhSz.jpg</snapshot10>
	</game>
	<game name="Crazy Climber (Japan)">
		<description>Crazy Climber (Japan)</description>
		<rom crc="C995274B" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan.zip/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan%2FCrazy%20Climber%20%28Japan%29.zip" sha1="67A80B7FB00C3AFE0CE9B0F8975C6D250A2CD49D" size="38085" />
		<title_clean>Crazy Climber</title_clean>
		<plot>[CR][B]Overview:[/B][CR]Crazy Climber is a 1980 Nihon Bussan arcade game in which the player must scale a tall building while avoiding dangers during their ascent. It is in some part inspired by the "Human Fly" craze of the late 70s.The game was eventually released on the Famicom in 1986 and came bundled with a special controller that allowed the player to control both arms of the climber. It was also available on other home systems, such as the Atari 2600.It is one of Nichibutsu's most highly acclaimed video games in its library. A precursor to the platformer genre, Crazy Climber was the first game revolving around climbing, specifically climbing buildings, before Nintendo's seminal 1981 release Donkey Kong.[CR][B]Lives:[/B][CR]The player is awarded 3 lives at the beginning of each games. An extra life is given after the players reaches 30,000 points.[CR][B]Score:[/B][CR]For every story of the building climber, the player scores1st Building - 100 points2nd Building - 150 points3rd Building - 200 points4th Building - 250 pointsBonus PointsBonus points are awarded when after successfully climbing each building and the climber is carried off by the helicopter. However, the bonus score decreases every ten seconds that the climber spends ascending the building.1st Building - 10,000 points2nd Building - 20,000 points3rd Building - 30,000 points4th Building - 40,000 points[CR][B]Trivia:[/B][CR]An Arcadia 2100 port was in the works, but never got released.Musical themes in the game include Baby Elephant Walk, The Pink Panther and The Entertainer.[CR][B]Legacy:[/B][CR]In 1981, Bandai Electronics manufactured a hand-held VFD version of the game.The game has also been ported to the Atari 2600 and the Japanese Famicom.A Japanese-only sequel, Crazy Climber 2, was produced in 1988. The game was essentially identical to Crazy Climber in gameplay but featured more sophisticated graphics and a few new features.On February 3, 1996, Hyper Crazy Climber was released only in Japan for the PlayStation. It has similar gameplay to that of the original game but also a few differences. Players can choose between three cartoony characters, each with their own strength/speed attributes. Several buildings can be selected from a Bomberman-style map screen, including an underwater building, a medieval clock tower, a haunted skyscraper, and a beanstalk. Power-ups are also used.On March 2, 2000, Crazy Climber 2000 was released for the PlayStation. This is more of a remake of the original arcade game using 3D graphics for the first time. A notable feature is the ability to turn corners and access different sides of the buildings, which now have a variety of designs (including one with a cylindrical, tower-like shape). The game included the original port of the arcade Crazy Climber and a scan of the instruction panel. Like Hyper Crazy Climber which released for the same console 4 years earlier, Crazy Climber 2000 was released only in Japan.On July 21, 2005, Japanese publisher HAMSTER released the arcade version of Crazy Climber under their Oretachi Geasen Zoku Sono (&#12458;&#12524;&#12383;&#12385;&#12466;&#12540;&#12475;&#12531;&#26063;) classic game line for the PlayStation 2.Another sequel or remake, Crazy Climber Wii was released for the Wii in Japan on December 20, 2007, but no North American or European release date has been confirmed.The arcade game was later re-released on the Virtual Console in Japan on February 23, 2010.  [CR]</plot>
		<releasedate>29/7/1999</releasedate>
		<year>1999</year>
		<genre>Action</genre>
		<studio>Nihon Bussan Co.</studio>
		<nplayers>1</nplayers>
		<perspective>3rd-Person</perspective>
		<videoid>nahVT592wNc</videoid>
		<thegamesdb_id>19547</thegamesdb_id>
		<mobygames_url>https://www.mobygames.com/game/wonderswan/crazy-climber</mobygames_url>
		<giantbomb_url>https://www.giantbomb.com/crazy-climber/3030-15334/</giantbomb_url>
		<boxart1>K9BPgdQ.jpg</boxart1>
		<boxart2>FOdUSBI.jpg</boxart2>
		<snapshot1>8eaqOTC.png</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>eZwrQsW.gif</snapshot2>
		<snapshot3>V3i3GXe.gif</snapshot3>
		<snapshot4>FOtvPBc.gif</snapshot4>
		<snapshot5>g6mNdST.gif</snapshot5>
		<snapshot6>Jxj2lBb.gif</snapshot6>
		<snapshot7>6BKsLGK.jpg</snapshot7>
		<snapshot8>6oEHroO.jpg</snapshot8>
		<snapshot9>tCOg8E0.jpg</snapshot9>
		<snapshot10>GDiwRCc.jpg</snapshot10>
	</game>
	<game name="D's Garage 21 Koubo Game - Tane o Maku Tori (Japan)">
		<description>D's Garage 21 Koubo Game - Tane o Maku Tori (Japan)</description>
		<rom crc="B1CAEC06" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan.zip/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan%2FD%27s%20Garage%2021%20Koubo%20Game%20-%20Tane%20o%20Maku%20Tori%20%28Japan%29.zip" sha1="83E190AF2E25FBB3E93B1D5835C52FE6F1D279CE" size="151117" />
		<title_clean>D's Garage 21 Koubo Game - Tane o Maku Tori</title_clean>
		<plot>The raven has made a friend. But sorrow be to this raven, for this fellow avian migrates, and will not return for seasons. Filled with sadness and regret the raven takes wing. As he soars through his lonely world his tears begin to fall... and water dying flowers. At last he knows what he must do until his friend returns, he will make new friends in the flowers. He will help them grow and spread their seeds. [CR]Each level in Tane wo Maku Tori contains four pillars bridged by a series of horizontal or vertical rows. These rows are different for each of the three spaces formed by the pillar. The rows may be moved up and down, one set at a time. At the foot of a column, up to three in harder areas, will be a nascent flower. Water drops will fall along the path of the pillars, which will have a different theme for each level, and eventually either fall onto the ground or a flower. Water drops will always move along a bridge if it intersects their path, drops can't go up diagonals. Drops an combine to create larger faster moving drops. Any more than three drops and it will simply fall off the pillar, or bridge, and be of no use.[CR]When a flower gets enough rain drops, or tear drops, it will bloom, when all the flowers on the stage bloom it will be cleared. [CR]Enemies also roam the stage, gobbling up hydrogen based solution and plants. They follow the same laws as the drops and will move along beams when encountered, however they can go up vertical beams. Should one reach a flower it will nibble at it until dead. This ends the game; however, enemies can be destroyed by three drops combined. [CR]A time mode is available where the player picks a difficulty level and then plays on the level until a flower is eaten or they run out of time, each completed flower will add to the time. [CR]A two player mode is available through the Communication Cable[CR]This game is played vertically.</plot>
		<releasedate>22/12/1999</releasedate>
		<genre>Action, Strategy</genre>
		<studio>Bandai Co.</studio>
		<nplayers>1-2 Alt</nplayers>
		<perspective>3rd-Person</perspective>
		<thegamesdb_id>27595</thegamesdb_id>
		<mobygames_url>https://www.mobygames.com/game/wonderswan/ds-garage-21-koubo-game-tane-wo-maku-tori</mobygames_url>
		<giantbomb_url>https://www.giantbomb.com/ds-garage-21-koubo-game-tane-wo-maku-tori/3030-32019/</giantbomb_url>
		<boxart1>hlEbVTJ.jpg</boxart1>
		<snapshot1>PsUbK6L.png</snapshot1>
	</game>
	<game name="Densha de Go! (Japan)">
		<description>Densha de Go! (Japan)</description>
		<rom crc="B62E5DD0" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan.zip/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan%2FDensha%20de%20Go%21%20%28Japan%29.zip" sha1="D3DA0AE529C6F78162682141154A95879F288CA7" size="2738463" />
		<title_clean>Densha de Go!</title_clean>
		<plot>Based on the 1996 arcade game, Densha de Go! was one of the first commercial train-driving simulation games, and went on to spawn numerous successors.[CR]The player can choose from a variety of tracks and trains and will then have to drive the train to the designated stations while sticking to the tight schedule, stopping exactly at the marked positions, obeying all signs and signals, and ensuring passenger safety and comfort.[CR]Whenever the player makes a mistake, points are deducted from a counter which at the start of each round is initialized to a value depending on the selected difficulty. If it reaches zero, the game is over.[CR]The following lines are featured:[CR]1. Sagano Main Line (Sanin Line) from Kameoka to Kyoto[CR]2. Keihin-Tohoku Line from Shinagawa to Yokohama[CR]3. Tokaido Main Line (JR Kyoto Line) from Kyoto to Osaka[CR]4. Yamanote Line (Inner Circle) from Shibuya to Tokyo Station[CR]5. Tokaido Main Line EX from Takatsuki to Osaka, part of the rapid Tokaido Main Line from the original version, but this time with stops at every station (Windows only)[CR]6. Sagano Line EX from Kameoka to Kyoto, without the shortcut from Saga-Arashiyama to Tambaguchi from the original version (Windows only)</plot>
		<releasedate>4/3/1999</releasedate>
		<year>1999</year>
		<genre>Simulation</genre>
		<studio>Taito Corporation</studio>
		<nplayers>1</nplayers>
		<perspective>1st-Person</perspective>
		<thegamesdb_id>27596</thegamesdb_id>
		<mobygames_url>https://www.mobygames.com/game/wonderswan/densha-de-go</mobygames_url>
		<giantbomb_url>https://www.giantbomb.com/densha-de-go/3030-7590/</giantbomb_url>
		<boxart1>wYbaoQn.jpg</boxart1>
		<boxart2>eUl5UQE.jpg</boxart2>
		<boxart3>wdXdh4i.jpg</boxart3>
		<snapshot1>sTbXCp3.png</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>nDSwJCA.png</snapshot2>
		<snapshot3>tHhqMIU.png</snapshot3>
		<snapshot4>vQ7nKjC.png</snapshot4>
		<snapshot5>1Y4attb.png</snapshot5>
		<snapshot6>sZocRfq.png</snapshot6>
		<snapshot7>WqtZ4Cz.png</snapshot7>
		<snapshot8>Uon7mte.png</snapshot8>
		<snapshot9>fYL7HdZ.png</snapshot9>
	</game>
	<game name="Densha de Go! 2 (Japan)">
		<description>Densha de Go! 2 (Japan)</description>
		<rom crc="AF9D8F42" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan.zip/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan%2FDensha%20de%20Go%21%202%20%28Japan%29.zip" sha1="C07F776AC4374B648D1A49EFD9D6FCD0DB2AC1FA" size="3236233" />
		<title_clean>Densha de Go! 2</title_clean>
		<plot>The 1998 sequel of the popular Japanese train driving game by Taito has once again been ported to various home systems. For the first time on the PlayStation, it is possible to drive through the snow, and take a seat in the cockpit of a Shinkansen bullet train.[CR]The gameplay is more arcade than simulation. The focus is on stopping at the stations at the perfect moment and position, keeping up with the schedule, obeying signals and speed limits, and ensuring the safety and comfort of the passengers. Mistakes result in points being deducted from a counter. If it reaches 0, the game is over.[CR]The following routes are available:[CR]1. Hokuhoku Line from Naoetsu to Uragawara[CR]2. Tohoku Shinkansen from Morioka to Shin-Hanamaki[CR]3. Akita Shinkansen from Akita to Omagari[CR]4. Keihin-Tohoku Line from Shinagawa to Ueno[CR]5. Osaka Loop Line from Osaka to Tennoji (not in the Arcade original)[CR]6. Kagoshima Main Line from Hakata to Kokura (only in PlayStation and Windows versions)</plot>
		<releasedate>4/7/1999</releasedate>
		<year>1999</year>
		<genre>Simulation</genre>
		<studio>CyberFront Corporation</studio>
		<nplayers>1</nplayers>
		<perspective>1st-Person</perspective>
		<thegamesdb_id>27597</thegamesdb_id>
		<mobygames_url>https://www.mobygames.com/game/wonderswan/densha-de-go-2</mobygames_url>
		<giantbomb_url>https://www.giantbomb.com/densha-de-go-2/3030-18862/</giantbomb_url>
		<boxart1>Qs4z4hQ.jpg</boxart1>
		<boxart2>4Vh0w9E.jpg</boxart2>
		<boxart3>YNp3j6v.jpg</boxart3>
		<snapshot1>XCNVa3c.png</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>ZSQ9Zy0.gif</snapshot2>
		<snapshot3>JS3BWAf.gif</snapshot3>
		<snapshot4>sLAakh3.gif</snapshot4>
		<snapshot5>kslKfkO.gif</snapshot5>
		<snapshot6>n5LTfcy.gif</snapshot6>
		<snapshot7>rdsK6EC.gif</snapshot7>
		<snapshot8>tBkQ7ai.gif</snapshot8>
	</game>
	<game name="Digimon - Ver. WonderSwan (Asia)">
		<description>Digimon - Ver. WonderSwan (Asia)</description>
		<rom crc="94EA6FFC" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan.zip/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan%2FDigimon%20-%20Ver.%20WonderSwan%20%28Asia%29.zip" sha1="5CC59EC1687FE83EC5FB048D3DFC37849747DF34" size="880441" />
		<title_clean>Digimon - Ver. WonderSwan</title_clean>
		<plot>[CR][B]Overview:[/B][CR]Digimon Adventure: Anode Tamer is a role-playing game developed by Sims Co. and published by Bandai Co. for the WonderSwan platform.[CR]</plot>
		<releasedate>15/12/1999</releasedate>
		<giantbomb_url>https://www.giantbomb.com/digimon-adventure-anode-tamer/3030-6834/</giantbomb_url>
		<boxart1>rTSHloq.jpg</boxart1>
		<snapshot1>APV2HtM.png</snapshot1>
	</game>
	<game name="Digimon Adventure - Anode Tamer (Japan)">
		<description>Digimon Adventure - Anode Tamer (Japan)</description>
		<rom crc="6E9DD148" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan.zip/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan%2FDigimon%20Adventure%20-%20Anode%20Tamer%20%28Japan%29.zip" sha1="9DB54826C2887DEA07AAC774BD15E092596E37AF" size="869748" />
		<title_clean>Digimon Adventure - Anode Tamer</title_clean>
		<plot>The game is based on the popular manga series Digimon, which follows the adventures of children who can gain access into the digital world and fight digital monsters there. In this game, the evil Milenniamon has kidnapped several children and is planning to take control over the Digiworld. One of the good monsters, Agumon, escaped, and transported the hero Ryou to the Digiworld. Now Ryou has to fight monsters, capture them, and assemble an army to overthrow Milenniamon and to rescue his friends.[CR]The gameplay involves mainly hunting monsters in dungeons and then sending them to fight other monsters. In the town you can buy supplies and take care of your monsters. The battles are turn-based, and you can move freely over the battle field. Once a contact with an enemy is initiated, an automatic battle sequence follows.</plot>
		<releasedate>15/12/1999</releasedate>
		<year>1999</year>
		<genre>RPG</genre>
		<studio>Bandai Co.</studio>
		<nplayers>1</nplayers>
		<perspective>Isometric</perspective>
		<thegamesdb_id>27600</thegamesdb_id>
		<mobygames_url>https://www.mobygames.com/game/wonderswan/digimon-adventure-anode-tamer</mobygames_url>
		<giantbomb_url>https://www.giantbomb.com/digimon-adventure-anode-tamer/3030-6834/</giantbomb_url>
		<boxart1>rJeHAXD.jpg</boxart1>
		<boxart3>SpggSXK.jpg</boxart3>
		<snapshot1>O3CPl0F.png</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>oXfYhFe.gif</snapshot2>
		<snapshot3>CC0SdII.gif</snapshot3>
		<snapshot4>zKd1lr5.gif</snapshot4>
		<snapshot5>OcQje72.gif</snapshot5>
		<snapshot6>lhd3KgY.gif</snapshot6>
		<snapshot7>AJCNhR7.gif</snapshot7>
		<snapshot8>plwLLbl.gif</snapshot8>
		<snapshot9>l0W9NFm.gif</snapshot9>
		<snapshot10>K5b3YDJ.gif</snapshot10>
	</game>
	<game name="Digimon Adventure - Cathode Tamer (Japan)">
		<description>Digimon Adventure - Cathode Tamer (Japan)</description>
		<rom crc="42AD238B" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan.zip/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan%2FDigimon%20Adventure%20-%20Cathode%20Tamer%20%28Japan%29.zip" sha1="0B54CC1D350AB92C42CE8214784389B994562BF6" size="882184" />
		<title_clean>Digimon Adventure - Cathode Tamer</title_clean>
		<plot>This is the second game in Digimon Adventure series, a kind of an add-on to  Anode Tamer. The game is based on the popular manga Digimon. The hero, a boy named Ryou, has to travel to digital world in order to free his friends from the clutches of the evil digital monster Milenniamon.[CR]The story of this game is identical to that of "Anode Tamer", and gameplay mechanics are exactly the same: you descend into dungeons to fight monsters in turn-based style, capture the monsters after the battles and then send them to fight new ones. The difference between the two games are the monsters themselves: "Cathode Tamers" features a brand new set of monsters, and since the beginning of the game you encounter different foes. The full collection of monsters can be achieved only if you complete both games.</plot>
		<releasedate>20/1/2000</releasedate>
		<year>2000</year>
		<genre>RPG</genre>
		<studio>Bandai Co.</studio>
		<nplayers>1</nplayers>
		<perspective>Isometric</perspective>
		<thegamesdb_id>27601</thegamesdb_id>
		<mobygames_url>https://www.mobygames.com/game/wonderswan/digimon-adventure-cathode-tamer</mobygames_url>
		<giantbomb_url>https://www.giantbomb.com/digimon-adventure-cathode-tamer/3030-4794/</giantbomb_url>
		<boxart1>7p5Cj0D.jpg</boxart1>
		<snapshot1>owUEOwL.png</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>h8m0Rln.gif</snapshot2>
		<snapshot3>jC8Fll0.gif</snapshot3>
		<snapshot4>s2hQMJo.gif</snapshot4>
		<snapshot5>PHiGiBs.gif</snapshot5>
		<snapshot6>20F4FLB.gif</snapshot6>
		<snapshot7>HiQ3HNF.gif</snapshot7>
		<snapshot8>SC1JRh5.gif</snapshot8>
		<snapshot9>YIEhcGi.gif</snapshot9>
		<snapshot10>AeeIJMR.gif</snapshot10>
	</game>
	<game name="Digimon Adventure 02 - Tag Tamers (Japan)">
		<description>Digimon Adventure 02 - Tag Tamers (Japan)</description>
		<rom crc="6EDEDAF8" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan.zip/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan%2FDigimon%20Adventure%2002%20-%20Tag%20Tamers%20%28Japan%29.zip" sha1="44A5502B70EA75926B87377E3F634C8093BC574A" size="950996" />
		<title_clean>Digimon Adventure 02 - Tag Tamers</title_clean>
		<plot>The game is based on the manga series Digimon, in which children can travel to a digital world and help good digital monsters to defeat evil ones. In this game, the two heroes, Ryou and Ken, are summoned to the Digiworld to fight against the archenemy Millenniumon and his side-kick Diablomon. Upon defeating the two evil monsters once again, the heroes realize that Millenniumon has taken a different shape and is reborn to conquer the Digiworld anew. Now you must recruit digital monsters and lead them into the ultimate battle.[CR]The gameplay follows traditional Digimon outlines: you descend into dungeons and have your monster friends fight other monsters in turn-based combat. Upon returning to the town, you can make those monsters participate in future battles. Unlike the two previous Digimon Adventure games,  Anode and  Cathode Tamers, you cannot move over the battle field.</plot>
		<releasedate>3/8/2000</releasedate>
		<year>2000</year>
		<genre>RPG</genre>
		<studio>Bandai Co.</studio>
		<nplayers>1</nplayers>
		<perspective>Isometric</perspective>
		<thegamesdb_id>27599</thegamesdb_id>
		<mobygames_url>https://www.mobygames.com/game/wonderswan/digimon-adventure-02-tag-tamers</mobygames_url>
		<giantbomb_url>https://www.giantbomb.com/digimon-adventure-02-tag-tamers/3030-2151/</giantbomb_url>
		<boxart1>Zh2AZXu.jpg</boxart1>
		<snapshot1>nW4x5dU.png</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>VdBqvSe.gif</snapshot2>
		<snapshot3>jnzKx5m.gif</snapshot3>
		<snapshot4>PNvpLcM.gif</snapshot4>
		<snapshot5>QLzyXdV.gif</snapshot5>
		<snapshot6>8yrXqaI.gif</snapshot6>
		<snapshot7>fR6KCKq.gif</snapshot7>
		<snapshot8>1xClmOA.gif</snapshot8>
		<snapshot9>Z9mAkf5.gif</snapshot9>
		<snapshot10>cNPyS98.gif</snapshot10>
	</game>
	<game name="Digital Monster - Ver. WonderSwan (Japan)">
		<description>Digital Monster - Ver. WonderSwan (Japan)</description>
		<rom crc="AB59DE2E" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan.zip/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan%2FDigital%20Monster%20-%20Ver.%20WonderSwan%20%28Japan%29.zip" sha1="ECEA24DB6E65254AB4D6E312DE0EB951C7DF716F" size="874928" />
		<title_clean>Digital Monster - Ver. WonderSwan</title_clean>
		<plot>Digital Monster Ver. WonderSwan is a Japanese handheld version of the original Tamagotchi-like Digimon pet for the WonderSwan. It includes all of the original Digimon from the five different pet devices. In this game the player can have up to five different Digimon with them at a time. It even has computer controlled opponents to battle with. The game has the ability to connect to another WonderSwan through a special link cable. It can also hook up to the original pets through a Digimon "dock N rock" connector that comes packaged with the game. Digital Monster Ver. S: Digimon Tamers did much the same thing, only on the Sega Saturn.</plot>
		<releasedate>25/3/1999</releasedate>
		<genre>Strategy</genre>
		<nplayers>1-2 Alt</nplayers>
		<thegamesdb_id>27598</thegamesdb_id>
		<boxart1>oRq7IQB.jpg</boxart1>
		<snapshot1>7WF5Pgh.png</snapshot1>
	</game>
	<game name="Digital Partner (Japan)">
		<description>Digital Partner (Japan)</description>
		<rom crc="B5E675AE" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan.zip/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan%2FDigital%20Partner%20%28Japan%29.zip" sha1="C622F6742CA3F0129FC12DCE0A1C17D292388FFB" size="901044" />
		<title_clean>Digital Partner</title_clean>
		<plot>Digital Partner is a Strategy game, developed by Tom Create and published by Bandai, which was released in Japan in 2000.</plot>
		<releasedate>25/5/2000</releasedate>
		<genre>RPG</genre>
		<nplayers>1</nplayers>
		<thegamesdb_id>27602</thegamesdb_id>
		<boxart1>hsaVOoi.jpg</boxart1>
		<snapshot1>PpXl3dG.png</snapshot1>
	</game>
	<game name="Dokodemo Hamster (Japan)">
		<description>Dokodemo Hamster (Japan)</description>
		<rom crc="89E7D950" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan.zip/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan%2FDokodemo%20Hamster%20%28Japan%29.zip" sha1="3D5A1ED77E721908EB1145AAEDEF17C0EE6355AE" size="250960" />
		<title_clean>Dokodemo Hamster</title_clean>
		<plot>In this game, you are the owner of a hamster. Your hamster is inside a cage, and is living its life in real time, regardless of your actions, walking around, sleeping, etc. However, you can do many things to help your hamster feel better. There is a list of topics you can "discuss" with the hamster: for example, you can order it to run inside a wheel, or ask it whether it is hungry or not. You can feed it some typical hamster food, clean the cage from time to time, and even write e-mails to your hamster. Depending on your actions the disposition of the hamster will change.</plot>
		<releasedate>16/1/2001</releasedate>
		<year>2000</year>
		<genre>Simulation</genre>
		<studio>Bandai Co.</studio>
		<nplayers>1</nplayers>
		<perspective>1st-Person</perspective>
		<thegamesdb_id>27603</thegamesdb_id>
		<mobygames_url>https://www.mobygames.com/game/wonderswan/dokodemo-hamster</mobygames_url>
		<giantbomb_url>https://www.giantbomb.com/dokodemo-hamster/3030-11359/</giantbomb_url>
		<boxart1>cqshCX7.jpg</boxart1>
		<boxart2>HFer16E.jpg</boxart2>
		<boxart3>zGuxJBz.jpg</boxart3>
		<snapshot1>lO9eYBf.png</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>XlqpMyn.gif</snapshot2>
		<snapshot3>D716eiY.gif</snapshot3>
		<snapshot4>Ha4H5XQ.gif</snapshot4>
		<snapshot5>JSLRdRp.gif</snapshot5>
		<snapshot6>Yij7WNg.gif</snapshot6>
		<snapshot7>dK2oS8M.gif</snapshot7>
		<snapshot8>NWR03PV.gif</snapshot8>
		<snapshot9>9iTWZ25.gif</snapshot9>
		<snapshot10>ixNEZuz.gif</snapshot10>
	</game>
	<game name="Engacho! for WonderSwan (Japan)">
		<description>Engacho! for WonderSwan (Japan)</description>
		<rom crc="4E467626" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan.zip/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan%2FEngacho%21%20for%20WonderSwan%20%28Japan%29.zip" sha1="F79451034B6D844F0E10C825306BBC26F26A5466" size="493318" />
		<title_clean>Engacho! for WonderSwan</title_clean>
		<plot>Engacho! for WonderSwan is a Puzzle game, developed and published by NAC Geographic Products Inc., which was released in Japan in 1999.[CR]https://www.gamefaqs.com/portable/wswan/home/576649.html[CR]</plot>
		<releasedate>4/7/1999</releasedate>
		<genre>Puzzle</genre>
		<studio>NAC Geographic Products Inc.</studio>
		<giantbomb_url>https://www.giantbomb.com/engacho/3030-11872/</giantbomb_url>
		<boxart1>qBFPIRB.jpg</boxart1>
		<snapshot1>z35isDx.png</snapshot1>
	</game>
	<game name="Fever - Sankyo Koushiki Pachinko Simulation for WonderSwan (Japan)">
		<description>Fever - Sankyo Koushiki Pachinko Simulation for WonderSwan (Japan)</description>
		<rom crc="8922DD0B" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan.zip/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan%2FFever%20-%20Sankyo%20Koushiki%20Pachinko%20Simulation%20for%20WonderSwan%20%28Japan%29.zip" sha1="F26B0215C49E04CB8EF6F031B627DFF6A49D2015" size="521648" />
		<title_clean>Fever - Sankyo Koushiki Pachinko Simulation for WonderSwan</title_clean>
		<snapshot1>gZG44pI.png</snapshot1>
	</game>
	<game name="Final Lap 2000 (Japan)">
		<description>Final Lap 2000 (Japan)</description>
		<rom crc="CE2F1A1D" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan.zip/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan%2FFinal%20Lap%202000%20%28Japan%29.zip" sha1="CFCB14BE6D2F1DBFFDFCEFB8C8D83B4F39BC102B" size="328431" />
		<title_clean>Final Lap 2000</title_clean>
		<plot>Final Lap 2000 is the first hand-held incarnation of Namco's Final Lap racing games. [CR]This version presents a number of modes, a track building feature, and only one vehicle; an open-wheel car.[CR]The modes are as follows:[CR]1. World Tour: in the mode the player will compete against five other racers and progress through many tracks located around the world. Although the graphics are not  very descriptive of location, the course's shape and curves will always change.[CR]2. Arcade: in this classic mode you'll race against a single opponent through one of the many global tracks of your choosing.[CR]3. Time Trial: here the player will attempt to make the best time on a course of his choosing. The player is the only car on the track for this mode.[CR]The track editing feature can only be used to make simple tracks at the start of the game; however, playing the World Tour will unlock new track parts based on your performance. Using the communication cable players can transfer tracks between different copies of Final Lap 2000.</plot>
		<releasedate>23/3/2000</releasedate>
		<year>2000</year>
		<genre>Driving, Racing</genre>
		<studio>Bandai Co.</studio>
		<nplayers>1-2 Alt</nplayers>
		<perspective>3rd-Person</perspective>
		<thegamesdb_id>27605</thegamesdb_id>
		<mobygames_url>https://www.mobygames.com/game/wonderswan/final-lap-2000</mobygames_url>
		<giantbomb_url>https://www.giantbomb.com/final-lap-2000/3030-32873/</giantbomb_url>
		<boxart1>D1RDFus.jpg</boxart1>
		<boxart2>ImDtgxT.jpg</boxart2>
		<boxart3>lBdR1pT.jpg</boxart3>
		<snapshot1>rxFEEwM.png</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>Vzuejct.png</snapshot2>
		<snapshot3>LAU9OoO.png</snapshot3>
		<snapshot4>tLdTEjV.png</snapshot4>
		<snapshot5>B8OLsu6.png</snapshot5>
		<snapshot6>U4CEcHt.png</snapshot6>
		<snapshot7>2O2PKLN.png</snapshot7>
		<snapshot8>n3xtFhD.png</snapshot8>
		<snapshot9>szPHcrR.png</snapshot9>
		<snapshot10>s0RSd6q.png</snapshot10>
	</game>
	<game name="Fire Pro Wrestling for WonderSwan (Japan)">
		<description>Fire Pro Wrestling for WonderSwan (Japan)</description>
		<rom crc="F246A68E" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan.zip/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan%2FFire%20Pro%20Wrestling%20for%20WonderSwan%20%28Japan%29.zip" sha1="FBB745B016CC710FF6F82EC3091A181415D8DE61" size="2034717" />
		<title_clean>Fire Pro Wrestling for WonderSwan</title_clean>
		<plot>Fire ProWrestling for WonderSwan is a Sports game, developed by Shimada Kikaku and published by Kaga Tech, which was released in Japan in 2000.</plot>
		<releasedate>31/8/2000</releasedate>
		<genre>Sports</genre>
		<nplayers>1-2 Alt</nplayers>
		<thegamesdb_id>27606</thegamesdb_id>
		<giantbomb_url>https://www.giantbomb.com/shin-nippon-pro-wrestling-toukon-retsuden/3030-46985/</giantbomb_url>
		<boxart1>yNoLfRf.png</boxart1>
		<snapshot1>VpqROKH.png</snapshot1>
	</game>
	<game name="Fishing Freaks - Bass Rise for WonderSwan (Japan)">
		<description>Fishing Freaks - Bass Rise for WonderSwan (Japan)</description>
		<rom crc="A1FB16FC" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan.zip/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan%2FFishing%20Freaks%20-%20Bass%20Rise%20for%20WonderSwan%20%28Japan%29.zip" sha1="F8F077DA30F227F3793E97C7F1D656559F08B9D4" size="403187" />
		<title_clean>Fishing Freaks - Bass Rise for WonderSwan</title_clean>
		<plot>Following in the footsteps of the fishing simulation/rpg Bass Rise this portable remake. Although one can no longer select the gender of  the character there  still remains a great variety of lures and poles to select. As well as five locations. Once a location has been selected a prompt to fill the tacklebox with the lures that and rod that might be most appropriate for the environment. The player then selects where to want to stand on the shore and then the ideal location for a cast.[CR]The view then switches to a closer overhead of the body of water and the player's avatar. A power meter sways over head and should the play manage to stop the meter at just the right point he will be rewarded with his cast going closer to where he intended. Once in the water the player's lure will always be in the center of the screen.[CR]Catching fish is no easy matter as the PlayStation version frequently points out; it is all about finesse. The player will have to entice the fish with wiggles and jolts from the lure... this is of course assuming that the player has selected the right lure. Once a fish is caught a small screen will pop up within the screen, showing a close up of the fish's shadow on the surface of the water. The player will get a chance to see if he hooked something good should the fish jump, as they reel it in.[CR]Records can be shared by means of the Communication Cable.</plot>
		<releasedate>24/2/2000</releasedate>
		<year>2000</year>
		<genre>Simulation, Sports</genre>
		<studio>Interbec</studio>
		<nplayers>1</nplayers>
		<perspective>Top-Down</perspective>
		<thegamesdb_id>27607</thegamesdb_id>
		<mobygames_url>https://www.mobygames.com/game/wonderswan/fishing-freaks-bassrise-for-wonderswan</mobygames_url>
		<boxart1>OICOuBn.jpg</boxart1>
		<snapshot1>iR58zeD.png</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>S2IxmyC.png</snapshot2>
		<snapshot3>KLcPO2N.png</snapshot3>
		<snapshot4>vvhGtcq.png</snapshot4>
		<snapshot5>nQEUCPW.png</snapshot5>
		<snapshot6>jeTSHxb.png</snapshot6>
		<snapshot7>pfdXYCC.png</snapshot7>
		<snapshot8>0dHeLqm.png</snapshot8>
		<snapshot9>th8Frqf.png</snapshot9>
		<snapshot10>UMw7WYM.png</snapshot10>
	</game>
	<game name="From TV Animation One Piece - Mezase Kaizoku Ou! (Japan)">
		<description>From TV Animation One Piece - Mezase Kaizoku Ou! (Japan)</description>
		<rom crc="F2E362B8" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan.zip/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan%2FFrom%20TV%20Animation%20One%20Piece%20-%20Mezase%20Kaizoku%20Ou%21%20%28Japan%29.zip" sha1="99C831C27C478064E3D3FA8F9F089CC28F0E946F" size="517772" />
		<title_clean>From TV Animation One Piece - Mezase Kaizoku Ou!</title_clean>
		<plot>From TV Animation: One Piece is an Adventure game, developed and published by Bandai, which was released in Japan in 2000.</plot>
		<releasedate>19/7/2000</releasedate>
		<genre>Adventure</genre>
		<nplayers>1-4 Alt</nplayers>
		<thegamesdb_id>27608</thegamesdb_id>
		<giantbomb_url>https://www.giantbomb.com/one-piece-mezase-kaizokuou/3030-46672/</giantbomb_url>
		<boxart1>f6TOts9.jpg</boxart1>
		<snapshot1>zBgRhKn.png</snapshot1>
	</game>
	<game name="Ganso Jajamaru-kun (Japan)">
		<description>Ganso Jajamaru-kun (Japan)</description>
		<rom crc="A193458C" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan.zip/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan%2FGanso%20Jajamaru-kun%20%28Japan%29.zip" sha1="CBF6455E89B20A000B6121E5C485BE1A20D1F726" size="224738" />
		<title_clean>Ganso Jajamaru-kun</title_clean>
		<plot>Ganso JaJaMaru-kun is a remake of the NES platformer Ninja JaJaMaru-kun. It includes new levels and bosses that stretch the gameplay in novel ways.[CR]Lord Namazu Dayuu has kidnapped JaJaMaru-kun's beloved Princess Sakura. This piratical lord is no laughing matter, despite his sadistically gleeful disposition, he possess an army of creatures drawn from Japanese folklore to prevent you from reuniting with your princess ever again.[CR]The game is quite simple and plays, for the most part, much like its predecessor. Jajamaru-kun begins on the bottom of a three tiered horizontal field. On each level of this field there are two enemies on each tier. The tiers have weak brick points in that Jajamaru-kun can break by hitting them with his head while, a common trait for arcade heroes. Once a passage is made Jajamaru-kun can move through them as can enemies. To clear a level all enemies must be defeated, most enemies can be killed by having a shuriken thrown at them, the only weapon available without a power-up, some need to be stunned either by falling through a hole in a tier or by being jumped on. Enemy projectiles can also be canceled out by the shuriken. Being touched by an enemy projectile, or in a few cases an enemies body, will instantly kill Jajamaru-kun. After an enemy has been killed its spirit will ascend, you can grab this for extra points.[CR]Each of these stages has a leader who will posses some special attribute and present a new sprite. After the level in which the leader appears he/she/it will show up in the following levels as a standard level enemy often a bit weaker. Each stage gives you two minutes to complete it, except bosses and special stages. When about one minute remains Lord Namazu will send an orb of fire onto the stage that will slowly home after Jajamaru-kun.[CR]You start the game with two extra lives and three continues. More lives can be found in the game, or by accruing points.  [CR]There are four levels in each game area, village, graveyard, castle and town, seaside and ship, and the hidden island. However it is not enough to kill all the enemies in a stage to progress to the next area. Each level has its a cherry blossom that will descend from the top of the screen at a certain point. If you should kill all the enemies before the blossom arrives or the blossom floats of the bottom of the screen you'll go onto the next level but have to return to get it later, in this case all the enemies will have returned. Collecting all four cherry blossoms will allow you to go onto a special stage and the area boss.[CR]Each game area has one special stage. These stages use the familiar tiers but now they scroll upwards and are littered with traps and hazards; such as, wheels of fire, falling logs, spikes, conveyor belts, etc.. As the scrolling is automatic should Jajamaru-kun not keep up and fall off the bottom of the screen he will die, touching any deadly hazard will also dispatch our hero. Should the player reach the top of the tiers he will be confronted with a gate that his shuriken will open, this leads to a boss.[CR]Each area boss is attacked in a unique boxed in area, sometimes with platforms. The final boss is the only area where Jajamaru-kun may throw his shuriken vertically. There are no power-ups in boss rooms.[CR]The power-ups that can be found in the bricks between tiers wear out after a certain amount of time, with the exception of the frog. They will appear on the upper right hand corner of the screen so you know which ones you've picked up recently, getting the frog clears this list.[CR]1. Invisibility potion: an invisible ninja is an unstoppable ninja. Once a ninja takes the potion you'll become an ninja outline and can go through enemies. Nothing can harm you, but that doesn't limit your ability to dispatch foes.[CR]2. Ninja Cart: this is a small velocoped for ninja, one in this cart you'll be able to kill enemies by barreling into them, even though it doesn't make physical sense you can still jump in this cart.[CR]3. Big Shuriken: this will make your ninja stars about as big as you are, easily defeating evasive enemies[CR]4. Long Distance: this weapon upgrade will make your attacks go across the entire screen.[CR]5. Katana: a fearsome sword, the katana can do away with any foe, regardless of if they have armor or are to low to hit with your normal attack. The katana also destroys incoming projectiles, however, this blade has a very limited range so be careful.[CR]6. Boomerang: causes your shuriken to fly back at you, it wont harm you, but it is great for picking off foes that are weak from behind.[CR]7. Speed increase: this spherical power-up increases Jajamaru-kun speed to the the peril of his enemies, and himself.[CR]8. Watch: this item will give you more time.[CR]9. Extra Ninja: this item will grant you an extra life, very rare! They do not count as a collected item.[CR]10. Inscribed Coin: these coins available in white and black are worth varying amounts of points. They do not count as a collected item.[CR]11. Bombs: these items look like two speed boost orbs, or the wheels of the cart, however, they are a trap. Jumping into these means instant death for Jajamaru-kun[CR]12. Trusty Frog: Jajamaru-kun's noble steed, a humongous man-eating frog. Should you collect four power-ups instead of receiving the power of the fourth you will get to ride on your gigantic frog and eat all the enemies on the stage. This can be dangerous though if you have not yet gotten the stages petal as once on the frog it won't show up. There is no time limit on how long the frog stays, unless of course the time runs out entirely before you gobble up all the enemies. Once a stage ends you will have to repeat the item collection process to ride the frog again. Items in your collection carry over between stages so you can strategically pick a fourth on a stage where you need the frog.</plot>
		<releasedate>15/4/1999</releasedate>
		<year>1999</year>
		<genre>Action</genre>
		<studio>Jaleco Ltd.</studio>
		<nplayers>1</nplayers>
		<perspective>3rd-Person</perspective>
		<rating>3.0</rating>
		<thegamesdb_id>27609</thegamesdb_id>
		<mobygames_url>https://www.mobygames.com/game/wonderswan/ganso-jajamaru-kun</mobygames_url>
		<giantbomb_url>https://www.giantbomb.com/ganso-jajamarukun/3030-45318/</giantbomb_url>
		<boxart1>jPfDDnd.jpg</boxart1>
		<boxart2>kq9ugNj.jpg</boxart2>
		<boxart3>HKYJBUy.jpg</boxart3>
		<snapshot1>dtwVMv7.png</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>LwxXUj7.png</snapshot2>
		<snapshot3>OJE3IGM.png</snapshot3>
		<snapshot4>y8b2vlk.png</snapshot4>
		<snapshot5>wfEVWjM.png</snapshot5>
		<snapshot6>CGyYbFt.png</snapshot6>
		<snapshot7>IFUaxYD.png</snapshot7>
		<snapshot8>9f54MrZ.png</snapshot8>
		<snapshot9>1UaWlJR.png</snapshot9>
		<snapshot10>f5kB61e.png</snapshot10>
	</game>
	<game name="Glocal Hexcite (Japan)">
		<description>Glocal Hexcite (Japan)</description>
		<rom crc="8FCD6D2C" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan.zip/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan%2FGlocal%20Hexcite%20%28Japan%29.zip" sha1="E100D54E5C63512DBD655F0439870E08CED439DD" size="88893" />
		<title_clean>Glocal Hexcite</title_clean>
		<plot>[CR][B]Overview:[/B][CR]Hexcite: The Shapes of Victory is a puzzle game originally developed by Gu, Inc. and ported to the Game Boy Color by Landwarf. The game was published by Ubisoft Entertainment (US Game Boy Color release), NEC Interchannel (Japanese Game Boy Color release), and Success Corp. (Japanese WonderSwan release).[CR][B]Gameplay:[/B][CR]The Starting Game BoardIn Hexcite two players compete to score the highest number of points by placing different geometric game pieces on a hex based board. The board is laid out with a hexagon in the middle and is surrounded by six identical sized hexagons.Each player has a set number of geometric game pieces such as hexagons, triangles, ect. and takes turns placing the pieces on the correct spots on the board. Bonus points are given to the player that completes filling in one of the seven hexagons on the board.The game can be played in single player or multiplayer. Players can play two player by either passing the system back and forth or by playing with a link cable.[CR]</plot>
		<releasedate>29/6/2000</releasedate>
		<genre>Puzzle</genre>
		<nplayers>1-2 Alt</nplayers>
		<thegamesdb_id>19614</thegamesdb_id>
		<giantbomb_url>https://www.giantbomb.com/hexcite-the-shapes-of-victory/3030-871/</giantbomb_url>
		<boxart1>vBaRGFf.jpg</boxart1>
		<boxart2>yxV1pby.jpg</boxart2>
		<snapshot1>ZNBgCWW.png</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>vY0IMPm.jpg</snapshot2>
		<snapshot3>zRLsazt.jpg</snapshot3>
		<snapshot4>SkHXLCo.jpg</snapshot4>
		<snapshot5>QsLgSub.jpg</snapshot5>
		<snapshot6>XKf6xGp.jpg</snapshot6>
		<snapshot7>fSbZtFQ.jpg</snapshot7>
		<snapshot8>5cEmv0d.jpg</snapshot8>
	</game>
	<game name="Gomoku Narabe &amp; Reversi - Touryuumon (Japan)">
		<description>Gomoku Narabe &amp; Reversi - Touryuumon (Japan)</description>
		<rom crc="6CD1411E" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan.zip/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan%2FGomoku%20Narabe%20%26%20Reversi%20-%20Touryuumon%20%28Japan%29.zip" sha1="867F23963E33B26A781AA96851748E483E41FCAD" size="89961" />
		<title_clean>Gomoku Narabe &amp; Reversi - Touryuumon</title_clean>
		<plot>A simple collection of two classic puzzle games Gomoku Narabe &amp; Reversi/Othello.[CR]Gomoku Narabe, is a ancient Japanese game the title of which means "five stones in a row". The goal of the game is to place five tokens of your color (white or black) in a row. Of course your opponent will be trying to block you. The game ends when  a player achieves tis penta-worthy task. The board is 14 x 14.[CR]Reversi is a game commonly know under the name that it is marketed by Pressman, Othello. In reversi ones goal is to flip the opponents tiles (white or black) by surrounding the opposing token(s) on either end with your own. The board is 8x8.[CR]A challenge mode approaches! You can battle your way through ranks of board game master beginning with a horrid smiling goblin and moving up to a mysterious old guru.[CR]Two players can play the game through the Communication Cable, which is odd as it would seem feasible to play the games on a single system, but what can ya do?</plot>
		<releasedate>13/1/2000</releasedate>
		<year>2000</year>
		<genre>Strategy</genre>
		<studio>Sammy Corporation</studio>
		<nplayers>1-2 Alt</nplayers>
		<perspective>Top-Down</perspective>
		<thegamesdb_id>27610</thegamesdb_id>
		<mobygames_url>https://www.mobygames.com/game/wonderswan/gomoku-narabe-reversi-touryuumon</mobygames_url>
		<boxart1>Y18CrvO.jpg</boxart1>
		<snapshot1>bf6vOhD.png</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>w8HoMT8.png</snapshot2>
		<snapshot3>6G4b9bx.png</snapshot3>
		<snapshot4>xEi2jjk.png</snapshot4>
		<snapshot5>YXC33ox.png</snapshot5>
		<snapshot6>nytn0gB.png</snapshot6>
		<snapshot7>EZuirxi.png</snapshot7>
		<snapshot8>7SbKTUg.png</snapshot8>
		<snapshot9>gtzdXBp.png</snapshot9>
		<snapshot10>Sedve9S.png</snapshot10>
	</game>
	<game name="Goraku Ou Tango! (Japan)">
		<description>Goraku Ou Tango! (Japan)</description>
		<rom crc="00137E86" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan.zip/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan%2FGoraku%20Ou%20Tango%21%20%28Japan%29.zip" sha1="AF3FE9DA3F5EE0F5A7B06B0440223DB88FCB3BF2" size="139333" />
		<title_clean>Goraku Ou Tango!</title_clean>
		<plot>Go Raku Ou Tango! is a simple word game mimicking the puzzles found in the pages of popular printed Japanese word-puzzle publisher Sekai Bunka. These puzzles consist of taking words writing in English and the two syllabaries of Japan Hiragana, or Katakana, and moving tiles around beneath the word(s) to recreate them in a different writing style. There are several variants on this gameplay.[CR]There is a story mode featuring a family of archaeologists who are digging up Japanese orthography across the globe. Sweden, for instance, is known not only as being the home of lost Atlantis but also troves of buried Japanese writing! A family member is missing perhaps there will be clues in this the ruins of these global ancient Japanese ruins? By completing the puzzles you will get to see a scene and a new more difficult puzzle.</plot>
		<releasedate>1/4/1999</releasedate>
		<year>1999</year>
		<studio>Mebius</studio>
		<nplayers>1</nplayers>
		<thegamesdb_id>27611</thegamesdb_id>
		<mobygames_url>https://www.mobygames.com/game/wonderswan/goraku-ou-tango</mobygames_url>
		<giantbomb_url>https://www.giantbomb.com/goraku-ou-tango/3030-38200/</giantbomb_url>
		<boxart1>nbubYLh.jpg</boxart1>
		<boxart2>kPqrXmJ.jpg</boxart2>
		<boxart3>AcETvuO.jpg</boxart3>
		<snapshot1>8UBjUe0.png</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>pzAIQNa.png</snapshot2>
		<snapshot3>oCrJzp9.png</snapshot3>
		<snapshot4>Fbn2ZNO.png</snapshot4>
		<snapshot5>5PR00gx.png</snapshot5>
		<snapshot6>KOB7ESE.png</snapshot6>
		<snapshot7>qCyzaoG.png</snapshot7>
		<snapshot8>iC26C90.png</snapshot8>
		<snapshot9>a2g5mjM.png</snapshot9>
		<snapshot10>vCBONXr.png</snapshot10>
	</game>
	<game name="GunPey (Japan)">
		<description>GunPey (Japan)</description>
		<rom crc="A1656BBB" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan.zip/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan%2FGunPey%20%28Japan%29.zip" sha1="EE4B777F029BAC9561E60C19407D08360E733822" size="562300" />
		<title_clean>GunPey</title_clean>
		<plot>[CR][B]History:[/B][CR]Gunpey was created by Gunpei Yokoi, best known for his role as head of Nintendo's R&amp;D 1, as a game for the WonderSwan handheld which he developed for Bandai.  He passed away before the release of the console, and as a tribute the game was named after him.[CR][B]Gameplay:[/B][CR]The game consists of a board five tiles wide.  Tiles which contain one of four different lines (connecting at the top or bottom corner on the left and right sides) move up from the bottom of the board.  Tiles can be moved by a cursor which covers two vertical tile areas.  Moving the cursor will "flip" the tiles that the cursor covers.  By positioning the tiles so that a line is created which goes across the screen, those tiles will disappear and you will score points.  The longer the lines, the more points are scored.  Tiles will continue to move up from the bottom of the board until a tile reaches the top of the screen, at which point the game is over.[CR]Style[CR]The original WonderSwan game had a old west motif which carried over to the PlayStation release as well as the DS.  The PSP version, published by Q Entertainment, is reminiscent of the style of their other puzzle games, such as Lumines and Every Extend Extra.[CR]</plot>
		<releasedate>4/3/1999</releasedate>
		<year>1999</year>
		<studio>Bandai Co.</studio>
		<nplayers>1-2 Alt</nplayers>
		<thegamesdb_id>27612</thegamesdb_id>
		<mobygames_url>https://www.mobygames.com/game/wonderswan/gunpey</mobygames_url>
		<giantbomb_url>https://www.giantbomb.com/gunpey/3030-13414/</giantbomb_url>
		<boxart1>NcYMuQz.jpg</boxart1>
		<boxart2>x60NsSi.jpg</boxart2>
		<boxart3>fZEXIwY.jpg</boxart3>
		<snapshot1>NlB0zd2.png</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>sGxtVih.png</snapshot2>
		<snapshot3>NYWmE6U.png</snapshot3>
		<snapshot4>UbGO9BD.png</snapshot4>
		<snapshot5>HNLXZiw.png</snapshot5>
		<snapshot6>X2Flu4W.png</snapshot6>
		<snapshot7>3XYr3Gz.png</snapshot7>
		<snapshot8>oOMxGJz.png</snapshot8>
		<snapshot9>uRXRbwz.png</snapshot9>
		<snapshot10>cbzMxoP.png</snapshot10>
	</game>
	<game name="Hanafuda Shiyouyo (Japan)">
		<description>Hanafuda Shiyouyo (Japan)</description>
		<rom crc="8E027330" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan.zip/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan%2FHanafuda%20Shiyouyo%20%28Japan%29.zip" sha1="4504B62212E1637DFD92E4F985A8497FA38941CD" size="101806" />
		<title_clean>Hanafuda Shiyouyo</title_clean>
		<plot>Hanafuda Shiyouyo is a Miscellaneous game, published by Success, which was released in Japan in 2000.</plot>
		<releasedate>17/2/2000</releasedate>
		<genre>Strategy</genre>
		<nplayers>1-2 Alt</nplayers>
		<thegamesdb_id>27613</thegamesdb_id>
		<boxart1>tscJRhr.jpg</boxart1>
		<snapshot1>OXHLBIx.png</snapshot1>
	</game>
	<game name="Harobots (Japan)">
		<description>Harobots (Japan)</description>
		<rom crc="AA525C04" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan.zip/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan%2FHarobots%20%28Japan%29.zip" sha1="1F42C5694A798DE8FF3C68F63DFC7395BE1669A5" size="868764" />
		<title_clean>Harobots</title_clean>
		<plot>[CR][B]Overview:[/B][CR] Harobots was first released on the Wonderswan in 1999 and then on the Game Boy Color (as Harobots GB) in 2000. It was developed by anime giant Sunrise's videogame division, and draws on the company's vast library of robot anime series. It follows the formula of many   Pokemon-like RPGs and features a young protagonist who wants to become a "Harobots Battle" Master.  [CR]Represented Anime[CR] Harobots features more than three dozen robot anime series. Interestingly enough, aside from the Haro itself Mobile Suit Gundam is not represented in any way.  G-BreakerBlue Comet SPT LayznerThe Brave of Gold GoldranGasarakiPanzer World GalientMetal Armor DragonarRound Vernian VifamEnergetic Explosion GanbarugerStrongest Robo DaiojaWhirlwind! Iron LeaguerGiant GorgHeavy Metal L-GaimAura Battler DunbineOutlaw StarAbsolutely Invincible Raijin-OhCombat Mecha XabungleArmored Trooper VotomsFang of the Sun DougramSun Brave FyvardBrave RaideenSuper Robo GalattThe Vision of EscaflowneSpace Runaway IdeonBrave of Legend Da-GarnHot-Blooded Strongest Go-SaurerLord of Lords Ryu KnightSpirit Hero WataruSorcerer King GranzortInvincible Steel Man Daitarn 3Invincible Super Man Zambot 3Invincible Robo Trider G7Brave ExkaiserBrave Police J-DeckerThe Brave Express Might GaineThe King of Braves GaogaigarThe King of Braves Gaogaigar FINALBrain PowerdBettermanThe Big OInfinite Ryvius[CR]</plot>
		<releasedate>7/10/1999</releasedate>
		<genre>RPG</genre>
		<nplayers>1-2 Alt</nplayers>
		<thegamesdb_id>27614</thegamesdb_id>
		<giantbomb_url>https://www.giantbomb.com/harobots/3030-31318/</giantbomb_url>
		<boxart1>oajIbhF.jpg</boxart1>
		<snapshot1>3vCq6Ao.png</snapshot1>
	</game>
	<game name="Hunter X Hunter - Ishi o Tsugu Mono (Japan)">
		<description>Hunter X Hunter - Ishi o Tsugu Mono (Japan)</description>
		<rom crc="70AA800E" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan.zip/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan%2FHunter%20X%20Hunter%20-%20Ishi%20o%20Tsugu%20Mono%20%28Japan%29.zip" sha1="57B4278FC5812F52413CA65F45225922D4F2EC3D" size="846920" />
		<title_clean>Hunter X Hunter - Ishi o Tsugu Mono</title_clean>
		<plot>Hunter X Hunter is a Role-Playing game, developed by Access and published by Bandai, which was released in Japan in 2000.</plot>
		<releasedate>1/6/2000</releasedate>
		<genre>RPG</genre>
		<nplayers>1</nplayers>
		<thegamesdb_id>27624</thegamesdb_id>
		<giantbomb_url>https://www.giantbomb.com/hunter-x-hunter-ishi-o-tsugomono/3030-48792/</giantbomb_url>
		<boxart1>ul5qIFP.jpg</boxart1>
		<snapshot1>1DypQ2x.png</snapshot1>
	</game>
	<game name="Itou Junji Uzumaki - Noroi Simulation (Japan)">
		<description>Itou Junji Uzumaki - Noroi Simulation (Japan)</description>
		<rom crc="CA3F0B00" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan.zip/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan%2FItou%20Junji%20Uzumaki%20-%20Noroi%20Simulation%20%28Japan%29.zip" sha1="38F708A4C0C4FCEC0CF4D6CE051D1FF76466D617" size="715385" />
		<title_clean>Itou Junji Uzumaki - Noroi Simulation</title_clean>
		<plot>In this game you take play as the "Spiral Curse" of Uzumaki trying to bring curling madness to all of Kurzu-Cho! Kirie Goshima returns but no longer as a beloved protagonist. Now she is a target, one of many, that you will try to infect with the spiral curse. In this oddly comic twist on the old horror story, not to say that this game is devoid of similar horrific elements of its predecessor.[CR]After a brief explanation of your role as the Spiral Curse, given by Uzumaki Sen'nin (The Spiral Master) you begin your task. Generally you make life worse as merry mischief making curse.[CR]You will be presented with a map of Kurzu-Cho; from which you can select where to travel. At each locations you will meet different people and be able to collect unique items. Items can be used to make the influence of the Spiral grow in certain areas, along with interacting with various people. [CR]As you cause more mayhem more areas being to open, which allow you torment the old heroes even more![CR]A small human/slug monster hybrid virtual pet can be accessed from the main menu.</plot>
		<releasedate>4/3/2000</releasedate>
		<genre>Adventure, Simulation</genre>
		<studio>Omega Micott Inc.</studio>
		<nplayers>1</nplayers>
		<perspective>3rd-Person</perspective>
		<rating>3.2</rating>
		<mobygames_url>https://www.mobygames.com/game/wonderswan/uzumaki-noroi-simulation</mobygames_url>
		<giantbomb_url>https://www.giantbomb.com/uzumaki-noroi-simulation/3030-4022/</giantbomb_url>
		<boxart1>pi4pnnV.jpg</boxart1>
		<boxart2>PXtyfUV.jpg</boxart2>
		<boxart3>ybVTFnr.jpg</boxart3>
		<snapshot1>nLkp5SJ.png</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>abnd94C.png</snapshot2>
		<snapshot3>wNbiCwO.png</snapshot3>
		<snapshot4>4f7YRTX.png</snapshot4>
		<snapshot5>oB1sAgL.png</snapshot5>
		<snapshot6>wgq9clt.png</snapshot6>
		<snapshot7>ga3D5BR.png</snapshot7>
		<snapshot8>ewg93VC.png</snapshot8>
		<snapshot9>HGNZio3.png</snapshot9>
		<snapshot10>WjF55fN.png</snapshot10>
	</game>
	<game name="Kakutou Ryouri Densetsu Bistro Recipe - Wonder Battle Hen (Japan)">
		<description>Kakutou Ryouri Densetsu Bistro Recipe - Wonder Battle Hen (Japan)</description>
		<rom crc="4D103236" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan.zip/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan%2FKakutou%20Ryouri%20Densetsu%20Bistro%20Recipe%20-%20Wonder%20Battle%20Hen%20%28Japan%29.zip" sha1="B40FBC7B72921C9AC31330831C0F77E4133EC7D6" size="415372" />
		<title_clean>Kakutou Ryouri Densetsu Bistro Recipe - Wonder Battle Hen</title_clean>
		<plot>Bistro Recipe is a Strategy game, developed and published by Banpresto, which was released in Japan in 1999.</plot>
		<releasedate>30/9/1999</releasedate>
		<genre>Strategy</genre>
		<nplayers>1</nplayers>
		<thegamesdb_id>27627</thegamesdb_id>
		<giantbomb_url>https://www.giantbomb.com/bistro-recipe/3030-31084/</giantbomb_url>
		<boxart1>tEwFIBb.jpg</boxart1>
		<snapshot1>4Gu4GV7.png</snapshot1>
	</game>
	<game name="Kaze no Klonoa - Moonlight Museum (Japan)">
		<description>Kaze no Klonoa - Moonlight Museum (Japan)</description>
		<rom crc="80C6EF12" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan.zip/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan%2FKaze%20no%20Klonoa%20-%20Moonlight%20Museum%20%28Japan%29.zip" sha1="207A3CEB9A09EABCA6E455DEEB7035E7E04C9795" size="412882" />
		<title_clean>Kaze no Klonoa - Moonlight Museum</title_clean>
		<plot>In this game, you control a boy named Klonoa. One day he sees a dream in which he learns that somebody has stolen a fragment of the moon. He is told that the thieves are probably some painters who took the moon fragment into a museum. As Klonoa enters the music, he gets teleported into a mysterious world. Now he has to use his wit in order to overcome all the obstacles in this world and retrieve the moon fragment.[CR]Kaze no Klonoa: Moonlight Museum is a platform game with an emphasis on puzzle-solving. The enemies you encounter can be inflated with the help of Klonoa's yo-yo, and carried around. You can throw them at other enemies, or use them to jump to higher ledges. In addition, there are various kinds of symbols you have to collect to open locked doors, teleporters, switches, time bombs, and other ingredients for puzzles.</plot>
		<releasedate>19/5/1999</releasedate>
		<year>1999</year>
		<genre>Action</genre>
		<studio>Bandai Co.</studio>
		<nplayers>1</nplayers>
		<perspective>Platform</perspective>
		<thegamesdb_id>27628</thegamesdb_id>
		<mobygames_url>https://www.mobygames.com/game/wonderswan/kaze-no-klonoa-moonlight-museum</mobygames_url>
		<giantbomb_url>https://www.giantbomb.com/kaze-no-klonoa-moonlight-museum/3030-2202/</giantbomb_url>
		<boxart1>lVZU882.jpg</boxart1>
		<boxart2>KGJFwNV.jpg</boxart2>
		<boxart3>BRVAwpu.jpg</boxart3>
		<snapshot1>oNsltWz.png</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>a0snJPC.gif</snapshot2>
		<snapshot3>iPUpoEI.gif</snapshot3>
		<snapshot4>3dBSgJn.gif</snapshot4>
		<snapshot5>fRHP6jc.gif</snapshot5>
		<snapshot6>ckcA4MI.gif</snapshot6>
		<snapshot7>XkdRXvH.gif</snapshot7>
		<snapshot8>66Rg2Wk.gif</snapshot8>
		<snapshot9>VCK6fpW.gif</snapshot9>
		<snapshot10>zPJpkqA.gif</snapshot10>
	</game>
	<game name="Keiba Yosou Shien Soft - Yosou Shinkaron (Japan)">
		<description>Keiba Yosou Shien Soft - Yosou Shinkaron (Japan)</description>
		<rom crc="945FC213" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan.zip/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan%2FKeiba%20Yosou%20Shien%20Soft%20-%20Yosou%20Shinkaron%20%28Japan%29.zip" sha1="461F87E6E301B0DBB6324D908D4CA7EFD7518E20" size="249813" />
		<title_clean>Keiba Yosou Shien Soft - Yosou Shinkaron</title_clean>
		<snapshot1>XuQAw5P.png</snapshot1>
	</game>
	<game name="Kiss Yori... - Seaside Serenade (Japan)">
		<description>Kiss Yori... - Seaside Serenade (Japan)</description>
		<rom crc="3B4C60C6" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan.zip/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan%2FKiss%20Yori...%20-%20Seaside%20Serenade%20%28Japan%29.zip" sha1="9EF89B6FE68C5A06D34344E8C783EC24114AD959" size="1094045" />
		<title_clean>Kiss Yori... - Seaside Serenade</title_clean>
		<plot>KISS Yori... Seaside Serenade is an Adventure game, developed and published by Kid, which was released in Japan in 1999.</plot>
		<releasedate>2/12/1999</releasedate>
		<genre>Adventure</genre>
		<nplayers>1</nplayers>
		<thegamesdb_id>27629</thegamesdb_id>
		<boxart1>HGDe88e.jpg</boxart1>
		<snapshot1>OhpEik4.png</snapshot1>
	</game>
	<game name="Kosodate Quiz Dokodemo - My Angel (Japan)">
		<description>Kosodate Quiz Dokodemo - My Angel (Japan)</description>
		<rom crc="4C48624C" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan.zip/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan%2FKosodate%20Quiz%20Dokodemo%20-%20My%20Angel%20%28Japan%29.zip" sha1="52B154A3E36D01357649A9F7F614139CE6CC46B8" size="1061366" />
		<title_clean>Kosodate Quiz Dokodemo - My Angel</title_clean>
		<plot>Kosodate Quiz Dokodemo: My Angel is a Miscellaneous game, developed by Namco and published by Bandai, which was released in Japan in 1999.</plot>
		<releasedate>15/4/1999</releasedate>
		<genre>Puzzle</genre>
		<nplayers>1-2 Alt</nplayers>
		<thegamesdb_id>27630</thegamesdb_id>
		<boxart1>abYAxLj.jpg</boxart1>
		<snapshot1>eiqgLT9.png</snapshot1>
	</game>
	<game name="Kyousouba Ikusei Simulation - Keiba (Japan)">
		<description>Kyousouba Ikusei Simulation - Keiba (Japan)</description>
		<rom crc="ECFBCB1D" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan.zip/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan%2FKyousouba%20Ikusei%20Simulation%20-%20Keiba%20%28Japan%29.zip" sha1="A309A430FBBED6C42F41D8CCAF4ABA82E96D6A7B" size="251193" />
		<title_clean>Kyousouba Ikusei Simulation - Keiba</title_clean>
		<plot>This game begins by asking you to name your own stable, and then your first horse, quickly introducing you to the world of this horse raising, breeding, and racing game. The majority of the gameplay focuses on micromanaging your horses training and care. You an select the races that you think you're horse is ready for in an attempt to win coveted ribbons, and wealth beyond the dreams of avarice![CR]Once you enter a race you'll be taken out of control and see if all you're hard work has payed off as your beast makes it around the track. An announcer follows the competition of there Muybridge wannabes, narrating what you see.[CR]Regardless how good your horse is it will be economically prudent to continue its line. Through shrewd husbandry you can translate the positive traits of race horse to a new generation. You'll be able to select a proper mate from other stables. [CR]Horse information and stable data can be shared with other players via the Communication Cable.</plot>
		<releasedate>18/11/1999</releasedate>
		<year>1999</year>
		<genre>Sports</genre>
		<studio>Interbec</studio>
		<nplayers>1</nplayers>
		<perspective>3rd-Person</perspective>
		<thegamesdb_id>27631</thegamesdb_id>
		<mobygames_url>https://www.mobygames.com/game/wonderswan/kyousouba-ikusei-simulation-keiba</mobygames_url>
		<boxart1>uLAkZ2g.jpg</boxart1>
		<snapshot1>2OUXho4.png</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>9bbsf5b.png</snapshot2>
		<snapshot3>YcKgc3T.png</snapshot3>
		<snapshot4>2ROiiOC.png</snapshot4>
		<snapshot5>4EqSwNM.png</snapshot5>
		<snapshot6>dekl6L4.png</snapshot6>
		<snapshot7>pcj0dlG.png</snapshot7>
		<snapshot8>E6pvffD.png</snapshot8>
		<snapshot9>6LWiKkP.png</snapshot9>
		<snapshot10>rr9cuik.png</snapshot10>
	</game>
	<game name="Langrisser Millennium WS - The Last Century (Japan)">
		<description>Langrisser Millennium WS - The Last Century (Japan)</description>
		<rom crc="9E0854E2" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan.zip/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan%2FLangrisser%20Millennium%20WS%20-%20The%20Last%20Century%20%28Japan%29.zip" sha1="9FDF3F5821F2A4488139525FE49E87B23DE4571F" size="370995" />
		<title_clean>Langrisser Millennium WS - The Last Century</title_clean>
		<plot>Langrisser Millennium WS: The Last Century is a Strategy game, developed and published by Bandai, which was released in Japan in 2000.</plot>
		<releasedate>9/3/2000</releasedate>
		<genre>Strategy</genre>
		<nplayers>1</nplayers>
		<thegamesdb_id>27632</thegamesdb_id>
		<giantbomb_url>https://www.giantbomb.com/langrisser-millennium-ws-the-last-century/3030-44185/</giantbomb_url>
		<boxart1>fj3tFFB.jpg</boxart1>
		<snapshot1>DceA8TK.png</snapshot1>
	</game>
	<game name="Last Stand (Japan)">
		<description>Last Stand (Japan)</description>
		<rom crc="CCCAF8A1" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan.zip/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan%2FLast%20Stand%20%28Japan%29.zip" sha1="D524DA01F2BFAD92C2FA080950229955A3030EF2" size="617597" />
		<title_clean>Last Stand</title_clean>
		<plot>Last Stand is a Strategy game, developed by Soft Machine and published by Bandai, which was released in Japan in 1999.</plot>
		<releasedate>27/3/1999</releasedate>
		<genre>Strategy</genre>
		<nplayers>1</nplayers>
		<thegamesdb_id>27633</thegamesdb_id>
		<boxart1>CLaNKNm.jpg</boxart1>
		<snapshot1>ye4e4uD.png</snapshot1>
	</game>
	<game name="Lode Runner for WonderSwan (Japan)">
		<description>Lode Runner for WonderSwan (Japan)</description>
		<rom crc="E407CABF" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan.zip/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan%2FLode%20Runner%20for%20WonderSwan%20%28Japan%29.zip" sha1="91595CD5D5192DB50EDA883157852FF81994990C" size="166910" />
		<title_clean>Lode Runner for WonderSwan</title_clean>
		<plot>Lode Runner for WonderSwan is a 2D Platformer game, developed and published by Banpresto, which was released in Japan in 2000.[CR]https://www.gamefaqs.com/portable/wswan/home/577323.html[CR]</plot>
		<releasedate>4/7/2000</releasedate>
		<genre>Platform</genre>
		<studio>Banpresto</studio>
		<nplayers>1</nplayers>
		<thegamesdb_id>27634</thegamesdb_id>
		<boxart1>DbiGhtk.jpg</boxart1>
		<snapshot1>h8AmeTR.png</snapshot1>
	</game>
	<game name="Macross - True Love Song (Japan)">
		<description>Macross - True Love Song (Japan)</description>
		<rom crc="62D419CD" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan.zip/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan%2FMacross%20-%20True%20Love%20Song%20%28Japan%29.zip" sha1="211E051DB3FD4D7AE1EA143E043F87CFBCEC5F1C" size="2100536" />
		<title_clean>Macross - True Love Song</title_clean>
		<plot>Macross: True Love Song is a Strategy game, developed and published by Lay-Up, which was released in Japan in 2000.</plot>
		<releasedate>23/3/2000</releasedate>
		<genre>Strategy</genre>
		<nplayers>1</nplayers>
		<thegamesdb_id>27635</thegamesdb_id>
		<boxart1>gIAJjrS.jpg</boxart1>
		<snapshot1>iY8zw8Y.png</snapshot1>
	</game>
	<game name="Magical Drop for WonderSwan (Japan)">
		<description>Magical Drop for WonderSwan (Japan)</description>
		<rom crc="637ADA93" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan.zip/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan%2FMagical%20Drop%20for%20WonderSwan%20%28Japan%29.zip" sha1="A25944969068EE495254F94C2C48DFFFCB66CE8D" size="457093" />
		<title_clean>Magical Drop for WonderSwan</title_clean>
		<plot>Magical Drop for WonderSwan is a Matching Puzzle game, developed and published by Data East, which was released in Japan in 1999.[CR]https://www.gamefaqs.com/portable/wswan/home/576648.html[CR]</plot>
		<releasedate>4/7/1999</releasedate>
		<genre>Puzzle</genre>
		<studio>Data East</studio>
		<nplayers>1-2 Alt</nplayers>
		<thegamesdb_id>27636</thegamesdb_id>
		<giantbomb_url>https://www.giantbomb.com/magical-drop-for-wonderswan/3030-46656/</giantbomb_url>
		<boxart1>t7abBeu.jpg</boxart1>
		<snapshot1>9Dy1i1W.png</snapshot1>
	</game>
	<game name="Mahjong Touryuumon (Japan)">
		<description>Mahjong Touryuumon (Japan)</description>
		<rom crc="E7E7FD4C" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan.zip/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan%2FMahjong%20Touryuumon%20%28Japan%29.zip" sha1="281079B22CB213EE4DDA5C304B5B5BE028130929" size="153617" />
		<title_clean>Mahjong Touryuumon</title_clean>
		<snapshot1>BKdJGYS.png</snapshot1>
	</game>
	<game name="Makai Mura for WonderSwan (Japan)">
		<description>Makai Mura for WonderSwan (Japan)</description>
		<rom crc="00B31FBB" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan.zip/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan%2FMakai%20Mura%20for%20WonderSwan%20%28Japan%29.zip" sha1="5EAEAB859E5F647FAC354DAD285A311387EA126B" size="914429" />
		<title_clean>Makai Mura for WonderSwan</title_clean>
		<plot>  [CR]</plot>
		<releasedate>22/7/1999</releasedate>
		<year>1999</year>
		<genre>Action</genre>
		<studio>Bandai Co.</studio>
		<nplayers>1</nplayers>
		<thegamesdb_id>19548</thegamesdb_id>
		<mobygames_url>https://www.mobygames.com/game/wonderswan/makaimura-for-wonderswan</mobygames_url>
		<giantbomb_url>https://www.giantbomb.com/makaimura-for-wonderswan/3030-42058/</giantbomb_url>
		<boxart1>XNQ1ysu.jpg</boxart1>
		<boxart2>0ryORck.jpg</boxart2>
		<boxart3>3KbBAw7.jpg</boxart3>
		<snapshot1>YEvZXtj.png</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>TT6A9bY.gif</snapshot2>
		<snapshot3>5izFb24.gif</snapshot3>
		<snapshot4>xtIgVny.gif</snapshot4>
		<snapshot5>wkqLc71.gif</snapshot5>
		<snapshot6>yYmZOJ5.gif</snapshot6>
		<snapshot7>3z2qZxv.gif</snapshot7>
		<snapshot8>46o1fCd.gif</snapshot8>
		<snapshot9>8kVriYS.gif</snapshot9>
		<snapshot10>gFxayvk.gif</snapshot10>
	</game>
	<game name="Medarot Perfect Edition - Kabuto Version (Japan)">
		<description>Medarot Perfect Edition - Kabuto Version (Japan)</description>
		<rom crc="12FB8B28" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan.zip/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan%2FMedarot%20Perfect%20Edition%20-%20Kabuto%20Version%20%28Japan%29.zip" sha1="509E5748E5EFDFB56093C78AE886153DD1838215" size="649692" />
		<title_clean>Medarot Perfect Edition - Kabuto Version</title_clean>
		<plot>[CR]</plot>
		<releasedate>4/5/1999</releasedate>
		<genre>RPG</genre>
		<nplayers>1-2 Alt</nplayers>
		<thegamesdb_id>27639</thegamesdb_id>
		<giantbomb_url>https://www.giantbomb.com/medarot-kabutokuwagata/3030-31488/</giantbomb_url>
		<boxart1>7L5fI84.jpg</boxart1>
		<snapshot1>N4jrtYq.png</snapshot1>
	</game>
	<game name="Medarot Perfect Edition - Kuwagata Version (Japan)">
		<description>Medarot Perfect Edition - Kuwagata Version (Japan)</description>
		<rom crc="2B40745D" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan.zip/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan%2FMedarot%20Perfect%20Edition%20-%20Kuwagata%20Version%20%28Japan%29.zip" sha1="315061E4739E947175D6AD7F006498CD61A33F8C" size="664362" />
		<title_clean>Medarot Perfect Edition - Kuwagata Version</title_clean>
		<plot>[CR]</plot>
		<releasedate>4/5/1999</releasedate>
		<genre>RPG</genre>
		<nplayers>1-2 Alt</nplayers>
		<thegamesdb_id>27640</thegamesdb_id>
		<giantbomb_url>https://www.giantbomb.com/medarot-kabutokuwagata/3030-31488/</giantbomb_url>
		<boxart1>R33tOvx.jpg</boxart1>
		<snapshot1>Tg84AzS.png</snapshot1>
	</game>
	<game name="Meitantei Conan - Majutsushi no Chousenjou! (Japan)">
		<description>Meitantei Conan - Majutsushi no Chousenjou! (Japan)</description>
		<rom crc="92FBF7FB" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan.zip/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan%2FMeitantei%20Conan%20-%20Majutsushi%20no%20Chousenjou%21%20%28Japan%29.zip" sha1="8F3F97BE31F3BD0E6922AB7795AA6F04BC5CFE2A" size="579699" />
		<title_clean>Meitantei Conan - Majutsushi no Chousenjou!</title_clean>
		<plot>Conan Edogawa is the pseudonym of Shin'ichi Kudo, but more than just a pseudonym, a pseudoform. Shin'ichi Kudo, an inquisitive seventeen year old student, was investigating a blackmail case when attacked by members of the Black Organization. He was forced to take an experimental APTX 4869 drug which caused, in a rare side-effect, his body to transform into that of a seven-year-old. [CR]This does not stop Shin'ichi, adopting the name Conan Edogawa he moves in with Ran Mori, his childhood friend and sweetheart. Enrolling in a elementary school to complete his disguise he vows to find out who is backing the Black Organization, and to have his revenge. With the help of his his oddball classmates, an ex-member of the Black Organization Ai Haibara, whose also been turned into a child, and his beloved he just might do it...[CR]The games story follows the Conan through his school life which intertwines with his search for justice. He forms a Junior Detective League in his school to help him out. This cast of characters will help supply you information throughout the game.[CR]The gameplay consists of using a map screen to travel to a number of areas collecting clues for the case you are on. Each area offers you the ability to examine the area, talk to bystanders, collect items, and sometimes attack if a threat is apparent. [CR]After collecting information you will have the chance to open your notebook, which will cause the WonderSwan to switch to a vertical orientation, and review your information. Also in the note books is a logic grid. On the grid you will have to select where you've deduced something intersects,who was at the scene at what time, by marking it with a circle and voiding all impossibilities with crosses. Once you've completed an entire grid you'll be able to present your deductions or press a point further allowing you to progress. If you've gotten your reasoning wrong, however, it is back to the drawing board and time to recheck you evidence and maybe time to see if you missed some clues.[CR]This game includes five scenarios, roughly translated to English as:[CR]1. Continuous high school girl kidnapping[CR]2. Murder on the suspense drama set[CR]3. Jack the Ripper murder[CR]The mysteries incident's letter of notice[CR]4. Treasure cases at the end of the century</plot>
		<releasedate>5/8/1999</releasedate>
		<year>1999</year>
		<genre>Adventure, Educational</genre>
		<studio>Bandai Co.</studio>
		<nplayers>1</nplayers>
		<thegamesdb_id>27641</thegamesdb_id>
		<mobygames_url>https://www.mobygames.com/game/wonderswan/meitantei-conan-majutsushi-no-chsenj</mobygames_url>
		<boxart1>ZYCvIoG.jpg</boxart1>
		<boxart2>FZyN7U2.jpg</boxart2>
		<boxart3>YhtKij7.jpg</boxart3>
		<snapshot1>WkGKMP1.png</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>jnYd79y.png</snapshot2>
		<snapshot3>z2YBtBz.png</snapshot3>
		<snapshot4>dwM3Orw.png</snapshot4>
		<snapshot5>q3kUEf2.png</snapshot5>
		<snapshot6>qyLpbOH.png</snapshot6>
		<snapshot7>qoRaKLb.png</snapshot7>
		<snapshot8>msj5EOz.png</snapshot8>
		<snapshot9>xhVkFFS.png</snapshot9>
		<snapshot10>1QcBmsb.png</snapshot10>
	</game>
	<game name="Meitantei Conan - Nishi no Meitantei Saidai no Kiki! (Japan)">
		<description>Meitantei Conan - Nishi no Meitantei Saidai no Kiki! (Japan)</description>
		<rom crc="E226863B" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan.zip/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan%2FMeitantei%20Conan%20-%20Nishi%20no%20Meitantei%20Saidai%20no%20Kiki%21%20%28Japan%29.zip" sha1="E5684789E81F9D739010DB575022A12A448B5509" size="878378" />
		<title_clean>Meitantei Conan - Nishi no Meitantei Saidai no Kiki!</title_clean>
		<plot>Detective Conan returns to the WonderSwans continuing his efforts to thwart the dreaded Black Organization. The game features new mysteries and new characters from the Conan universe. [CR]New features include finding keys. Keys represent actual bits of evidence you can use to solve the logic puzzles in the game once you find all the keys you will be able to attempt to solve the puzzle. However, often in the search for keys one finds hints. Hints are bits of information that will point you in the right direction of a key. Hints also be presented, singularly or combined, to various people in an attempt to extract information, or keys. Once you have all the keys you will be able to have an entire logic grid, otherwise there will be grayed out areas on the grid.[CR]There is also now a mode in some cases where Conan will have to chase the suspect through several areas before subduing him. [CR]The game records your information at the start of the game to work a character based off of you into the game. This character can be swapped with other owners of [CR]Meitantei Conan: Nishi no Meitantei Saidai no Kiki !? through the Communication Cable.[CR]This game alternates between horizontal display for regular play and investigation, and vertical display for Conan's detective notebook.</plot>
		<releasedate>27/7/2000</releasedate>
		<year>2000</year>
		<studio>Bandai Co.</studio>
		<nplayers>1</nplayers>
		<thegamesdb_id>27642</thegamesdb_id>
		<mobygames_url>https://www.mobygames.com/game/wonderswan/meitantei-conan-nishi-no-meitantei-saidai-no-kiki-</mobygames_url>
		<boxart1>eOmjPE0.jpg</boxart1>
		<boxart2>nQ4n800.jpg</boxart2>
		<boxart3>mWqwmzg.jpg</boxart3>
		<snapshot1>aDxNnmB.png</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>YboppPX.png</snapshot2>
		<snapshot3>p961nlH.png</snapshot3>
		<snapshot4>OkiRX5V.png</snapshot4>
		<snapshot5>kWtDzvi.png</snapshot5>
		<snapshot6>IdBxtdY.png</snapshot6>
		<snapshot7>QUZ4zet.png</snapshot7>
		<snapshot8>OPWUocw.png</snapshot8>
		<snapshot9>zvD1Gjj.png</snapshot9>
		<snapshot10>t8Ugc1E.png</snapshot10>
	</game>
	<game name="Metakomi Theraphy - Nee Kiite! (Japan)">
		<description>Metakomi Theraphy - Nee Kiite! (Japan)</description>
		<rom crc="A3EAD689" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan.zip/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan%2FMetakomi%20Theraphy%20-%20Nee%20Kiite%21%20%28Japan%29.zip" sha1="DC94E17A942ACFDC1EB0C38D91BF72460A4BB8F9" size="1129263" />
		<title_clean>Metakomi Theraphy - Nee Kiite!</title_clean>
		<snapshot1>2sRVDKd.png</snapshot1>
	</game>
	<game name="Mingle Magnet (Japan)">
		<description>Mingle Magnet (Japan)</description>
		<rom crc="9BAAC7BB" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan.zip/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan%2FMingle%20Magnet%20%28Japan%29.zip" sha1="C7230EF709F6CEAEF9A220541C8CDC05C0CD549F" size="21947" />
		<title_clean>Mingle Magnet</title_clean>
		<plot>Mingle Magnet is a simple puzzle game of the falling block variety. The player oversees a 10 x 10 square field where the first four rows (three on easy) have been filled by blocks. Each block shows one of three symbols, a dark gray circle, a light gray circle, and a white circle. When ever any of blocks with matching symbols touch they will form a link. By moving the cursor over a chain and clicking on it the player will be given points based on its size on the chain will be removed. The goal is to get a large score while making sure that new pieces can still enter the field. Once no more pieces can enter the game ends. Blocks fall at the same time one square apart, when the next set of blocks fall they will occupy the space given by the previous drop.[CR]The "magnet" aspect of Mingle Magnet come into play in how the player can control the placement of the blocks. All the blocks are attracted to a magnet which, although not seen, can be placed on any side of the field. All blocks will be drawn to the magnet. For example, if one has the magnet at the south of the field and then puts it to the north what was the top of the block pile will now be the bottom, and blocks will fall onto what was the bottom. The direction of the magnet is indicated by a magnetic field animation behind the action.[CR]This game is played vertically.</plot>
		<releasedate>2/11/1999</releasedate>
		<year>1999</year>
		<studio>HAL Laboratory</studio>
		<nplayers>1</nplayers>
		<thegamesdb_id>27643</thegamesdb_id>
		<mobygames_url>https://www.mobygames.com/game/wonderswan/mingle-magnet</mobygames_url>
		<giantbomb_url>https://www.giantbomb.com/mingle-magnet/3030-34678/</giantbomb_url>
		<boxart1>skvFQxC.jpg</boxart1>
		<snapshot1>9P64UuL.png</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>bCOMROV.png</snapshot2>
		<snapshot3>DVNJZcX.png</snapshot3>
		<snapshot4>vDudjB7.png</snapshot4>
		<snapshot5>B7ZsStO.png</snapshot5>
		<snapshot6>mXagBBz.png</snapshot6>
		<snapshot7>X7E7DmP.png</snapshot7>
		<snapshot8>mcLRvPF.png</snapshot8>
		<snapshot9>4EQQQpa.png</snapshot9>
		<snapshot10>GlfhaFd.png</snapshot10>
	</game>
	<game name="Mobile Suit Gundam MSVS (Japan)">
		<description>Mobile Suit Gundam MSVS (Japan)</description>
		<rom crc="53B9FEF8" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan.zip/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan%2FMobile%20Suit%20Gundam%20MSVS%20%28Japan%29.zip" sha1="2688CA67AC31CE3D5C3523B0E11CAD55E70FA257" size="895920" />
		<title_clean>Mobile Suit Gundam MSVS</title_clean>
		<plot>A simulation game. Players assume the role of an Anaheim Electronics test pilot as they utilize various Mobile Suits from Gundam's One Year War era.</plot>
		<releasedate>26/8/1999</releasedate>
		<genre>Flight Simulator</genre>
		<nplayers>1-2 Alt</nplayers>
		<thegamesdb_id>19549</thegamesdb_id>
		<giantbomb_url>https://www.giantbomb.com/mobile-suit-gundam-msvs/3030-31325/</giantbomb_url>
		<boxart1>PSRdNfb.jpg</boxart1>
		<boxart2>JhxFR9n.jpg</boxart2>
		<snapshot1>PWDY4tD.png</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>ddebCWb.jpg</snapshot2>
		<snapshot3>R8U3MMj.jpg</snapshot3>
	</game>
	<game name="MobileWonderGate (Japan)">
		<description>MobileWonderGate (Japan)</description>
		<rom crc="80DE367D" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan.zip/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan%2FMobileWonderGate%20%28Japan%29.zip" sha1="92D4A6FF6F2B1152D8935025F38F910155E5D709" size="1050650" />
		<title_clean>MobileWonderGate</title_clean>
		<snapshot1>kageAr7.png</snapshot1>
	</game>
	<game name="Moero!! Pro Yakyuu Rookies (Japan)">
		<description>Moero!! Pro Yakyuu Rookies (Japan)</description>
		<rom crc="EB995E86" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan.zip/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan%2FMoero%21%21%20Pro%20Yakyuu%20Rookies%20%28Japan%29.zip" sha1="E88E659CC04FC08A04B8C881F62FE086C5CDAB06" size="463233" />
		<title_clean>Moero!! Pro Yakyuu Rookies</title_clean>
		<plot>Moero!! Pro Yakyuu Rookies is a Sports game, developed by TOSE and published by Jaleco Entertainment, which was released in Japan in 2000.</plot>
		<releasedate>30/3/2000</releasedate>
		<genre>Sports</genre>
		<nplayers>1-2 Alt</nplayers>
		<thegamesdb_id>27644</thegamesdb_id>
		<giantbomb_url>https://www.giantbomb.com/moero-pro-yakyuu-rookies/3030-50372/</giantbomb_url>
		<boxart1>AWSRtz6.jpg</boxart1>
		<snapshot1>IzspnGe.png</snapshot1>
	</game>
	<game name="Morita Shougi for WonderSwan (Japan)">
		<description>Morita Shougi for WonderSwan (Japan)</description>
		<rom crc="B159C30D" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan.zip/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan%2FMorita%20Shougi%20for%20WonderSwan%20%28Japan%29.zip" sha1="D70FBC6BE9A9A0F12CEA8A9F7C98AA415E41AAFD" size="101938" />
		<title_clean>Morita Shougi for WonderSwan</title_clean>
		<snapshot1>dgzV2SZ.png</snapshot1>
	</game>
	<game name="Nazo Ou Pocket (Japan)">
		<description>Nazo Ou Pocket (Japan)</description>
		<rom crc="4ED8820C" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan.zip/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan%2FNazo%20Ou%20Pocket%20%28Japan%29.zip" sha1="B358C65BAE818C4B3DE6BF668D16C311534036C2" size="524873" />
		<title_clean>Nazo Ou Pocket</title_clean>
		<plot>Nazo-Oh Pocket is an Adventure game, developed by Bandai Visual and published by Bandai, which was released in Japan in 1999.</plot>
		<releasedate>18/11/1999</releasedate>
		<genre>Adventure</genre>
		<nplayers>1</nplayers>
		<thegamesdb_id>27645</thegamesdb_id>
		<boxart1>GtZJH4s.jpg</boxart1>
		<snapshot1>fNNkaBh.png</snapshot1>
	</game>
	<game name="Neon Genesis Evangelion - Shito Ikusei (Japan)">
		<description>Neon Genesis Evangelion - Shito Ikusei (Japan)</description>
		<rom crc="BF8D9212" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan.zip/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan%2FNeon%20Genesis%20Evangelion%20-%20Shito%20Ikusei%20%28Japan%29.zip" sha1="AE31488CEE1C91F383EFBE3083B4ABEC092DDA36" size="819464" />
		<title_clean>Neon Genesis Evangelion - Shito Ikusei</title_clean>
		<plot>Neon Genesis Evangelion is a Role-Playing game, developed by Soft Machine and published by Bandai, which was released in Japan in 1999.</plot>
		<releasedate>22/7/1999</releasedate>
		<genre>RPG</genre>
		<nplayers>1-2 Alt</nplayers>
		<thegamesdb_id>27646</thegamesdb_id>
		<boxart1>CHx24OH.jpg</boxart1>
		<snapshot1>s3XxG8m.png</snapshot1>
	</game>
	<game name="Nice On (Japan)">
		<description>Nice On (Japan)</description>
		<rom crc="B5DBCF12" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan.zip/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan%2FNice%20On%20%28Japan%29.zip" sha1="6A479EE45E69CD3D6CC6CDDA5A60EFF3077953B0" size="195205" />
		<title_clean>Nice On</title_clean>
		<plot>A simple golf game; Nice On brings the gray-gradient green into the hands itinerant gamers. [CR]The mechanism for golfing in this game is simple as it is classic. The players chibi avatar stands by the tee club aloft whilst a 'power bar' fluctuates up and down beside it. When the player presses a button the power bars movements will stop and how height the bar was will effect the distance of the shot. Before this the player may of course state the direction they'd like to hit the ball and where on it's surface they would like to strike it. Hazards are or course a threat to the novice, such as sand traps, meddlesome trees, etc. The flight of the ball is shown in an overhead view.[CR]Once the ball is on the putting green the view remains over head regardless if the ball is in motion or being struck. The player may here select the direction of the strike to the ball, and the power bar will recommence it's spasms; however, the golfer ball will move of its own accord without any golfer in sight. The putting green is covered by marks that indicate the subtle slopping of the ground that seeks to keep you away from your triple bogey. [CR]Should you find endlessly teeing off with yourself a bit tedious you may use the Communication Cable to play with another human, or you may challenge the npc character. This veritable samurai of the rough, swarthily attired in a fly fishing hat, will critique your game as he putts against you.</plot>
		<releasedate>8/4/1999</releasedate>
		<year>1999</year>
		<genre>Sports</genre>
		<studio>Sammy Corporation</studio>
		<nplayers>1-2 Alt</nplayers>
		<perspective>3rd-Person</perspective>
		<thegamesdb_id>27647</thegamesdb_id>
		<mobygames_url>https://www.mobygames.com/game/wonderswan/nice-on</mobygames_url>
		<boxart1>Kj3TAPc.jpg</boxart1>
		<boxart2>Ctb6JX7.jpg</boxart2>
		<boxart3>fPzLwZa.jpg</boxart3>
		<snapshot1>13hRKSL.png</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>jYj0R5m.png</snapshot2>
		<snapshot3>vewVAaR.png</snapshot3>
		<snapshot4>bKHgGNv.png</snapshot4>
		<snapshot5>PaEim8X.png</snapshot5>
		<snapshot6>u5bIG7r.png</snapshot6>
		<snapshot7>5LPgi4Y.png</snapshot7>
		<snapshot8>wDXEjzh.png</snapshot8>
		<snapshot9>riMLtNG.png</snapshot9>
		<snapshot10>agAJbO7.png</snapshot10>
	</game>
	<game name="Nihon Pro Mahjong Renmei Kounin - Tetsuman (Japan)">
		<description>Nihon Pro Mahjong Renmei Kounin - Tetsuman (Japan)</description>
		<rom crc="44B3E67C" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan.zip/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan%2FNihon%20Pro%20Mahjong%20Renmei%20Kounin%20-%20Tetsuman%20%28Japan%29.zip" sha1="4EEFC5A51008C2AB33E8D04064EC9BDCBC03D036" size="556023" />
		<title_clean>Nihon Pro Mahjong Renmei Kounin - Tetsuman</title_clean>
		<snapshot1>W7Okkur.png</snapshot1>
	</game>
	<game name="Nobunaga no Yabou for WonderSwan (Japan)">
		<description>Nobunaga no Yabou for WonderSwan (Japan)</description>
		<rom crc="C1734309" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan.zip/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan%2FNobunaga%20no%20Yabou%20for%20WonderSwan%20%28Japan%29.zip" sha1="B143CECE1E7DB9D9F660F4E9CA3A95B02A71DCD3" size="167161" />
		<title_clean>Nobunaga no Yabou for WonderSwan</title_clean>
		<snapshot1>oAr8JIx.png</snapshot1>
	</game>
	<game name="Ou-chan no Oekaki Logic (Japan)">
		<description>Ou-chan no Oekaki Logic (Japan)</description>
		<rom crc="631BD97A" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan.zip/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan%2FOu-chan%20no%20Oekaki%20Logic%20%28Japan%29.zip" sha1="0F73D3112B1184F74E728CF1252FFBEE6A146FA6" size="199253" />
		<title_clean>Ou-chan no Oekaki Logic</title_clean>
		<plot>Ou-chan no Oekaki Logic is a digital conversion, with anime mascots, of the classic Japanese newspaper puzzle nonograms. A nonogram is a puzzle on a square or rectangular grid the object of which is to reveal a hidden picture. Along each row and column there is a number or series of numbers which indicate how many squares will be colored in that row or grid. Example; "5 9 4" would mean there would be sets of five, nine, and four colored squares in the grid, in that order, with at least one blank in between. [CR]Ou-chan no Oekaki Logic adds a story mode where Ou-Chan, representing the player, competes with other blobby anime characters in finding hidden images in the nonogram grids.</plot>
		<releasedate>4/7/1999</releasedate>
		<year>2000</year>
		<studio>SunSoft</studio>
		<nplayers>1</nplayers>
		<thegamesdb_id>27649</thegamesdb_id>
		<mobygames_url>https://www.mobygames.com/game/wonderswan/ou-chan-no-oekaki-logic</mobygames_url>
		<giantbomb_url>https://www.giantbomb.com/ochan-no-oekaki-logic/3030-28406/</giantbomb_url>
		<boxart1>xoSY6gl.jpg</boxart1>
		<snapshot1>3w1EHt7.png</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>czxRePF.png</snapshot2>
		<snapshot3>ygPVboz.png</snapshot3>
		<snapshot4>24OFkOY.png</snapshot4>
		<snapshot5>y3vMD9C.png</snapshot5>
		<snapshot6>mi38XfI.png</snapshot6>
		<snapshot7>RzIUrha.png</snapshot7>
		<snapshot8>HWTKzDu.png</snapshot8>
		<snapshot9>SPqPP0o.png</snapshot9>
		<snapshot10>q70KPa9.png</snapshot10>
	</game>
	<game name="Pocket Fighter (Japan)">
		<description>Pocket Fighter (Japan)</description>
		<rom crc="35361250" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan.zip/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan%2FPocket%20Fighter%20%28Japan%29.zip" sha1="FB8D0F4E58A4192989EC71EB6E392D182AAA3EEC" size="1284248" />
		<title_clean>Pocket Fighter</title_clean>
		<plot>[CR][B]Overview:[/B][CR]Pocket Fighter (Also known as Super Gem Fighter: Mini Mix in North America) is an arcade game released by Capcom for it's CPS-2 arcade system, and was later ported to the WonderSwan,  PlayStation, Sega Saturn, as well as to the PlayStation 2 in Street Fighter Alpha's Anthology Collection. Pocket Fighter is a "super deformed" or "chibi" take on Capcom's fighting series, by offering a new animesque graphical style, where all the characters are dramatically shrunken in size. The game could be considered a parody or homage from Capcom to it's fighting series, due to the fact that it has a large variety of cameos/playable characters from all it's different fighting series, such as; Chun Li, Ryu and Zangief who are from Street Fighter II, Ibuki from Street Fighter 3, Morrigan and Felicia, from the Darkstalkers series and Tessa from Red Earth. [CR][B]Gameplay:[/B][CR]Unlike many other fighters, Pocket Fighter has a relatively simple control scheme. In Pocket Fighter, only a punch, kick and "special" button is used, which in turn makes the game much easier and accessible to beginners. Another feature that is not included in other fighters, is the use of gems to control what special moves your character can do. These gems are dropped when you hit an opponent or a treasure chest.  The more gems you collect of one color, the more powerful the special move is that relates to that color. In relation to other series that Capcom produced, each character keeps his/her own special move. Another unique feature of Pocket fighter, is the addition of power-ups - you can collect food to decrease damage on the health bar, as well as collect "orbs" that have some special function, such as a bomb that can be thrown, or turn the player into ice. [CR]Cameos[CR]Amazon Boardwalk                                                                     Elena is eating some ice cream.                                                                      Blanka is inside the ice shop.                                                                       Rikuo is inside the snakes mouth while his son Alba cheers him on.                                                                        Dhalsim washes the elephants back with his long arms while his wife sits ontop of it.Two                                                                            Sasquatch are reaching for the                                                                           banana's while                                                                          Mai-Ling is in their way.The snake in the background is possibly a reference to Blanka's                                                                             Street Fighter II stage that also shares a photographer like this one. Some say the Snake maybe akin to the one from the first                                                                              Resident Evil game.Chinatown Restaurant                                                                    Guy is hiding on the very left.                                                                   Jon Talbain is ontop of the giant plate of food while                                                                   Gen is in front of it.At the first table                                                                 Birdie,                                                                M.Bison and Sodom eat while                                                               Fei-long sits above them and                                                                  Rolento is seen crawling on the ground.The second table has                                                             Victor and                                                              Bishamon.Under the sign near the dragon is                                                            Adon.All alone in the right hand corner sits                                                           Charlie.A panda riding ontop of a ball will roll on by. This is the same panda and ball that                                                         Hsien-Ko turns into when hit by                                                          Anakaris' Pharoahs Curse. Maximum BarIn the balcony is                                                     Guy,                                                    Rolento and                                                   rose.In front of the toilet door is                                                  Birdie. In                                                 Street Fighter Alpha 2, Birdie's stage is inside a male restroom.Sitting together at the table is                                                       Guile and                                                      Charlie.At the bar,                                                Cammy jumps up and down on her chair.                                              Dee Jay is behind the bar dancing.                                             E.Honda is watching Cammy.                                            Huitzil is holding a drum with flowers in it. This is reference to his win pose in                                            Darkstalkers were he pulls out a drum and tuba.                                          June is on the cashier.Above June,                                          Sagat,                                         M.Bison and                                        Adon watch the flight below. Demitri's Moving Castle                                     Jedah is laying on the red rug. This form of Jedah is the one he transforms into during                                     Demitri's Midnight Bliss. Demitri teleports and slides across the floor.The portrait above is also seen in Demitri's Darkstalkers stage as well as in one of                                   Anita's attacks in                                    Marvel Super Heroes; only in Pocket Fighter the man is shown cross dressing from the waist down.Ghouls are seen lugging in Demitri's throne. The girls on this stage appear in various versions of Demitri's other stages.The iron maiden on the far right belongs to                                  Donovan.Dhalsims ToyshopBlodia from                                Cyberbots: Full Metal Madness is seen in the background. Blodia is piloted by                               Jin Saotome.                             M.Bison and                             Cammy are looking into the toy shop while                            Donovan is above on the balcony searching for a lost                           Anita who, is only around the corner, in front of the toy shop.                         Balrog is seen looking at a giant                       Chun-li toy or doll with                         B.B.Hood and                        Jon Talbain are to his right.The shop windows has many references to                      Plasma Sword including in the top right window, Rimgal (the Dinosaur), the face of                     Bistein in the left bottom window and a hologram of                    June.The windows also feature Darkstalkers refrences, a small bat in the top left window, a Hsien-Ko toy in a sled being pulled by pandas, the snowmen seen in various                   Sasquatch moves and poses as well as his Pharoahs Curse form.                  Rikuo is also seen in his Pharoah's curse form as a frog latched onto the window.La Menkoi Ski Resort      Vega is seen wearing no shirt in the cold.     M.Bison is seen sitting on a sled, laughing.The two girls outside of the              igloo are from                 Bishamon's                Darkstalkers: Night Warriors stage while Bishamon and               Sodom are inside of the igloo. The dog, Taro, outside and the statue are also references to Bishamon's stage.Above the stage,            Oro is latched to the the ski lift sleeping, a           Sasquatch is holding onto a line nearby while             Balrog is trying not to fall off a broken chair.In the background        Yun   and         Yang will appear flying through the air one on skis and one on a snowboard.Moonlight Dark Castle   Jon Talbain is seen howling at the moon.In the carriage sits one of   Morrigan's servants. This stage is also a reference to Morrigan's Darkstalkers stage as the fountains are from the game.Tessa's Den Lilith appears sitting above the chest, on the window as long as Morrigan isn't fighting on the stage.Leo is seen polishing his sword while sitting in the chair in front of the fireplace.Felicia, as long as she's not fighting, will appear on the floor napping. The ghost in the bed is from one of Tessa's attacks while a portrait of her appears on the wall.[CR]</plot>
		<releasedate>6/4/2000</releasedate>
		<year>2000</year>
		<genre>Action</genre>
		<studio>Bandai Co.</studio>
		<nplayers>1-2 Alt</nplayers>
		<perspective>Side-Scrolling</perspective>
		<thegamesdb_id>19615</thegamesdb_id>
		<mobygames_url>https://www.mobygames.com/game/wonderswan/pocket-fighter_</mobygames_url>
		<giantbomb_url>https://www.giantbomb.com/pocket-fighter/3030-1329/</giantbomb_url>
		<boxart1>C6XYCML.jpg</boxart1>
		<boxart2>97yWb9Z.jpg</boxart2>
		<snapshot1>I66lLjm.png</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>DEfDW4G.png</snapshot2>
		<snapshot3>2tWd4VJ.png</snapshot3>
		<snapshot4>iddk07g.png</snapshot4>
		<snapshot5>RkAyvDV.png</snapshot5>
		<snapshot6>Q4Jo9yC.png</snapshot6>
		<snapshot7>Txt4xky.png</snapshot7>
		<snapshot8>tB9yglR.png</snapshot8>
		<snapshot9>oGeBo7y.png</snapshot9>
		<snapshot10>NH8QIqp.jpg</snapshot10>
	</game>
	<game name="Pro Mahjong Kiwame for WonderSwan (Japan)">
		<description>Pro Mahjong Kiwame for WonderSwan (Japan)</description>
		<rom crc="90F7E6D6" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan.zip/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan%2FPro%20Mahjong%20Kiwame%20for%20WonderSwan%20%28Japan%29.zip" sha1="32013A7A745A3AA2FD63CC9427C5E1F2635655ED" size="411464" />
		<title_clean>Pro Mahjong Kiwame for WonderSwan</title_clean>
		<snapshot1>Impgw9K.png</snapshot1>
	</game>
	<game name="Puyo Puyo Tsuu (Japan)">
		<description>Puyo Puyo Tsuu (Japan)</description>
		<rom crc="5A41A7BA" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan.zip/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan%2FPuyo%20Puyo%20Tsuu%20%28Japan%29.zip" sha1="D72C1221C2CE3E281A0EE288A3D079AA8E1B714B" size="431856" />
		<title_clean>Puyo Puyo Tsuu</title_clean>
		<plot>Puyo Puyo Tsuu (2) is a Matching Puzzle game, developed and published by Bandai, which was released in Japan in 1999.[CR]https://www.gamefaqs.com/portable/wswan/home/576614.html[CR]</plot>
		<releasedate>4/7/1999</releasedate>
		<genre>Puzzle</genre>
		<studio>Bandai</studio>
		<nplayers>1-2 Alt</nplayers>
		<thegamesdb_id>27650</thegamesdb_id>
		<mobygames_url>https://www.mobygames.com/game/wonderswan/puyo-puyo-2</mobygames_url>
		<giantbomb_url>https://www.giantbomb.com/puyo-puyo-2/3030-4929/</giantbomb_url>
		<boxart1>TRla1wi.jpg</boxart1>
		<snapshot1>4HnE7h8.png</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>hIqK9oy.png</snapshot2>
		<snapshot3>HE7IofX.png</snapshot3>
		<snapshot4>zqGGx0W.png</snapshot4>
		<snapshot5>PN4U21B.png</snapshot5>
		<snapshot6>pZlZg7n.png</snapshot6>
		<snapshot7>ZH3oUf8.png</snapshot7>
		<snapshot8>HT5NN2C.png</snapshot8>
		<snapshot9>5wchhCx.png</snapshot9>
		<snapshot10>KhV0qVN.png</snapshot10>
	</game>
	<game name="Puzzle Bobble (Japan)">
		<description>Puzzle Bobble (Japan)</description>
		<rom crc="302499B9" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan.zip/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan%2FPuzzle%20Bobble%20%28Japan%29.zip" sha1="5E7DABB66B0CA580481AA79EE8B8A5B0C6CE6592" size="122090" />
		<title_clean>Puzzle Bobble</title_clean>
		<plot>Puzzle Bobble is a Matching Puzzle game, developed and published by SunSoft, which was released in Japan in 1999.[CR]https://www.gamefaqs.com/portable/wswan/home/576635.html[CR]</plot>
		<releasedate>4/7/1999</releasedate>
		<genre>Puzzle</genre>
		<studio>SunSoft</studio>
		<nplayers>1-2 Alt</nplayers>
		<thegamesdb_id>27651</thegamesdb_id>
		<giantbomb_url>https://www.giantbomb.com/bust-a-move/3030-14228/</giantbomb_url>
		<boxart1>OADTzx9.jpg</boxart1>
		<boxart2>ikpeeTc.jpg</boxart2>
		<snapshot1>Xwf45ea.png</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>vxdQ9on.jpg</snapshot2>
		<snapshot3>z6jVDdt.jpg</snapshot3>
		<snapshot4>qX7Cf7E.jpg</snapshot4>
		<snapshot5>Pu8v2nE.jpg</snapshot5>
		<snapshot6>8wWQW9N.jpg</snapshot6>
		<snapshot7>qqRuYX5.jpg</snapshot7>
		<snapshot8>1YxfFxb.jpg</snapshot8>
		<snapshot9>7JiaAc6.jpg</snapshot9>
		<snapshot10>vvRyqw9.jpg</snapshot10>
	</game>
	<game name="Rainbow Islands - Putty's Party (Japan)">
		<description>Rainbow Islands - Putty's Party (Japan)</description>
		<rom crc="8F8608AD" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan.zip/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan%2FRainbow%20Islands%20-%20Putty%27s%20Party%20%28Japan%29.zip" sha1="759DEB79A3FC3BEFED705D7264E4B88ADBADACC7" size="885966" />
		<title_clean>Rainbow Islands - Putty's Party</title_clean>
		<plot>A spin-off of the Rainbow Islands games, this title features Putty instead of the classic Bub &amp; Bob. Like the previous games set on the island the character's main tools and weapons are rainbows. These rainbows can be walked on to scale heights or cover gaps. Rainbows can also be used to kill enemies by striking them with the arc as it is created, or after it has taken form jumping on it so that it breaks and the shards rain death on those below. Enemies can also be trapped in rainbows. Enemies killed by rainbow shards will sometimes drop a special item or a gem. A series of gems are needed to properly clear each level.[CR]The goal of each area, aside from collecting gems, is to scale to the top of the island. Islands are made out of a series of themed platforms covered with associated enemies. These areas are scattered with items, mostly food, that will increase your score. Sometimes a rainbow will dislodge hidden food or an enemy will drop some when killed. If your score is high enough you will start to  send out more than one rainbow at a time. At the end of each island there will be a boss. If you fulfilled certain requirements in the level you may get a special item.[CR]The islands in this game are, here listed with their theme:[CR]1. Insect Island: Insects and nature[CR]2. Monster Island: Classic horror monsters[CR]3. Doh Island: Geometric[CR]4. Darius Island: Machines[CR]This game plays vertically.</plot>
		<releasedate>29/6/2000</releasedate>
		<year>2000</year>
		<genre>Action</genre>
		<studio>TAKARA Co.</studio>
		<nplayers>1</nplayers>
		<perspective>Platform</perspective>
		<thegamesdb_id>27652</thegamesdb_id>
		<mobygames_url>https://www.mobygames.com/game/wonderswan/rainbow-islands-puttys-party</mobygames_url>
		<giantbomb_url>https://www.giantbomb.com/rainbow-islands-puttys-party/3030-40494/</giantbomb_url>
		<boxart1>hiditcU.jpg</boxart1>
		<snapshot1>EukQ8IL.png</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>FREU7Se.png</snapshot2>
		<snapshot3>fVRYnV6.png</snapshot3>
		<snapshot4>EB2aFQE.png</snapshot4>
		<snapshot5>n9oBhIP.png</snapshot5>
		<snapshot6>CpKkdyB.png</snapshot6>
		<snapshot7>Oc4abwx.png</snapshot7>
		<snapshot8>nAk0Gmw.png</snapshot8>
		<snapshot9>VcpntZ2.png</snapshot9>
		<snapshot10>seEvXeN.png</snapshot10>
	</game>
	<game name="Ring Infinity (Japan)">
		<description>Ring Infinity (Japan)</description>
		<rom crc="14ADBD4B" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan.zip/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan%2FRing%20Infinity%20%28Japan%29.zip" sha1="9896D93C97381DC06B6F044DE6C9BD112CA0C94B" size="3172768" />
		<title_clean>Ring Infinity</title_clean>
		<plot>Ring: Infinity (&#12522;&#12531;&#12464; &#8734;) is a visual novel game for the WonderSwan released only in Japan in 2000. The game begins much like the other stories in the "Ring" series do by introducing you to the "Cursed Videotape." From there, you must find a way to save yourself, or perish.</plot>
		<releasedate>10/8/2000</releasedate>
		<year>2000</year>
		<genre>Adventure</genre>
		<studio>Kadokawa Shoten</studio>
		<nplayers>1</nplayers>
		<thegamesdb_id>27653</thegamesdb_id>
		<mobygames_url>https://www.mobygames.com/game/wonderswan/ring-</mobygames_url>
		<giantbomb_url>https://www.giantbomb.com/ring-infinity/3030-34677/</giantbomb_url>
		<boxart1>WNXJE2t.png</boxart1>
		<boxart3>JbPr3Ft.jpg</boxart3>
		<snapshot1>IAw7zfi.png</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>Ju2GAp1.png</snapshot2>
		<snapshot3>xWmRhYH.png</snapshot3>
		<snapshot4>9N2kRCH.png</snapshot4>
		<snapshot5>FdTIhuw.png</snapshot5>
		<snapshot6>MareSu1.png</snapshot6>
		<snapshot7>q1Eee2O.png</snapshot7>
		<snapshot8>Yc6iEiO.png</snapshot8>
		<snapshot9>yrRMDYf.png</snapshot9>
		<snapshot10>SqqTfuf.png</snapshot10>
	</game>
	<game name="Robot Works (Asia) (En,Ja)">
		<description>Robot Works (Asia) (En,Ja)</description>
		<rom crc="BE6BE690" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan.zip/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan%2FRobot%20Works%20%28Asia%29%20%28En%2CJa%29.zip" sha1="2117ED92E8CB4AE61868535F1D4D16851B480890" size="294453" />
		<title_clean>Robot Works</title_clean>
		<snapshot1>sd0uulY.png</snapshot1>
	</game>
	<game name="Robot Works (Japan)">
		<description>Robot Works (Japan)</description>
		<rom crc="6ADF0E32" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan.zip/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan%2FRobot%20Works%20%28Japan%29.zip" sha1="4D4D4A3FDE6B1DBBC8F008FBD035FB59624DFBA7" size="273955" />
		<title_clean>Robot Works</title_clean>
		<snapshot1>sd0uulY.png</snapshot1>
	</game>
	<game name="Rockman &amp; Forte - Mirai Kara no Chousensha (Japan)">
		<description>Rockman &amp; Forte - Mirai Kara no Chousensha (Japan)</description>
		<rom crc="CD206A9E" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan.zip/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan%2FRockman%20%26%20Forte%20-%20Mirai%20Kara%20no%20Chousensha%20%28Japan%29.zip" sha1="9F8829AA8EA523E8370CBB2ACD2ACCE056BB7958" size="331925" />
		<title_clean>Rockman &amp; Forte - Mirai Kara no Chousensha</title_clean>
		<plot>[CR][B]Overview:[/B][CR]The game's title screen.Rockman &amp; Forte: Mirai kara no Ch&#333;sensha (literally translated as Rockman &amp; Forte: Challenger from the Future) was released on October 28, 1999 in Japan for the WonderSwan. The game was developed by  Capcom and published by  Bandai. Rockman &amp; Forte is in the  Mega Man franchise; pertaining more to the games that starring  Mega Man and  Bass (Rockman and Forte in Japan).The Dimensions[CR][B]Plot:[/B][CR]It is the year 20XX in Symphony City, where robots and humans can live in harmony and peace. Suddenly, a group of robots calling themselves the Dimensions attacks Symphony City. Their leader is a robot with similar power to Rockman who has dubbed himself Rockman Shadow. Rockman sees this tragedy from  Dr. Light's laboratory, and goes to investigate. At the same time,  Dr. Wily sees the event from his laboratory and sends Forte to investigate.[CR][B]Gameplay:[/B][CR]A screenshot of Rockman, early in the game.As in the previous title,  Mega Man &amp; Bass, there are two characters to select: Rockman and Forte. Rockman handles just about the same, with the ability to charge his attacks and slide on the ground. Forte can shoot quickly, but cannot charge, and can dash and double jump as opposed to sliding. A notable difference from previous Mega Man games is the fact that  Robot Masters do not have a period of invincibility after they have been hit, making it possible to continually hit them. A unique stage, Aircon Man's stage, requires that the handheld be tilted so that the game can be played vertically. There are five weapons to be gathered in this game, with only Compass Man not giving up a weapon.[CR]</plot>
		<releasedate>4/7/1999</releasedate>
		<genre>Platform</genre>
		<studio>Bandai</studio>
		<giantbomb_url>https://www.giantbomb.com/rockman-forte-mirai-kara-no-chousensha/3030-24425/</giantbomb_url>
		<boxart1>VGCnsDz.jpg</boxart1>
		<boxart2>6tAwsj0.jpg</boxart2>
		<snapshot1>HuzprLL.png</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>1vB3Wpl.png</snapshot2>
	</game>
	<game name="Sangokushi for WonderSwan (Japan)">
		<description>Sangokushi for WonderSwan (Japan)</description>
		<rom crc="E385EE88" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan.zip/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan%2FSangokushi%20for%20WonderSwan%20%28Japan%29.zip" sha1="D064B94F31B15564C9A3DBD3A68690244EA043AC" size="219574" />
		<title_clean>Sangokushi for WonderSwan</title_clean>
		<snapshot1>ED109bl.png</snapshot1>
	</game>
	<game name="Sangokushi II for WonderSwan (Japan)">
		<description>Sangokushi II for WonderSwan (Japan)</description>
		<rom crc="812B720D" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan.zip/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan%2FSangokushi%20II%20for%20WonderSwan%20%28Japan%29.zip" sha1="59D904149C3F405357B2715468D509095388A194" size="276857" />
		<title_clean>Sangokushi II for WonderSwan</title_clean>
		<snapshot1>7I6kxzZ.png</snapshot1>
	</game>
	<game name="SD Gundam - Emotional Jam (Japan)">
		<description>SD Gundam - Emotional Jam (Japan)</description>
		<rom crc="AE83F873" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan.zip/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan%2FSD%20Gundam%20-%20Emotional%20Jam%20%28Japan%29.zip" sha1="AE54A1F8916A2D37A1E0C82C5A9B5D8FE0EEAE51" size="1132626" />
		<title_clean>SD Gundam - Emotional Jam</title_clean>
		<plot>SD Gundam: Emotional Jam is a Strategy game, developed by Tom Create and published by Bandai, which was released in Japan in 1999.</plot>
		<releasedate>27/5/1999</releasedate>
		<genre>Strategy</genre>
		<nplayers>1-2 Alt</nplayers>
		<thegamesdb_id>27656</thegamesdb_id>
		<boxart1>ZTQeBG6.jpg</boxart1>
		<snapshot1>eGNSYzZ.png</snapshot1>
	</game>
	<game name="SD Gundam G Generation - Gather Beat (Japan)">
		<description>SD Gundam G Generation - Gather Beat (Japan)</description>
		<rom crc="E4EB3AB1" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan.zip/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan%2FSD%20Gundam%20G%20Generation%20-%20Gather%20Beat%20%28Japan%29.zip" sha1="5E5DB8B066E1B41C5C12A2D4FFA97B73ED6C3F03" size="1644334" />
		<title_clean>SD Gundam G Generation - Gather Beat</title_clean>
		<plot>SD Gundam G Generation: Gather Beat is a Strategy game, developed by Vanguard Works and published by Bandai, which was released in Japan in 2000.</plot>
		<releasedate>13/7/2000</releasedate>
		<genre>Strategy</genre>
		<nplayers>1-2 Alt</nplayers>
		<thegamesdb_id>27657</thegamesdb_id>
		<boxart1>zhH1Ttm.jpg</boxart1>
		<snapshot1>pqVwyS3.png</snapshot1>
	</game>
	<game name="SD Gundam Gashapon Senki - Episode 1 (Japan)">
		<description>SD Gundam Gashapon Senki - Episode 1 (Japan)</description>
		<rom crc="21EB4C59" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan.zip/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan%2FSD%20Gundam%20Gashapon%20Senki%20-%20Episode%201%20%28Japan%29.zip" sha1="E6899DE5B53F73C8978E3330DCA0F2DAAF95F140" size="208753" />
		<title_clean>SD Gundam Gashapon Senki - Episode 1</title_clean>
		<plot>SD Gundam: Gashapon Senki Episode 1 is a Strategy game, developed by Graphic Research and published by Bandai, which was released in Japan in 1999.</plot>
		<releasedate>29/12/1999</releasedate>
		<genre>Strategy</genre>
		<nplayers>1-2 Alt</nplayers>
		<thegamesdb_id>27658</thegamesdb_id>
		<boxart1>E866tPd.jpg</boxart1>
		<snapshot1>ZjjYARd.png</snapshot1>
	</game>
	<game name="Senkaiden - TV Animation Senkaiden Houshin Engi Yori (Japan)">
		<description>Senkaiden - TV Animation Senkaiden Houshin Engi Yori (Japan)</description>
		<rom crc="07A3DD46" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan.zip/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan%2FSenkaiden%20-%20TV%20Animation%20Senkaiden%20Houshin%20Engi%20Yori%20%28Japan%29.zip" sha1="FC8B0B9B7EFEAC54812E7AE54153B7AE0CB9C12F" size="847091" />
		<title_clean>Senkaiden - TV Animation Senkaiden Houshin Engi Yori</title_clean>
		<plot>Senkaiden is a Role-Playing game, developed by Graphic Research and published by Bandai, which was released in Japan in 2000.</plot>
		<releasedate>24/2/2000</releasedate>
		<genre>RPG</genre>
		<nplayers>1-2 Alt</nplayers>
		<thegamesdb_id>27659</thegamesdb_id>
		<boxart1>AVkDdN5.jpg</boxart1>
		<snapshot1>b8w6Gh3.png</snapshot1>
	</game>
	<game name="Sennou Millennium (Japan)">
		<description>Sennou Millennium (Japan)</description>
		<rom crc="301436AC" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan.zip/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan%2FSennou%20Millennium%20%28Japan%29.zip" sha1="708288E70B3186F6C0EF07ACAEF1B50FE6B7AB22" size="622910" />
		<title_clean>Sennou Millennium</title_clean>
		<plot>"Langrisser Millennium" is yet another installment of the long-running Japanese strategy RPG series. You control five main characters: Taji, a young boy whom was chosen as the ruler of the country Salem; Nei Lee Sun, the ruler of Chin, who helps Taji when he gets involved in a war; Masariva, a half-beast and a former slave who became a queen, but preferred the life of a wanderer; Rumaty Marf, the queen of the country Misla, on a quest for an angel who appeared in her dream; and Saryune, the ruler of Vidern, whose only desire is power. Those five rulers meet each other, when they get involved in a war with hostile countries. However, soon they learn a greater evil has appeared in the world - they must reach a faraway island to prevent the reincarnation of an evil god...[CR]The gameplay "Langrisser Millenium" is divided into "Map Mode" and "Battle Mode". In map mode, you move your characters over a map, trying to reach enemy fortresses and to prevent the enemy to reach yours. Everything happens in real time: if you do nothing, the enemy will come and conquer your country. Once in battle mode, you control several teams. You only assign actions to the team leaders, while others fight automatically in round-based strategy combat.</plot>
		<releasedate>16/3/2000</releasedate>
		<genre>Adventure, RPG, Strategy</genre>
		<studio>NCS Corporation</studio>
		<nplayers>1-2 Alt</nplayers>
		<perspective>3rd-Person</perspective>
		<thegamesdb_id>27660</thegamesdb_id>
		<mobygames_url>https://www.mobygames.com/game/wonderswan/langrisser-millennium</mobygames_url>
		<boxart1>A6X6O3V.jpg</boxart1>
		<boxart2>5udrHNl.jpg</boxart2>
		<boxart3>VjvOPKV.jpg</boxart3>
		<snapshot1>t1nZ4N7.png</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>9nCz8yG.gif</snapshot2>
		<snapshot3>YLGgN3j.gif</snapshot3>
		<snapshot4>goawXeY.gif</snapshot4>
		<snapshot5>1BF7rHE.gif</snapshot5>
		<snapshot6>YWkgW3A.gif</snapshot6>
		<snapshot7>rXhNSZq.gif</snapshot7>
		<snapshot8>yJGb4H1.gif</snapshot8>
		<snapshot9>bGQm2c1.gif</snapshot9>
		<snapshot10>J6tGvbv.gif</snapshot10>
	</game>
	<game name="Shanghai Pocket (Japan)">
		<description>Shanghai Pocket (Japan)</description>
		<rom crc="1C489351" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan.zip/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan%2FShanghai%20Pocket%20%28Japan%29.zip" sha1="D64B9B2D567D1CEA5960F64E5BDF83D4514446DA" size="114664" />
		<title_clean>Shanghai Pocket</title_clean>
		<plot>This is a portable edition of the solitaire game Shanghai, the game uses traditional Mah Jong tiles. The aim of the game is to match tiles, four of each type will be put on the playing field, when two tiles are matched they are removed when none remain you win. Only tiles that can be moved freely to the left or right may be matched. A wrong move may result in you not being able to clear the field. [CR]A slight story mode is presented in the Shanghai mode; each tile setup is based on a Zodiac animal that needs it power restored. The goal is to complete all twelve of these stages there by restoring the animals power. [CR]Some variants are also included:[CR]1. Kong Kong: Compete against a computer to clear tiles. If you go slowly you will have tiles sent over to your by your opponent. This type of play is similar to games like Puyo Pop. Kong Kong may be played against another player by using a link cable or against a computer.[CR]2. Challenge (WonderSwan only): A large Shanghai game that you'll try to race through to get the best score. [CR]3. Goldrush: In this mode you will race against an opponent to reach a tile marked 'G'. G is for GOLD, boy! So get cracking.</plot>
		<releasedate>1/4/1999</releasedate>
		<year>1999</year>
		<genre>Simulation, Strategy</genre>
		<studio>SunSoft</studio>
		<nplayers>1-2 Alt</nplayers>
		<perspective>Top-Down</perspective>
		<rating>2.5</rating>
		<thegamesdb_id>27661</thegamesdb_id>
		<mobygames_url>https://www.mobygames.com/game/wonderswan/shanghai-pocket</mobygames_url>
		<giantbomb_url>https://www.giantbomb.com/shanghai-pocket/3030-21853/</giantbomb_url>
		<boxart1>7LPNzc9.jpg</boxart1>
		<snapshot1>yrAwS7L.png</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>M39LpUH.png</snapshot2>
		<snapshot3>L2MjWse.png</snapshot3>
		<snapshot4>iy6NktY.png</snapshot4>
		<snapshot5>b8KGnDv.png</snapshot5>
		<snapshot6>O1D7MoZ.png</snapshot6>
		<snapshot7>uVQUN8k.png</snapshot7>
		<snapshot8>VCg6jk5.png</snapshot8>
		<snapshot9>xqEuw30.png</snapshot9>
		<snapshot10>BbXexdP.png</snapshot10>
	</game>
	<game name="Shin Nihon Pro Wrestling - Toukon Retsuden (Japan)">
		<description>Shin Nihon Pro Wrestling - Toukon Retsuden (Japan)</description>
		<rom crc="5B76F901" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan.zip/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan%2FShin%20Nihon%20Pro%20Wrestling%20-%20Toukon%20Retsuden%20%28Japan%29.zip" sha1="7324C5939B8B64858C96BD9726F5B5C483A11E22" size="377764" />
		<title_clean>Shin Nihon Pro Wrestling - Toukon Retsuden</title_clean>
		<plot>Straight from the National Japan Pro-Wrestling (NJPW) come the greatest wrestlers of the Land of the Rising Sun; beware the Thunder Lyger![CR]Shin Nihon Pro Wrestling Toukon Retsuden is a simple wrestling game where the player takes control of one of six wrestlers, who were current figures at the time of the games publication. Random battles can be arranged or competition in a tournament against all the games wrestlers.[CR]A player controls their wrestler with the directional X buttons and the A &amp; B buttons. A &amp; B perform punches and kicks, in close enough a punch can perform a grab. Once a wrestler is locked in a grab they can be tossed according to the directional buttons. The more abuse a character take the longer it will take them to stand up, this makes them very agreeable to kick or jump upon. [CR]By punching a fallen gladiator you will get him in a lock. When done closer to the injured legs you will usually try to bend them and when done closer to his head you will crush his cranium between your mighty thighs. If you can do this for ten seconds without him breaking free, your chosen wrestler will win.</plot>
		<releasedate>4/3/1999</releasedate>
		<year>1999</year>
		<studio>Tomy</studio>
		<nplayers>1</nplayers>
		<thegamesdb_id>27662</thegamesdb_id>
		<mobygames_url>https://www.mobygames.com/game/wonderswan/shin-nihon-pro-wrestling-toukon-retsuden</mobygames_url>
		<giantbomb_url>https://www.giantbomb.com/shin-nippon-pro-wrestling-toukon-retsuden/3030-46985/</giantbomb_url>
		<boxart1>lblj5gY.jpg</boxart1>
		<boxart2>hEh8YNg.jpg</boxart2>
		<boxart3>mq5sKgv.jpg</boxart3>
		<snapshot1>pJ0kZR1.png</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>hwhC1cF.png</snapshot2>
		<snapshot3>seroDrY.png</snapshot3>
		<snapshot4>DbuXVpr.png</snapshot4>
		<snapshot5>0FJj0bI.png</snapshot5>
		<snapshot6>iIwI3fY.png</snapshot6>
		<snapshot7>tavJDn6.png</snapshot7>
		<snapshot8>LOvCgTH.png</snapshot8>
		<snapshot9>GIn9uiU.png</snapshot9>
		<snapshot10>pQe16Kx.png</snapshot10>
	</game>
	<game name="Shougi Touryuumon (Japan)">
		<description>Shougi Touryuumon (Japan)</description>
		<rom crc="FFF1C0D6" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan.zip/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan%2FShougi%20Touryuumon%20%28Japan%29.zip" sha1="C42339590A6D7864CB4F5728B84C4CCE09779F0A" size="147437" />
		<title_clean>Shougi Touryuumon</title_clean>
		<snapshot1>O8otqyD.png</snapshot1>
	</game>
	<game name="Side Pocket for WonderSwan (Japan)">
		<description>Side Pocket for WonderSwan (Japan)</description>
		<rom crc="8655269E" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan.zip/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan%2FSide%20Pocket%20for%20WonderSwan%20%28Japan%29.zip" sha1="4A756DAB81E0101475DC2E5494270F3DF7DAC1E6" size="753289" />
		<title_clean>Side Pocket for WonderSwan</title_clean>
		<plot>[CR][B]Overview:[/B][CR]Created especially for the US market by Data East (though later released in Japan), Side Pocket is a pool simulator that saw several different ports for the various consoles of the era. The game is set around the tournament scene and gets progressively more difficult as the player goes from venue to venue, eventually entering a global competition.The WonderSwan version is the last game that Data East released before their bankruptcy.[CR][B]Gameplay:[/B][CR]The game controls like many pool simulators (as well as several golf simulators of the time) by allowing the player to select which direction they wish to hit the cue ball in, with a handy dotted line to indicate its trajectory, and then they must tap a button to start the power gauge and tap it again to stop at the desired level of power. The balls then move around and if a ball is potted (provided it wasn't the cue ball) then the player is able to take an immediate additional turn. Play continues until the 8 ball has been sunk.Side Pocket is notable for how it tabulates a player's score: As well as scoring points for winning the game, sinking several balls consecutively and sinking them in numerical order, there are occasionally times where a pocket will light up and the player is able to score a bonus if they're able to sink a ball in that particular pocket. These points are racked up at the end of the match and dictate the overall score.Occasionally there is an opportunity for a bonus trick shot after the game is over to score additional points. These tend to involve potting specific balls in specific pockets, sometimes while avoiding obstacles on the table.[CR]</plot>
		<releasedate>25/11/1999</releasedate>
		<genre>Sports</genre>
		<nplayers>1-2 Alt</nplayers>
		<thegamesdb_id>27663</thegamesdb_id>
		<giantbomb_url>https://www.giantbomb.com/side-pocket/3030-2042/</giantbomb_url>
		<boxart1>N1qyHij.jpg</boxart1>
		<boxart2>LjQ0aLp.jpg</boxart2>
		<snapshot1>wMJd3nh.png</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>NVpqtK5.jpg</snapshot2>
		<snapshot3>V2Pm6PT.jpg</snapshot3>
		<snapshot4>ykKYQbr.jpg</snapshot4>
		<snapshot5>R2TLcSh.png</snapshot5>
		<snapshot6>LuJgVK4.jpg</snapshot6>
		<snapshot7>Kz1Mmxn.png</snapshot7>
		<snapshot8>OmYKdnS.png</snapshot8>
		<snapshot9>lJFo9rl.png</snapshot9>
		<snapshot10>5nKdMXy.png</snapshot10>
	</game>
	<game name="Slither Link (Japan)">
		<description>Slither Link (Japan)</description>
		<rom crc="F00A0330" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan.zip/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan%2FSlither%20Link%20%28Japan%29.zip" sha1="3E31BEACA985AC5041C6E95E0D07F163168E190D" size="141507" />
		<title_clean>Slither Link</title_clean>
		<plot>Slither Link is a fiendishly simple puzzle game from the pages of the Nikoli puzzle magazine. While Nikoli is widely known for coining the puzzle name Sudoku they also have produced a myriad of puzzles often dealing with numbers. [CR]In this puzzle the player needs to create a loop around the fields grid with out having the loop's line cross itself. This would of course present little challenge if it weren't for those pesky numbers. The field is dotted with numerals that signal how many times the line may be next to it. The number one may only have the line contiguous with it on one side, the two two sides, the three three side. Four of course does not exist as that would, by a requirement to have four sides, create a square and thus a intersection of the line. Zeros also exist these may not have any lines bordering them at all. [CR]When a loop has been created so that all numbers are 'touched' appropriately and the line make a full loop you've cleared the puzzle. The game possesses six levels of difficulty and is played vertically on the WonderSwan.</plot>
		<releasedate>20/4/2000</releasedate>
		<year>2000</year>
		<studio>Bandai Co., Ltd.|Nikoli Co.</studio>
		<nplayers>1</nplayers>
		<thegamesdb_id>27664</thegamesdb_id>
		<mobygames_url>https://www.mobygames.com/game/wonderswan/slither-link</mobygames_url>
		<giantbomb_url>https://www.giantbomb.com/slither-link/3030-34679/</giantbomb_url>
		<boxart1>fyEGCKt.jpg</boxart1>
		<boxart3>meHQ2P6.jpg</boxart3>
		<snapshot1>4jTWjla.png</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>UHXFZqU.png</snapshot2>
		<snapshot3>MriXajb.png</snapshot3>
		<snapshot4>J2C8jTH.png</snapshot4>
		<snapshot5>4esXoZM.png</snapshot5>
		<snapshot6>qTOG2zr.png</snapshot6>
		<snapshot7>dwo5BCP.png</snapshot7>
		<snapshot8>4iFMOI7.png</snapshot8>
		<snapshot9>r7TKKtS.png</snapshot9>
		<snapshot10>TPxHvjq.png</snapshot10>
	</game>
	<game name="Soccer Yarou! - Challenge the World (Japan)">
		<description>Soccer Yarou! - Challenge the World (Japan)</description>
		<rom crc="D7438E58" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan.zip/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan%2FSoccer%20Yarou%21%20-%20Challenge%20the%20World%20%28Japan%29.zip" sha1="6EEC04244F4D85807988A2331E7031D0C3549646" size="128799" />
		<title_clean>Soccer Yarou! - Challenge the World</title_clean>
		<plot>Like Coconuts Japan Entertainment Co., Ltd.'s other WonderSwan title Soccer Yarou! ~Challenge The World~ can largely be summed up by it's title; you will pick one of many global soccer teams and set off on a crusade against the rest.[CR]The player controls a single one of their chosen team's members. The AI clumsily takes care of the rest. The player's selected splinter of the team avatar will move in the direction the player presses while dribbling the ball, should it be in his possession. When a button is pressed the ball will be kicked, should fortune spare your 2.49 inch screen a glance, to another player on your team. If another team member gets the ball you will automatically switch to that player. Kicking the ball is achieved by pressing a button which will more likely cause the player's character to fall on his face.[CR]A penalty shot mini-game is included where the view shifts to behind the player making the shot.</plot>
		<releasedate>12/8/1999</releasedate>
		<year>1999</year>
		<studio>Coconuts Japan Entertainment Co.</studio>
		<nplayers>1</nplayers>
		<rating>1.4</rating>
		<thegamesdb_id>27665</thegamesdb_id>
		<mobygames_url>https://www.mobygames.com/game/wonderswan/soccer-yarou-challenge-the-world-</mobygames_url>
		<boxart1>ljKdULt.jpg</boxart1>
		<boxart2>j1hPUwq.jpg</boxart2>
		<boxart3>7VGFlVc.jpg</boxart3>
		<snapshot1>iZnVV6H.png</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>J9d4LBZ.png</snapshot2>
		<snapshot3>dgaAhV9.png</snapshot3>
		<snapshot4>iHVKpev.png</snapshot4>
		<snapshot5>M81Ww1B.png</snapshot5>
		<snapshot6>CxwF20B.png</snapshot6>
		<snapshot7>GMRi4hG.png</snapshot7>
		<snapshot8>GgDlDPq.png</snapshot8>
		<snapshot9>Cj12t5X.png</snapshot9>
		<snapshot10>8GCJbmi.png</snapshot10>
	</game>
	<game name="Sotsugyou for WonderSwan (Japan)">
		<description>Sotsugyou for WonderSwan (Japan)</description>
		<rom crc="F016DFE1" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan.zip/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan%2FSotsugyou%20for%20WonderSwan%20%28Japan%29.zip" sha1="E461762566D529D1B103F119DA50353902D180D7" size="1300355" />
		<title_clean>Sotsugyou for WonderSwan</title_clean>
		<releasedate>25/6/1992</releasedate>
		<giantbomb_url>https://www.giantbomb.com/sotsugyou-graduation/3030-49676/</giantbomb_url>
		<boxart1>46nmLog.png</boxart1>
		<snapshot1>Vx3Fwwh.png</snapshot1>
	</game>
	<game name="Space Invaders (Japan)">
		<description>Space Invaders (Japan)</description>
		<rom crc="8D83014F" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan.zip/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan%2FSpace%20Invaders%20%28Japan%29.zip" sha1="54DD6E3FE81A8A384A0FFDD7A39211A5DE9174C7" size="78221" />
		<title_clean>Space Invaders</title_clean>
		<plot>[CR][B]Overview:[/B][CR]One of the earliest shooting games, Space Invaders was released by Taito in Japan on June 19, 1978. Gameplay involves attempting to defeat waves of aliens cascading down from the top of the screen with a laser cannon that moves along a fixed horizontal axis. The only goal is to earn as many points as possible. Designer Tomohiro Nishikado was in charge of planning, graphic design, and programming for the game and drew creative inspiration from such diverse sources as Gun Fight, Breakout, The War of the Worlds, and Star Wars. The game&#8217;s development cycle lasted for one year, during which Nishikado created custom hardware and software. The game achieved massive popularity upon its release (leading to a temporary shortage of one hundred yen coins in Japan), and helped usher in the golden age of arcade video games (circa 1978-1984).Space Invaders sold over 400,000 arcade cabinets worldwide and grossed around $3.8 billion in revenue by 1982, equivalent to over $13 billion in 2014, making it the highest-grossing video game of all time.[CR][B]Gameplay:[/B][CR]Arcade (cabaret/cocktail) versionGameplay in Space Invaders is relatively simple. The player controls a small ship that can only move laterally across the bottom of the screen and fires vertically. Five rows of eleven aliens each advance slowly from one side of the screen to the other, dropping down one space and reversing direction when they reach either side. The player&#8217;s task is to acquire points by eliminating enemies and to destroy all of the aliens before they reach the bottom of the screen and complete their &#8220;invasion.&#8221; As aliens are destroyed, the speed of the remaining enemies increases, as does the tempo of the music. Once all of the enemies are destroyed, the wave resets and the difficulty increases (a cycle that can continue indefinitely).The Invaders constantly shoot back at the player as they advance from side to side across the screen. To help avoid their attacks, the player can hide behind a number of destructible barriers or &#8220;bunkers&#8221; near the bottom of the screen (four in the original version). Occasionally a &#8220;mystery ship&#8221; will appear near the top of the screen and move quickly from one side to the other while making a distinctive klaxon noise. Destroying it rewards the player with a sizeable point bonus.[CR]Development[CR]While working for the Taito Corporation, designer Nishikado was inspired to create Space Invaders by an early Taito electro-mechanical game called Space Monsters, and by the Atari arcade game Breakout. The game was planned to have tanks, planes, and battleships as enemies, but Nishikado was not happy with their onscreen movements. He considered making the enemies human (which would have been easier to animate), but scrapped the idea since he thought it would be immoral for players to shoot them. After he saw a magazine featuring the 1977 film Star Wars, he decided to use a space theme, and based his alien enemies on the squid-like antagonists from the 1953 movie version of The War of the Worlds.Upright cabinetDue to the limitations of 1970s microprocessors, Nishikado was forced to design and build his own hardware and development tools. The arcade board he put together contained a variety of both Japanese and American components. It used an Intel 8080 central processing unit (designed by American and Japanese engineers), which could output raster graphics on a CRT monitor, but was slow when it came to drawing sprite graphics, so a dedicated Fujitsu MB14241 video shifter (an early example of a graphics chip) was used to accelerate the drawing of sprite graphics to a bitmap framebuffer. Monaural sound was hosted by a combination of analogue circuitry and a Texas Instruments SN76477 sound chip. The system that he put together is now known as the Taito 8080 arcade system board.In spite of his efforts, Nishikado was unable to program the game exactly as he wanted. The hardware that he had assembled was not powerful enough to display graphics in color and the enemies moved slower than he had intended. Fortunately he discovered that the more enemies that were removed from play, the faster the processor could render those that remained. Rather than attempt to design the game to compensate for the speed increase, he opted to leave it in as a challenging gameplay mechanic.It was originally released in Japan by Taito as a cocktail cabinet, with monochrome graphics enhanced by a rainbow-colored cellophane overlay to simulate color graphics. Taito and American licence-holder Bally/Midway then created an upright cabinet that used strips of orange and green cellophane applied to the screen to simulate color graphics, though this version only simulated several colors (compared to Taito's original cocktail version simulating a wider range of colors). Both the Japanese and American upright cabinets also included a painted backdrop of a lunar surface and a starscape, and cabinet art featuring large humanoid creatures that bore little resemblance to the in-game enemies. Nishikado claims that this was due to the artist basing his interpretation on the game&#8217;s original title, Space Monsters.[CR]Impact and Legacy[CR]Soon after its release in Japan, Space Invaders became a huge success, completely taking over certain arcades and earning Taito a tidy profit. By the end of 1978, Taito had installed 100,000 machines across the country and grossed over $600 million dollars. An oft-quoted urban legend states that there was a shortage of 100-yen coins&#8212;and subsequent production increase&#8212;in Japan attributed to the game. By 1980, 300,000 cabinets had been sold in Japan and an additional 60,000 in the United States. By 1981, Space Invaders had made Taito more than $1 billion, and continued to gross an average of $600 million per year, through to 1982, by which time it had grossed $2 billion in quarters (equivalent to $4.6 billion in 2011). This made it the best-selling video game and highest-grossing entertainment product of its time, surpassing the then highest-grossing film Star Wars, which had grossed $486 million in movie tickets.Atari 2600 versionThe 1980 Atari 2600 version represented the first official licensed port of an arcade game to a home console, and and became the first "killer app" for video game consoles by quadrupling sales of the 2600. It sold over two million units in its first year on sale as a home console game, becoming the first title to sell over a million cartridges. Ports were also released for the Atari 8-bit computer line and the Atari 5200, as well as the Nintendo Entertainment System, Game Boy and SNES. Numerous unofficial clones were made as well, such as the popular computer games Super Invader (1979) and TI Invaders (1981).Game designer Shigeru Miyamoto considered Space Invaders a game that revolutionized the video game industry; he was never interested in video games before seeing it. Hideo Kojima also described it as the first video game that impressed him and got him interested in video games. Several publications ascribed the expansion of the video game industry from a novelty into a global industry to the success of the game. Edge magazine attributed the shift of video games from bars and arcades to more mainstream locations like restaurants and department stores to Space Invaders. Its popularity was such that it was the first game where an arcade machine's owner could make up for the cost of the machine in under one month, or in some places within one week.Technology journalist Jason Whittaker credited the game's success to ending the video game crash of 1977, which had earlier been caused by Pong clones flooding the market, and beginning the golden age of video arcade games.According to The Observer, the home console versions were popular and encouraged users to learn programming; many who later became industry leaders. 1UP stated that Space Invaders showed that video games could compete against the major entertainment media at the time: movies, music, and television IGN attributed the launch of the arcade phenomenon in North America in part to Space Invaders. Electronic Games credited the game's success as the impetus behind video gaming becoming a rapidly growing hobby and as "the single most popular coin-operated attraction of all time." Game Informer considered it, along with Pac-Man, one of the most popular arcade games that tapped into popular culture and generated excitement during the golden age of arcades.IGN listed it as one of the "Top 10 Most Influential Games" in 2007, citing the source of inspiration to video game designers and the impact it had on the shooting genre. 1UP ranked it at No. 3 in its list of "The 60 Most Influential Games of All Time," stating that, in contrast to earlier arcade games which "were attempts to simulate already-existing things," Space Invaders was "the first video game as a video game, instead of merely a playable electronic representation of something else." In 2008, Guinness World Records listed it as the top-rated arcade game in technical, creative, and cultural impact.As one of the earliest shooting games, it set precedents and helped pave the way for future titles and for the shooting genre. Space Invaders popularized a more interactive style of gameplay with the enemies responding to the player controlled cannon's movement, and was the first video game to popularize the concept of achieving a high score, being the first to save the player's score. While earlier shooting games allowed the player to shoot at targets, Space Invaders was the first in which targets could fire back at the player. It was also the first game where players were given multiple lives, had to repel hordes of enemies, could take cover from enemy fire, and use destructible barriers,in addition to being the first game to use a continuous background soundtrack, with four simple diatonic descending bass notes repeating in a loop, which was dynamic and changed pace during stages, like a heartbeat sound that increases pace as enemies approached.It also introduced the concept of a difficulty curve, with the aliens moving faster as the player kills more of them, making the game more difficult as it progresses. The game's concept of scaling difficulty became the basis for modern single-player video gaming.Cited by influential creators like Shigeru Miyamoto and Hideo Kojima as a major inspiration, Space Invaders revolutionized the industry following the video game crash of 1977 (brought on by a glut of Pong clones on the market and the departure of manufacturers like RCA and Fairchild). Proving that video games were capable of competing with movies, music and television, Space Invaders has since become recognized as one of the most influential games ever released. It was one of the first games to utilize the concept of a &#8220;high score,&#8221; and was the first to save the player&#8217;s score. It was the first shooter that allowed enemies to shoot back at the player, the first to give the player multiple lives and provide destructible cover against enemy fire. Its success effectively launched an entire genre of space shooters, including Atari&#8217;s Asteroids, Williams&#8217; Defender, and Namco&#8217;s Galaxian series.It moved the gaming industry away from Pong-inspired sports games grounded in real-world situations towards action games involving fantastical situations. Whittaker commented that Space Invaders helped action games become the most dominant genre on both arcades and consoles, through to contemporary times. Guinness World Records considered Space Invaders one of the most successful arcade shooting games by 2008. In describing it as a "seminal arcade classic", IGN listed it as the number eight "classic shoot 'em up". Space Invaders set the template for the shoot 'em up genre. Its worldwide success created a demand for a wide variety of science fiction games, inspiring the development of arcade games, such as Atari's Asteroids, Williams Electronic's Defender, and Namco's Galaxian and Galaga, which were modeled after Space Invaders' gameplay and design. This influence extends to most shooting games released to the present day, including first-person shooters such as Wolfenstein, Doom, Halo, and Call of Duty. Space Invaders also had an influence on early computer dungeon crawl games such as Dungeons of Daggorath, which used similar heartbeat sounds to indicate player health. Space Invaders' concept of a gradually increasing difficulty level also revolutionized the gaming industry.Remakes and sequelsSpace Invaders '95, one of many sequelsRecent ports and remakes include Space Invaders Anniversary, released in 2003 for the PlayStation 2 and including nine variants of the core game. Space Invaders, Space Invaders Part II and Return of the Invaders were featured in the arcade compilation Taito Legends (released in 2005), and Space Invaders '91, Space Invaders '95, and Space Invaders DX were featured in Taito Legends 2 (released in 2006). A remake of the game called Space Invaders Extreme was released for the PSP and Nintendo DS in 2008 and on Xbox Live Arcade in 2009. A second remake, Space Invaders Infinity Gene, was released in 2009 on PlayStation Network, Xbox Live Arcade, and iOS devices. [CR]</plot>
		<releasedate>13/5/1999</releasedate>
		<year>1999</year>
		<studio>SunSoft</studio>
		<nplayers>1-2 Alt</nplayers>
		<rating>5.0</rating>
		<videoid>UO221REd91o</videoid>
		<thegamesdb_id>27667</thegamesdb_id>
		<mobygames_url>https://www.mobygames.com/game/wonderswan/space-invaders_</mobygames_url>
		<giantbomb_url>https://www.giantbomb.com/space-invaders/3030-5099/</giantbomb_url>
		<boxart1>jMwOU9x.jpg</boxart1>
		<boxart2>IBEJDrx.jpg</boxart2>
		<boxart3>GAQbgst.jpg</boxart3>
		<snapshot1>flnVOxb.png</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>5iMKOob.png</snapshot2>
		<snapshot3>PFs0xHh.png</snapshot3>
		<snapshot4>sWScpBD.png</snapshot4>
		<snapshot5>BUZZJFx.png</snapshot5>
		<snapshot6>7HtANlS.png</snapshot6>
		<snapshot7>p3ZeNxv.png</snapshot7>
		<snapshot8>jV50Lhk.jpg</snapshot8>
		<snapshot9>PFAV9y7.jpg</snapshot9>
		<snapshot10>Y7CwWzv.jpg</snapshot10>
		<clearlogo1>HURJstA.png</clearlogo1>
	</game>
	<game name="Super Robot Taisen Compact (Japan)">
		<description>Super Robot Taisen Compact (Japan)</description>
		<rom crc="7021D54F" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan.zip/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan%2FSuper%20Robot%20Taisen%20Compact%20%28Japan%29.zip" sha1="E93D58AB5819992E54223F5D1C4D5AEB6983D6A3" size="854109" />
		<title_clean>Super Robot Taisen Compact</title_clean>
		<plot>[CR][B]Story:[/B][CR]With the brewing conflict between Oldtypes and Newtypes, Dr. Souzou Haran decided to usher in the next step in human evolution by way of the Meganoids. However, his experiment went terribly wrong, as two Meganoids (Zauser and Koros) destroyed Dr. Haran's Martian laboratory. Seeking to expand the Meganoid project, the two declared war on Earth. At the same time, the Muge Empire would stage an invasion, resulting in mass chaos. Luckily, the White Base (with cooperation from the Photon Power Plant, Saotome Research Institute, and Dancougar) would push back the invaders, causing them to scatter across space.One year later, just as Dr. Haran predicted, conflict between Earth Federation and the space-based Principality of Zeon broke out, resulting in the One Year War. The members of the White Base team would be renamed Londo Bell, and would be given the task of defending the Earth.Elsewhere, the aliens from Planet Barm have lost their homeland, and now plot to make the Earth their own...[CR]Featured Series[CR]A list of the anime series which are featured in the game. Super Robot Wars Compact introduced no new series.Mobile Suit Gundam Mobile Suit Gundam 0080: War in the Pocket Mobile Suit Gundam 0083: Stardust Memory Mobile Suit Zeta Gundam Mobile Suit Gundam ZZ Mobile Suit Gundam: Char's Counterattack Mobile Suit Gundam F91 New Mobile Report Gundam Wing: Endless Waltz Mazinger Z Great Mazinger Getter Robo Getter Robo G Shin Getter Robo (manga version) Brave Raideen Brave Leader Daimos Invincible Steel Man Daitarn 3 Aura Battler Dunbine Heavy Metal L-Gaim Super Beast Machine God Dancougar  [CR]New Features[CR]Select Scenario System. Instead of going through the missions in a predetermined path, the game is set up into several chapters. Each chapter has 3-5 missions that can be chosen in any order, before taking on a final mission that closes out that chapter. This is used in all other Compact games, Impact, and MX.End of Mission Bonus. The game rewards the player a skill based on how many turns it took to clear the stage.[CR]</plot>
		<releasedate>28/4/1999</releasedate>
		<genre>Strategy</genre>
		<nplayers>1</nplayers>
		<thegamesdb_id>27668</thegamesdb_id>
		<giantbomb_url>https://www.giantbomb.com/super-robot-wars-compact/3030-23090/</giantbomb_url>
		<boxart1>slJk288.jpg</boxart1>
		<snapshot1>On76bi4.png</snapshot1>
	</game>
	<game name="Super Robot Taisen Compact 2 - Dai-1-bu - Chijou Gekidou Hen (Japan)">
		<description>Super Robot Taisen Compact 2 - Dai-1-bu - Chijou Gekidou Hen (Japan)</description>
		<rom crc="782877BC" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan.zip/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan%2FSuper%20Robot%20Taisen%20Compact%202%20-%20Dai-1-bu%20-%20Chijou%20Gekidou%20Hen%20%28Japan%29.zip" sha1="E6911E5BB0A742BA299E05B20EE81F2FAA4854A5" size="1410474" />
		<title_clean>Super Robot Taisen Compact 2 - Dai-1-bu - Chijou Gekidou Hen</title_clean>
		<plot>[CR][B]Overview:[/B] [CR]Super Robot Wars Compact 2 was the second       Super Robot Wars strategy RPG to be released on the WonderSwan. Like      Super Robot Wars F/    F Final before it, Compact 2 is split into multiple parts: Part 1 and    Part 2 occur simultaneously, while   Part 3 continues from Part 2. Using the WonderSwan's internal memory, players can send their clear data to each successive game; several events are altered based on the player's previous save, gained items are carried over to Part 3, and a special final scenario can be unlocked by clearing the entire trilogy within 777 turns. The game, like  its predecessor, borrows almost all of its gameplay mechanics from F/F Final; however, it introduces the "Support System" which immediately became a core mechanic of the SRW franchise.   Earth Crisis introduces Ninja Senshi Tobikage and Hyper Combat Unit Dangaioh, while Cosmoquake features the debut of Machine Robo: Revenge of Cronos.  The entirety of Compact 2 was remade into  Super Robot Wars Impact for the PlayStation 2.[CR][B]Story:[/B][CR]After the One Year War, the elite Earth Federation forces known as the Titans ran out of control; in the resulting Gryps War, the megalomaniac Paptimus Scirocco would be defeated by the Argama team. As the war raged on, several enemies would appear to take advantage of the chaos: Dr. Hell, the Meganoids, the Dinosaur Empire, and the Muge Zorbados Empire. However, each of these groups would be crushed by the Super Robots.With the war seemingly over, the Earth Federation decided to reduce their military might. Unfortunately, the Vegan army appears, along with the Titan/Neo Zeon remnants and the mysterious Gaizok. Thus, the Earth again faces a crisis.The story begins on Earth, at the Federation Army Far East Division's Cyber Beast Force Base...[CR]Featured Series[CR] A list of the anime series which are featured in the game. Series that premiered in the Super Robot Wars series in this game are marked with "(new)". Special Note: As the events of SRW Compact 2-1 and Compact 2-2 occur simultaneously, many robots will appear in a game, only to later disappear from the roster completely; therefore, this list only covers units that are available at the end of the game. For a more complete series list, see         SRW Compact 2-3 or        Super Robot Wars Impact.Mobile Suit Gundam Mobile Suit Gundam: The 08th MS Team Mobile Suit Gundam 0080: War in the Pocket Mobile Suit Zeta Gundam Mobile Suit Gundam: Char's Counterattack Mazinger Z* Great Mazinger* Getter Robo Getter Robo G Super Electromagnetic Robo Combattler V Aura Battler Dunbine Super Beast Machine God Dancougar Dangaioh (new) Ninja Senshi Tobikage (new) Banpresto Originals (Original characters created for the game)   *Early on, the player is forced to send one team into space, removing them from the game.[CR]New Features[CR]Support Attack/Support Defense. By standing adjacent to an attacking unit, a second unit can attack after the enemy has had a chance to counter. Likewise, a unit standing next to an attacked unit may take the hit. While very basic in Compact 2, future games would further refine the system.[CR]</plot>
		<releasedate>30/3/2000</releasedate>
		<genre>Strategy</genre>
		<nplayers>1</nplayers>
		<thegamesdb_id>27669</thegamesdb_id>
		<giantbomb_url>https://www.giantbomb.com/super-robot-wars-compact-2-part-1-earth-crisis/3030-23040/</giantbomb_url>
		<boxart1>oZZ3P5Z.jpg</boxart1>
		<snapshot1>pfc8GMf.png</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>GoKxsh7.jpg</snapshot2>
		<snapshot3>j4i5Yzr.jpg</snapshot3>
		<snapshot4>O2aXj57.jpg</snapshot4>
	</game>
	<game name="Super Robot Taisen Compact 2 - Dai-2-bu - Uchuu Gekishin Hen (Japan)">
		<description>Super Robot Taisen Compact 2 - Dai-2-bu - Uchuu Gekishin Hen (Japan)</description>
		<rom crc="ECBB46DE" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan.zip/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan%2FSuper%20Robot%20Taisen%20Compact%202%20-%20Dai-2-bu%20-%20Uchuu%20Gekishin%20Hen%20%28Japan%29.zip" sha1="6014AC0B8978E710F26C9CC41180CDF788584743" size="1645577" />
		<title_clean>Super Robot Taisen Compact 2 - Dai-2-bu - Uchuu Gekishin Hen</title_clean>
		<plot>[CR][B]Overview:[/B] [CR]Super Robot Wars Compact 2 was the second       Super Robot Wars strategy RPG to be released on the WonderSwan. Like      Super Robot Wars F/    F Final before it, Compact 2 is split into multiple parts: Part 1 and    Part 2 occur simultaneously, while   Part 3 continues from Part 2. Using the WonderSwan's internal memory, players can send their clear data to each successive game; several events are altered based on the player's previous save, gained items are carried over to Part 3, and a special final scenario can be unlocked by clearing the entire trilogy within 777 turns. The game, like  its predecessor, borrows almost all of its gameplay mechanics from F/F Final; however, it introduces the "Support System" which immediately became a core mechanic of the SRW franchise.   Earth Crisis introduces Ninja Senshi Tobikage and Hyper Combat Unit Dangaioh, while Cosmoquake features the debut of Machine Robo: Revenge of Cronos.  The entirety of Compact 2 was remade into  Super Robot Wars Impact for the PlayStation 2.[CR][B]Story:[/B][CR]After the One Year War, the elite Earth Federation forces known as the Titans ran out of control; in the resulting Gryps War, the megalomaniac Paptimus Scirocco would be defeated by the Argama team. As the war raged on, several enemies would appear to take advantage of the chaos: Dr. Hell, the Meganoids, the Dinosaur Empire, and the Muge Zorbados Empire. However, each of these groups would be crushed by the Super Robots.With the war seemingly over, the Earth Federation decided to reduce their military might. Unfortunately, the Vegan army appears, along with the Titan/Neo Zeon remnants and the mysterious Gaizok. Thus, the Earth again faces a crisis.The story begins on Earth, at the Federation Army Far East Division's Cyber Beast Force Base...[CR]Featured Series[CR] A list of the anime series which are featured in the game. Series that premiered in the Super Robot Wars series in this game are marked with "(new)". Special Note: As the events of SRW Compact 2-1 and Compact 2-2 occur simultaneously, many robots will appear in a game, only to later disappear from the roster completely; therefore, this list only covers units that are available at the end of the game. For a more complete series list, see         SRW Compact 2-3 or        Super Robot Wars Impact.Mobile Suit Gundam Mobile Suit Gundam: The 08th MS Team Mobile Suit Gundam 0080: War in the Pocket Mobile Suit Zeta Gundam Mobile Suit Gundam: Char's Counterattack Mazinger Z* Great Mazinger* Getter Robo Getter Robo G Super Electromagnetic Robo Combattler V Aura Battler Dunbine Super Beast Machine God Dancougar Dangaioh (new) Ninja Senshi Tobikage (new) Banpresto Originals (Original characters created for the game)   *Early on, the player is forced to send one team into space, removing them from the game.[CR]New Features[CR]Support Attack/Support Defense. By standing adjacent to an attacking unit, a second unit can attack after the enemy has had a chance to counter. Likewise, a unit standing next to an attacked unit may take the hit. While very basic in Compact 2, future games would further refine the system.[CR]</plot>
		<releasedate>14/9/2000</releasedate>
		<genre>Strategy</genre>
		<nplayers>1</nplayers>
		<thegamesdb_id>27670</thegamesdb_id>
		<giantbomb_url>https://www.giantbomb.com/super-robot-wars-compact-2-part-1-earth-crisis/3030-23040/</giantbomb_url>
		<boxart1>4GNtXRt.jpg</boxart1>
		<snapshot1>CKWPtdy.png</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>GoKxsh7.jpg</snapshot2>
		<snapshot3>j4i5Yzr.jpg</snapshot3>
		<snapshot4>O2aXj57.jpg</snapshot4>
	</game>
	<game name="Super Robot Taisen Compact 2 - Dai-3-bu - Ginga Kessen Hen (Japan)">
		<description>Super Robot Taisen Compact 2 - Dai-3-bu - Ginga Kessen Hen (Japan)</description>
		<rom crc="0B0F8981" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan.zip/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan%2FSuper%20Robot%20Taisen%20Compact%202%20-%20Dai-3-bu%20-%20Ginga%20Kessen%20Hen%20%28Japan%29.zip" sha1="D24D8CEA57C5C487E877EAA523EEFB0DD184556D" size="1763529" />
		<title_clean>Super Robot Taisen Compact 2 - Dai-3-bu - Ginga Kessen Hen</title_clean>
		<plot>[CR][B]Overview:[/B] [CR]Super Robot Wars Compact 2 was the second        Super Robot Wars strategy RPG to be released on the WonderSwan. Like       Super Robot Wars F/     F Final before it, Compact 2 is split into multiple parts:  Part 1 and     Part 2 occur simultaneously, while Part 3 continues from Part 2. Using the WonderSwan's internal memory, players  can send their clear data to each successive game; several events are  altered based on the player's previous save, gained items are carried  over to Part 3, and a special final scenario can be unlocked by clearing  the entire trilogy within 777 turns. The game, like   its predecessor,  borrows almost all of its gameplay mechanics from F/F Final; however,  it introduces the "Support System" which immediately became a core  mechanic of the SRW franchise.      The entirety of Compact 2 was remade into  Super Robot Wars Impact for the PlayStation 2.[CR][B]Story:[/B][CR]As the asteroid (introduced in Compact 2-2) approaches Earth, Londo Bell worries that they may not have enough power to destroy it. Meanwhile, both Kyosuke and Excellen receive a message from the Einsts, causing Kyosuke to worry about his girlfriend. Excellen falls into a hypnotic state, and abruptly leaves the Ra Cailum.The Gandol is able to make contact with the Ra Cailum, and the dragon-battleship moves to unite with Londo Bell. However, the Einst appear in what seems to be an attempt to stop the infiltration of the asteroid...[CR]Featured Series[CR] A list of the anime series which are featured in the game. This game introduces no new series. Mobile Suit Gundam Mobile Suit Gundam: The 08th MS Team Mobile Suit Gundam 0080: War in the Pocket Mobile Suit Gundam 0083: Stardust Memory Mobile Suit Zeta Gundam Mobile Suit Gundam ZZ Mobile Suit Gundam: Char's Counterattack Mobile Suit Gundam F91 Mazinger Z Great Mazinger UFO Robo Grendizer Getter Robo Getter Robo G Shin Getter Robo (manga version) Brave Raideen Super Electromagnetic Robo Combattler V Invincible Super Man Zambot 3 Invincible Steel Man Daitarn 3 Aura Battler Dunbine New Story of Aura Battler Dunbine (units only) Super Beast Machine God Dancougar Dangaioh  Ninja Senshi Tobikage  Machine Robo: Revenge of Chronos  Banpresto Originals (original characters created for the game)  [CR]</plot>
		<releasedate>28/1/2001</releasedate>
		<genre>Strategy</genre>
		<nplayers>1</nplayers>
		<thegamesdb_id>27671</thegamesdb_id>
		<giantbomb_url>https://www.giantbomb.com/super-robot-wars-compact-2-part-3-galaxy-showdown/3030-23044/</giantbomb_url>
		<boxart1>YOOw8f9.jpg</boxart1>
		<snapshot1>3ZfrLFX.png</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>ZRqwnnv.jpg</snapshot2>
		<snapshot3>gS5CxSx.jpg</snapshot3>
	</game>
	<game name="Taikyoku Igo - Heisei Kiin (Japan)">
		<description>Taikyoku Igo - Heisei Kiin (Japan)</description>
		<rom crc="9597F37F" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan.zip/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan%2FTaikyoku%20Igo%20-%20Heisei%20Kiin%20%28Japan%29.zip" sha1="813F296B5B0DDAA34F1D3E5AA9955B1DB1918F7D" size="125840" />
		<title_clean>Taikyoku Igo - Heisei Kiin</title_clean>
		<thegamesdb_id>31927</thegamesdb_id>
		<boxart1>seszOS2.jpg</boxart1>
		<snapshot1>tpE1eTE.png</snapshot1>
	</game>
	<game name="Tanjou Debut for WonderSwan (Japan)">
		<description>Tanjou Debut for WonderSwan (Japan)</description>
		<rom crc="8B74F59A" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan.zip/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan%2FTanjou%20Debut%20for%20WonderSwan%20%28Japan%29.zip" sha1="2F35D250B8DDEB98CA3A2704A4AD85713F4C71B0" size="1091226" />
		<title_clean>Tanjou Debut for WonderSwan</title_clean>
		<plot>Tanjou Debut for WonderSwan is a Strategy game, developed and published by Bandai Visual, which was released in Japan in 2000.</plot>
		<releasedate>24/2/2000</releasedate>
		<genre>Strategy</genre>
		<nplayers>1</nplayers>
		<thegamesdb_id>27672</thegamesdb_id>
		<giantbomb_url>https://www.giantbomb.com/tanjou-debut/3030-33131/</giantbomb_url>
		<boxart1>ydgBhon.jpg</boxart1>
		<snapshot1>eZFf43s.png</snapshot1>
	</game>
	<game name="Tare Panda no GunPey (Japan)">
		<description>Tare Panda no GunPey (Japan)</description>
		<rom crc="A5643AA3" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan.zip/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan%2FTare%20Panda%20no%20GunPey%20%28Japan%29.zip" sha1="9622C65C939F05A9DFAE288919EC5BD15C348F14" size="436711" />
		<title_clean>Tare Panda no GunPey</title_clean>
		<plot>Tarepanda no Gunpey is a Puzzle game, published by Bandai, which was released in Japan in 1999.[CR]https://www.gamefaqs.com/portable/wswan/home/576560.html[CR]</plot>
		<releasedate>4/7/1999</releasedate>
		<year>1999</year>
		<genre>Puzzle</genre>
		<studio>Bandai</studio>
		<nplayers>1-2 Alt</nplayers>
		<thegamesdb_id>27673</thegamesdb_id>
		<mobygames_url>https://www.mobygames.com/game/wonderswan/tarepanda-no-gunpey</mobygames_url>
		<giantbomb_url>https://www.giantbomb.com/gunpey/3030-13414/</giantbomb_url>
		<boxart1>ws11kwu.jpg</boxart1>
		<boxart2>UtiQq9C.jpg</boxart2>
		<boxart3>R80dyz3.jpg</boxart3>
		<snapshot1>3XZrTYJ.png</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>okmtcaw.png</snapshot2>
		<snapshot3>Ox3qc1e.png</snapshot3>
		<snapshot4>4FHrVzI.png</snapshot4>
		<snapshot5>JhSb44I.png</snapshot5>
		<snapshot6>1L13Xx8.png</snapshot6>
		<snapshot7>v6kbYZY.png</snapshot7>
		<snapshot8>MOInRBZ.png</snapshot8>
		<snapshot9>L1uziHL.png</snapshot9>
		<snapshot10>rqPPZ1n.png</snapshot10>
	</game>
	<game name="Tekken Card Challenge (Japan)">
		<description>Tekken Card Challenge (Japan)</description>
		<rom crc="E7C608E5" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan.zip/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan%2FTekken%20Card%20Challenge%20%28Japan%29.zip" sha1="96A9CE5E56DC0C9648027AD4454E6F35E88D9A07" size="522151" />
		<title_clean>Tekken Card Challenge</title_clean>
		<plot>Fighting games are generally interested in making a player hit a complex mash of buttons to perform pugilistic wonders. This game is however card based, how can that work? During a battle between two opponents a set of five moves will appear on a roulette. The player hits a button to stop the rotation of the selector to semi-randomly select a field. A higher number card will always cancels out a lower number card. Higher number cards also do more damage. Block cards and counter cards also exist.[CR]A number of different attacks are available: combo cards pile up, allowing multiple cards to be selected until a combo card is reselected or a non-combo card is selected; juggling cards which allow for classic fighting game mechanics by allowing another attack after the first; charge cards allow the player to wait a turn to do extra damage should the player use an attack the next turn.[CR]All cards have different visuals, and oft times different names, for different characters. [CR]There are several game modes: a classic arcade battle where the player selects a character and a computer controlled character to face; an adventure mode where the player finds new cards and unlocks new character by defeating them; and a multiplayer vs. match for WonderSwan wielding humans.[CR]The story mode plays on a 15x15 grid map covered with shrines, villages, and impassible mountains. You will only have a certain number of steps to make it to stage exit or you'll lose. Of course this Harshadic field is populated with a grave propensity of villains. Roving in the dark, for all the area of the world is obscured by 'fog' until the player walks there, are mysterious stormtroopers called Crow, Owl, Eagle. Also wandering the land are Tekken characters who hold long standing grudges against the player's character. Above it all in a high tower is the heinous Ogre, can he be defeated? [CR]Along the way cards can be found that will increase the amount of moves that can be performed in combat. Sacred ziggurats exist, two per map, that will heal wounds and, if enough enemies have been defeated since the last shrine, a new form of attack card be obtained. These shrines may not be reentered. [CR]Players may fight their friends or foes using the Communication Cable to connect two WonderSwans for a fight.</plot>
		<releasedate>17/6/1999</releasedate>
		<year>1999</year>
		<genre>Action, Adventure, RPG</genre>
		<studio>Bandai Co.</studio>
		<nplayers>1-2 Alt</nplayers>
		<perspective>3rd-Person</perspective>
		<thegamesdb_id>27674</thegamesdb_id>
		<mobygames_url>https://www.mobygames.com/game/wonderswan/tekken-card-challenge</mobygames_url>
		<giantbomb_url>https://www.giantbomb.com/tekken-card-challenge/3030-31581/</giantbomb_url>
		<boxart1>K7ajInX.jpg</boxart1>
		<boxart2>BbqowVZ.jpg</boxart2>
		<boxart3>sYD9ylh.jpg</boxart3>
		<snapshot1>BKyFan9.png</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>asr2hQQ.png</snapshot2>
		<snapshot3>c1smmzp.png</snapshot3>
		<snapshot4>XVfslOP.png</snapshot4>
		<snapshot5>RXJNfkU.png</snapshot5>
		<snapshot6>apTH9kq.png</snapshot6>
		<snapshot7>176qoyg.png</snapshot7>
		<snapshot8>VFOKPT7.png</snapshot8>
		<snapshot9>K1u6F0Y.png</snapshot9>
		<snapshot10>XCnr7Jp.png</snapshot10>
	</game>
	<game name="Terrors (Japan)">
		<description>Terrors (Japan)</description>
		<rom crc="EF5B6B82" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan.zip/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan%2FTerrors%20%28Japan%29.zip" sha1="7148D750F12B5DA9A0EFD99F5A5A7CCADECBDF60" size="2710033" />
		<title_clean>Terrors</title_clean>
		<plot>Terrors is an Adventure game, developed by Megas and published by Bandai, which was released in Japan in 1999.</plot>
		<releasedate>5/8/1999</releasedate>
		<genre>Adventure</genre>
		<nplayers>1</nplayers>
		<thegamesdb_id>27675</thegamesdb_id>
		<giantbomb_url>https://www.giantbomb.com/terrors/3030-46412/</giantbomb_url>
		<boxart1>nYSpvdp.jpg</boxart1>
		<snapshot1>7vO4C9H.png</snapshot1>
	</game>
	<game name="Tetsujin 28 Gou (Japan)">
		<description>Tetsujin 28 Gou (Japan)</description>
		<rom crc="6F304DCA" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan.zip/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan%2FTetsujin%2028%20Gou%20%28Japan%29.zip" sha1="65C4C6AAA36328BBA5D56419AF59AF5D3420ED78" size="3280430" />
		<title_clean>Tetsujin 28 Gou</title_clean>
		<plot>Tetsujin 28-gou is an Adventure game, published by MegaHouse, which was released in Japan in 1999.</plot>
		<releasedate>22/12/1999</releasedate>
		<genre>Adventure</genre>
		<nplayers>1</nplayers>
		<thegamesdb_id>27676</thegamesdb_id>
		<boxart1>uCkpSAv.jpg</boxart1>
		<snapshot1>WGhbZbn.png</snapshot1>
	</game>
	<game name="Time Bokan Series - Bokan Densetsu - Butamo Odaterya Doronbou (Japan)">
		<description>Time Bokan Series - Bokan Densetsu - Butamo Odaterya Doronbou (Japan)</description>
		<rom crc="7DA6ACB9" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan.zip/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan%2FTime%20Bokan%20Series%20-%20Bokan%20Densetsu%20-%20Butamo%20Odaterya%20Doronbou%20%28Japan%29.zip" sha1="AD77D2E8429D5ED926D514D926050086F4EDBEEE" size="735995" />
		<title_clean>Time Bokan Series - Bokan Densetsu - Butamo Odaterya Doronbou</title_clean>
		<plot>Time Bokan Series: Bokan Densetsu - Buta mo Odaterya Doronboo is a Role-Playing game, developed by Alpha Unit and published by Banpresto, which was released in Japan in 2000.</plot>
		<releasedate>27/4/2000</releasedate>
		<genre>RPG</genre>
		<nplayers>1</nplayers>
		<thegamesdb_id>27677</thegamesdb_id>
		<giantbomb_url>https://www.giantbomb.com/time-bokan-series-bokan-densetsu-buta-mo-o-daterya/3030-30026/</giantbomb_url>
		<boxart1>njT5fVC.jpg</boxart1>
		<snapshot1>uGoSA7R.png</snapshot1>
	</game>
	<game name="Tokyo Majin Gakuen - Fuju Houroku (Japan)">
		<description>Tokyo Majin Gakuen - Fuju Houroku (Japan)</description>
		<rom crc="91117D1B" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan.zip/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan%2FTokyo%20Majin%20Gakuen%20-%20Fuju%20Houroku%20%28Japan%29.zip" sha1="866C67737A4FBB5F09A0B13BBDB89397BCAB1F55" size="3018514" />
		<title_clean>Tokyo Majin Gakuen - Fuju Houroku</title_clean>
		<plot>Tokyo Majin Gakuen is a Role-Playing game, developed by Shout! Designworks and published by Asmik Ace Entertainment, Inc, which was released in Japan in 2000.</plot>
		<releasedate>12/10/2000</releasedate>
		<genre>RPG</genre>
		<nplayers>1-2 Alt</nplayers>
		<thegamesdb_id>27678</thegamesdb_id>
		<giantbomb_url>https://www.giantbomb.com/tokyo-majin-gakuen/3030-33479/</giantbomb_url>
		<boxart1>RSiWVZA.jpg</boxart1>
		<snapshot1>pljP7TG.png</snapshot1>
	</game>
	<game name="Trump Collection - Bottom-Up Teki Trump Seikatsu (Japan)">
		<description>Trump Collection - Bottom-Up Teki Trump Seikatsu (Japan)</description>
		<rom crc="07A3B862" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan.zip/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan%2FTrump%20Collection%20-%20Bottom-Up%20Teki%20Trump%20Seikatsu%20%28Japan%29.zip" sha1="AB3C925BF1BFD36403335AF0C0365BE8A2950CA8" size="137520" />
		<title_clean>Trump Collection - Bottom-Up Teki Trump Seikatsu</title_clean>
		<plot>Trump Collection is a Miscellaneous game, published by Bottom Up, which was released in Japan in 1999.[CR]https://www.gamefaqs.com/portable/wswan/home/576634.html[CR]</plot>
		<releasedate>4/7/1999</releasedate>
		<genre>Card</genre>
		<studio>Bottom Up</studio>
		<snapshot1>FnD3utq.png</snapshot1>
	</game>
	<game name="Trump Collection 2 - Bottom-Up Teki Sekaiisshuu no Tabi (Japan)">
		<description>Trump Collection 2 - Bottom-Up Teki Sekaiisshuu no Tabi (Japan)</description>
		<rom crc="A18AA7AF" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan.zip/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan%2FTrump%20Collection%202%20-%20Bottom-Up%20Teki%20Sekaiisshuu%20no%20Tabi%20%28Japan%29.zip" sha1="64A3053C0F92681EB514E55ADABC8BA0DA1CB1A1" size="163279" />
		<title_clean>Trump Collection 2 - Bottom-Up Teki Sekaiisshuu no Tabi</title_clean>
		<plot>Trump Collection 2: Bottom Up Teki Sekai Isshuu no Tabi is a Miscellaneous game, published by Bottom Up, which was released in Japan in 2000.[CR]https://www.gamefaqs.com/portable/wscolor/home/579260.html[CR]</plot>
		<releasedate>4/7/2000</releasedate>
		<genre>Card</genre>
		<studio>Bottom Up</studio>
		<snapshot1>mZUceGy.png</snapshot1>
	</game>
	<game name="Turntablist - DJ Battle (Japan)">
		<description>Turntablist - DJ Battle (Japan)</description>
		<rom crc="0D5171F0" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan.zip/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan%2FTurntablist%20-%20DJ%20Battle%20%28Japan%29.zip" sha1="858F1F57B5522A1701CC8A0ABAE43CEC948E26A6" size="2186204" />
		<title_clean>Turntablist - DJ Battle</title_clean>
		<plot>Turntablist: DJ Battle is an Action game, developed and published by Bandai, which was released in Japan in 1999.</plot>
		<releasedate>25/11/1999</releasedate>
		<genre>Action</genre>
		<nplayers>1</nplayers>
		<thegamesdb_id>27680</thegamesdb_id>
		<boxart1>0XPrRej.jpg</boxart1>
		<snapshot1>FCksIJ9.png</snapshot1>
	</game>
	<game name="Umizuri ni Ikou! (Japan)">
		<description>Umizuri ni Ikou! (Japan)</description>
		<rom crc="86B56511" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan.zip/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan%2FUmizuri%20ni%20Ikou%21%20%28Japan%29.zip" sha1="4F739292D11A45490851EAF40C0A7081824AD75A" size="259892" />
		<title_clean>Umizuri ni Ikou!</title_clean>
		<plot>Umizuri ni Ikou! is a Sports game, published by Coconuts Japan, which was released in Japan in 1999.</plot>
		<releasedate>1/4/1999</releasedate>
		<year>1999</year>
		<genre>Sports</genre>
		<studio>Coconuts Japan Entertainment Co.</studio>
		<nplayers>1</nplayers>
		<perspective>3rd-Person</perspective>
		<rating>2.0</rating>
		<thegamesdb_id>27681</thegamesdb_id>
		<mobygames_url>https://www.mobygames.com/game/wonderswan/umitsuri-ni-ikou</mobygames_url>
		<boxart1>B7OcO8e.jpg</boxart1>
		<boxart2>hNjUjGE.jpg</boxart2>
		<boxart3>Qmbhhfi.jpg</boxart3>
		<snapshot1>MpV6LLq.png</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>hrpvWtw.png</snapshot2>
		<snapshot3>lr0rMjF.png</snapshot3>
		<snapshot4>VtnJJsS.png</snapshot4>
		<snapshot5>bn5xvac.png</snapshot5>
		<snapshot6>dPl1An4.png</snapshot6>
		<snapshot7>zdFEUzG.png</snapshot7>
		<snapshot8>KgSlI8s.png</snapshot8>
		<snapshot9>UWoNLnP.png</snapshot9>
		<snapshot10>Gf4hiiO.png</snapshot10>
	</game>
	<game name="Uzumaki - Denshi Kaiki Hen (Japan)">
		<description>Uzumaki - Denshi Kaiki Hen (Japan)</description>
		<rom crc="812020EF" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan.zip/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan%2FUzumaki%20-%20Denshi%20Kaiki%20Hen%20%28Japan%29.zip" sha1="4C8166E0632BDB8C098D586A7B1522ED7B63B5F7" size="1110726" />
		<title_clean>Uzumaki - Denshi Kaiki Hen</title_clean>
		<plot>[CR][B]Overview:[/B][CR]Uzumaki: Denshi Kaikihen is an interactive horror manga based on the manga Uzumaki by Junji Ito. It is a the struggles of a girl in an isolated Japanese town as it comes to be possessed by the very concept of the spiral shape ("Uzumaki" is the Japanese word for "spiral").[CR]</plot>
		<releasedate>3/2/2000</releasedate>
		<year>2000</year>
		<genre>Adventure</genre>
		<studio>Omega Micott Inc.</studio>
		<nplayers>1</nplayers>
		<rating>4.4</rating>
		<thegamesdb_id>27625</thegamesdb_id>
		<mobygames_url>https://www.mobygames.com/game/wonderswan/uzumaki-denshi-kaikihen</mobygames_url>
		<giantbomb_url>https://www.giantbomb.com/uzumaki-denshi-kaikihen/3030-4965/</giantbomb_url>
		<boxart1>iQ2x6wm.jpg</boxart1>
		<boxart2>BJc3Qst.jpg</boxart2>
		<boxart3>qzNvODA.jpg</boxart3>
		<snapshot1>96SEwKE.png</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>d5pTqxL.png</snapshot2>
		<snapshot3>zfYuUGZ.png</snapshot3>
		<snapshot4>BNVYJWH.png</snapshot4>
		<snapshot5>I7ufGvn.png</snapshot5>
		<snapshot6>glCJB23.png</snapshot6>
		<snapshot7>pp2NpAg.png</snapshot7>
		<snapshot8>i2Z1vYj.png</snapshot8>
		<snapshot9>xVIDP3Z.png</snapshot9>
		<snapshot10>RS8d9UE.png</snapshot10>
	</game>
	<game name="Vaitz Blade (Japan)">
		<description>Vaitz Blade (Japan)</description>
		<rom crc="8FC9E145" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan.zip/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan%2FVaitz%20Blade%20%28Japan%29.zip" sha1="CFB877F0988920C8FE4DA5CDD7583197799DF621" size="2007012" />
		<title_clean>Vaitz Blade</title_clean>
		<plot>Vaitz Blade is a Role-Playing game, developed by Tom Create and published by Bandai, which was released in Japan in 1999.</plot>
		<releasedate>24/6/1999</releasedate>
		<genre>RPG</genre>
		<nplayers>1</nplayers>
		<thegamesdb_id>27682</thegamesdb_id>
		<boxart1>rQpnkf9.jpg</boxart1>
		<snapshot1>9dTFHBL.png</snapshot1>
	</game>
	<game name="Wasabi Produce - Street Dancer (Japan)">
		<description>Wasabi Produce - Street Dancer (Japan)</description>
		<rom crc="1860B655" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan.zip/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan%2FWasabi%20Produce%20-%20Street%20Dancer%20%28Japan%29.zip" sha1="672CFC0E4547B2721D11B67476391B6E6CCA81AE" size="1830574" />
		<title_clean>Wasabi Produce - Street Dancer</title_clean>
		<releasedate>27/4/2000</releasedate>
		<giantbomb_url>https://www.giantbomb.com/wuzb-produce-street-dancer/3030-25039/</giantbomb_url>
		<boxart1>dQGClgA.jpg</boxart1>
		<snapshot1>gqholJo.png</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>uKbMzmV.jpg</snapshot2>
		<snapshot3>GboLBGW.jpg</snapshot3>
		<snapshot4>oNNT5x7.jpg</snapshot4>
		<snapshot5>3hMX3to.jpg</snapshot5>
		<snapshot6>46MwMd7.jpg</snapshot6>
		<snapshot7>f2WuRN3.jpg</snapshot7>
		<snapshot8>2kGtjgJ.jpg</snapshot8>
		<snapshot9>e92hUZN.jpg</snapshot9>
		<snapshot10>Dr7L02b.jpg</snapshot10>
	</game>
	<game name="Wonder Stadium (Japan)">
		<description>Wonder Stadium (Japan)</description>
		<rom crc="23BC0309" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan.zip/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan%2FWonder%20Stadium%20%28Japan%29.zip" sha1="CB9454A8277BB2A7D5A6E3B4DDC84194FCBB1231" size="302818" />
		<title_clean>Wonder Stadium</title_clean>
		<plot>Wonder Stadium, not to be confused with the near identical Wonder Stadium '99, presents a monochrome baseball experience for the WonderSwan. Players will quickly be able to start playing as one of fourteen teams, twelve professional two fictional, in All-Star Duel, Exhibition Game, or Homerun Competition modes. Player can also personalize their teams by giving the generic characters who comprise the teams names. [CR]When starting a game you'll be asked to select a team, a stadium; classic, seaside, or space, and how many innings the game will run from 1 to 9.[CR]Hitting the ball is the 'simple' affair that it usually is, time your swing and if you timed well your ball will fly into or out of the field. Wonder Stadium does give the ability to bunt and tweak the direction that bunt will go. [CR]While playing the field you'll have considerable command over a number of different pitches. From moving your pitchers subtly around the mound to how hard a throw you'll give. Once your opposing team manages to get a hit the game stops giving you the view from behind the plate a switches to a birds-eye view of the field.[CR]Each ballplayer is hooked to another for instance when you move your man on first base the fellow in the field behind him will move in the same way, a bit clumsy but an acceptable compromise. The person nearest the ball will always be under your control. Once you get the ball you may throw it toward a base of your choice.</plot>
		<releasedate>11/3/1999</releasedate>
		<year>1999</year>
		<genre>Simulation, Sports</genre>
		<studio>Bandai Co.</studio>
		<nplayers>1-2 Alt</nplayers>
		<perspective>3rd-Person</perspective>
		<thegamesdb_id>27685</thegamesdb_id>
		<mobygames_url>https://www.mobygames.com/game/wonderswan/wonder-stadium</mobygames_url>
		<boxart1>Zngu7yB.jpg</boxart1>
		<boxart3>fS6jGmT.jpg</boxart3>
		<snapshot1>T8pMCOW.png</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>9s51Yul.png</snapshot2>
		<snapshot3>miD0alY.png</snapshot3>
		<snapshot4>nfhEgry.png</snapshot4>
		<snapshot5>GzQudK3.png</snapshot5>
		<snapshot6>16Y8IuS.png</snapshot6>
		<snapshot7>k9pIT9I.png</snapshot7>
		<snapshot8>pfd3HFu.png</snapshot8>
		<snapshot9>KcJMeqX.png</snapshot9>
		<snapshot10>Klw2qRa.png</snapshot10>
	</game>
	<game name="Wonder Stadium '99 (Japan)">
		<description>Wonder Stadium '99 (Japan)</description>
		<rom crc="E252919D" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan.zip/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan%2FWonder%20Stadium%20%2799%20%28Japan%29.zip" sha1="BB138765346D9F4D77615444D090B1328A59818A" size="303618" />
		<title_clean>Wonder Stadium '99</title_clean>
		<plot>Wonder Stadium '99 was released a mere five months after the original Wonder Stadium and does not add much in the way of gameplay. This update adds information about the 1999 Japanese baseball season to the game. Such as Seibu's Matsuzaka and Uehara of the Yomiuri Giants.[CR]The game gives you a selection of 14 fictional and professional teams as well as three different stadiums, just as the original did.</plot>
		<releasedate>30/9/1999</releasedate>
		<year>1999</year>
		<genre>Simulation, Sports</genre>
		<studio>Bandai Co.</studio>
		<nplayers>1-2 Alt</nplayers>
		<perspective>3rd-Person</perspective>
		<thegamesdb_id>27687</thegamesdb_id>
		<mobygames_url>https://www.mobygames.com/game/wonderswan/wonder-stadium-99</mobygames_url>
		<boxart1>M4faef6.jpg</boxart1>
		<boxart2>TvxJMUE.jpg</boxart2>
		<boxart3>rfU6Cs8.jpg</boxart3>
		<snapshot1>18oMn4q.png</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>5ZvTIEu.png</snapshot2>
	</game>
	<game name="WonderSwan Handy Sonar (Japan)">
		<description>WonderSwan Handy Sonar (Japan)</description>
		<rom crc="2AB9852D" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan.zip/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan%2FWonderSwan%20Handy%20Sonar%20%28Japan%29.zip" sha1="70D65A936EE1DFC2B89C543312C205285D955EFB" size="267489" />
		<title_clean>WonderSwan Handy Sonar</title_clean>
		<plot>WonderSwan Handy Sonar is a Sports game, developed and published by Bandai, which was released in Japan in 1999.</plot>
		<releasedate>13/5/1999</releasedate>
		<genre>Sports</genre>
		<nplayers>1</nplayers>
		<videoid>3OK9zXuw7oI</videoid>
		<thegamesdb_id>27688</thegamesdb_id>
		<boxart1>uj6JC6H.jpg</boxart1>
		<snapshot1>p6bV7pF.png</snapshot1>
	</game>
</datafile>