<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<datafile>
	<header>
		<emu_name>WonderSwan Color</emu_name>
		<emu_description>WonderSwan Color</emu_description>
		<emu_category>Handheld, Bandai, 16 Bit, 1990s</emu_category>
		<emu_version>04012018</emu_version>
		<emu_date>03/03/2015</emu_date>
		<emu_author>Zach Morris</emu_author>
		<emu_visibility>visible</emu_visibility>
		<emu_homepage>http://www.no-intro.org</emu_homepage>
		<emu_baseurl>https://archive.org/download/</emu_baseurl>
		<emu_launcher>retroplayer</emu_launcher>
		<emu_default_addon>none</emu_default_addon>
		<emu_ext_launch_cmd>none</emu_ext_launch_cmd>
		<emu_downloadpath>default</emu_downloadpath>
		<emu_postdlaction>unzip_rom</emu_postdlaction>
		<emu_comment>The WonderSwan Color was released on December 9, 2000 in Japan, and was a moderate success. The original WonderSwan had only a black and white screen. Although the WonderSwan Color was slightly larger and heavier (7 mm and 2 g) compared to the original WonderSwan, the color version featured 512KB of RAM and a larger color LCD screen. In addition, the WonderSwan Color is compatible with the original WonderSwan library of games. Prior to WonderSwans release, Nintendo had a virtual monopoly in the Japanese video game handheld market. After the release of the WonderSwan Color, Bandai took approximately 8% of the market share in Japan partly due to its low price of 6800 Japanese yen (approximately 59 USD). Another reason for the WonderSwans success in Japan was the fact that Bandai managed to get a deal with Square to port over the original Famicom Final Fantasy games with improved graphics and controls. However, with the popularity of the Game Boy Advance and the reconciliation between Square and Nintendo, the WonderSwan Color and its successor, the SwanCrystal, quickly lost its competitive advantage.[CR]Developer:Bandai[CR]Manufacturer:Bandai[CR]CPU"  SPGY-1002[CR]Memory:  512 kB VRAM/WRAM[CR]Sound:  4 digital audio channels[CR]Display:  224 x 144[CR]Media:  Cartridge[CR]Max Controllers:  1</emu_comment>
		<emu_thumb>b9dnsLQ.jpg</emu_thumb>
		<emu_banner>8rCf1vR.jpg</emu_banner>
		<emu_fanart>Ef5smSf.jpg</emu_fanart>
		<emu_logo>veT3qmx.png</emu_logo>
		<emu_trailer>pWirVzfN0dY</emu_trailer>
	</header>
	<game name="Alchemist Marie &amp; Elie - Futari no Atelier (Japan)">
		<description>Alchemist Marie &amp; Elie - Futari no Atelier (Japan)</description>
		<rom crc="B18CDC0D" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan%20Color.zip/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan%20Color%2FAlchemist%20Marie%20%26%20Elie%20-%20Futari%20no%20Atelier%20%28Japan%29.zip" sha1="99D9D7F951AE589059F34E76AEA7489AE4CD79F1" size="1264932" />
		<title_clean>Alchemist Marie &amp; Elie - Futari no Atelier</title_clean>
		<plot>In the city of Salburg, there has always been a long tradition of alchemy - a magical science that dealt with combining various materials and turning metals into gold. You play as two young girls, Marlone and Elvira, who have to study at the Academy of alchemy, make powerful items, and prove to their masters they are worthy to be real alchemists.[CR]The game is a combination of role-playing and simulation. You have to read books and talk to people in order to learn more about items, and then to buy these items or to to find them somewhere. You must combine powerful items in order to impress your teachers. You also develop your characters in a standard RPG fashion. You can equip weapons and armor on them, and fight random enemies in wilderness areas. You gain levels and become stronger the more enemies you fight. The battles are automatic, and you can only assign a general strategy to your characters.</plot>
		<releasedate>4/7/2001</releasedate>
		<year>2001</year>
		<genre>Adventure, RPG, Simulation</genre>
		<studio>Gust Co.</studio>
		<nplayers>1</nplayers>
		<perspective>1st-Person</perspective>
		<rating>4.2</rating>
		<videoid>Lka9vUiIJ0M</videoid>
		<thegamesdb_id>27693</thegamesdb_id>
		<mobygames_url>https://www.mobygames.com/game/wonderswan-color/alchemist-marie-elie-futari-no-atelier</mobygames_url>
		<giantbomb_url>https://www.giantbomb.com/alchemist-marie-elie-futari-no-atelier/3030-273/</giantbomb_url>
		<boxart1>jmmLDYO.jpg</boxart1>
		<snapshot1>qlIfxFE.png</snapshot1>
	</game>
	<game name="Another Heaven - Memory of those Days (Japan)">
		<description>Another Heaven - Memory of those Days (Japan)</description>
		<rom crc="D7A0AB74" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan%20Color.zip/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan%20Color%2FAnother%20Heaven%20-%20Memory%20of%20those%20Days%20%28Japan%29.zip" sha1="CAF4A8DE853DED732B2A72619ACF2784EECEAFC7" size="1531532" />
		<title_clean>Another Heaven - Memory of those Days</title_clean>
		<plot>Another Heaven: Memory of Those Days is an Adventure game, developed and published by Omega Micott, which was released in Japan in 2000.</plot>
		<releasedate>21/12/2000</releasedate>
		<year>2000</year>
		<genre>Adventure</genre>
		<nplayers>1</nplayers>
		<thegamesdb_id>27694</thegamesdb_id>
		<giantbomb_url>https://www.giantbomb.com/another-heaven-memory-of-those-days/3030-31032/</giantbomb_url>
		<boxart1>vuW7Uht.jpg</boxart1>
		<snapshot1>JVhRygs.png</snapshot1>
	</game>
	<game name="Arc the Lad - Kishin Fukkatsu (Japan)">
		<description>Arc the Lad - Kishin Fukkatsu (Japan)</description>
		<rom crc="E2317345" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan%20Color.zip/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan%20Color%2FArc%20the%20Lad%20-%20Kishin%20Fukkatsu%20%28Japan%29.zip" sha1="68981C05D8118D4189100EED462EE6639328DC59" size="3160164" />
		<title_clean>Arc the Lad - Kishin Fukkatsu</title_clean>
		<plot>Arc the Lad: Kijin Fukkatsu focuses on Elc rather than Arc, whose village was burned and his family was shot. Elc's story eventually intertwines with Arc's story. This is a spin-off that was released in 2002 and is related to  Arc the Lad II, which was released on the PlayStation in 1996.[CR]</plot>
		<releasedate>4/7/2002</releasedate>
		<year>2002</year>
		<genre>RPG</genre>
		<studio>Bandai Co.</studio>
		<nplayers>1</nplayers>
		<perspective>Top-Down</perspective>
		<rating>3.2</rating>
		<thegamesdb_id>27695</thegamesdb_id>
		<mobygames_url>https://www.mobygames.com/game/wonderswan-color/arc-the-lad-kijin-fukkatsu</mobygames_url>
		<giantbomb_url>https://www.giantbomb.com/arc-the-lad-kijin-fukkatsu/3030-17068/</giantbomb_url>
		<boxart1>3W4Jdk2.jpg</boxart1>
		<boxart2>EmUx87H.jpg</boxart2>
		<boxart3>qG0n1QD.jpg</boxart3>
		<snapshot1>lyqbTnN.png</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>2nktnZm.gif</snapshot2>
		<snapshot3>NjHarBz.gif</snapshot3>
		<snapshot4>dYEZ3EZ.gif</snapshot4>
		<snapshot5>TAt5Oxc.gif</snapshot5>
		<snapshot6>CcM7d0f.gif</snapshot6>
		<snapshot7>Q7nPxWL.gif</snapshot7>
		<snapshot8>BwfRWSL.gif</snapshot8>
		<snapshot9>ggbyXiN.gif</snapshot9>
		<snapshot10>6uDxB8i.gif</snapshot10>
	</game>
	<game name="Battle Spirit - Digimon Frontier (Japan)">
		<description>Battle Spirit - Digimon Frontier (Japan)</description>
		<rom crc="8BA49DAB" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan%20Color.zip/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan%20Color%2FBattle%20Spirit%20-%20Digimon%20Frontier%20%28Japan%29.zip" sha1="FFFB1AEA34E0A96113CD10BA9DE515000D27BFE6" size="1384468" />
		<title_clean>Battle Spirit - Digimon Frontier</title_clean>
		<plot>[CR][B]Overview:[/B][CR]The digital world of Digimon is full of cool digital monsters and Digi-destined kids. The Digimon BattleSpirit video game for the Nintendo Gameboy Advance and SP puts you in control of your fave digital monster as it fights to prove that it's the strongest digital monster of all!The Digimon BattleSpirit game lets you choose from seven different Digimon to battle the other Digital Monsters and face the massive Millenniumon. Each Digimon has some fun moves, there are cool places to battle and a chance to Digivolve with some help from Culumon. Plus, you can unlock more Digimon to battle with and play two-player mode with a friend.[CR]</plot>
		<releasedate>7/12/2002</releasedate>
		<year>2002</year>
		<genre>Action</genre>
		<nplayers>1-2 Alt</nplayers>
		<thegamesdb_id>19633</thegamesdb_id>
		<giantbomb_url>https://www.giantbomb.com/digimon-battle-spirit/3030-20334/</giantbomb_url>
		<boxart1>2fnsFGy.jpg</boxart1>
		<snapshot1>4LVNJjj.png</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>B6zVS1O.png</snapshot2>
		<snapshot3>V70mTTo.png</snapshot3>
		<snapshot4>q6vc1GB.png</snapshot4>
		<snapshot5>XVxIrG2.png</snapshot5>
		<snapshot6>XanBQx2.png</snapshot6>
		<snapshot7>AG39uRo.png</snapshot7>
		<snapshot8>fdGK4IC.png</snapshot8>
		<snapshot9>mgU5yWU.png</snapshot9>
		<snapshot10>5M05ixX.png</snapshot10>
	</game>
	<game name="Blue Wing Blitz (Japan)">
		<description>Blue Wing Blitz (Japan)</description>
		<rom crc="99027238" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan%20Color.zip/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan%20Color%2FBlue%20Wing%20Blitz%20%28Japan%29.zip" sha1="02103FC5FC97C3A38834CED32A3CFE6523832535" size="719430" />
		<title_clean>Blue Wing Blitz</title_clean>
		<plot>There are six nations living in the world of floating islands. The most powerful one is the Ordia Empire, possessing the best aircrafts in the world. But its leaders were hungry for even more power, and planned to invade and to occupy the other five nations. The other nations tried to maintain diplomatic relationship with the Empire as long as possible. But one of those countries, the Esk Republic, decided to send a special strike team of skillful pilots, attempting to initiate a secret rebellion against the Empire. A young pilot named Keid, guided by his senior partner, the girl Payer, is the one who was chosen for this mission.[CR]"Blue Wing Blitz" is a turn-based strategy RPG with a twist: instead of fighters or soldier units, you command aircrafts. You navigate your planes over a battle field, which consists of airspaces, in round-based fashion. Once you land on a space occupied by an enemy plane, a battle follows. During those battles you have control over your aircraft, performing various attacks or defending. After several turns, the battle stops, but will resume if the enemy planes are still standing on the same space.</plot>
		<releasedate>4/7/2001</releasedate>
		<year>2001</year>
		<genre>RPG, Strategy</genre>
		<studio>Square Co.</studio>
		<nplayers>1</nplayers>
		<perspective>Isometric</perspective>
		<rating>2.5</rating>
		<thegamesdb_id>19544</thegamesdb_id>
		<mobygames_url>https://www.mobygames.com/game/wonderswan-color/blue-wing-blitz</mobygames_url>
		<giantbomb_url>https://www.giantbomb.com/blue-wing-blitz/3030-17818/</giantbomb_url>
		<boxart1>ilXUYIo.jpg</boxart1>
		<snapshot1>rDeTaSd.png</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>HWpDIkV.gif</snapshot2>
		<snapshot3>GjINxHu.gif</snapshot3>
		<snapshot4>OzJ5icv.gif</snapshot4>
		<snapshot5>vK2dJWl.gif</snapshot5>
		<snapshot6>cpcyjTW.gif</snapshot6>
		<snapshot7>RvK89bV.gif</snapshot7>
		<snapshot8>KGA4LWz.gif</snapshot8>
		<snapshot9>xcIiFTq.png</snapshot9>
		<snapshot10>QPrMupq.png</snapshot10>
		<clearlogo1>cYc9qLu.png</clearlogo1>
	</game>
	<game name="Dark Eyes - Battle Gate (Japan)">
		<description>Dark Eyes - Battle Gate (Japan)</description>
		<rom crc="12AE932C" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan%20Color.zip/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan%20Color%2FDark%20Eyes%20-%20Battle%20Gate%20%28Japan%29.zip" sha1="C2188171DC0F78FB6A13BBB55B4E85BDF7B82FD5" size="1338571" />
		<title_clean>Dark Eyes - Battle Gate</title_clean>
		<plot>Dark Eyes: BattleGate is a Strategy game, developed by NexTech and published by Bandai, which was released in Japan in 2001.</plot>
		<releasedate>15/3/2001</releasedate>
		<year>2001</year>
		<genre>Strategy</genre>
		<nplayers>1</nplayers>
		<thegamesdb_id>27697</thegamesdb_id>
		<boxart1>DtMGXkI.jpg</boxart1>
		<snapshot1>xg3nxGi.png</snapshot1>
	</game>
	<game name="Dicing Knight. (Japan)">
		<description>Dicing Knight. (Japan)</description>
		<rom crc="D28DC930" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan%20Color.zip/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan%20Color%2FDicing%20Knight.%20%28Japan%29.zip" sha1="79658575C736FCAD18E9225AA0E62398B086093B" size="255470" />
		<title_clean>Dicing Knight.</title_clean>
		<plot>Dicing Knight. follows the journey of a nameless knight fighting through a series of randomly generated dungeons.  The game will start on the floor of a dungeon, your goal being to find the floors key to progress to the next floor. Eventually you will reach a dungeon boss, after you beat it youll be allowed access to a new more difficult dungeon. Dungeons are timed by a Food Gauge which when depleted will force you to exit the dungeon.[CR]The dungeons are named:[CR]1. Lindwurm - German term for dragon, meant to establish the mythic setting. This dungeon has a heavenly aura.[CR]2. Shootingstar - A fiery land that will start to test your knowledge of the controls from Lindwurm.[CR]3. Jabberwock - A whimsical land that is bathed in night. When the night shall end is unknown.[CR]4. Quetzalcoatl - The area named for the Aztec sky god and creator. The entire map can no longer be seen.[CR]5. Jrmungandr - The serpent that shall kill Thor. This stage is a mythic earthy setting.[CR]The A button swings your sword and the B rings up your shield, the key items of any knight. Slashing your foes with your sword and devouring projectiles with your shield will increase your special meter, which when filled will allow you to perform a deadly special attack Shining Sword or "Blazing Sword".[CR]One interesting features of Dicing Knight is the dicing every time you attack an enemy dice will pop out of it and roll, youll deal damage to the foe based on the rolls you get. Likewise when you are hit dice also roll to determine youre damaged. [CR]The Y buttons will be mapped to four different items, which can be found inside your foes. A variety of items are included in the game such as an item that will predict or alter dice rolls, a variety of stat altering potions, invincibility items,  and a drill that will let you progress through dungeon wall to avoid monster filled rooms. Various orbs are also obtainable, via a lottery system, which will improve your abilities. [CR]After you beat the game on Knight Mode youll obtain a, Fortuner Mode, which will alter the game play, keeping the dungeon crawling style but giving you the ability to shoot to you and more of the monsters. The A button will be transformed into a double pistol, and the B will lob grenades. As well as two new specials that allow you to absorb enemy bullets or do a powerful shock attack. A new stage with a fitting title will also appear:[CR]1. Ouroboros - The snake eating its own tail, an alchemical symbol of immortality, this dungeon rests betwixt time, eternal, and waiting.</plot>
		<releasedate>31/5/2004</releasedate>
		<year>2004</year>
		<genre>Action, Adventure, RPG</genre>
		<studio>Qute</studio>
		<nplayers>1</nplayers>
		<perspective>Top-Down</perspective>
		<mobygames_url>https://www.mobygames.com/game/wonderswan-color/dicing-knight</mobygames_url>
		<giantbomb_url>https://www.giantbomb.com/dicing-knight/3030-19673/</giantbomb_url>
		<boxart1>IVXF7Np.jpg</boxart1>
		<snapshot1>6AzGMLh.png</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>ZPee6iw.jpg</snapshot2>
		<snapshot3>4chEdOD.jpg</snapshot3>
		<snapshot4>SRvIPth.jpg</snapshot4>
		<snapshot5>wesKJEu.jpg</snapshot5>
		<snapshot6>KpzxbhP.jpg</snapshot6>
		<snapshot7>vYZOfOo.jpg</snapshot7>
		<snapshot8>JVYe4ZG.jpg</snapshot8>
		<snapshot9>HYgCPRK.jpg</snapshot9>
		<snapshot10>9bUlVBo.jpg</snapshot10>
	</game>
	<game name="Digimon - Anode Tamer &amp; Cathode Tamer (Asia)">
		<description>Digimon - Anode Tamer &amp; Cathode Tamer (Asia)</description>
		<rom crc="77689273" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan%20Color.zip/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan%20Color%2FDigimon%20-%20Anode%20Tamer%20%26%20Cathode%20Tamer%20%28Asia%29.zip" sha1="7A6411CF8A4D91E8A4E0532779F11BDD25B92363" size="1711503" />
		<title_clean>Digimon - Anode Tamer &amp; Cathode Tamer</title_clean>
		<plot>Distributed by Bandai Asia mainly to Hong Kong and possibly other English-speaking Asian countries.[CR]</plot>
		<releasedate>18/9/2001</releasedate>
		<year>2001</year>
		<genre>RPG</genre>
		<studio>Bandai Co.</studio>
		<nplayers>1-2 Sim</nplayers>
		<perspective>Isometric</perspective>
		<rating>3.3</rating>
		<mobygames_url>https://www.mobygames.com/game/wonderswan-color/digimon-anode-cathode-tamer-veedramon-version</mobygames_url>
		<giantbomb_url>https://www.giantbomb.com/digimon-anode-cathode-tamer-veedramon-version/3030-16941/</giantbomb_url>
		<boxart1>PFOyEF7.jpg</boxart1>
		<snapshot1>snQwDCj.png</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>f8MfnQ9.gif</snapshot2>
		<snapshot3>78AMWxm.gif</snapshot3>
		<snapshot4>GGV02Dj.gif</snapshot4>
		<snapshot5>1MMyQBz.gif</snapshot5>
		<snapshot6>PsxSULQ.gif</snapshot6>
		<snapshot7>PAdRtyp.gif</snapshot7>
		<snapshot8>qazpVf4.gif</snapshot8>
		<snapshot9>2sPqzpm.gif</snapshot9>
		<snapshot10>0cpBWRl.gif</snapshot10>
	</game>
	<game name="Digimon Adventure 02 - D1 Tamers (Japan)">
		<description>Digimon Adventure 02 - D1 Tamers (Japan)</description>
		<rom crc="4D28637E" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan%20Color.zip/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan%20Color%2FDigimon%20Adventure%2002%20-%20D1%20Tamers%20%28Japan%29.zip" sha1="18D3DFE25D82964AB7BB61AF363D368FD12F4D4B" size="2168025" />
		<title_clean>Digimon Adventure 02 - D1 Tamers</title_clean>
		<plot>This is a sequel to  Digimon Adventure 02: Tag Tamers, set in the world of digital monsters based on the popular manga series. After having defeated the evil Millenniumon, our hero Ryou thought that would be his last travel to the Digiworld. However, the four sacred Digimons summon him once again, to participate in the D1 monster fighting tournament. But that is not all: it appears that Millenniumon is still alive, and is looking for revenge! Now Ryou has to win the tournament and defeat his archenemy once again.[CR]The gameplay is nearly identical to that of the previous game. You travel through top-down and isometric locations, fighting monsters with your own monster team, and then recruiting new monsters and assembling a collection. The battles are turn-based and are viewed from an isometric perspective. The monsters have various kinds of attacks in their disposal. Each attack is shown as a short animated sequence.</plot>
		<releasedate>8/12/2000</releasedate>
		<year>2000</year>
		<genre>RPG</genre>
		<studio>Bandai Co.</studio>
		<nplayers>1</nplayers>
		<perspective>Isometric</perspective>
		<rating>2.5</rating>
		<thegamesdb_id>27699</thegamesdb_id>
		<mobygames_url>https://www.mobygames.com/game/wonderswan-color/digimon-adventure-02-d1-tamers</mobygames_url>
		<giantbomb_url>https://www.giantbomb.com/digimon-adventure-02-d1-tamers/3030-15368/</giantbomb_url>
		<boxart1>v8fZAsB.jpg</boxart1>
		<boxart2>LhmCl8Q.jpg</boxart2>
		<boxart3>tij8wO2.jpg</boxart3>
		<snapshot1>ejBPP88.png</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>7clq1JS.gif</snapshot2>
		<snapshot3>jeT3GKk.gif</snapshot3>
		<snapshot4>usufToi.gif</snapshot4>
		<snapshot5>bPwc7rW.gif</snapshot5>
		<snapshot6>BqL7gOo.gif</snapshot6>
		<snapshot7>LVO4oNZ.gif</snapshot7>
		<snapshot8>JzSnZUF.gif</snapshot8>
		<snapshot9>MURRHne.gif</snapshot9>
		<snapshot10>ziSIcW0.gif</snapshot10>
	</game>
	<game name="Digimon Tamers - Battle Spirit (Japan) (En,Ja)">
		<description>Digimon Tamers - Battle Spirit (Japan) (En,Ja)</description>
		<rom crc="C927BFCB" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan%20Color.zip/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan%20Color%2FDigimon%20Tamers%20-%20Battle%20Spirit%20%28Japan%29%20%28En%2CJa%29.zip" sha1="757E92177385A14D979227EDEE1CB544B4C56BD6" size="1384336" />
		<title_clean>Digimon Tamers - Battle Spirit</title_clean>
		<plot>[CR][B]Overview:[/B][CR]The digital world of Digimon is full of cool digital monsters and Digi-destined kids. The Digimon BattleSpirit video game for the Nintendo Gameboy Advance and SP puts you in control of your fave digital monster as it fights to prove that it's the strongest digital monster of all!The Digimon BattleSpirit game lets you choose from seven different Digimon to battle the other Digital Monsters and face the massive Millenniumon. Each Digimon has some fun moves, there are cool places to battle and a chance to Digivolve with some help from Culumon. Plus, you can unlock more Digimon to battle with and play two-player mode with a friend.[CR]</plot>
		<releasedate>5/10/2001</releasedate>
		<year>2001</year>
		<genre>Fighting</genre>
		<nplayers>1-2 Alt</nplayers>
		<thegamesdb_id>27696</thegamesdb_id>
		<giantbomb_url>https://www.giantbomb.com/digimon-battle-spirit/3030-20334/</giantbomb_url>
		<boxart1>JYbiDew.jpg</boxart1>
		<snapshot1>ITLr5sg.png</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>B6zVS1O.png</snapshot2>
		<snapshot3>V70mTTo.png</snapshot3>
		<snapshot4>q6vc1GB.png</snapshot4>
		<snapshot5>XVxIrG2.png</snapshot5>
		<snapshot6>XanBQx2.png</snapshot6>
		<snapshot7>AG39uRo.png</snapshot7>
		<snapshot8>fdGK4IC.png</snapshot8>
		<snapshot9>mgU5yWU.png</snapshot9>
		<snapshot10>5M05ixX.png</snapshot10>
	</game>
	<game name="Digimon Tamers - Battle Spirit Ver. 1.5 (Japan)">
		<description>Digimon Tamers - Battle Spirit Ver. 1.5 (Japan)</description>
		<rom crc="6CAAD4A2" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan%20Color.zip/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan%20Color%2FDigimon%20Tamers%20-%20Battle%20Spirit%20Ver.%201.5%20%28Japan%29.zip" sha1="3F39FF494A3D8DD9D55A2E7CF86B47F1C8E8A156" size="1986878" />
		<title_clean>Digimon Tamers - Battle Spirit Ver. 1.5</title_clean>
		<plot>  [CR]</plot>
		<releasedate>27/4/2002</releasedate>
		<year>2002</year>
		<giantbomb_url>https://www.giantbomb.com/digimon-tamers-battle-spirit-ver-15/3030-41325/</giantbomb_url>
		<boxart1>GKnJbYm.jpg</boxart1>
		<snapshot1>wuPdMSj.png</snapshot1>
	</game>
	<game name="Digimon Tamers - Brave Tamer (Japan)">
		<description>Digimon Tamers - Brave Tamer (Japan)</description>
		<rom crc="F1F4D41F" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan%20Color.zip/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan%20Color%2FDigimon%20Tamers%20-%20Brave%20Tamer%20%28Japan%29.zip" sha1="31A718CFBCFF2DAB56AB9606A0B5B2DFCCECBBCB" size="2026046" />
		<title_clean>Digimon Tamers - Brave Tamer</title_clean>
		<plot>Based on the popular Digimon manga, this is a sequel to  Digimon Adventure 02: D1 Tamers. The game picks up directly where the previous one ended. After yet another ultimate battle against the evil Millenniumon, during which he revealed to the hero Ryou a terrifying secret, there was a great explosion. Ryou comes to his senses in an unknown place. The only digital monster there explains to him that the explosion send Millenniumon to the future, while Ryou ended up in the past. And now Millenniumon is trying to take control over the main computer in the Digiworld, and it is Ryou's task to stop him once and for all, and to finally find the truth about his and his archenemy's identities.[CR]The gameplay is similar to that of the predecessors: you navigate your hero over the top-down view, descend into dungeons, fight monsters in turn-based combat, recruit them into your party, and send the new teams to fight new enemies. The battle are not isometric any more, but viewed entirely as anim-style pictures. Attacks are also depicted as animated sequences.</plot>
		<releasedate>28/12/2001</releasedate>
		<year>2001</year>
		<genre>RPG</genre>
		<studio>Bandai Co.</studio>
		<nplayers>1</nplayers>
		<perspective>Top-Down</perspective>
		<rating>3.8</rating>
		<thegamesdb_id>27700</thegamesdb_id>
		<mobygames_url>https://www.mobygames.com/game/wonderswan-color/digimon-tamers-brave-tamer</mobygames_url>
		<giantbomb_url>https://www.giantbomb.com/digimon-tamers-brave-tamer/3030-16254/</giantbomb_url>
		<boxart1>Q5MpcnZ.jpg</boxart1>
		<snapshot1>1n7OeAy.png</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>WhP0JON.gif</snapshot2>
		<snapshot3>kcwGpti.gif</snapshot3>
		<snapshot4>FP2DCGq.gif</snapshot4>
		<snapshot5>Zna9YMC.gif</snapshot5>
		<snapshot6>IMwd8jw.gif</snapshot6>
		<snapshot7>7lGCLaf.gif</snapshot7>
		<snapshot8>yLqryue.gif</snapshot8>
		<snapshot9>ExvlOyf.gif</snapshot9>
		<snapshot10>dju54sd.gif</snapshot10>
	</game>
	<game name="Digimon Tamers - Digimon Medley (Japan)">
		<description>Digimon Tamers - Digimon Medley (Japan)</description>
		<rom crc="FA92418D" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan%20Color.zip/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan%20Color%2FDigimon%20Tamers%20-%20Digimon%20Medley%20%28Japan%29.zip" sha1="8638737E5A35C6BE05A888DC81E504E0D80FD756" size="1584081" />
		<title_clean>Digimon Tamers - Digimon Medley</title_clean>
		<plot>"Digimon Medley" is based on the popular manga and and anim series Digimon, in which ordinary Japanese children find a way into a digital world, where they help good digital monsters fight against evil ones. The game is not directly plot-related to  Digimon Adventure or Digimon Tamers: Brave Tamer games. Instead, it follows more closely the actual episodes of the series. You play as various characters, such as the main hero Taichi and his friend Yamato from the first episodes, as well as heroes from the Digimon Tamers sub-series: Takato, Ruki, and Lee. The game is divided into short episodes, each one of which revives one of the battles in the series. You start with Digimon Tamers, as they venture into the DigiWorld, only to meet the enigmatic digimon named Impmon, who is up to some mischief. [CR]Each episode can be played as one of several available characters. Each character also has his/her own digimon who fights all the battles. The battles are random and occur while you are navigating your heroes through top-down dungeons. The attacks are displayed as short anim-style sequences. During your turn, you must press the A button repeatedly to increase the power of your attack. The enemy attacks simultaneously, and you have to invest enough power in your attack in order for it to connect.</plot>
		<releasedate>12/7/2001</releasedate>
		<year>2001</year>
		<genre>RPG</genre>
		<studio>Bandai Co.</studio>
		<nplayers>1</nplayers>
		<perspective>Top-Down</perspective>
		<rating>3.0</rating>
		<thegamesdb_id>27701</thegamesdb_id>
		<mobygames_url>https://www.mobygames.com/game/wonderswan-color/digimon-tamers-digimon-medley</mobygames_url>
		<giantbomb_url>https://www.giantbomb.com/digimon-tamers-digimon-medley/3030-14870/</giantbomb_url>
		<boxart1>54envvO.jpg</boxart1>
		<snapshot1>pfOIb2m.png</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>9fGK3b0.gif</snapshot2>
		<snapshot3>iAJB0nP.gif</snapshot3>
		<snapshot4>ELto0gL.gif</snapshot4>
		<snapshot5>Ghw9WoC.gif</snapshot5>
		<snapshot6>ri6Ce18.gif</snapshot6>
		<snapshot7>WO4yAsk.gif</snapshot7>
		<snapshot8>BQywXfN.gif</snapshot8>
		<snapshot9>0fDSGy3.gif</snapshot9>
		<snapshot10>Ea1yXjJ.gif</snapshot10>
	</game>
	<game name="Digital Monster - D-Project (Japan)">
		<description>Digital Monster - D-Project (Japan)</description>
		<rom crc="FAAEFBCB" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan%20Color.zip/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan%20Color%2FDigital%20Monster%20-%20D-Project%20%28Japan%29.zip" sha1="3E8FFFE1F607EA5F855397D9D877CECB285507F7" size="1034794" />
		<title_clean>Digital Monster - D-Project</title_clean>
		<plot>Digital Monsters: D Project is a Role-Playing game, developed by Sting and published by Bandai, which was released in Japan in 2002.</plot>
		<releasedate>3/8/2002</releasedate>
		<year>2002</year>
		<genre>RPG</genre>
		<nplayers>1</nplayers>
		<thegamesdb_id>27702</thegamesdb_id>
		<boxart1>4e5sOtK.jpg</boxart1>
		<snapshot1>oUjyspg.png</snapshot1>
	</game>
	<game name="Digital Monster Card Game - Ver. WonderSwan Color (Japan)">
		<description>Digital Monster Card Game - Ver. WonderSwan Color (Japan)</description>
		<rom crc="603CB5E6" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan%20Color.zip/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan%20Color%2FDigital%20Monster%20Card%20Game%20-%20Ver.%20WonderSwan%20Color%20%28Japan%29.zip" sha1="BA16A0770F7A71DD49E2879799FD04A4F04F7E60" size="1755055" />
		<title_clean>Digital Monster Card Game - Ver. WonderSwan Color</title_clean>
		<plot>Digital Monsters Card Game Ver. WonderSwan Color is a Strategy game, developed by Tom Create and published by Bandai, which was released in Japan in 2002.</plot>
		<releasedate>16/3/2002</releasedate>
		<year>2002</year>
		<genre>Strategy</genre>
		<nplayers>1-2 Alt</nplayers>
		<thegamesdb_id>27703</thegamesdb_id>
		<boxart1>bGbWpHq.jpg</boxart1>
		<snapshot1>ybE87gh.png</snapshot1>
	</game>
	<game name="Dokodemo Hamster 3 - Odekake Saffron (Japan)">
		<description>Dokodemo Hamster 3 - Odekake Saffron (Japan)</description>
		<rom crc="93E19F13" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan%20Color.zip/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan%20Color%2FDokodemo%20Hamster%203%20-%20Odekake%20Saffron%20%28Japan%29.zip" sha1="66B4BD15EF67DC324736A1CC78D6ACA335F03389" size="400341" />
		<title_clean>Dokodemo Hamster 3 - Odekake Saffron</title_clean>
		<plot>This is the third in Bandai's "hamster simulation" series. In this game, you are the "master" of a hamster. The game flows in real time, but you can interfere and perform various actions. The hamster has its own room in a house, with a table and a wheel. There are many things you can do with the hamster. You can take in to a stroll in the forest, go shopping with it, make it play with a ball, and so on. You can also perform actions unrelated to the hamster, like re-decorating the house or writing and painting on a piece of paper. The game features a point-and-click interface: you move your cursor over an object (such as hamster or calendar), which brings up an action menu.</plot>
		<releasedate>14/12/2000</releasedate>
		<year>2000</year>
		<genre>Simulation</genre>
		<studio>Bandai Co.</studio>
		<nplayers>1</nplayers>
		<perspective>1st-Person</perspective>
		<rating>3.2</rating>
		<thegamesdb_id>27704</thegamesdb_id>
		<mobygames_url>https://www.mobygames.com/game/wonderswan-color/dokodemo-hamster-3-o-dekake-safuran</mobygames_url>
		<giantbomb_url>https://www.giantbomb.com/dokodemo-hamster-3-o-dekake-safuran/3030-18786/</giantbomb_url>
		<boxart1>9qtu98s.jpg</boxart1>
		<snapshot1>j60iExx.png</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>Id4VKtN.gif</snapshot2>
		<snapshot3>ZNTSABS.gif</snapshot3>
		<snapshot4>E5jI50x.gif</snapshot4>
		<snapshot5>tou7IHw.gif</snapshot5>
		<snapshot6>OJXwmkK.gif</snapshot6>
		<snapshot7>TUTEntV.gif</snapshot7>
		<snapshot8>rD4reCP.gif</snapshot8>
		<snapshot9>LmAmk6S.gif</snapshot9>
		<snapshot10>kacEjvj.gif</snapshot10>
	</game>
	<game name="Dragon Ball (Japan)">
		<description>Dragon Ball (Japan)</description>
		<rom crc="067238D1" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan%20Color.zip/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan%20Color%2FDragon%20Ball%20%28Japan%29.zip" sha1="5384F9974C66E5E26129A4709976DE0BB1AE1F17" size="1137415" />
		<title_clean>Dragon Ball</title_clean>
		<plot>Dragon Ball is a Role-Playing game, developed by TOSE and published by Bandai, which was released in Japan in 2003.</plot>
		<releasedate>20/11/2003</releasedate>
		<year>2003</year>
		<genre>RPG</genre>
		<nplayers>1</nplayers>
		<thegamesdb_id>19796</thegamesdb_id>
		<giantbomb_url>https://www.giantbomb.com/dragon-ball/3030-30307/</giantbomb_url>
		<boxart1>QFJ3lEl.jpg</boxart1>
		<boxart2>i2fJ4rS.jpg</boxart2>
		<snapshot1>6GRugML.png</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>3tPfTcN.jpg</snapshot2>
		<snapshot3>SK1nxdD.jpg</snapshot3>
		<snapshot4>JEOdJmX.jpg</snapshot4>
	</game>
	<game name="Final Fantasy (Japan)">
		<description>Final Fantasy (Japan)</description>
		<rom crc="B7243E88" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan%20Color.zip/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan%20Color%2FFinal%20Fantasy%20%28Japan%29.zip" sha1="26628EB76C16880B6FAF2E706778D91A60144078" size="2079231" />
		<title_clean>Final Fantasy</title_clean>
		<plot>[CR][B]History:[/B][CR]In 1987 a small and struggling video game company called Square put all their remaining resources entirely into the hands of the Director of Planning and Development named Hironobu Sakaguchi. They earnestly hoped that whatever game he made would be a hit. As Hironobu was convinced this would be his last game ever, he called it Final Fantasy.[CR][B]Overview:[/B][CR] Opening text. Final Fantasy is a single player role-playing game (RPG) which lets the player control four characters called the "Light Warriors." They begin by rescuing a princess from the Notorious Knight Garland. Soon after, they are given the world spanning task of collecting four Orbs of Light and defeating four fiends. The fiends went by the names of Lich, Kary, Kraken, and Tiamat. They had taken the Orbs from the rightful place they belonged and spread corruption over all the lands, skies, and seas. After many battles the Light warriors had collected items, gold and experience. When all the fiends were defeated, it was revealed that they took Garland&#8217;s corpse and sent it back in time. He had now become a mass of living evil known as Chaos. Confusingly Chaos sent the four fiends into the future where they currently plagued the world. Only when Chaos was defeated in the past and the four fiends were defeated in the present, was the world's natural balance finally restored.Final Fantasy was originally considered overbearingly difficult. Saves only came at resting in a Town&#8217;s Inn or using an expensive item known as a House. Spells in the late game cost more than half a million gil, and had a limited number of charges that could only be replenished by resting. Monster encounters could go from simplistic to overpowering at a moment&#8217;s notice.[CR]Battle System[CR] Fighting wolves in the MSX version.Attacks were played out in turn based combat. All characters and monsters all were told what to do before the round began, be it cast a spell, use an item, or commit a basic attack, and all actions were then played out from the fastest person on the battlefield to the slowest. In the original game, some attacks could be useless. For example, if a Fighter and a Thief were both instructed to attack a goblin they would both do so. If the Thief killed him, it wouldn't stop the fighter from doing exactly as he was told by swinging his sword at the space the goblin once stood instead of at the other enemies present. This was later altered in the re-releases for the PSOne, Game Boy Advance, PSP, and iPhone versions, so the attacker would automatically attack the next available target.[CR]Innovation[CR] Crafting a party from six available classes. Pictured is the default party setup: Fi, Th, BB, RM.The player chose their party of four with some combination of Black Mage, White Mage, Red Mage, Thief, Fighter, and Black Belt characters. These classes could be upgraded by the Dragon King, to; White Wizard, Black Wizard, Red Wizard, Ninja, Knight, and Master. Players traveled the world in vehicles, such as; boats, airships, and canoes. In combat, up to 9 monsters of various types could battle the player's party. Unless they soared through the skies in an airship or strolled in a safe area like a town, 'random encounters' were always possible. In these Encounters, a band of monsters could emerge and strike the party. Mages had a limited amount of spells they could learn.Final Fantasy had almost 20 musical tracks. Some of which, like the tune played after 'Victorious battle' and the 'Opening Theme', remained in one form or another in Final Fantasy games for decades to come.[CR][B]Music:[/B][CR]The music for Final Fantasy was composed by Nobuo Uematsu. Some of the tracks became the trademarks to the Final Fantasy series: like the "Prelude", played on the title screen, and the "Victory Fanfare", which is played after every victorious battle.[CR]Version Differences[CR]Wonderswan and PlayStationThe PSOne release of Final Fantasy was under the title of Final Fantasy Origins and contained enhanced remakes of both Final Fantasy I and II using higher quality MIDI and cleaner 16-bit graphics. These enhanced remakes were initially ports of the Wonderswan re-releases that never made it to the US for various reasons, most notably because the Wonderswan Color was never released in the US. Aside from the obvious graphical face-lift, various changes exist in the PSOne version that differ from the original NES version. An easy mode was created for the original Final Fantasy (increased Gil and EXP curves), auto-re-targeting, a temporary quicksave, and the addition of new items such as Phoenix Downs (revive a fallen ally) and Gold Needles (remove petrification).Game Boy AdvanceUsing the same enhanced graphical look of the PSOne release, the Gameboy Advance release of Final Fantasy, known as Dawn of Souls, was most notable for drastically reducing the difficulty. The version also included bonus dungeons for each game, though the complex battle transitions and music quality were reduced due to the technical limitations of the system. All changes to the battle system of the PSOne release carry over, however the magic system (previously levels of magic "slots" with limited number of uses) was changed to use Magic Points instead. Speculative reasons for the changes include Nintendo's fear that an overly difficult RPG would turn away the younger player-base, arguably a larger portion of the overall audience than on the PSOne.PSPThe PSP re-release featured the same difficulty reduction and added bonus dungeons of the Gameboy Advance re-release, but featured an even bigger graphical overhaul, with various post-processing effects added such as cloud overcast and hi-res sprites (including spells). However, unlike Origins and Dawn of Souls, these two versions were not sold together and retailed individually at release for $29.99 USD each. Together, these two releases doubled the price of the initial release of both Final Fantasy Origins and Dawn of Souls ($29.99). The price, in addition to the numerous other re-releases of the games on other platforms, resulted in the game receiving much criticism from the gaming press.iPhone Giant D-PadOn February 25, 2010, Square-Enix released an updated version of this game onto the iPhone and iPod Touch. Retailing for $8.99, it is essentially a port of the PSP version of the game. The graphics are higher resolution than the Dawn of Souls remake, and are essentially on-par with the sprites seen in the PSP version. In addition, the Soul of Chaos, Labyrinth of Time, and the 4 special element-based dungeons are also included (which are unlocked after defeating one of the four Elemental Masters). The game immediately rocketed up to the #2 spot on the Top Grossing Apps list. Big Buttons for easy pressingnessThe game has a specialized control scheme for the touch screen. The overworld has a simple D-pad overlay, and the battles are equipped with some large buttons and a simple tapping interface to select what action to perform and which enemy to perform it on. This is a highly efficient method for playing the game, but whereas in other games the player could just hold a button down to skip past the battles, it requires continued taps in this version, which can actually slow down the game. It currently sits around 4.5 stars on iTunes.[CR]</plot>
		<releasedate>9/12/2000</releasedate>
		<year>2000</year>
		<genre>RPG</genre>
		<studio>Square Co.</studio>
		<nplayers>1</nplayers>
		<perspective>Top-Down</perspective>
		<rating>2.8</rating>
		<thegamesdb_id>19797</thegamesdb_id>
		<mobygames_url>https://www.mobygames.com/game/wonderswan-color/final-fantasy</mobygames_url>
		<giantbomb_url>https://www.giantbomb.com/final-fantasy/3030-8403/</giantbomb_url>
		<boxart1>HBc7A75.png</boxart1>
		<boxart2>nVh1cpz.jpg</boxart2>
		<boxart3>A3vEW1V.jpg</boxart3>
		<boxart4>bOyMNgI.jpg</boxart4>
		<boxart5>L0FG91N.jpg</boxart5>
		<boxart6>VVbbfC4.jpg</boxart6>
		<boxart7>qRA3HNZ.jpg</boxart7>
		<snapshot1>G78LQ1D.png</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>1wSpVO3.png</snapshot2>
		<snapshot3>GXYgJjU.png</snapshot3>
		<snapshot4>6wLychs.png</snapshot4>
		<snapshot5>GAYYIpo.png</snapshot5>
		<snapshot6>ccjd0zr.png</snapshot6>
		<snapshot7>gknmnsy.png</snapshot7>
		<snapshot8>dc8DROC.png</snapshot8>
		<snapshot9>cshDFwk.png</snapshot9>
		<snapshot10>FT2G3YR.png</snapshot10>
	</game>
	<game name="Final Fantasy II (Japan)">
		<description>Final Fantasy II (Japan)</description>
		<rom crc="F09E752F" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan%20Color.zip/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan%20Color%2FFinal%20Fantasy%20II%20%28Japan%29.zip" sha1="959321E3B971516E38A4CBF95B0FC3EFC0B0A825" size="2367188" />
		<title_clean>Final Fantasy II</title_clean>
		<plot>[CR][B]Overview:[/B][CR]Battle from the Famicom version.Final Fantasy II is a sequel to Square's Final Fantasy and was only released in Japan on the Famicom in 1988. An English-language NES release was originally planned under the title "Shadow of Palamecia", but it was never completed. The game has since then been remade on various other platforms including the WonderSwan Color, PlayStation, PSP, Game Boy Advance and iPhone. The game does not share any connection with the original Final Fantasy's world or characters, establishing a precedent all entries in the primary Final Fantasy series have since followed.[CR][B]Story:[/B][CR]Beavers are crucial to the story of Final Fantasy II.Final Fantasy II is about four heroes, including main protagonist Firion, who join a resistance group called Wild Rose and try to stop the Empire of Palamecia from taking over the world. The dialogue in Final Fantasy II is a lot more dynamic than the first; players can ask NPCs about key terms and items to advance the plot or unlock certain events. It is also the first Final Fantasy where party members can join and leave the party during the game. Final Fantasy II also introduced elements that have since become defining concepts of the Final Fantasy series. It is the first game to feature the chocobo, a mount that would let the player ride across the world without any random encounters, and a character named Cid.[CR][B]Gameplay:[/B][CR]Battle scene from the PSP remake.Final Fantasy II's combat and character progression use different systems than were seen in the original game. Instead of gaining experience points to increase in level and raise stats across the board, the heroes gain skill levels for the attributes they use in battle. For example, if they use swords, their strength and sword skill will increase; if they get hit in battle, their hit points will increase.A glitch in the Famicom version of the game registers canceled stat-boosting commands. If the player were to repeatedly input and cancel a particular command, they could conceivably give the related stats a substantial boost before the end of a single battle. This glitch was fixed in later ports.Final Fantasy II also introduced the idea of party formation to the franchise. The player could move their characters to the back of the line in battle, reducing their chances of taking damage while limiting their own attack capabilities to using bows or magic.[CR]Version Differences[CR]As stated above, Final Fantasy II has seen numerous iterations since its conception. What follows below are the different versions released over the years and the iterative changes with each subsequent release.Famicom (1988 and 1994)The original Final Fantasy II was released for the Famicom in Japan and was set to release in North America supposedly with the subtitle Dark Shadow Over Palakia. With the looming release of the Super Nintendo and a long localization process, the 8-bit version never made its way outside of Japan despite the success of the first Final Fantasy and Square advertisements of the beta version. The Famicom version was re-released in Japan as part of a compilation with the first Final Fantasy in 1994. This version still remains exclusive to Japan despite Nintendo's claims that each pre-PlayStation Final Fantasy would be released over its Virtual Console service.WonderSwan Color (2001)More than a decade after Final Fantasy II's original release, Square decided to put support behind the WonderSwan Color, a Japan handheld gaming device. Along with this support came re-releases of Final Fantasies I, II and III, whose graphics were updated to suit the 16-bit handheld. The game also had fully drawn backgrounds for battle sequences and remastered audio. Final Fantasy II for the WonderSwan was a release title and was also featured in a limited edition bundle. The bundle included the game, a specially branded system and a premium strap with Final Fantasy II branding.PlayStation (2002 and 2003)Nearly 15 years later, gamers outside of Japan could purchase a version of Final Fantasy representative of their own territory. The PlayStation version added CG cutscenes and featured technical improvements beyond that of the WonderSwan Color version. It was released separately or compiled in Japan and released solely as the compilation Final Fantasy Origins overseas.Mobile Phones (2004 and 2006)Due to the immense popularity of cell phone gaming in Japan, a mobile phone version was released over three services providers on different dates. The graphics and sound most closely resemble that of the more widely known Game Boy Advance version. This version remains exclusive to Japan.Game Boy Advance (2004)This version of Final Fantasy II signaled Square's returning support for Nintendo handhelds as well as Final Fantasy II's first official release in the Australia territory. Released under the compilation Final Fantasy I &amp; II: Dawn of Souls, the reworked title also featured a new post-game sequence called Souls of Rebirth, in which players can control the various support characters that died during the main storyline.PlayStation Portable (2007 and 2008)To commemorate the 20th anniversary of the Final Fantasy series, Square-Enix brought Final Fantasy II out of the vault once more for the release of Final Fantasy II Anniversary Edition. It is considered as the ultimate version of Final Fantasy II as it includes all the bonuses from previous versions as well as updated graphics and sound, a rebalanced combat system and two extra dungeons.iPhone (2010)The iPhone version retains all aspects of the PSP anniversary release. The only main difference between the two versions is the method of control. Whereas the PSP utilizes digital button inputs, the iPhone version is controlled solely by its touch screen interface.[CR][B]Soundtrack:[/B][CR]The original soundtrack was composed by Nobuo Uematsu. The remakes of the game have sound produced and arranged by Tsuyoshi Sekito.PlayStation track listing:1. "Opening Movie"2. "Opening Movie SE"3. "Opening Theme"4. "Prelude"5. "Battle Scene 1"6. "Time of Revival"7. " Reunion"8. "Rebel Army Theme"9. "Town"10. "Main Theme"11. "Pandemonium Castle"12. "Imperial Army Theme"13. "Chocobo's Theme"14. "Tower of Magic-users"15. "Escape!"16. "Ancient Castle"17. "Dungeon"18. "Emperor's Revival"19. "Victory"20. "Waltz"21. "Temptation of the Princess"22. "Dead Music"23. "Fanfare"24. "Include in the Group"25. "Inn"26. "Battle Scene A"27. "Battle Scene B"28. "Battle Scene 2"29. "Finale"[CR]</plot>
		<releasedate>28/3/2002</releasedate>
		<year>2001</year>
		<genre>RPG</genre>
		<studio>Square Co.</studio>
		<nplayers>1</nplayers>
		<perspective>Top-Down</perspective>
		<rating>3.5</rating>
		<thegamesdb_id>27705</thegamesdb_id>
		<mobygames_url>https://www.mobygames.com/game/wonderswan-color/final-fantasy-ii_</mobygames_url>
		<giantbomb_url>https://www.giantbomb.com/final-fantasy-ii/3030-2094/</giantbomb_url>
		<boxart1>PlfT0za.jpg</boxart1>
		<boxart2>OFF75Dn.jpg</boxart2>
		<boxart3>gmNwLOv.jpg</boxart3>
		<snapshot1>sNOKoFP.png</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>J117kTa.gif</snapshot2>
		<snapshot3>vSGmQse.gif</snapshot3>
		<snapshot4>2KxTtO3.gif</snapshot4>
		<snapshot5>YSUHwJ1.gif</snapshot5>
		<snapshot6>rA0Ejgy.gif</snapshot6>
		<snapshot7>6IoFsSU.gif</snapshot7>
		<snapshot8>7aKUCFY.gif</snapshot8>
		<snapshot9>xKp9kWP.gif</snapshot9>
		<snapshot10>JUYhHJE.gif</snapshot10>
	</game>
	<game name="Final Fantasy IV (Japan)">
		<description>Final Fantasy IV (Japan)</description>
		<rom crc="F699D6D1" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan%20Color.zip/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan%20Color%2FFinal%20Fantasy%20IV%20%28Japan%29.zip" sha1="6D707E88C85D1B5EF708631E709668006A9EE244" size="1270385" />
		<title_clean>Final Fantasy IV</title_clean>
		<plot>[CR][B]Overview:[/B][CR]Final Fantasy IV (originally released as Final Fantasy II outside of Japan), is a console RPG in the Final Fantasy series first published by Square in 1991. It quickly became a fan favorite, a factor that has fuelled the several remakes of the game that have been created to date. The game's first appearance was on the Super Nintendo Entertainment System and was released twice in Japan and once in the US: The US version was made purposefully easier, and the Japanese market would later receive the same version with the subtitle "Easy Type" three months after the original. Square later capitalized on its growing popularity with ports on the Sony PlayStation and the Game Boy Advance, and in 2008, nearly two decades after the original release, a completely overhauled remake was developed for the Nintendo DS.The game has had both critical and commercial success. It has also had a direct impact not only on future Final Fantasy games but on RPGs in general, with the introduction of a storyline driven by characters and character interaction and the use of new gameplay mechanics, such as the Active Time Battle system. Final Fantasy IV also made use of Mode 7, which allowed 2D backgrounds to be rotated and viewed in a way that gave the impression of 3D. The music was composed by Nobuo Uematsu.A sequel, Final Fantasy IV: The After Years, was released for mobiles in 2008 and on WiiWare in 2009.[CR][B]Gameplay:[/B][CR]The overworld (DS)Final Fantasy IV lets the player take control of a party, led by the protagonist, Cecil Harvey. Throughout the game, the party explores towns and dungeons to progress the story. The individual locations are all tied together in an overworld, which the player can traverse on foot, though by the end of the game, a hovercraft and a number of different airships are available to get around the overworld faster and to cross shoals and oceans.Random encounters populate the overworld and dungeons. When the player is met by one, the party is thrown into a battle against up to five enemies. Winning the battle rewards the party with experience points, gil, and occasionally a dropped item. Gil is the game's currency and is used in shops to buy new weapons, armor, or other items in towns, while by accumulating experience points, a character may gain a level and subsequently receive a boost in stats. The party will also come across bosses over the course of the game, who are often tougher to defeat than regular enemies from random encounters as they usually have more health and stronger attacks.The town of Baron (SNES)Besides fighting through dungeons, there are also a large number of castles, towns, and villages that usually include several NPCs, an inn (where the party can rest for the night for a small fee), and a few shops. Progress can be permanently saved either in the overworld or at save points sparsely scattered in dungeons or, more rarely, towns. The DS remake includes a portable-friendly quicksave feature that lets the player save at any point, but once this quicksave file is loaded, it is erased.Though Final Fantasy IV has twelve playable characters in total, only five are present at any one time. This means that the player never decides the party members. Cecil is the only character who remains in the party for the entire duration of the game, and characters often leave the party due to story-related reasons with very little warning. Party members' equipment can be customized, as well as the party's formation. The party is arranged into two rows, front and back, and each row holds a maximum of three members. Characters in the back row receive slightly less damage compared to the front, being further back, but attacks do less damage.Battle SystemThe ATB system (GBA)Final Fantasy IV has an ATB (Active Time Battle) system, which was eventually used in many subsequent Final Fantasy games. Each character has a gauge that fills up automatically as time passes. A character with a high speed statistic will have their gauge filled more quickly. When a character's gauge is full, the character can perform an action. In Final Fantasy IV, attacking, using an ability or item, summoning, and casting a spell all counts as one action. Once this action is complete, the gauge is reset. Enemies also have their own gauges, but these are kept hidden to the player. Slow and Haste spells can be cast to affect how quickly gauges are filled.Members on both sides all enter a battle with a number of HP (hit points), the game's equivalent to health. Damage is dealt to someone by performing physical or magical attacks. When someone's HP reaches zero, they are KO'd and no longer play a part in battle unless they are revived. A side is victorious when all of their enemies are KO'd or Petrified (turned to stone), although a battle ends earlier if one side flees. Party members have options to restore HP, through Cure spells and items like potions, and revive a KO'd character, through Raise spells and phoenix downs.Characters also have a reserve of MP (magic points). This number dictates what magic spells or summons can be cast. Each act of magic comes with an MP cost, with more powerful or useful magic usually coming at a higher price, and that cost is subtracted from the character's overall MP reserve whenever it is used. Magic is divided into two types: White Magic and Black Magic. White consists of holy spells that usually focus on healing; Black has spells that look to harm their targets.Rydia inflicted with the Toad status (DS)Another key aspect is the assortment of status effects that can be inflicted on characters. These are usually casted by magic users. Positive status effects include Protect and Shell, which raises the character's physical and magical defense respectively. Blink temporarily makes the character much harder to hit. There are plenty of harmful ones, too. For example, Poison slowly drains the character of their health, while Silence prevents them from spellcasting. Characters inflicted with Sleep cannot do anything until they awaken. Negative status effects can be cured through the spell Esuna or particular items.Each playable character in the game also comes with their own unique abilities. Kain comes with the Jump ability, allowing him to stay airborne for a while before crashing down on an enemy dealing double damage, while Yang has Kick, which enables him to deal physical damage to all enemies in one turn.In the DS remake, these abilities can be taught to other characters via items called augments, obtained by story events or by other means. There are no character restrictions when it comes to augments, which means any character can learn anything. However, in battle, a maximum of four abilities can be used (not including the auto-battle feature). The fifth slot is given to items. This remake also introduces new abilities that are only available through augments. Some are active, like Tsunami, a powerful water attack, while others are passive, like Treasure Hunter, which increases the chance of enemies dropping items after the battle.Summons/EidolonsDuring battle, Rydia can summon an Eidolon to perform a powerful attack on the enemies. When Cecil first meets Rydia as a young girl, she only knows how to summon a Chocobo, but she is eventually able to bring forth much more powerful summons as the game is progressed. By the end of the game, she can summon the following Eidolons, providing all the relevant sidequests are completed and treasures are collected:Leviathan using Tidal Wave (DS)ChocoboIfritShivaRamuhDragonTitanOdinSylphAsuraLeviathanBahamutGoblinBombMindflayerCockatriceWhyt (DS version only)Exclusive to the DS version of the game, Whyt is unique to every other summon in that it can fight in Rydia's place, and as it is the only one whose stats can be increased. Boosting stats is done by playing a group of minigames.New Game Plus (DS version only)The DS remake includes a New Game Plus feature, with which players can begin a second playthrough with some of the benefits from the previous playthrough. Map data, augments (both used and unused), and certain special items are carried over. Gil, levels, and nearly all of the equipment are not. New Game Plus can only be utilized two times for a single "game", meaning three playthroughs of the game are allowed.[CR][B]Story:[/B][CR]Warning: This section depicts the events that happen from beginning to end, and thus contains major spoilers.The Light CrystalsCecil returning from MysidiaThe game starts as Cecil Harvey, Lord Captain of the Red Wings and a dark knight, is returning to the kingdom of Baron, having collected the Crystal of Water from the city of Mysidia on the king's orders. At the castle, he questions the motives behind attacking the peaceful Mysidians and forcefully taking what is theirs, but is subsequently stripped of his rank. Protesting his loyalty to the king, Cecil accepts a mission along with friend and dragoon Kain to deliver a ring to the village of Mist, its power unknown to him. Upon arriving, the ring automatically lets out a group of bombs that explode and destroy the village. In the wake of what has been done, Cecil and Kain vow to rebel against the King of Baron.They stumble upon the village's only survivor, a young girl named Rydia, who is devastated by the loss of her mother. Out of rage, she summons Titan, causing an earthquake that separates Cecil from Kain. Alone with an unconscious Rydia, Cecil takes the girl to an inn at the nearest town, Kaipo. When Baron soldiers arrive at the inn looking to take away Rydia, Cecil defends her against them. Rydia witnesses the scene and warms to Cecil after his gesture. Not long afterwards, Rosa (whom Cecil has feelings for) is found outside Kaipo, sick from an illness called desert fever. She grew concerned after hearing about the events in Mist and went in search of him. Cecil and Rydia head to Damcyan Castle for assistance in finding a sand pearl, the cure, and are joined by Tellah, an old sage looking for his eloping daughter.Cecil and Rydia meeting EdwardHowever, the trio find Damcyan Castle being attacked by the Red Wings, and by the time they reach inside, they find a significant number of casualties, including Tellah's daughter, Anna. Edward, the bard Anna eloped with, is also the Prince of Damcyan, and tells of how Golbez led the Red Wings and took the Fire Crystal for themselves. Tellah, enraged by his daughter's death, leaves by himself to exact revenge on Golbez. After snapping out of a state of mourning by Cecil, Edward helps Cecil and Rydia retrieve a sand pearl from an antlion, and Rosa recovers from desert fever. Through Edward's knowledge, the party learns that Fabul is the next target of the Red Wings, as it has the Wind Crystal.Golbez's first appearanceAs they head towards the next Crystal, the quartet encounter a Fabul monk, Yang. Yang heeds their warning about the impending attack and takes them to Fabul Castle, moments before Golbez's Red Wings arrive. They are forced to retreat to the Crystal chamber, where Kain, now working for Golbez, defeats Cecil in a duel. At this moment, Golbez makes his entrance, easily fending off attacks from the party, and orders Kain to retrieve the Crystal. While Kain complies, Golbez notices that Cecil cares for Rosa, and kidnaps her before taking his leave with Kain and the Crystal.Cecil realizes that they are no match against the airships of the Red Wings, and so the party starts heading towards Baron seeking the aid of Cid, the constructor of the airships. However, while at sea, they come across Leviathan, a feared monster known as the Lord of All Waters. Cecil ends up washed ashore near Mysidia, separated from everyone else. The Mysidians are hostile towards Cecil, but despite this, the Elder of Mysidia agrees to help Cecil in his plight against Golbez, and tells the dark knight that a dark sword cannot slay Golbez. Cecil must first rid himself of darkness at the top of Mount Ordeals.Cleansing the DarknessAccompanied by twin mages Palom and Porom, Cecil ascends the mountain. Halfway up, he reunites with Tellah, who is seeking to learn the powerful spell Meteor to defeat Golbez, even if using the spell means losing his life. The four of them reach the summit, overpowering Scarmiglione, one of four elemental archfiends working for Golbez, along the way. At the mountaintop, a light greets the party, calling Cecil "son", before teleporting everyone to an isolated room, where Cecil proves his worth by defeating the dark knight version of himself. Cecil is rewarded by being made a paladin and receives a sword of light.Porom and Palom agreeing to sacrifice their livesIn Baron, after reuniting with Yang (he tells Cecil that Rydia was swallowed by Leviathan), Cecil and his companions attempt to rescue Cid, who is locked inside the castle. They first confront the King of Baron, and find out that another archfiend working for Golbez, Cagnazzo, killed and was impersonating the king all along. After defeating Cagnazzo, the party find Cid and together, they plan to leave on Cid's latest airship invention, which he calls the Enterprise. However, Cagnazzo's last act is to trap the party in a room where the walls are caving in on them. Palom and Porom sacrifice their lives by turning themselves into stone to stop the walls.Golbez, meanwhile, arrives at a complication in trying to obtain the fourth and final Crystal, as it has already been stolen by a dark elf, so Kain proposes an exchange to the party: the Earth Crystal from Troia for Rosa. The party kills the dark elf with outside assistance from Edward, who was found recovering in Troia Castle's infirmary. With the Earth Crystal, Cecil and his companions are led to the Tower of Zot to make the exchange. However, Golbez doesn't stick to his end of the bargain after taking the Crystal.Tellah confronts the man responsible for the death of his daughter and unleashes Meteor on him, but it does little damage against Golbez (though he loses his hold on a mind-controlled Kain), while mortally wounding the sage. Cecil lashes out at Golbez, but is easily swatted down. As Golbez prepares to deliver the final blow, he becomes shocked by a reason unbenownst to everyone else and walks away. Cecil, Yang, and Cid tend to Tellah, who dies from his wounds, his last words begging for Anna to be avenged. Kain, now free to control his own actions, leads Cecil to Rosa, and the pair are reunited once more. With archfiend Barbariccia killed, Rosa teleports everyone out from the crumbling tower.The UnderworldThe Dwarven CastleBack at Baron Castle, Kain tells the group that there are actually eight Crystals that Golbez needs. While Golbez has the four Light Crystals, there are four Dark Crystals in the underworld. These Crystals can be used to open a "way to the moon". The party travel to the village of Agart, where they open the seal, and once they reach the underworld, they see the Red Wings engaged in combat against a dwarven tank battalion. Inside the Dwarven Castle, King Giott informs Cecil and his friends that Golbez already has two Dark Crystals (a total of six Crystals in his possession).Golbez enters to steal the seventh Crystal from the Crystal chamber, revealing that he intends to use the Crystals to reactivate the Tower of Babil and thus the gate to the moon. With help from Rydia, now a young lady, Cecil's party overpowers their nemesis, but fails to stop him from escaping with the Crystal. Rydia explains that Leviathan carried her to the Feymarch, the land of the Eidolons. She lived among the Eidolons for several years, and because time flows differently in the Feymarch, she now appears to have grown so much in such a short space of time.The final Crystal lies in the Sealed Cave up north, but King Giott tells Cecil to go to the Tower of Babil and try to steal the other seven Crystals while Golbez is distracted in acquiring the eighth. On the way to the summit of the tower, Yang and Cid both sacrifice their lives. Yang destroys the Tower of Babil's cannons, which were about to destroy the dwarven army, while Cid activates a bomb to give the rest of the party enough time to flee Golbez's pursuing airship.Edge swearing revenge against RubicanteCecil and his group also encounter Edge, Eblan's prince, who is pursuing revenge against the last archfiend, Rubicante, responsible for Eblan Castle's slaughter and the demise of his parents. Together, they defeat Rubicante and have the seven Crystals in their sight before they fall down several floors through a trap door. They are forced to abandon their plans of reacquiring the Crystals and make their way to the Sealed Cave. After the group beats Golbez to the final Crystal, though, Kain's mind is once again taken over by Golbez, and the dragoon steals the Crystal from them and takes it to Golbez. When the party reports back the news that Golbez now has all eight Crystals, King Giott tells them to go to Mysidia.The MoonFusoya the LunarianCecil and his companions make their way back to Mysidia, where the Elder's prayers summon the Lunar Whale, an extremely technologically advanced ship, from the ocean. With it, they travel to the moon and meet Fusoya, a Lunarian and inhabitant of the moon. Fusoya is the guardian of the Lunarians, charged with preserving the tranquility of their slumber. The Lunarians came from another planet, but were forced to flee after its destruction. They came across Earth, but because the people of Earth were still evolving and had not caught up with the Lunarians, they decided to hibernate until Earth had caught up.However, one Lunarian named Zemus did not want to sleep, and wanted to destroy all existing life on Earth to claim the planet as their own. He was forced into hibernation with the others, but his will grew stronger in sleep and took a consciousness of its own, reaching out to Golbez and manipulating him to do his bidding. The Crystals function as a source of energy, and all eight combined will be enough to summon the Giant of Babil, a robotic being powerful enough to extinguish all life on Earth. Fusoya also had a younger brother, Kluya. The Lunar Whale belonged to Kluya, and he flew it to Earth where he fell in love with a woman and had two children, one of whom was Cecil. Cecil realizes that the voice he heard at Mount Ordeals was in fact Kluya's.Fusoya accompanies Cecil and his party back to Earth to stop the Giant of Babil. Yang, Cid, Palom, and Porom, all thought to have been deceased, are alive and along with Edward stagger the Giant, allowing Cecil's party to enter inside to destroy the controls from within. After successfully obliterating the CPU, they are met by an angry Golbez. Fusoya, however, performs a spell to help Golbez break out of Zemus' hold. Golbez reveals that he is also a son of Kluya, and thus Cecil's brother. Golbez was easily manipulated by Zemus as a young child after his father was killed by villagers and his mother died in childbirth when Cecil was born. Golbez took Cecil and left him at the edge of Baron; Cecil was found and raised by the king. Wanting to put an end to all of this madness, Golbez now sets off to the moon to kill Zemus. He is accompanied by Fusoya.Zemus is killedKain, now free from Golbez's mind control, rejoins Cecil, Rosa, Rydia, and Edge, and the five head for the moon's core to assist in defeating Zemus. They see Golbez and Fusoya end Zemus' life, but Zemus' spirit is resurrected as Zeromus, fed by Zemus' hate. Golbez and Fusoya are no match for Zeromus, and are easily defeated. Cecil's party then faces Zeromus, but once again, Zeromus is too strong. All seems to be lost until the prayers of Cecil's friends on Earth, led by the Mysidian Elder, bestow strength and vitality on the party, and the party defeats Zeromus.After the final battle, Fusoya returns to hibernation and is joined by Golbez, who admits that he can't return to Earth after everything he has done. As Golbez leaves, Cecil acknowledges Golbez as his brother. Back on Earth, while Cecil is preparing for his coronation ceremony with Rosa, he hears Golbez's voice bidding him farewell as the moon leaves the Earth's orbit. The final scene is the coronation itself, as all of Cecil and Rosa's friends, except for Kain who is on Mount Ordeals, come to see the couple being crowned as Baron's new king and queen.[CR][B]Characters:[/B][CR]Final Fantasy IV includes twelve playable characters.Cecil Harvey as a paladinCecil - Dark Knight / Paladin - The game's central protagonist. Cecil Harvey used to command the Red Wings airship fleet, prior to being banished from the Kingdom of Baron after doubting the king's motives. He soon finds himself trying to stop the Earth's Crystals falling into the wrong hands. Cecil's "Dark Wave" attack as a Dark Knight is missing from the North American 1991 SNES release.Kain - Dragoon - Despite being childhood friends with Cecil, Kain Highwind's true allegiance is unclear. Kain has feelings towards Rosa, but hides them to avoid sabotaging the relationship between her and Cecil. In battle, he is a powerful fighter, with strong attacks and armor.Rydia - Summoner - Rydia, a seven year-old girl, is a summoner from the village of Mist, forced to accompany Cecil following the destruction of her home. Though she is handy with magic, Rydia becomes much more powerful later in the game, when she learns how to command powerful magic spells and summon an array of powerful creatures to aid her companions in battle. Her "Summon" command is localized as "Call", and the Eidolons are referred to as "summoned monsters" in the 1991 North American SNES release.Tellah - Sage - A sage hailing from Mysidia, Tellah knows a great deal of powerful magic spells. He seeks to track down his daughter Anna, who has eloped with a bard. Tellah is growing old, and acknowledges that he might not have many years left.Edward - Bard - Edward Chris von Muir is not only a bard with a harp but also the Prince of Damcyan. While not being the strongest of fighters, Edward is a useful addition to the party. For example, his mystical songs can help to put enemies to sleep.Rosa FarrellRosa - White Mage - An experienced yet kind-hearted mage, Rosa Farrell can learn a number of healing spells to strengthen up the party without having to resort to using up precious items. She is also competent with the bow. Rosa and Cecil have romantic feelings for each other. Rosa's "Pray" ability is missing from the original 1991 North American SNES release.Yang - Monk - Yang Fang Leiden is an extremely respected monk of Fabul, who aids Cecil in his quest. Humble, loyal, and married, he knows how to deal strong physical damage to his enemies that stand in his way. Yang is missing two abilities from the original 1991 North American SNES release: one which enables him to sacrifice his turn to double the power of his next attack; and one which enables him to sacrifice his turn to double his defense for that turn.Palom - Black Mage - Though young and inexperienced, Palom is a talented mage. He comes from Mysidia, and while being noted for his arrogance (he declares himself as "The Mysidian Genius"), this is kept in check by his twin sister, Porom. Palom is missing his "Bluff" ability in the 1991 North American SNES release, which buffed his black magic power.Porom - White Mage - Despite being already proficient in the art of magic, Porom has a great deal to learn. As an apprentice, she wants all the experience she can get. Porom is quite the opposite of Palom, as she has polite and well-mannered compared to her twin brother's confident personality. Porom is missing her "Cry" ability from the North American 1991 SNES release, which flusters the party's enemies and increases the chance for a successful escape.Cid - Engineer - Cid Pollendina is the constructor of the Red Wings airships. He has a daughter in Baron and is the main source of comic relief when he travels with Cecil. Cid is a physical fighter, but can also check an enemy's stats and weaknesses.Edge - Ninja - Edge's hot temper is counteracted only by his thirst for justice. He is the prince of the ancient island of Eblan, and has honed his abilities to a high standard. Edge often flirts with women and thinks rather highly of himself.Fusoya - Sage - Fusoya is a Lunarian and an inhabitant of the moon. First appearing near the endgame, he is aware of why the Crystals are so keenly sought for, and knows some things about Cecil that the protagonist doesn't even know. FuSoYa is missing his whole-party "Regen" battle command in the 1991 North American SNES release.[CR][B]References:[/B][CR]Dante Alighieri's InfernoFinal Fantasy IV features villains named after five of the Malebranches from Dante Alighieri's The Divine Comedy, specifically Inferno. The game's elemental fiends are named directly after Scarmiglione (earth), Cagnazzo (water), Barbariccia (wind) and Rubicante (fire). In the original SNES North American 1991 release, they were spelled "Milon", "Kainazzo", "Valvalis" and "Rubicant" respectively. Another boss encounter features a collection of enemies known as Calcabrina, also misspelled in the 1991 North American release as "Calbrena".Mythology and ReligionAs is commonplace throughout the Final Fantasy series, Final Fantasy IV features references to Norse mythology, Hinduism, Islam and other religions and lore, including but not limited to the following:SummonsOdin (Norse Mythology)Bahamut (Islam)Ifrit (Islam)Shiva (Hinduism)Asura (Hinduism)Titan (Greek Mythology)Leviathan (Judaism, Christianity)WeaponryRagnarok (Norse mythology); originally localized as a "Crystal" sword in the original 1991 SNES North American releaseExcalibur (King Arthur)Gungnir (Norse mythology)Murasame (from the Japanese novel, Nans&#333; Satomi Hakkenden)Artemis Bow (Greek mythology)ArmorMinerva Bustier (Roman mythology)Gaia Gear (Greek mythology)Aegis Shield (Greek mythology)Hades Helmet and Gloves (Greek mythology)Other Final Fantasy GamesThe game features several series staples, such as Chocobos, the character Cid, airships, and the Crystals.The original Final Fantasy II (which first appeared on Nintendo's Famicom) also contains a town named Mysidia.In addition, the music that plays in the Tower of Babil is almost identical to that which plays in an endgame tower in The Final Fantasy Legend (Game Boy), known originally as SaGa in Japan.[CR]Version Differences[CR]Final Fantasy IV has been released numerous times over the years with various tweaks that distinguish one from another:Final Fantasy IV on the SNESFinal Fantasy IV: The standard version of Final Fantasy IV originally released for the Super Famicom in Japan.Final Fantasy IV Easy Type: A rebalanced version of the game that is easier than the standard difficulty. Certain features and items, such as Cecil's Darkness ability, were also stripped from the game in order to further simplify it. Ailment-specific healing items, for example, were combined into a single, all-encompassing, more expensive healing item. Although it is believed that this is the version of the game originally released in North America as Final Fantasy II for the SNES, Final Fantasy II and Final Fantasy IV Easy Type have certain differences, such as thematic censorship, different removed abilities, and a completely different version of Zeromus.Final Fantasy II: To prevent confusion among consumers, the original North American version of the game for the Super Nintendo was renamed because the Famicom games Final Fantasy II and Final Fantasy III weren't available outside of Japan at the time. This version of the game is largely identical to the Japanese Final Fantasy IV Easy Type edition of the game, but features additional cuts and alterations for the North American audience. Two of the more prominent cuts were removing certain story details about Fusoya being Cecil's uncle and Kain's desire to live in his father's footsteps as a Dragon Knight instead of being pushed into a life as a Black Knight. Some parts of the game were also censored, most notably references to death as well as scenes and dialogue that could have been considered "more PG-13 than PG".Final Fantasy IV (Final Fantasy Chronicles release): A PlayStation port released in North America as part of a bundle with the PlayStation port of Chrono Trigger. It is a translated version of Hard Type, but as a port it suffers from long loading times not present in the Super Famicom/SNES release. There is also some choppiness in scenes that utilize Mode 7 because the PlayStation doesn't support it.Final Fantasy IV Advance: A port of Hard Type for the Game Boy Advance, complete with a rewritten translation and an extra dungeon not found in the original console versions. The North American version of the game is known for suffering from numerous bugs, such as Yang's HP not increasing after level 60, some of the weapons being treated as armor, random extra turns being given to characters in battle, and certain weapons designed to be long-range not counting as long-range attacks. Many of the bugs were fixed for other regional releases.Final Fantasy IV DS: A fully re-done version of the game for the Nintendo DS, complete with 3D graphics, a new script with added scenes and dialogue, and voice acting. The game lacks the extra dungeon found in the GBA release, but does contain extras such as the augment feature, New Game, an event theater to watch cutscenes, and Whyt, a new Eidolon for Rydia who can replace Rydia in battle and whose stats can be raised by scoring well in a collection of new minigames. The DS version also added several fully 3D CGI cutscenes. For more information about the key changes of this remake, see the DS page of Final Fantasy IV.Final Fantasy IV: The Complete Collection: A hi-res version of Final Fantasy IV for the PSP featuring completely redone graphics and the inclusion of the Lunar Ruins bonus dungeon from Final Fantasy IV Advance. The collection also comes with a graphically remade version of the Wii release The After Years and a new Final Fantasy IV Interlude that bridges the gap between the original game and the After Years.[CR][B]Soundtrack:[/B][CR]The Final Fantasy IV Original Sound Version was released on June 14, 1991, and includes 44 tracks from the game composed by Nobuo Uematsu. "Theme of Love" is one of Final Fantasy IV's most well-known tunes.Track ListingThe PreludeThe Red WingsKingdom of BaronTheme of LovePrologueWelcome to Our Town!Main Theme of Final Fantasy IVBattle 1FanfareEnter Fat ChocoboChocobo ChocoboInto the DarknessBattle 2Bomb RingRydiaDamcyan CastleSorrow and LossEdward's HarpMt. OrdealsFabulRun!SuspicionGolbez, Clad in DarknessHey Cid!Mystic MysidiaA Long Way to GoPalom and PoromBattle with the Four FiendsThe AirshipTroian BeautySamba de Chocobo!Tower of Bab-ilSomewhere in the World...Land of DwarvesGiott, King of the DwarvesDancing CalbrenaTower of ZotThe Land of SummonsLunar WhaleAnother MoonThe LunariansWithin the GiantThe Final BattleEpilogue[CR][B]Legacy:[/B][CR]You spoony bard!One of Final Fantasy's most well-known quotes also originated from this game as a result of a poor translation in the SNES release. During a relatively early part of the story, Tellah vents his fury at Edward, a bard, and shouts:You spoony bard!This line became famous enough that it has been retained in all subsequent remakes. It was referenced in Phoenix Wright: Ace Attorney - Trials and Tribulations.Final Fantasy IV's presence was also felt in Super Mario RPG: Legend of the Seven Stars. Culex, a hidden boss in the game who is designed to appear like a Final Fantasy boss, arrives in the Mushroom Kingdom to conquer it, but finds it uninhabitable. on his return home, he encounters Mario and challenges him. His boss theme is the same as the regular boss theme of Final Fantasy IV, while his epilogue tune is also the main theme of Final Fantasy.[CR]Final Fantasy IV: The After Years[CR]The sequel to Final Fantasy IVFinal Fantasy IV: The After Years is a mobile phone and Wii sequel to Final Fantasy IV. It is set seventeen years after the events of the original, and follows Ceodore, the son of Cecil and Rosa. The first two chapters of the game were released in February 2008 in Japan. In June 2009, they were released for the Wii's Wiiware service in North America and Europe. The remaining nine episodes are now available on Wiiware.The After Years features random encounters and an ATB system like the original, but also introduces some fresh gameplay elements, such as the Age of the Moon and the Band System.[CR]Final Fantasy IV: The Complete Collection[CR]Final Fantasy IV: The Complete Collection is a PSP compilation featuring Final Fantasy IV and its episodic sequel, The After Years. The collection also features an all-new episode set between the events of the original game and its sequel. This game allows players to start with either the Interlude portion, The After Years, or the original Final Fantasy IV story. The only exception is that the player must complete the first episode of The After Years to open the other episodes, which can then be played in any order.[CR]</plot>
		<releasedate>29/3/2002</releasedate>
		<year>2001</year>
		<genre>RPG</genre>
		<studio>Square Co.</studio>
		<nplayers>1</nplayers>
		<perspective>Top-Down</perspective>
		<rating>3.5</rating>
		<thegamesdb_id>27706</thegamesdb_id>
		<mobygames_url>https://www.mobygames.com/game/wonderswan-color/final-fantasy-ii___</mobygames_url>
		<giantbomb_url>https://www.giantbomb.com/final-fantasy-iv/3030-20829/</giantbomb_url>
		<boxart1>aCYiELz.jpg</boxart1>
		<boxart2>6dtilbj.jpg</boxart2>
		<boxart3>GhoQ7Dk.jpg</boxart3>
		<snapshot1>Kg8MtSY.png</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>e4sTU6H.gif</snapshot2>
		<snapshot3>tBZFy19.gif</snapshot3>
		<snapshot4>SSWMN64.gif</snapshot4>
		<snapshot5>7v5ee5O.gif</snapshot5>
		<snapshot6>suluWQs.gif</snapshot6>
		<snapshot7>IwzDh8w.gif</snapshot7>
		<snapshot8>WrOCdWY.gif</snapshot8>
		<snapshot9>KjbKLlw.gif</snapshot9>
		<snapshot10>PGPfW2L.gif</snapshot10>
	</game>
	<game name="Final Lap Special - GT &amp; Formula Machine (Japan)">
		<description>Final Lap Special - GT &amp; Formula Machine (Japan)</description>
		<rom crc="B07E6A56" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan%20Color.zip/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan%20Color%2FFinal%20Lap%20Special%20-%20GT%20%26%20Formula%20Machine%20%28Japan%29.zip" sha1="4C3F092B095BDB0AFDAF8D32D4C54B4D6C209C96" size="2211131" />
		<title_clean>Final Lap Special - GT &amp; Formula Machine</title_clean>
		<plot>Final Lap Special is a Racing game, developed and published by Bandai, which was released in Japan in 2001.[CR]https://www.gamefaqs.com/portable/wscolor/home/566007.html[CR]</plot>
		<releasedate>4/7/2001</releasedate>
		<year>2001</year>
		<genre>Driving, Racing</genre>
		<studio>Bandai</studio>
		<nplayers>1-2 Alt</nplayers>
		<thegamesdb_id>19636</thegamesdb_id>
		<boxart1>XaztqzH.jpg</boxart1>
		<snapshot1>rVsQzkH.png</snapshot1>
	</game>
	<game name="Flash Koibito-kun (Japan)">
		<description>Flash Koibito-kun (Japan)</description>
		<rom crc="69D8D433" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan%20Color.zip/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan%20Color%2FFlash%20Koibito-kun%20%28Japan%29.zip" sha1="A3D6717EFDB8F243FE86B4C3D869A9734A2E02D3" size="543616" />
		<title_clean>Flash Koibito-kun</title_clean>
		<plot>Flash Koibito-Kun is a Puzzle game, developed by Koto and published by Koubunsha, which was released in Japan in 2000.</plot>
		<releasedate>28/12/2000</releasedate>
		<year>2000</year>
		<genre>RPG</genre>
		<nplayers>1</nplayers>
		<thegamesdb_id>27707</thegamesdb_id>
		<boxart1>Sqia2tE.jpg</boxart1>
		<snapshot1>IXno23E.png</snapshot1>
	</game>
	<game name="From TV Animation One Piece - Chopper no Daibouken (Japan)">
		<description>From TV Animation One Piece - Chopper no Daibouken (Japan)</description>
		<rom crc="8E120B5A" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan%20Color.zip/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan%20Color%2FFrom%20TV%20Animation%20One%20Piece%20-%20Chopper%20no%20Daibouken%20%28Japan%29.zip" sha1="221F48E97EC2C6D0046213956E1F36E923C0DEC2" size="1081991" />
		<title_clean>From TV Animation One Piece - Chopper no Daibouken</title_clean>
		<releasedate>16/10/2003</releasedate>
		<year>2003</year>
		<giantbomb_url>https://www.giantbomb.com/one-piece-chopper-no-dai-bouken/3030-36388/</giantbomb_url>
		<boxart1>YRLot9X.jpg</boxart1>
		<snapshot1>WriNDFa.png</snapshot1>
	</game>
	<game name="From TV Animation One Piece - Grand Battle Swan Colosseum (Japan)">
		<description>From TV Animation One Piece - Grand Battle Swan Colosseum (Japan)</description>
		<rom crc="F8A1DD2B" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan%20Color.zip/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan%20Color%2FFrom%20TV%20Animation%20One%20Piece%20-%20Grand%20Battle%20Swan%20Colosseum%20%28Japan%29.zip" sha1="01E765BF356CDCB413BFD27C6321F7449465766A" size="3097908" />
		<title_clean>From TV Animation One Piece - Grand Battle Swan Colosseum</title_clean>
		<plot>[CR][B]Overview:[/B][CR] One Piece Grand Battle: Swan Colosseum came out in  Japan on July 12, 2002. It is available only for the  Wonderswan Color, a console that came only in  Japan and never made it stateside.  [CR][B]Gameplay:[/B][CR] The game plays very similarly to games like  Super Smash Bros. The game takes place on a 2D plane, and the levels are large and freely navigate-able. There are two types of basic attacks, light and strong attacks. In addition there are also special attacks that are preformed by doing certain button combinations, and super attacks that can be done when the players fills up a  super meter. The game only has two combatants on screen at a time, but is very fast and fluid. [CR][B]Game Modes:[/B][CR] Story  The Story mode goes through a series of fights for each fighter. ExhibitionMultiplayer  Multiplayer is available when you use the  Wonderswan link cable to connect two  Wonderswan Color systems, each system needs a copy   of the game. [CR][B]Characters:[/B][CR] Fighters in the game include, but are not limited to:  Luffy Zoro Nami Chopper Sanji Usopp[CR]</plot>
		<releasedate>12/7/2002</releasedate>
		<year>2002</year>
		<giantbomb_url>https://www.giantbomb.com/one-piece-grand-battle-swan-colosseum/3030-30633/</giantbomb_url>
		<boxart1>9x3BfIM.jpg</boxart1>
		<snapshot1>pcBecNk.png</snapshot1>
	</game>
	<game name="From TV Animation One Piece - Niji no Shima Densetsu (Japan)">
		<description>From TV Animation One Piece - Niji no Shima Densetsu (Japan)</description>
		<rom crc="427056C4" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan%20Color.zip/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan%20Color%2FFrom%20TV%20Animation%20One%20Piece%20-%20Niji%20no%20Shima%20Densetsu%20%28Japan%29.zip" sha1="2410690AD46667C52B63402DF9E95FC8A75CEE62" size="2404815" />
		<title_clean>From TV Animation One Piece - Niji no Shima Densetsu</title_clean>
		<snapshot1>AaoMEUQ.png</snapshot1>
	</game>
	<game name="From TV Animation One Piece - Treasure Wars (Japan)">
		<description>From TV Animation One Piece - Treasure Wars (Japan)</description>
		<rom crc="205503C3" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan%20Color.zip/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan%20Color%2FFrom%20TV%20Animation%20One%20Piece%20-%20Treasure%20Wars%20%28Japan%29.zip" sha1="DD1E6E5467B72FCB5848F07A9747AA66BB207D45" size="1461863" />
		<title_clean>From TV Animation One Piece - Treasure Wars</title_clean>
		<plot>[CR][B]Gameplay:[/B][CR]In the game you play as one of the straw hats and then fights versus another straw hat in a board game. The goal is to get the treasure first.  [CR]Playable Characters[CR]Monkey D. Luffy Roronoa Zoro Nami Usopp Sanji Tony Tony Chopper[CR]</plot>
		<releasedate>3/1/2002</releasedate>
		<year>2002</year>
		<giantbomb_url>https://www.giantbomb.com/one-piece-treasure-wars/3030-36302/</giantbomb_url>
		<boxart1>EZVDI6C.jpg</boxart1>
		<snapshot1>neXEFPi.png</snapshot1>
	</game>
	<game name="From TV Animation One Piece - Treasure Wars 2 - Buggy Land e Youkoso (Japan)">
		<description>From TV Animation One Piece - Treasure Wars 2 - Buggy Land e Youkoso (Japan)</description>
		<rom crc="0D1048F0" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan%20Color.zip/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan%20Color%2FFrom%20TV%20Animation%20One%20Piece%20-%20Treasure%20Wars%202%20-%20Buggy%20Land%20e%20Youkoso%20%28Japan%29.zip" sha1="B7775E8F60FD62DC07F2865F8FAD29A11E12DBB5" size="2595448" />
		<title_clean>From TV Animation One Piece - Treasure Wars 2 - Buggy Land e Youkoso</title_clean>
		<plot>[CR][B]Gameplay:[/B][CR]In the game you play as one of the straw hats and then fights versus another straw hat in a board game. The goal is to get the treasure first.  [CR]Playable Characters[CR]Monkey D. Luffy Roronoa Zoro Nami Usopp Sanji Tony Tony Chopper[CR]</plot>
		<releasedate>3/1/2002</releasedate>
		<year>2002</year>
		<giantbomb_url>https://www.giantbomb.com/one-piece-treasure-wars/3030-36302/</giantbomb_url>
		<boxart1>EZVDI6C.jpg</boxart1>
		<snapshot1>p4ZthLq.png</snapshot1>
	</game>
	<game name="Front Mission (Japan)">
		<description>Front Mission (Japan)</description>
		<rom crc="2F9E2560" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan%20Color.zip/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan%20Color%2FFront%20Mission%20%28Japan%29.zip" sha1="3C752694AB651F9A00CCD39C334A2E3FF78F5CB2" size="2530314" />
		<title_clean>Front Mission</title_clean>
		<plot>[CR][B]Overview:[/B][CR]Front Mission is the first video game in the Front Mission franchise. Released on February 24, 1995, the game was a distinctive title in the turn-based strategy and RPG markets in Japan. Set in a near-future version of the planet Earth in the late 21st century, Front Mission's storyline weaves a complex tale of military, political, and technological conspiracy, all centered around a major conflict set in a fictional Pacific Ocean island known as Huffman Island. A central focus of this is the inclusion of mecha known as "wanderpanzers" (German for "walking armor") or "wanzers" in short. This tale was the first of many that would later be revealed as small parts of an overarching serialized storyline running through numerous Front Mission titles.Front Mission received a direct port for the Bandai WonderSwan Color on July 12, 2002 in Japan. This port came with no new features other than the ability to speed up the battle sequences. One year later, a remake of the game titled  Front Mission 1st was released for the Sony PlayStation on October 23, 2003 in Japan. This remake had many changes and additions, the most notable of which was a second campaign to play the game through. Front Mission 1st would later get an enhanced port on the Nintendo DS, with even more changes and additions to the game. This version of the game was the only one to be localized into English and was released in North America on October 23, 2007.[CR][B]Story:[/B][CR]The story of Front Mission is set on a near-future Earth in A.D. 2090. In the early 21st century, a global recession and other worldwide crises forced many nations to set aside their differences and form large regional entities known as supranational unions. These large super-states heralded in what was called the "globalization revolution", as many people around the world were willing to move past national boundaries to work for the greater good of mankind. However, it would not be long before new wars and conflicts were fought between the supranational unions and their member states.In 2070, a war breaks out between the Oceania Cooperative Union (O.C.U.) and the United States of the New Continent (U.S.N.). This war was triggered by territorial and natural resource disputes on a new Pacific Ocean island known as Huffman, as both super-states had colonized the island a few years prior to the conflict. After the war ended in 2072, a border was formed by the Mail River located in the center of Huffman. An uneasy peace was kept in the following years, but this would not last long.By 2086, a series of disputes across Huffman Island known as the Huffman Crisis leads both the O.C.U. and the U.S.N. to begin war preparations. Tensions began to rise and by 2089, the two super-states started to recruit mercenaries from all over the world to guard their borders at Mail River. An attack on a U.S.N. munitions plant in the Larcus District on June 3, 2090 becomes the catalyst for what would later be known as the 2nd Huffman Conflict.[CR][B]Gameplay:[/B][CR]Devising a strategyFront Mission is a turn-based strategy game, designed to resemble to Intelligent Design's  Fire Emblem series. The camera is angled isometrically on a grid-based map where characters are placed. Each round plays out beginning with the player acting first, followed by the opponent. Players move all of their characters in their turn. When characters engage in combat, the game shifts to another screen. Players choose the weapon they wish to use or the action to take if on defense. Then, in turn, each wanzer will take their action. Each wanzer has 4 health bars, two small bars for each arm, and two large bars, one for the body, and one for the legs. If an arm is destroyed, whatever the wanzer was carrying in that arm becomes unusable. If the legs are destroyed, the wanzer's movement is greatly limited. Finally, if the body is destroyed, the wanzer becomes inoperable.In between combat, players can customize their wanzers. The game's stores offer a variety of wanzer parts to beef up the player's units. There are a variety of weapons, bodies, legs, CPUs, and other items with which to customize. Each wanzer is limited by the supply of power it has, and its weight. The player cannot overload a wanzer with too many weapons, as it will surpass the allowed power. There are upgrades to power, but it is never unlimited. There are a variety of weapons in the game, melee, short-range, and long-range. Wanzers can simply punch with their arms, use hand-mounted melee weapons, shotguns, flamethrowers, machine guns, rifles, and the long range missiles. Each arm can carry one weapon, and a long range weapon or a shield can be place on the shoulder. There are also a number of options for the wanzer's legs and movement. The most common options are legs, but wheels, treads, and hover types are also available.Missions in the game are varied from taking out all opponents, certain opponents, escort missions, defense missions, and more.[CR]</plot>
		<releasedate>12/7/2002</releasedate>
		<year>2002</year>
		<genre>RPG, Strategy</genre>
		<studio>Square Co.</studio>
		<nplayers>1-2 Alt</nplayers>
		<perspective>1st-Person</perspective>
		<rating>3.5</rating>
		<thegamesdb_id>27712</thegamesdb_id>
		<mobygames_url>https://www.mobygames.com/game/wonderswan-color/front-mission</mobygames_url>
		<giantbomb_url>https://www.giantbomb.com/front-mission/3030-6052/</giantbomb_url>
		<boxart1>ABx0Y3e.jpg</boxart1>
		<snapshot1>r8kLrr0.png</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>mN5PpVY.png</snapshot2>
		<snapshot3>lBA7RiF.png</snapshot3>
		<snapshot4>ox7ClWg.png</snapshot4>
		<snapshot5>GU1QGk3.jpg</snapshot5>
		<snapshot6>54FYvCr.jpg</snapshot6>
		<snapshot7>M4jq2Mc.jpg</snapshot7>
		<snapshot8>FWtOj44.jpg</snapshot8>
		<snapshot9>5f3kQXj.jpg</snapshot9>
		<snapshot10>h6AdBWC.jpg</snapshot10>
	</game>
	<game name="Gekitou! Crash Gear Turbo - Gear Champion League (Japan)">
		<description>Gekitou! Crash Gear Turbo - Gear Champion League (Japan)</description>
		<rom crc="8A8B827C" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan%20Color.zip/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan%20Color%2FGekitou%21%20Crash%20Gear%20Turbo%20-%20Gear%20Champion%20League%20%28Japan%29.zip" sha1="1BC1E831B9E2AEFC59F2CAC5F19F7D22BE574FC1" size="688489" />
		<title_clean>Gekitou! Crash Gear Turbo - Gear Champion League</title_clean>
		<plot>Gekitou! Crash Gear Turbo: Gear Champion League is an Action game, developed and published by Bandai, which was released in Japan in 2002.</plot>
		<releasedate>10/8/2002</releasedate>
		<year>2002</year>
		<genre>Action</genre>
		<nplayers>1-2 Alt</nplayers>
		<thegamesdb_id>27713</thegamesdb_id>
		<boxart1>kOWCJnb.jpg</boxart1>
		<snapshot1>4DxVSp2.png</snapshot1>
	</game>
	<game name="Gensou Maden Saiyuuki Retribution - Hi no Ataru Basho de (Japan)">
		<description>Gensou Maden Saiyuuki Retribution - Hi no Ataru Basho de (Japan)</description>
		<rom crc="446E2581" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan%20Color.zip/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan%20Color%2FGensou%20Maden%20Saiyuuki%20Retribution%20-%20Hi%20no%20Ataru%20Basho%20de%20%28Japan%29.zip" sha1="ADBE6E38A0BC6A2D19DA64A444071977B771F14F" size="540667" />
		<title_clean>Gensou Maden Saiyuuki Retribution - Hi no Ataru Basho de</title_clean>
		<plot>Gensou Maden Saiyuuki Retribution: Hi no Ataru Basho De is a Role-Playing game, developed by PicPac-Airreal and published by Mubik, which was released in Japan in 2001.</plot>
		<releasedate>7/6/2001</releasedate>
		<year>2001</year>
		<genre>RPG</genre>
		<nplayers>1</nplayers>
		<thegamesdb_id>27714</thegamesdb_id>
		<boxart1>shOtaYz.jpg</boxart1>
		<snapshot1>I89GKRs.png</snapshot1>
	</game>
	<game name="Golden Axe (Japan)">
		<description>Golden Axe (Japan)</description>
		<rom crc="BC944A98" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan%20Color.zip/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan%20Color%2FGolden%20Axe%20%28Japan%29.zip" sha1="87661841CA63E99B04C0F6DC4BA3454C897E0C6D" size="571635" />
		<title_clean>Golden Axe</title_clean>
		<plot>[CR][B]Overview:[/B][CR]Golden Axe is side-scrolling hack and slash game developed by Sega and released in 1989 as an arcade game. It was later ported to the Sega Genesis/Mega Drive, as well as a few other platforms including Xbox Live Arcade on July 11, 2007.[CR][B]Plot:[/B][CR]An evil being known as Death Adder has taken over the once peaceful land called Yuria. Having murdered many innocent people, he also captured the king and his daughter. Death Adder's coup de gr&#226;ce was finding the magical emblem of the land, the Golden Axe. And unless the people of Yuria accept him as the land's new king, he promises to destroy it.Starting the game requires players to select one of three characters, each of which is filled with revenge. While all three share the same goal of saving the king and his daughter, and stopping Death Adder from destroying the Golden Axe, each one has individual ambitions as well.Gilius Thunderhead - a battleaxe-wielding dwarf whose twin brother was killed by Death Adder's henchmen. His heart is filled with hate for the evil being.Ax Battler - a barbarian who wields a two-handed broadsword, his desire to stop Death Adder fueled by the hatred he feels for him, because the evil being killed his mother.Tyris Flare - a longsword-wielding amazon, she wants revenge on Death Adder for the murder of both of her parents.[CR][B]Gameplay:[/B][CR]Story modeTo advance through the game, players must fight through swarms of Death Adder's henchmen, including mace-wielders, giants, and barbarians riding dragons and other mythical creatures. Killing a henchman mounted on one of these creatures affords players the opportunity to ride it as well.Players possess the ability to cast magic spells, which require magic potions obtained by kicking small, strange-looking thieves. More magic potions equal more devastating magical attacks. Picking up meat by kicking thieves helps recover lost health on the health bar.It is also possible to play through the game cooperatively with a second player.Duel modeDuel mode was implemented in many of the ports, but it was never included in the original arcade version. In Duel mode, players must fight through a number of small stages. Each stage has a handful of enemies to defeat. Defeat all the enemies to advance to the next stage.Duel mode can be played with two players, but it changes the goal entirely. The two players will have to fight each other to see who is crowned best warrior.[CR]Port Differences[CR]The Genesis is considered the most faithful port, visually and gameplay-wise. The DOS port for PCs is based directly on the Genesis port, and is almost as faithful in terms of aesthetics when playing in VGA mode.When the game was ported to the Genesis, Sega added one extra level that takes place right after the players defeat Death Adder. Where the arcade version ends right then and there, in the Genesis version, the large dungeon doors in the background of the level open and the characters walk inside. The final level takes place in this dungeon, after which the players face a new final boss called Death Bringer.As mentioned prior, Duel Mode was a new addition to the Genesis port of the game.In the Genesis port, when enemies are defeated, they flash and disappear as opposed to turning to stone.Some of the more graphics-intensive varieties of spell effects did not make it over to the home ports of the game. For instance, when Ax Battler is carrying his maximum capacity of potions, the spell he unleashes in the arcade version features a mushroom cloud emanating from the floor with huge rocks erupting towards the screen. In the DOS version, this high-level spell merely looks like a series of small eruptions scattered around the screen. The Genesis version aims to replicate the spell more effectively, but the rocks are smaller and they spit out to the side rather than scaling towards the screen.[CR]</plot>
		<releasedate>28/2/2002</releasedate>
		<year>2002</year>
		<genre>Action</genre>
		<studio>Bandai Co.</studio>
		<nplayers>1-2 Alt</nplayers>
		<perspective>3rd-Person</perspective>
		<rating>3.7</rating>
		<thegamesdb_id>27715</thegamesdb_id>
		<mobygames_url>https://www.mobygames.com/game/wonderswan-color/golden-axe</mobygames_url>
		<giantbomb_url>https://www.giantbomb.com/golden-axe/3030-14351/</giantbomb_url>
		<boxart1>lqhRFQb.jpg</boxart1>
		<boxart2>7aROPL9.jpg</boxart2>
		<snapshot1>xXWxwLE.png</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>H4ncAnJ.gif</snapshot2>
		<snapshot3>TddsxHq.gif</snapshot3>
		<snapshot4>KHy1HZ7.gif</snapshot4>
		<snapshot5>I6C2ryK.gif</snapshot5>
		<snapshot6>ZY9A0Td.gif</snapshot6>
		<snapshot7>YzFPWv8.gif</snapshot7>
		<snapshot8>uaBLKYH.gif</snapshot8>
		<snapshot9>cwj9gdI.gif</snapshot9>
		<snapshot10>4KMcyBL.gif</snapshot10>
		<clearlogo1>BEyaCwW.png</clearlogo1>
	</game>
	<game name="Gransta Chronicle (Japan)">
		<description>Gransta Chronicle (Japan)</description>
		<rom crc="AF24F95C" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan%20Color.zip/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan%20Color%2FGransta%20Chronicle%20%28Japan%29.zip" sha1="3A4C5D1C08B74CF05B4CB64CBFD7C3DD8B1C3789" size="3260865" />
		<title_clean>Gransta Chronicle</title_clean>
		<plot>Gransta Chronicle is a Role-Playing game, developed by Tom Create and published by Omega Micott, which was released in Japan in 2002.</plot>
		<releasedate>13/6/2002</releasedate>
		<year>2002</year>
		<genre>RPG</genre>
		<nplayers>1</nplayers>
		<thegamesdb_id>27716</thegamesdb_id>
		<boxart1>lMckGGA.jpg</boxart1>
		<snapshot1>VhF9jgQ.png</snapshot1>
	</game>
	<game name="Guilty Gear Petit (Japan)">
		<description>Guilty Gear Petit (Japan)</description>
		<rom crc="9750BC2A" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan%20Color.zip/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan%20Color%2FGuilty%20Gear%20Petit%20%28Japan%29.zip" sha1="6D8F8FD330F32374B55CF6B998196A7DB2131073" size="682627" />
		<title_clean>Guilty Gear Petit</title_clean>
		<plot>[CR][B]Overview:[/B][CR]Fanny is unique to the two Petit games.Guilty Gear Petit is a game in the Guilty Gear franchise. Guilty Gear Petit is the first handheld game in the franchise. The game was released on January 25, 2001 in Japan for the WonderSwan Color. Guilty Gear Petit was developed by Arc System Works and published by Sammy. Guilty Gear Petit portrays its characters in the super-deformed style, similar to games such as Pocket Fighter and the handheld versions of Samurai Shodown.Fanny is a character exclusive to Guilty Gear Petit and its sequel, Guilty Gear Petit 2. Guilty Gear Petit also has six other playable characters from the Guilty Gear franchise[CR][B]Gameplay:[/B][CR]Guilty Gear Petit is a traditional 2D fighter. The game has seven playable characters (Sol Badguy, Ky Kiske, Millia Rage, May, Potemkin, Fanny, and Jam Kuradoberi). Each character has unique moves, special attacks, and abilities. The gameplay of Guilty Gear Petit is noticeably slower than other traditional 2D fighters (the characters can only attack each other when standing still). The game is played horizontally on the WonderSwan Color (the system has the ability to play games both horizontally and vertically).[CR]</plot>
		<releasedate>25/1/2001</releasedate>
		<year>2001</year>
		<genre>Action</genre>
		<studio>Sammy Corporation</studio>
		<nplayers>1-2 Alt</nplayers>
		<perspective>Platform</perspective>
		<rating>3.3</rating>
		<thegamesdb_id>27717</thegamesdb_id>
		<mobygames_url>https://www.mobygames.com/game/wonderswan-color/guilty-gear-petit</mobygames_url>
		<giantbomb_url>https://www.giantbomb.com/guilty-gear-petit/3030-14686/</giantbomb_url>
		<boxart1>l90Z52t.jpg</boxart1>
		<boxart3>fgG5dDh.jpg</boxart3>
		<snapshot1>ip3qcz7.png</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>fKLPT0D.gif</snapshot2>
		<snapshot3>gYzsMiS.gif</snapshot3>
		<snapshot4>ziDLlSD.gif</snapshot4>
		<snapshot5>vXhY1GI.gif</snapshot5>
		<snapshot6>kU5d3hu.gif</snapshot6>
		<snapshot7>7VLF7om.gif</snapshot7>
		<snapshot8>0lpwYu6.gif</snapshot8>
		<snapshot9>KM3bBUm.gif</snapshot9>
		<snapshot10>oLno3BS.gif</snapshot10>
	</game>
	<game name="Guilty Gear Petit 2 (Japan)">
		<description>Guilty Gear Petit 2 (Japan)</description>
		<rom crc="D7A12BD5" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan%20Color.zip/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan%20Color%2FGuilty%20Gear%20Petit%202%20%28Japan%29.zip" sha1="F7AEAB6724154F7EF6A389F9F18B7100045E1064" size="1501415" />
		<title_clean>Guilty Gear Petit 2</title_clean>
		<plot>In 22th century, scientists found a way to create artificial beings whom they called "gears". These gears were very powerful, but did not have wills of their own, and were completely obedient to the humans. However, a gear named Justice was able to free himself from the control and led a rebellion against the humans. Since then, the humanity lived in fear that the gears will one day gain the power on the Earth. For that purpose, the Sacred Order of the Holy Knights organized fighting tournaments to find out who is strong enough to face the renegade gears.[CR]"Guilty Gear Petit 2" is very similar to its  predecessor, having the same "super-deformed" graphical style, battle moves (including the tension system to accumulate power and combo attacks), as well as backgrounds for battles. Several new characters appear in "Guilty Gear Petit 2", such as Zato-1, the former head of the assassin guild, the pirate captain Johnny, the time traveler Axl Lou from the 20th century, the mysterious Faust, and others.</plot>
		<releasedate>27/9/2001</releasedate>
		<year>2001</year>
		<genre>Action</genre>
		<studio>Sammy Corporation</studio>
		<nplayers>1-2 Alt</nplayers>
		<perspective>Platform</perspective>
		<rating>4.0</rating>
		<thegamesdb_id>19637</thegamesdb_id>
		<mobygames_url>https://www.mobygames.com/game/wonderswan-color/guilty-gear-petit-2</mobygames_url>
		<giantbomb_url>https://www.giantbomb.com/guilty-gear-petit-2/3030-406/</giantbomb_url>
		<boxart1>KJbjelZ.jpg</boxart1>
		<snapshot1>upBvHOl.png</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>0V8GjP5.gif</snapshot2>
		<snapshot3>YtEqg5V.gif</snapshot3>
		<snapshot4>2vfmGGZ.gif</snapshot4>
		<snapshot5>PDvvPyA.gif</snapshot5>
		<snapshot6>H0QqOJJ.gif</snapshot6>
		<snapshot7>wKI2UD6.gif</snapshot7>
		<snapshot8>HhUHdOH.gif</snapshot8>
		<snapshot9>1NgrOHJ.gif</snapshot9>
		<snapshot10>MFgJnHb.gif</snapshot10>
	</game>
	<game name="GunPey EX (Japan)">
		<description>GunPey EX (Japan)</description>
		<rom crc="0C9CB12C" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan%20Color.zip/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan%20Color%2FGunPey%20EX%20%28Japan%29.zip" sha1="1EB729AA9AB0A7DF6F8A3470A6FEDE59D7622D4A" size="385842" />
		<title_clean>GunPey EX</title_clean>
		<plot>Direct sequel to the original Gunpey on the WonderSwan, Gunpey EX adds a number of new elements to the classic; most notably, color.[CR]In addition to earning points for completing a line across the field you will now earn points if those lines are of a matching color. Previously only gray lines were possible now red, blue, and green lines appear.[CR]Gunpey EX has the same modes as the previous game, except a story mode. Time Attack mode where one has to eliminate as many tiles as possible in two of five minutes. Endless mode give the player unlimited time to crank out whatever score they desire. Stage mode presents a set number of tiles to remove in a given time. Puzzle mode puts the player in the situation of having to remove a certain group of tiles, the player can change the color of the lines here when they swap their tiles positions.[CR]A link mode is available to play against another human with a WonderSwan and Gunpey EX. [CR]This game could access the internet through a wireless phone and the WonderGate where it was able to interact with an online high score board.</plot>
		<releasedate>9/12/2000</releasedate>
		<year>2000</year>
		<studio>Bandai Co.</studio>
		<nplayers>1-2 Alt</nplayers>
		<rating>2.8</rating>
		<thegamesdb_id>27718</thegamesdb_id>
		<mobygames_url>https://www.mobygames.com/game/wonderswan-color/gunpey-ex</mobygames_url>
		<giantbomb_url>https://www.giantbomb.com/gunpey/3030-13414/</giantbomb_url>
		<boxart1>M8OIA9w.png</boxart1>
		<snapshot1>8Wa7atQ.png</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>ecfrsgo.png</snapshot2>
		<snapshot3>jB80jvK.png</snapshot3>
		<snapshot4>uwvsRic.png</snapshot4>
		<snapshot5>k5V4asG.png</snapshot5>
		<snapshot6>DTUU56g.png</snapshot6>
		<snapshot7>iAJIkIJ.png</snapshot7>
		<snapshot8>xIeCC9j.png</snapshot8>
		<snapshot9>MQryvy1.png</snapshot9>
		<snapshot10>Lk4VrhI.png</snapshot10>
	</game>
	<game name="Hanjuku Hero - Ah, Sekai yo Hanjuku Nare...!! (Japan)">
		<description>Hanjuku Hero - Ah, Sekai yo Hanjuku Nare...!! (Japan)</description>
		<rom crc="31E09BED" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan%20Color.zip/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan%20Color%2FHanjuku%20Hero%20-%20Ah%2C%20Sekai%20yo%20Hanjuku%20Nare...%21%21%20%28Japan%29.zip" sha1="2E3F221D6965F53B29586D2019EE81DEC6D1AC30" size="988624" />
		<title_clean>Hanjuku Hero - Ah, Sekai yo Hanjuku Nare...!!</title_clean>
		<plot>[CR][B]Overview:[/B][CR]Hanjuku Eiyuu: Aa Sekai Yo Hanjuku Nare ("Soft-Boiled Hero: Let the World Become Soft-Boiled") is the second game in the Hanjuku Eiyuu series (and the first for the Super Famicom) of real-time strategy RPGs set in a comedic fantasy universe. The player must defend their nation from aggressive nearby kingdoms by creating units and sending them out to defeat rival armies. It is also possible to hatch stronger monsters from eggs to assist the player's armies.The series' comedy often hinges on parody humor, and Aa Sekai Yo Nare is no exception: several of the egg monsters that the player hatches are spoofs of Final Fantasy IV characters (from another Square franchise).The game was originally released on the Super Famicom, though an updated WonderSwan Color version would later be released with additional creatures to summon and a graphical overhaul.[CR]</plot>
		<releasedate>19/12/1992</releasedate>
		<year>2002</year>
		<genre>Strategy</genre>
		<studio>Square Co.</studio>
		<nplayers>1</nplayers>
		<perspective>Top-Down</perspective>
		<rating>4.2</rating>
		<thegamesdb_id>27719</thegamesdb_id>
		<mobygames_url>https://www.mobygames.com/game/wonderswan-color/hanjuku-eiy-aa-sekai-yo-hanjuku-nare</mobygames_url>
		<giantbomb_url>https://www.giantbomb.com/hanjuku-eiyuu-aa-sekai-yo-hanjuku-nare/3030-23418/</giantbomb_url>
		<boxart1>KCUWElq.jpg</boxart1>
		<snapshot1>5AlxUrT.png</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>cQAiv1H.gif</snapshot2>
		<snapshot3>Z9EGizw.gif</snapshot3>
		<snapshot4>mh50zBH.gif</snapshot4>
		<snapshot5>0XneYKS.gif</snapshot5>
		<snapshot6>x6Eg2ad.gif</snapshot6>
		<snapshot7>h3Oq0nh.gif</snapshot7>
		<snapshot8>a0bLLt4.gif</snapshot8>
		<snapshot9>hmJsclQ.gif</snapshot9>
		<snapshot10>LiL68ds.gif</snapshot10>
	</game>
	<game name="Hataraku Chocobo (Japan)">
		<description>Hataraku Chocobo (Japan)</description>
		<rom crc="7A29E9A6" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan%20Color.zip/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan%20Color%2FHataraku%20Chocobo%20%28Japan%29.zip" sha1="9BD63ED48926B27BE70333FBE07DA2CEED56328A" size="317974" />
		<title_clean>Hataraku Chocobo</title_clean>
		<plot>A sim featuring Square's mascot released on the WonderSwan Color in Japan only.</plot>
		<releasedate>21/9/2000</releasedate>
		<year>2000</year>
		<genre>Life Simulation</genre>
		<nplayers>1</nplayers>
		<thegamesdb_id>27720</thegamesdb_id>
		<giantbomb_url>https://www.giantbomb.com/hataraku-chocobo/3030-29065/</giantbomb_url>
		<boxart1>Pih97wQ.jpg</boxart1>
		<snapshot1>D3Ti7Lx.png</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>N1OLKXq.png</snapshot2>
		<snapshot3>Z0vCJjc.jpg</snapshot3>
		<snapshot4>IGbrOYq.jpg</snapshot4>
	</game>
	<game name="Hunter X Hunter - Greed Island (Japan)">
		<description>Hunter X Hunter - Greed Island (Japan)</description>
		<rom crc="A487B7A8" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan%20Color.zip/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan%20Color%2FHunter%20X%20Hunter%20-%20Greed%20Island%20%28Japan%29.zip" sha1="F66335B5AF87E7CB72AE311EB9B339534722F738" size="3252877" />
		<title_clean>Hunter X Hunter - Greed Island</title_clean>
		<plot>Hunter X Hunter: Greed Island is a Role-Playing game, developed by Access and published by Bandai, which was released in Japan in 2003.</plot>
		<releasedate>24/4/2003</releasedate>
		<year>2003</year>
		<genre>RPG</genre>
		<nplayers>1</nplayers>
		<videoid>or933kxShq4</videoid>
		<thegamesdb_id>27721</thegamesdb_id>
		<giantbomb_url>https://www.giantbomb.com/hunter-x-hunter-greed-island/3030-48798/</giantbomb_url>
		<boxart1>uIy4cnC.jpg</boxart1>
		<snapshot1>IRWhSif.png</snapshot1>
	</game>
	<game name="Hunter X Hunter - Michibikareshi Mono (Japan)">
		<description>Hunter X Hunter - Michibikareshi Mono (Japan)</description>
		<rom crc="9402BCA9" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan%20Color.zip/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan%20Color%2FHunter%20X%20Hunter%20-%20Michibikareshi%20Mono%20%28Japan%29.zip" sha1="BC591FC24D3F8E94B70503FD8B6A35FA58151139" size="2629481" />
		<title_clean>Hunter X Hunter - Michibikareshi Mono</title_clean>
		<plot>Hunter X Hunter: Michibi Kareshi Mono is a Role-Playing game, developed by Access and published by Bandai, which was released in Japan in 2001.</plot>
		<releasedate>23/8/2001</releasedate>
		<year>2001</year>
		<genre>RPG</genre>
		<nplayers>1</nplayers>
		<thegamesdb_id>27722</thegamesdb_id>
		<giantbomb_url>https://www.giantbomb.com/hunter-x-hunter-michikareshi-mono/3030-37684/</giantbomb_url>
		<boxart1>z7kUhyz.jpg</boxart1>
		<snapshot1>moMnjaa.png</snapshot1>
	</game>
	<game name="Hunter X Hunter - Sorezore no Ketsui (Japan)">
		<description>Hunter X Hunter - Sorezore no Ketsui (Japan)</description>
		<rom crc="D0B20C5A" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan%20Color.zip/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan%20Color%2FHunter%20X%20Hunter%20-%20Sorezore%20no%20Ketsui%20%28Japan%29.zip" sha1="2DA2A9BCFF4813ABCB5B2C88095258D89A575378" size="2465134" />
		<title_clean>Hunter X Hunter - Sorezore no Ketsui</title_clean>
		<plot>Hunter X Hunter: Sorezore no Ketsui is a Role-Playing game, developed by Access and published by Bandai, which was released in Japan in 2001.</plot>
		<releasedate>26/4/2001</releasedate>
		<year>2001</year>
		<genre>RPG</genre>
		<nplayers>1</nplayers>
		<thegamesdb_id>27724</thegamesdb_id>
		<giantbomb_url>https://www.giantbomb.com/hunter-x-hunter-sorezore-no-ketsui/3030-48799/</giantbomb_url>
		<boxart1>YPSgI0q.jpg</boxart1>
		<snapshot1>9DWk9Iu.png</snapshot1>
	</game>
	<game name="Inuyasha - Fuuun Emaki (Japan)">
		<description>Inuyasha - Fuuun Emaki (Japan)</description>
		<rom crc="3FF5791F" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan%20Color.zip/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan%20Color%2FInuyasha%20-%20Fuuun%20Emaki%20%28Japan%29.zip" sha1="99D5BDDE193685A1D09EA73BB79A54B4DA82625D" size="1045259" />
		<title_clean>Inuyasha - Fuuun Emaki</title_clean>
		<plot>Inuyasha: Fuuun Emaki is an Adventure game, developed and published by Bandai, which was released in Japan in 2002.</plot>
		<releasedate>27/7/2002</releasedate>
		<year>2002</year>
		<genre>Adventure</genre>
		<nplayers>1</nplayers>
		<thegamesdb_id>27725</thegamesdb_id>
		<boxart1>ztoc5zB.jpg</boxart1>
		<snapshot1>fvcVxVA.png</snapshot1>
	</game>
	<game name="Inuyasha - Kagome no Sengoku Nikki (Japan)">
		<description>Inuyasha - Kagome no Sengoku Nikki (Japan)</description>
		<rom crc="0C23D551" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan%20Color.zip/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan%20Color%2FInuyasha%20-%20Kagome%20no%20Sengoku%20Nikki%20%28Japan%29.zip" sha1="B4FBEA1A2C50D8566685F72820B360AF4B54F82F" size="1182382" />
		<title_clean>Inuyasha - Kagome no Sengoku Nikki</title_clean>
		<plot>Inuyasha: Kagome no Sengoku Nikki is a Role-Playing game, developed and published by Bandai, which was released in Japan in 2001.</plot>
		<releasedate>2/11/2001</releasedate>
		<year>2001</year>
		<genre>RPG</genre>
		<nplayers>1</nplayers>
		<thegamesdb_id>27726</thegamesdb_id>
		<giantbomb_url>https://www.giantbomb.com/inuyasha-kagome-no-sengoku-nikki/3030-47495/</giantbomb_url>
		<boxart1>s2X46Tm.jpg</boxart1>
		<snapshot1>5UfS1Ti.png</snapshot1>
	</game>
	<game name="Inuyasha - Kagome no Yume Nikki (Japan)">
		<description>Inuyasha - Kagome no Yume Nikki (Japan)</description>
		<rom crc="44453234" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan%20Color.zip/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan%20Color%2FInuyasha%20-%20Kagome%20no%20Yume%20Nikki%20%28Japan%29.zip" sha1="F7C8F8B6B6D036DF8FC4BDE72FCFAC2846DFFE35" size="2683201" />
		<title_clean>Inuyasha - Kagome no Yume Nikki</title_clean>
		<plot>Inuyasha: Kagome no Yume Nikki is a Role-Playing game, developed by Tomcat System and published by Bandai, which was released in Japan in 2002.</plot>
		<releasedate>16/11/2002</releasedate>
		<year>2002</year>
		<genre>RPG</genre>
		<nplayers>1</nplayers>
		<thegamesdb_id>27727</thegamesdb_id>
		<giantbomb_url>https://www.giantbomb.com/inuyasha-kagome-no-yume-nikki/3030-47496/</giantbomb_url>
		<boxart1>rYyAi8s.jpg</boxart1>
		<snapshot1>q7gfdS4.png</snapshot1>
	</game>
	<game name="Judgement Silversword - Rebirth Edition (Japan) (Rev 4321)">
		<description>Judgement Silversword - Rebirth Edition (Japan) (Rev 4321)</description>
		<rom crc="60191872" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan%20Color.zip/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan%20Color%2FJudgement%20Silversword%20-%20Rebirth%20Edition%20%28Japan%29%20%28Rev%204321%29.zip" sha1="657AEA8377E207B9B5A182B13966A27F46633640" size="271916" />
		<title_clean>Judgement Silversword - Rebirth Edition</title_clean>
		<plot>In your space fighter, the S-AIXAK, you'll be going up against the minions of the Judgement Silversword. Starting from a small space station above the earth your lone fighter will travail the bullet filled cosmos, always a shot away from death, to achieve this goal.[CR]Judgement Silversword is a vertically scrolling shooter in which wave upon wave of multifarious of opposing craft will try to take you down with bullets, bombs, lasers, or even their own fuselages. Using the Y-Buttons as a directional pad and the X-Buttons for your weaponry you'll try your hand at completing the S-AIXAKs destiny.[CR]You'll have three weapons at your disposal, spread cannon, concentrated cannon, and your energy shield. The spread cannon will fire an arch of bullet out before you, while a concentrated will fire only directly before you. Your energy shield can be used to absorb incoming shot, however, your back and sides will remain vulnerable. The shield can also be used to damage enemies by ramming them with it. As you use it the shield will run out of energy and need to be recharged. [CR]The game has thirty different areas each comprised of about ten sub areas. Scores are awarded based on kill ratio and completion time. New modes and easter eggs will be unlocked as you obtain higher scores.</plot>
		<releasedate>2/2/2004</releasedate>
		<year>2004</year>
		<genre>Action</genre>
		<studio>Qute</studio>
		<nplayers>1</nplayers>
		<perspective>Top-Down</perspective>
		<rating>5.0</rating>
		<thegamesdb_id>19638</thegamesdb_id>
		<mobygames_url>https://www.mobygames.com/game/wonderswan-color/judgement-silversword-rebirth-edition</mobygames_url>
		<giantbomb_url>https://www.giantbomb.com/judgement-silversword-rebirth-edition/3030-9541/</giantbomb_url>
		<boxart1>OS7Dh2N.jpg</boxart1>
		<boxart2>pCSlFaJ.jpg</boxart2>
		<boxart3>cZQOoFk.jpg</boxart3>
		<snapshot1>6GKDskm.png</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>b1Zv4sW.jpg</snapshot2>
		<snapshot3>CguL9lI.jpg</snapshot3>
		<snapshot4>a6rjoza.jpg</snapshot4>
		<snapshot5>TeuDw91.jpg</snapshot5>
		<snapshot6>khIk4jQ.jpg</snapshot6>
		<snapshot7>hTgwaxa.jpg</snapshot7>
		<snapshot8>JUrKZWY.jpg</snapshot8>
		<snapshot9>FZQ5d4B.jpg</snapshot9>
		<snapshot10>tS1Ovpw.jpg</snapshot10>
	</game>
	<game name="Judgement Silversword - Rebirth Edition (Japan) (Rev SC21)">
		<description>Judgement Silversword - Rebirth Edition (Japan) (Rev SC21)</description>
		<rom crc="4FCE380D" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan%20Color.zip/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan%20Color%2FJudgement%20Silversword%20-%20Rebirth%20Edition%20%28Japan%29%20%28Rev%20SC21%29.zip" sha1="A1D910123B6BE0B941F699EF70C745D16350D029" size="272730" />
		<title_clean>Judgement Silversword - Rebirth Edition</title_clean>
		<plot>In your space fighter, the S-AIXAK, you'll be going up against the minions of the Judgement Silversword. Starting from a small space station above the earth your lone fighter will travail the bullet filled cosmos, always a shot away from death, to achieve this goal.[CR]Judgement Silversword is a vertically scrolling shooter in which wave upon wave of multifarious of opposing craft will try to take you down with bullets, bombs, lasers, or even their own fuselages. Using the Y-Buttons as a directional pad and the X-Buttons for your weaponry you'll try your hand at completing the S-AIXAKs destiny.[CR]You'll have three weapons at your disposal, spread cannon, concentrated cannon, and your energy shield. The spread cannon will fire an arch of bullet out before you, while a concentrated will fire only directly before you. Your energy shield can be used to absorb incoming shot, however, your back and sides will remain vulnerable. The shield can also be used to damage enemies by ramming them with it. As you use it the shield will run out of energy and need to be recharged. [CR]The game has thirty different areas each comprised of about ten sub areas. Scores are awarded based on kill ratio and completion time. New modes and easter eggs will be unlocked as you obtain higher scores.</plot>
		<releasedate>2/2/2004</releasedate>
		<year>2004</year>
		<genre>Action</genre>
		<studio>Qute</studio>
		<nplayers>1</nplayers>
		<perspective>Top-Down</perspective>
		<rating>5.0</rating>
		<thegamesdb_id>19638</thegamesdb_id>
		<mobygames_url>https://www.mobygames.com/game/wonderswan-color/judgement-silversword-rebirth-edition</mobygames_url>
		<giantbomb_url>https://www.giantbomb.com/judgement-silversword-rebirth-edition/3030-9541/</giantbomb_url>
		<boxart1>cza5xfh.jpg</boxart1>
		<boxart2>pCSlFaJ.jpg</boxart2>
		<boxart3>cZQOoFk.jpg</boxart3>
		<snapshot1>6GKDskm.png</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>b1Zv4sW.jpg</snapshot2>
		<snapshot3>CguL9lI.jpg</snapshot3>
		<snapshot4>a6rjoza.jpg</snapshot4>
		<snapshot5>TeuDw91.jpg</snapshot5>
		<snapshot6>khIk4jQ.jpg</snapshot6>
		<snapshot7>hTgwaxa.jpg</snapshot7>
		<snapshot8>JUrKZWY.jpg</snapshot8>
		<snapshot9>FZQ5d4B.jpg</snapshot9>
		<snapshot10>tS1Ovpw.jpg</snapshot10>
	</game>
	<game name="Kidou Senshi Gundam - Giren no Yabou - Tokubetsu Hen - Aoki Hoshi no Hasha (Japan)">
		<description>Kidou Senshi Gundam - Giren no Yabou - Tokubetsu Hen - Aoki Hoshi no Hasha (Japan)</description>
		<rom crc="D4061551" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan%20Color.zip/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan%20Color%2FKidou%20Senshi%20Gundam%20-%20Giren%20no%20Yabou%20-%20Tokubetsu%20Hen%20-%20Aoki%20Hoshi%20no%20Hasha%20%28Japan%29.zip" sha1="20B671BC14A8AB6373DEECC641479D09658AC21F" size="1492462" />
		<title_clean>Kidou Senshi Gundam - Giren no Yabou - Tokubetsu Hen - Aoki Hoshi no Hasha</title_clean>
		<plot>Kidou Senshi Gundam: Giren no Yabou - Tokubetsu-hen Aokisei no Hasha is a Strategy game, developed by Vanguard Works and published by Bandai, which was released in Japan in 2003.</plot>
		<releasedate>2/5/2003</releasedate>
		<year>2003</year>
		<genre>Strategy</genre>
		<nplayers>1</nplayers>
		<thegamesdb_id>27732</thegamesdb_id>
		<giantbomb_url>https://www.giantbomb.com/kidou-senshi-gundam-giren-no-yabou-tokubetsu-hen-a/3030-37683/</giantbomb_url>
		<boxart1>Q9vkaDX.jpg</boxart1>
		<snapshot1>UllEthy.png</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>ApmgvQT.jpg</snapshot2>
		<snapshot3>FvCbK6Y.jpg</snapshot3>
		<snapshot4>i6gGIxI.jpg</snapshot4>
		<snapshot5>JuQgtVF.jpg</snapshot5>
	</game>
	<game name="Kidou Senshi Gundam Seed (Japan)">
		<description>Kidou Senshi Gundam Seed (Japan)</description>
		<rom crc="BCE15137" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan%20Color.zip/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan%20Color%2FKidou%20Senshi%20Gundam%20Seed%20%28Japan%29.zip" sha1="E933FF8EACE56A462019AE4654B0BAB1B21B1D6C" size="1436222" />
		<title_clean>Kidou Senshi Gundam Seed</title_clean>
		<plot>Kidou Senshi Gundam Seed is an Action game, developed and published by Bandai, which was released in Japan in 2003.</plot>
		<releasedate>15/3/2003</releasedate>
		<year>2003</year>
		<genre>Action</genre>
		<nplayers>1</nplayers>
		<thegamesdb_id>27728</thegamesdb_id>
		<giantbomb_url>https://www.giantbomb.com/mobile-suit-gundam-seed/3030-31317/</giantbomb_url>
		<boxart1>s5GCFQZ.jpg</boxart1>
		<snapshot1>B2JlOfn.png</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>KkaaQd4.jpg</snapshot2>
		<snapshot3>8ataJZo.jpg</snapshot3>
		<snapshot4>Rjz4S51.jpg</snapshot4>
	</game>
	<game name="Kidou Senshi Gundam Vol. 1 - Side 7 (Japan)">
		<description>Kidou Senshi Gundam Vol. 1 - Side 7 (Japan)</description>
		<rom crc="08C0247B" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan%20Color.zip/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan%20Color%2FKidou%20Senshi%20Gundam%20Vol.%201%20-%20Side%207%20%28Japan%29.zip" sha1="29E72E7F96F145A0FF56E447F577310DF2EC463B" size="2229486" />
		<title_clean>Kidou Senshi Gundam Vol. 1 - Side 7</title_clean>
		<plot>Kidou Senshi Gundam Vol. 1 SIDE7 is a Strategy game, developed by iNPLAS and published by Bandai, which was released in Japan in 2001.</plot>
		<releasedate>11/8/2001</releasedate>
		<year>2001</year>
		<genre>Strategy</genre>
		<nplayers>1</nplayers>
		<thegamesdb_id>27729</thegamesdb_id>
		<giantbomb_url>https://www.giantbomb.com/mobile-suit-gundam-vol-1-side-7/3030-31306/</giantbomb_url>
		<boxart1>ZgRnJhb.jpg</boxart1>
		<snapshot1>fZrrk8L.png</snapshot1>
	</game>
	<game name="Kidou Senshi Gundam Vol. 2 - Jaburo (Japan)">
		<description>Kidou Senshi Gundam Vol. 2 - Jaburo (Japan)</description>
		<rom crc="39A1391A" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan%20Color.zip/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan%20Color%2FKidou%20Senshi%20Gundam%20Vol.%202%20-%20Jaburo%20%28Japan%29.zip" sha1="DF1A794F7E3992B1E1E9DE14141B607746202202" size="4150077" />
		<title_clean>Kidou Senshi Gundam Vol. 2 - Jaburo</title_clean>
		<plot>Kidou Senshi Gundam Vol. 2 Jaburo is a Strategy game, developed and published by Bandai, which was released in Japan in 2001.</plot>
		<releasedate>16/8/2001</releasedate>
		<year>2001</year>
		<genre>Strategy</genre>
		<nplayers>1</nplayers>
		<thegamesdb_id>27730</thegamesdb_id>
		<giantbomb_url>https://www.giantbomb.com/mobile-suit-gundam-vol-2-jaburo/3030-31307/</giantbomb_url>
		<boxart1>P2c2XCv.jpg</boxart1>
		<snapshot1>KtZmY5S.png</snapshot1>
	</game>
	<game name="Kidou Senshi Gundam Vol. 3 - A Baoa Qu (Japan)">
		<description>Kidou Senshi Gundam Vol. 3 - A Baoa Qu (Japan)</description>
		<rom crc="A9F5BF54" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan%20Color.zip/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan%20Color%2FKidou%20Senshi%20Gundam%20Vol.%203%20-%20A%20Baoa%20Qu%20%28Japan%29.zip" sha1="35443E2EF8A20A0AD82DA1274B2768C16239DD46" size="4206547" />
		<title_clean>Kidou Senshi Gundam Vol. 3 - A Baoa Qu</title_clean>
		<plot>Kidou Senshi Gundam Vol. 3 is a Strategy game, developed and published by Bandai, which was released in Japan in 2002.</plot>
		<releasedate>25/5/2002</releasedate>
		<year>2002</year>
		<genre>Strategy</genre>
		<nplayers>1</nplayers>
		<thegamesdb_id>27731</thegamesdb_id>
		<giantbomb_url>https://www.giantbomb.com/mobile-suit-gundam-vol-3-a-baoa-qu/3030-31308/</giantbomb_url>
		<boxart1>pv9Y4f9.jpg</boxart1>
		<snapshot1>3q93zuF.png</snapshot1>
	</game>
	<game name="Kinnikuman II-Sei - Choujin Seisenshi (Japan)">
		<description>Kinnikuman II-Sei - Choujin Seisenshi (Japan)</description>
		<rom crc="6142FD9D" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan%20Color.zip/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan%20Color%2FKinnikuman%20II-Sei%20-%20Choujin%20Seisenshi%20%28Japan%29.zip" sha1="EFCF8F92357FFC6F6EC0E4AA960CD97A5070836E" size="2027631" />
		<title_clean>Kinnikuman II-Sei - Choujin Seisenshi</title_clean>
		<plot>This game is only released in Japan.[CR]</plot>
		<releasedate>30/1/2003</releasedate>
		<year>2003</year>
		<genre>RPG</genre>
		<studio>Bandai Co.</studio>
		<nplayers>1</nplayers>
		<rating>10</rating>
		<thegamesdb_id>27733</thegamesdb_id>
		<mobygames_url>https://www.mobygames.com/game/wonderswan-color/kinnikuman-nisei-chjin-seisenshi</mobygames_url>
		<giantbomb_url>https://www.giantbomb.com/kinnikuman-nisei-choujin-seisenshi/3030-35065/</giantbomb_url>
		<boxart1>AC6gCr3.jpg</boxart1>
		<boxart2>N2jA95t.jpg</boxart2>
		<boxart3>1UYbsEZ.jpg</boxart3>
		<snapshot1>GHFJrlt.png</snapshot1>
	</game>
	<game name="Kinnikuman II-Sei - Dream Tag Match (Japan)">
		<description>Kinnikuman II-Sei - Dream Tag Match (Japan)</description>
		<rom crc="462F9275" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan%20Color.zip/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan%20Color%2FKinnikuman%20II-Sei%20-%20Dream%20Tag%20Match%20%28Japan%29.zip" sha1="81DD3124CCE8A1AAFD423BFE0814187FB7C646CB" size="691678" />
		<title_clean>Kinnikuman II-Sei - Dream Tag Match</title_clean>
		<plot>[CR][B]Characters:[/B][CR]Kinniku MantaroTerry the KidSeiuchinGazellemanKevin MaskCheckmateScarfaceJadeKinniku SuguruRobin MaskWarsmanBuffalomanBrocken Jr.[CR]</plot>
		<releasedate>2/3/2002</releasedate>
		<year>2002</year>
		<genre>Action, Sports</genre>
		<studio>Bandai Co.</studio>
		<nplayers>1-2 Alt</nplayers>
		<perspective>3rd-Person</perspective>
		<thegamesdb_id>27734</thegamesdb_id>
		<mobygames_url>https://www.mobygames.com/game/wonderswan-color/kinnikuman-nisei-dream-tag-match</mobygames_url>
		<giantbomb_url>https://www.giantbomb.com/kinnikuman-nisei-dream-tag-match/3030-35066/</giantbomb_url>
		<boxart1>KGL4VzH.jpg</boxart1>
		<snapshot1>p5qCXva.png</snapshot1>
	</game>
	<game name="Kurupara! (Japan)">
		<description>Kurupara! (Japan)</description>
		<rom crc="274719F5" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan%20Color.zip/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan%20Color%2FKurupara%21%20%28Japan%29.zip" sha1="9942D1B7D1C00126B9891E560E6A3E264F8FDC2E" size="941572" />
		<title_clean>Kurupara!</title_clean>
		<plot>Kurupara is a Puzzle game, developed and published by Tom Create, which was released in Japan in 2001.[CR]https://www.gamefaqs.com/portable/wscolor/home/581504.html[CR]</plot>
		<releasedate>4/7/2001</releasedate>
		<year>2001</year>
		<genre>Puzzle</genre>
		<studio>Tom Create</studio>
		<nplayers>1-2 Alt</nplayers>
		<thegamesdb_id>27735</thegamesdb_id>
		<boxart1>WNPMYfc.jpg</boxart1>
		<snapshot1>48yiTBd.png</snapshot1>
	</game>
	<game name="Last Alive (Japan)">
		<description>Last Alive (Japan)</description>
		<rom crc="DA4479BF" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan%20Color.zip/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan%20Color%2FLast%20Alive%20%28Japan%29.zip" sha1="B019F41207E396D9FE3509DCCDBE1CC6E7AC46BB" size="3425958" />
		<title_clean>Last Alive</title_clean>
		<plot>Last Alive is an Adventure game, developed and published by Bandai, which was released in Japan in 2001.</plot>
		<releasedate>26/7/2001</releasedate>
		<year>2001</year>
		<genre>Adventure</genre>
		<nplayers>1</nplayers>
		<thegamesdb_id>27736</thegamesdb_id>
		<boxart1>iXHbyyG.jpg</boxart1>
		<snapshot1>aqe3qJE.png</snapshot1>
	</game>
	<game name="Makai Toushi Sa-Ga (Japan)">
		<description>Makai Toushi Sa-Ga (Japan)</description>
		<rom crc="1B6F5F30" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan%20Color.zip/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan%20Color%2FMakai%20Toushi%20Sa-Ga%20%28Japan%29.zip" sha1="6B7A9B810C932974CBDA4DE7178CF0EA5A90E628" size="1516974" />
		<title_clean>Makai Toushi Sa-Ga</title_clean>
		<plot>[CR][B]Overview:[/B][CR]You command a party of four warriors who journey through a variety of different worlds, connected by a central tower, in order to discover the tower's secrets--which, reportedly, lead to paradise. Each of the worlds is terrorized by a Fiend--a monster of great power--and the party is compelled to seek out and defeat these fiends, saving each world's denizens in the process. The final floor of the tower reveals a startling truth about the nature of the Fiends, the tower, and your party's involvement in all of the events that unfold throughout the game.Part of the SaGa series, SaGa--or Final Fantasy Legend, as it was known in North America--started some trends that repeated throughout the franchise. Instead of equipping a single weapon for attacking purposes, as was the case in the core Final Fantasy franchise, SaGa had each character equipping a "bag" of weapons and items, as described below in the Gameplay section. The series' method of character growth through taking actions and eating monster meat, as opposed to gaining experience levels, also originated here. (The "do X more and become better at Y" methodology did find its way into Final Fantasy II.) However, the multi-character, "non-linear" method of progression didn't really begin until the Super Famicom entries in the series, which were the Romancing SaGa games.[CR][B]Gameplay:[/B][CR]Final Fantasy Legend plays in a traditional turn-based queue style made popular by the Dragon Quest and Final Fantasy series. In other words, you select a command for each of your four party members before making a final confirmation, which leads to the beginning of the "round" between player and enemy. One notable difference between Legend's battle system and those of Dragon Quest / Final Fantasy is that each of your characters can equip multiple, distinct weapons, spells and shields -- most of which have limited uses before they break or otherwise expire. For instance, your fighter can carry a Rapier, Long Sword, Battle Axe and Psi Dagger, and is free to use whichever he pleases in a given round of combat. Shields similarly count as "consumable" items (i.e. use a shield for a round, and you're protected; but it'll break after multiple uses) as opposed to other armor (mail, helmets), which act as one might expect (they simply buff your defense stats; they are not "used" in battle).Your human characters must level up with the aid of potions, with one type of potion per main statistic. Furthermore, after you've reached a hit-point maximum of 600, further potions will only increase the maximum by one at a time. Mutant (the "mages" in this game) characters grow based on how you use them, similar to Final Fantasy II's (Famicom, Wonderswan, Playstation, Gameboy Advance) level-up system. If a mutant continues to attack with a Battle Axe or other strength-based weapon, eventually his strength statistics will increase. Attack with an agility-based weapon (whips, rapiers), and his agility will increase. Similarly, use of magic and magic-imbued items will increase a character's Mana. Oddly enough, Final Fantasy Legend never tells you when your statistics have increased naturally.Legend also offers monsters. Monsters don't level up; rather, they grow by eating the meat of stronger monsters left behind after battle. Eat the meat of a weaker monster, and your character will devolve accordingly. This monster class is one of the distinguishing factors of the Legend spin-offs, continuing in Legend II and being expanded upon in Legend III. The general logic of "eat the meat of a better monster to improve" applies, and there is a near-formulaic method of how the game determines which monster you'll end up having. However, to get one of the most powerful monsters, the Hi-Slime, you must be a certain monster and eat the meat of one of the reincarnations of one of the major bosses in the game. After that, you must have the resulting monster consume the meat of a potentially weaker, normal enemy.Players are given a choice of how to form their party at the outset of the game. If s/he so wishes, the party can be made up entirely of humans or monsters. This bucks conventional wisdom, of course, since these parties would be too devoid of magic and too inflexible, respectively.As opposed to characters whom you can revive infinitely, Final Fantasy Legend has characters who have three "lives" represented by hearts on the screen. Extra hearts could be purchased, but they were almost prohibitively expensive. Once a character dies, he loses a heart. After all hearts are lost, your only option is to go and recruit a new character from the guild--whom you'll also have to develop completely from the ground up. This mechanic was immediately removed in the sequel, where characters who were downed in battle would revive immediately afterwards with 1 hit point.[CR][B]Story:[/B][CR]Final Fantasy Legend's backstory is presented in a quick text blurb at the beginning of the game:"It has been said that the tower in the center of the World is connected to Paradise. Dreaming of a life in Paradise, many have challenged the secret of the tower, but no one knows what became of them. Now, there is another who will brave the adventure..."That "another" happens to be your lead character, whom you are prompted to select before starting the game. After choosing your lead, you find him (or her) dumped in front of the town that sits at the base of the tower. This is the appropriately-named "Base Town" where your lead will recruit three party members from Base Town's guild. As you take a tour of Base Town, you come across a top-hatted gentleman who tells you that a being named Gen-Bu has hidden the key to the door in a statue in a nearby town called "Hero."Heading down to the Town of Hero, the party notices the statue mentioned earlier. However, it's missing its shield, its sword, and its armor. Apparently, in order to get the key from Gen-Bu, the party has to restore it to its proper state. The three missing pieces are being held by three kings spread across the land. As you come across the bluntly-titled King Armor, he tells you that a small-town girl from the south whom he is in love with turned down his proposal for marriage. Traveling south, your party finds out that a gang leader has threatened to destroy the girl's village if she doesn't marry him.Such aggression will not stand, man, and the party decides to help out the village and King Armor. You travel to a cave where the bandits and their leader call home, smite the filthy reject, and upon returning to King Armor, he happily rewards your heroes with the first piece of the statue: a suit of armor.After the party travels to King Sword's domain to obtain the next piece for the statue, you discover that this king isn't quite so ready to give up his prized possession just yet. You must defeat him, he says, if you want the sword. The party takes him down with only minimal difficulty. Two down, and one left to go. Off to King Shield, then.King Shield's castle is full of hostile guards who, unwilling to even battle, take it upon themselves to throw the party out of the building as soon as they try to engage in any conversation. Finally reaching the King, you find that he's unwilling to give you his shield...because he's as dead as a doorknob. His Steward, whom you've caught red-handed, sends his minions after your party as he makes his way through a hidden passageway. Dispatching his thugs, you catch up to, corner, and ultimately defeat him.In possession of the three statue items, you return to the Town of Hero and replace the armor, shield and sword. Miraculously, your party is bequeathed the key--a black sphere--that is said to open the door to the tower at Base Town. But as you head back to make use of your new toy, Gen-Bu appears and engages you in battle. The party must withstand this giant turtle's powerful attacks, and it does so, with much difficulty. That arduous task being over with, the party heads back to Base Town to unlock that door.Inside the tower, the party sees a sprawling structure of many flights whose doors open up to different worlds. The first new world is dominated by a vast sea, and features a town with beautiful ports where your party figures that it'll need a boat to get around. Obviously. One of the townsfolk spits some seemingly absurd pointers your way: "I saw an island sailing like a ship." But hey, when you need a ship, you need a ship. The party ventures to an underwater cave and, sure enough, locates a small piece of floating land that seems to bend to the lead character's will, giving you the perfect "ship"--your very own piece of real estate--with which to sail the seas.During your time in town, you learn that you'll need a blue and red orb to pass through to the next level of the tower. The Red Orb is hidden underwater, and after receiving a tip from a nutso old man living in solutide, the party sets off to obtain the Airseed--a magical item that allows its bearer to breathe underwater. Once the party obtains the Airseed and ventures to an underwater town, the heroes learn that they must head to a nearby underwater castle to find the Red Orb. Their journey takes them to a room filled with orbs, and after sifting through them and finally finding the right one, the fearsome Sei-Ryu--a slithery dragon--attacks them. Though this is a more difficult battle than the one against Gen Bu, the party prevails and walks off with the Red Orb.And what of the Blue Orb? The party travels back to the old man on his island, at which point he asks them a riddle--to give him an item that costs the same as the total cost of a list of other items. After completing the arduous task of finding the items in question, doing some basic math, and buying an item that satisfies the riddle, the party is rewarded with the Blue Orb... which merges with the Red orb to form yet another Sphere which unlocks the next door in the tower.The party emerges, after a grueling trek up more tower floors, in a world floating in the clouds. Wandering into a nearby town called "Sky Town" for obvious reasons, you learn of Byak-Ko, the near-tyrannical leader of this world, and of the secret resistance plotting against him. Somehow, your heroes find their way into his employ and are sent by him to find Jeanne, whose background he doesn't divulge. He sends you off in a huff, providing you with a sky glider with which to travel between areas.Touring around a town, you find out why he wants Jeanne. It turns out that when she and her twin sister are united, the next sphere--and your ticket farther up the tower--will reveal itself. The party finds Jeanne being taken alive by some of Byak-Ko's other men. Honorable and just as your party members are, they rush in to defeat the grunts and save Jeanne. She begs you to save her twin sister Mileille, who's trapped in a floating palace.The party makes its way to the floating palace and fights its way to Mileille, who is standing helpless in a corner. She asks where her sister is, but after you divulge that information, Byak-Ko suddenly appears. "I knew you defeated Gen Bu and Sei-Ryu," he says. "I just used you." Now that he knows Jeanne's location, with the help of a treacherous Mileille who served as bait (she doesn't care anything about the resistance, and was apparently tempted by Byak-Ko's promises of power), he throws your heroes in jail.Bars can't hold your heroes, however, and they find their way back to the floating palace, where Byak-Ko is standing over both Mileille and Jeanne. He now has the sphere, or so he thinks, and as such he finds that he doesn't need Mileille anymore. As he's about to strike Mileille down, however, Jeanne takes the blow--despite her sister's previous traitorous ways--and suffers a mortal wound. A tiring battle between your heroes and Byak-Ko ensues. Byak-Ko is surprised at his failure, and as he dies, the sphere disappears as well. As the party wonders what's going on, Mileille begins to cry as her sister's life flickers away, with her tears forming the real sphere. It is time, it seems, to move on.The party fights its way through another few floors of the tower, but instead of being greeted by the ocean or the clouds, your heroes inhale the stinky wiff of a dingy, mundane dystopia. While wandering around, they are randomly assaulted--multiple times--by a fearsome (and apparently persistent) beast known as SuZaku. Attempts to battle SuZaku are all futile, and every encounter ends in the party fleeing to fight another day. Along your travels, you randomly bump into the top-hatted gentleman from Base Town (or perhaps an evil twin), who verifies that nothing works against SuZaku, and that running is the right and only move at this point.Your heroes also spot a damsel in distress, Sayaka, who--upon being rescued--leads you to a town. Once there, they hit--where else?--the pub and immediately get into an argument, but fortunately, it's with Sayaka's brother So-Cho, who stands down when he realizes you helped her. It comes to pass that there's a biker gang in town, and they're all gunning for SuZaku's head. Perhaps an alliance would best serve everybody.But in order to take down SuZaku, they have to take down his force field--which, currently, is an impossibility. The biker gang is working on building a machine--affectionately known as ERASE99--to help out in this regard, though, so the party agrees to retrieve parts scattered across this world to facilitate this task. By the time your party is ready to find the last component--some Plutonium--the heroes encounter a seemingly insurmountable obstacle: radioactive barriers blocking a doorway. So-Cho comes to the rescue, barreling his way through the barriers, but at the cost of his life.After the heroes mourn So-Cho's death (by calling him a fool for being so rash, natch), they take the Plutonium but are assaulted by a War Machine. A tough battle ensues, and when the party emerges victorious, your heroes find themselves back in town where SuZaku has absolutely decimated everything in sight. The party makes its way to the Skyscraper, climbing it in search of SuZaku so that vengeance can be exacted posthaste. After a difficult trek through the Skyscraper and through some subway cars, you come upon SuZaku who--with the aid of Sayaka--is now trapped. The party activates ERASE99, SuZaku's force field is brought down, and a real battle now begins.With his force field neutralized, SuZaku is vulnerable but still difficult to defeat. Eventually the party takes him down, and goes with Sayaka to mourn So-Cho at his freshly planted grave. By chance, Sayaka happens to have "something" and gives it to your heroes- it's the fourth and final sphere, allowing you access to the last areas of the tower and the ultimate enemy, the Arch-Fiend Ashura.On your party's travels up the tower, the heroes come across a few tower-dwellers who seem to be living peacefully. Ashura has made them rich, one says. Another claims that Ashura has made some fellow called "Creator" absolutely powerless. Further up the tower, the party encounters a series of messages stating that Ashura is being controlled by something, with the last piece of the message is illegible. The party will soon find out when it reaches the top and finally faces off against Ashura, the Arch-Fiend to end all Arch-Fiends.Near the summit, the top-hatted gentleman appears again, and warns the group that Ashura is just beyond the passage behind him. When your heroes finally confront him, he attempts to "make a deal" with them: "I'll give each of you a piece of the world. How does that sound?" Not keen on being turned into Ashura's own personal fiends, of course, the group dismisses this "offer" and engages in battle with the Arch-Fiend. Ashura, sporting four arms, sharp talons, a fanged and menacing face in his abdomen and horns sprouting from his head, turns out to be no simpleton, assaulting the team with curse spells and a vicious melee attack that strikes six times. Nevertheless the heroes prevail, as they always do, and push past Ashura's corpse into Paradise.Or so they think. Instead, they are greeted with a trap door that sends the four heroes tumbling down to the base of the tower, back in Base Town. However, it's not all bad news: The friends they've made along the way are standing there, imparting words of thanks and encouragement. As the party wanders around, the top-hatted gentleman appears again, standing in front of a door near the Innkeeper. "There is a road to Paradise," he tempts, "beyond the door."The road happens to be another trek up the same tower you just fell from all the way to the top. Again. As your heroes venture up again, Gen Bu, Sei-Ryu, Byak-Ko and SuZaku rear their ugly heads again as undead fiends, making the journey even more difficult. Fortunately, with the help of new weapons such as the Sun Sword, they fall easily to your heroes.More climbing and the party finally stumbles into what's supposed to be Paradise. A little exploration, and your heroes run into the top-hatted gentleman one last time. He reveals himself to be The Creator. The Creator claims to have created everything to see true courage. This much may have been true, but to your heroes, apparently it served much more to amuse him than to actually feel the fulfilment that seeing unbridled heroism would bring.The Creator and the heroes face off in a final battle, but in the end, the party wins, essentially "destroying God". They take a few steps forward and notice one last door. "Is there another world?" asks one hero. Perhaps, but they all decide that in the end, it's best to just go home--which they do, with much aplomb.End credits.[CR][B]Gameplay:[/B] Oddities[CR]Final Fantasy Legend's player experience is sometimes hampered by odd usability issues and oversights.The game doesn't tell you when your mutant's stats increase after battle. You'll have to continually check your mutants' status screen to see what their ratings are.The game doesn't tell you when your mutants gain or drop abilities. You'll have to keep checking your mutant's ability menu to see if you've gained or dropped abilities. Furthermore it also drops abilities at random, unlike in its sequel where the last ability listed in your mutant's abilities menu is always the one that's dropped.The ability menu doesn't let you sort your characters' abilities. With Humans, this is a non-issue because you can sort their commands using the laborious method of equipping and unequipping things until you have the desired menu order, but for mutants, it can lead to ugly menus with blank spots.During battle, players cannot take a pass in a round to defend or just sit idle. This means that you have to use an item or weapon, even if it happens to only have a single use left. This problem also exists in Final Fantasy Legend II.Human stats can level up to values higher than 99, but the game only displays 99. Furthermore, if you continue to level-up human stats past 255, the stat will actually loop around and lower itself to 1.The game is incredibly unbalanced with progression. Humans gain hit points, strength and agility through power-up items. STRONG and AGILITY potions cost 300 gp throughout the entire game, so it's possible to maximize your stats pretty early in the game with no scaling increase in effort. Furthermore, Mutants can increase their Mana statistic easily by using the ESP ability during battle. The sole purpose of this ability is to increase the chances that the caster's Mana will increase after a battle, so it's entirely possible to hit 99 Mana in the first half of the game.[CR]Selected cross-series / sequel trivia[CR]As you ascend the tower near the end of the game, the music that plays is very similar to the music used later in the Tower of Bab-il (Babel) from Final Fantasy IV (SNES, Playstation, GBA, NDS).Lich, Tiamat and Kraken appear as enemies in this game. In the original Final Fantasy and its remakes (NES, Playstation, GBA, PSP), these three were the elemental fiends of Earth, Wind and Water respectively.Major boss-level enemies in Legend re-appear in Legend II as regular, albeit powerful, enemies: Gen-Bu; Byak-Ko; Sei-Ryu; Su-Zaku.The visual representation of Ashura in Final Fantasy Legend use a sprite that is almost identical (if not entirely so) to the one seen in Final Fantasy Legend II. However, in the sequel, Ashura is one of the earliest boss characters you face in the game.The concept of the four fiends is a theme that appears in other Final Fantasy games, notably the original Final Fantasy and Final Fantasy IV. The four spheres relinquished by the fiends is analogous to the four crystals which the Final Fantasy series at large is known for.The cover art and logo for Final Fantasy Legend are different than most others in the series before the Playstation Era. The font used for the game's marquee is not the embossed gold lettering, but a flat curvy font. In addition, the cover art is a helmet, sword, and treasure chest under a ray of light. For the American covers of Final Fantasy Legend II, Final Fantasy Legend III, The Final Fantasy Adventure, and Final Fantasy IV (at least as it appeared in North America on the Super NES in 1991), the words "Final Fantasy" all used the same gold, embossed font sitting atop a single solid color (blue, purple, green and red, respectively). Furthermore, the sword replacing the letter "T" in "Fantasy" is missing.[CR]</plot>
		<releasedate>30/9/1990</releasedate>
		<year>1990</year>
		<genre>RPG</genre>
		<nplayers>1</nplayers>
		<thegamesdb_id>27738</thegamesdb_id>
		<giantbomb_url>https://www.giantbomb.com/the-final-fantasy-legend/3030-18601/</giantbomb_url>
		<boxart1>4hlOQTs.jpg</boxart1>
		<snapshot1>wCDsB8t.png</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>bxllsJI.jpg</snapshot2>
		<snapshot3>NifbEwe.jpg</snapshot3>
		<snapshot4>UqAX1wA.jpg</snapshot4>
		<snapshot5>JvQbhg6.jpg</snapshot5>
		<snapshot6>lvWIuzp.jpg</snapshot6>
		<snapshot7>7ZpmsRu.jpg</snapshot7>
		<snapshot8>UfAkR04.jpg</snapshot8>
		<snapshot9>E1xf2IQ.jpg</snapshot9>
	</game>
	<game name="Meitantei Conan - Yuugure no Koujo (Japan)">
		<description>Meitantei Conan - Yuugure no Koujo (Japan)</description>
		<rom crc="9F6E3F8D" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan%20Color.zip/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan%20Color%2FMeitantei%20Conan%20-%20Yuugure%20no%20Koujo%20%28Japan%29.zip" sha1="36D8BC2CE7920D940943358D48F056F81055AB34" size="1757457" />
		<title_clean>Meitantei Conan - Yuugure no Koujo</title_clean>
		<plot>Meitantei Conan: Yuugure no Ouju is an Adventure game, developed by Tomcat System and published by Bandai, which was released in Japan in 2001.</plot>
		<releasedate>15/4/2001</releasedate>
		<year>2001</year>
		<genre>Adventure</genre>
		<nplayers>1</nplayers>
		<thegamesdb_id>27739</thegamesdb_id>
		<boxart1>CdaHose.jpg</boxart1>
		<snapshot1>ZJ3MAsm.png</snapshot1>
	</game>
	<game name="Memories Off - Festa (Japan)">
		<description>Memories Off - Festa (Japan)</description>
		<rom crc="8E123373" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan%20Color.zip/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan%20Color%2FMemories%20Off%20-%20Festa%20%28Japan%29.zip" sha1="F47B4AB9197999BBEC351750601BAA20FBBD7177" size="525361" />
		<title_clean>Memories Off - Festa</title_clean>
		<plot>[CR][B]Overview:[/B][CR]Memories Off Festa is an adventure game developed and published by KID Corp. for the WonderSwan Color.[CR]</plot>
		<releasedate>8/3/2001</releasedate>
		<year>2001</year>
		<genre>Adventure</genre>
		<nplayers>1</nplayers>
		<thegamesdb_id>27740</thegamesdb_id>
		<giantbomb_url>https://www.giantbomb.com/memories-off-festa/3030-39239/</giantbomb_url>
		<boxart1>1EsLLKU.jpg</boxart1>
		<snapshot1>ck8cxuL.png</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>Dj9jeO9.png</snapshot2>
		<snapshot3>Blas01X.png</snapshot3>
		<snapshot4>mQKtVVX.png</snapshot4>
	</game>
	<game name="Mikeneko Holmes - Ghost Panic (Japan)">
		<description>Mikeneko Holmes - Ghost Panic (Japan)</description>
		<rom crc="D75EFFC2" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan%20Color.zip/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan%20Color%2FMikeneko%20Holmes%20-%20Ghost%20Panic%20%28Japan%29.zip" sha1="2358701531E8A38419859CD70BF2FBBD967B6745" size="2701491" />
		<title_clean>Mikeneko Holmes - Ghost Panic</title_clean>
		<plot>Mikeneko Holmes: Ghost Panic is an Adventure game, developed by Koto and published by Koubunsha, which was released in Japan in 2001.</plot>
		<releasedate>26/4/2001</releasedate>
		<year>2001</year>
		<genre>Adventure</genre>
		<nplayers>1</nplayers>
		<thegamesdb_id>27741</thegamesdb_id>
		<boxart1>Qqk2DLz.jpg</boxart1>
		<snapshot1>YBfUpa3.png</snapshot1>
	</game>
	<game name="Mr. Driller (Japan)">
		<description>Mr. Driller (Japan)</description>
		<rom crc="5555D95C" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan%20Color.zip/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan%20Color%2FMr.%20Driller%20%28Japan%29.zip" sha1="209232F1E91C05140529D466C0EF6B7AD3386DE1" size="256087" />
		<title_clean>Mr. Driller</title_clean>
		<plot>[CR]Development[CR]Mr. Driller originated from an unofficial project at Namco, worked on by a few staff on the side, to develop a new game in the Dig-Dug series. As such the working title of the game was Dig-Dug 3. The main character of the game is Susumu Hori, son of Taizou Hori from Dig-Dug. Later the project was endorsed by Namco and became official, transforming into Mr. Driller en-route.[CR][B]Gameplay:[/B][CR]The goal of Mr. Driller is to keep drilling down through a set amount of level (often depending on difficulty) of varying lengths. Upon clearing a level, all blocks above you are destroyed and you are given a boost to your air supply. Your Air supply is your life. You run out, you die. While your air supply constantly dwindles as you are progressing to the next stage, finding air tanks will refill portions of your air. Watch out for rock and boxes marked with an &#8220;X&#8221; for they take many drills to destroy (slowing you down) and once they are destroyed they take a portion of your air supply.The controls are rather simple: one button is your drill, while the D-pad or analog stick is your movement. You have the ability to use your drill in all four directions and you have the ability to jump up one block to your left or right, granted that there is space for you.As you drill, you will notice that similar colored blocks will link together. These linked blocks are what you should be aiming for because once you tap one part of it with your drill, all the blocks linked in that chain will disappear. Aiming for these while drilling down will clear out a path much faster than just going straight down. Pay attention though, blocks that are not linked and have no support under them will fall down, often on your Mr. Driller. Its not the scariest thing in the world, for blocks will link even if they are falling, providing some intense moments where you think your end has come only for the block to link at the last moment.[CR][B]Tips:[/B][CR]Don't forget to move left and right! Having the ability to move left and right will save you from falling objects while also giving you access to more linked blocksAir supplies count as blocks! When you get an Air Supply and there is a block (or many blocks) above it, it will fall. So grab them quick and get back to drilling!Take your time! If you are just starting with Mr. Driller, take the time to learn how fast he jumps up blocks and moves left to right. This will prevent you from trying to drill out of the way of falling blocks rather than just moving out of the way.Boxes and rocks marked with an X don't link! If you see these falling, avoid them at all costs. Its also good to give some space before you start drilling right under one. [Actually this tip is incorrect, X-blocks do link like any other block, and it is how you're supposed to get rid of them when they are surrounding an air capsule.][CR]iPhone version[CR]Mr. Driller for iPhone seems to be an updated version of the original Mr. Driller, the main difference being that Susumu's in-game sprites have been redrawn to resemble the current artwork.The app is only 1.99 US and, like any iPhone app, is compatible with the iPad.[CR]</plot>
		<releasedate>5/4/2001</releasedate>
		<year>2001</year>
		<genre>Simulation, Strategy</genre>
		<studio>Namco Limited</studio>
		<nplayers>1</nplayers>
		<perspective>Platform</perspective>
		<rating>4.4</rating>
		<thegamesdb_id>19798</thegamesdb_id>
		<mobygames_url>https://www.mobygames.com/game/wonderswan-color/mr-driller</mobygames_url>
		<giantbomb_url>https://www.giantbomb.com/mr-driller/3030-8221/</giantbomb_url>
		<boxart1>BOLnIzD.jpg</boxart1>
		<boxart2>hikesJB.jpg</boxart2>
		<boxart3>QVWNyUn.jpg</boxart3>
		<snapshot1>qLdMFEi.png</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>OrqxUtp.gif</snapshot2>
		<snapshot3>aIMRXDi.png</snapshot3>
		<snapshot4>up7d9rj.png</snapshot4>
		<snapshot5>RwB4bgA.png</snapshot5>
		<snapshot6>8Yy6z0B.png</snapshot6>
		<snapshot7>NdmUUg9.png</snapshot7>
		<snapshot8>c9L3Fru.png</snapshot8>
		<snapshot9>aiIwHQU.png</snapshot9>
		<snapshot10>5ypLFrP.png</snapshot10>
		<clearlogo1>fOi6Nhu.png</clearlogo1>
	</game>
	<game name="Namco Super Wars (Japan)">
		<description>Namco Super Wars (Japan)</description>
		<rom crc="8CE4652F" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan%20Color.zip/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan%20Color%2FNamco%20Super%20Wars%20%28Japan%29.zip" sha1="C48569FD0A46AB7B7CEAFEB5698BE90420CD4FBE" size="1253014" />
		<title_clean>Namco Super Wars</title_clean>
		<plot>Namco Super Wars is a tactical role-playing game developed by Namco and published by Bandai for the Wonderswan Color. It is a crossover game, featuring characters from several classic Namco titles.[CR]The game is played on a square grid, on which both the player's and computer's units are placed. Each side takes turns moving and making actions with their units. Every character has a variety of attacks and special moves that can be selected when performing an action. Some of these consume Spirit Points, which slowly regenerate each turn. The game is divided into stages. Between each stage, the player is able to visit a shop and prepare his units before starting the next stage. Unlike most RPGs, characters do not gain levels for directly defeating opponents. Instead, completion of a map will reward the players with a number of level ups, which they can then distribute among their units as they wish.</plot>
		<releasedate>31/10/2002</releasedate>
		<year>2002</year>
		<genre>Strategy</genre>
		<nplayers>1</nplayers>
		<thegamesdb_id>27742</thegamesdb_id>
		<giantbomb_url>https://www.giantbomb.com/namco-super-wars/3030-42463/</giantbomb_url>
		<boxart1>202UKe5.jpg</boxart1>
		<snapshot1>8J00jNO.png</snapshot1>
	</game>
	<game name="Naruto - Konoha Ninpouchou (Japan)">
		<description>Naruto - Konoha Ninpouchou (Japan)</description>
		<rom crc="71556E6A" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan%20Color.zip/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan%20Color%2FNaruto%20-%20Konoha%20Ninpouchou%20%28Japan%29.zip" sha1="DBAA50FD56E69E72FDFE49362EF5FE4437D66667" size="2130899" />
		<title_clean>Naruto - Konoha Ninpouchou</title_clean>
		<plot>Naruto: Konoha Ninpouchou is a Role-Playing game, developed by Bec and published by Bandai, which was released in Japan in 2003.</plot>
		<releasedate>27/3/2003</releasedate>
		<year>2003</year>
		<genre>RPG</genre>
		<nplayers>1</nplayers>
		<thegamesdb_id>27743</thegamesdb_id>
		<giantbomb_url>https://www.giantbomb.com/naruto-konoha-ninpo-chou/3030-43662/</giantbomb_url>
		<boxart1>hkp7lmE.jpg</boxart1>
		<snapshot1>mCKNov2.png</snapshot1>
	</game>
	<game name="Pocket no Naka no Doraemon (Japan)">
		<description>Pocket no Naka no Doraemon (Japan)</description>
		<rom crc="2B61BB2B" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan%20Color.zip/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan%20Color%2FPocket%20no%20Naka%20no%20Doraemon%20%28Japan%29.zip" sha1="57338999B949589C36CE116A30F433E9618685E4" size="2412528" />
		<title_clean>Pocket no Naka no Doraemon</title_clean>
		<plot>Pocket no Naka no Doraemon is a Strategy game, developed and published by Bandai, which was released in Japan in 2001.</plot>
		<releasedate>24/5/2001</releasedate>
		<year>2001</year>
		<genre>Strategy</genre>
		<nplayers>1</nplayers>
		<thegamesdb_id>27744</thegamesdb_id>
		<giantbomb_url>https://www.giantbomb.com/pocket-no-chuu-no-doraemon/3030-33916/</giantbomb_url>
		<boxart1>5oZA1cH.jpg</boxart1>
		<snapshot1>kVRuIHJ.png</snapshot1>
	</game>
	<game name="Raku Jongg (Japan)">
		<description>Raku Jongg (Japan)</description>
		<rom crc="FE4FF701" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan%20Color.zip/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan%20Color%2FRaku%20Jongg%20%28Japan%29.zip" sha1="977D5830E45C78B9020E9D06A63A9AD6BC623745" size="429949" />
		<title_clean>Raku Jongg</title_clean>
		<plot>Raku Jongg is a Miscellaneous game, developed by Enterbrain and published by Bandai, which was released in Japan in 2001.</plot>
		<releasedate>31/5/2001</releasedate>
		<year>2001</year>
		<genre>Strategy</genre>
		<studio>Bandai Co.</studio>
		<nplayers>1</nplayers>
		<thegamesdb_id>27745</thegamesdb_id>
		<mobygames_url>https://www.mobygames.com/game/wonderswan-color/raku-jongg</mobygames_url>
		<boxart1>51yzXDH.jpg</boxart1>
		<snapshot1>MmPScXB.png</snapshot1>
	</game>
	<game name="Rhyme Rider Kerorican (Japan)">
		<description>Rhyme Rider Kerorican (Japan)</description>
		<rom crc="60706555" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan%20Color.zip/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan%20Color%2FRhyme%20Rider%20Kerorican%20%28Japan%29.zip" sha1="5973306A864C3804EE10B209E45067807D39A4DE" size="2157048" />
		<title_clean>Rhyme Rider Kerorican</title_clean>
		<plot>[CR][B]Overview:[/B][CR]KeroricanRhyme Rider Kerorican is a rhythm game designed by the famed Masaya Matsuura (founder of NanaOn-Sha and credited with the creation of the music game genre). Rhyme Rider Kerorican is very similar to another one of Masaya Matsuura's games, Vib Ribbon. Rhyme Rider Kerorican was released for the WonderSwan Color on December 9, 2000 (only in Japan) and was published by Bandai. Rhyme Rider Kerorican was criticized for its very difficult gameplay, including its difficulty of timing and hard button combinations (in addition, if the player makes one error, it is instant death for Kerorican). Despite this, there is a "one-button" easy mode, in which there are no difficult button combinations.[CR][B]Gameplay:[/B][CR]Kerorican flies over several obstacles.The game stars Kerorican, the titular female astronaut of the game. She walks along to techno music. The player must guide her as she encounters enemies and obstacles (jumping, kicking, or dodging these to the music). As she does so, more notes are added to the song. The more obstacles that Kerorican clears, the higher her combo meter goes. If this combo meter goes high enough, she can skip over certain obstacles (by flying over them). This happens more when there are harder button combos. The game is four levels long, for which it was criticized.[CR]</plot>
		<releasedate>9/12/2000</releasedate>
		<year>2000</year>
		<genre>Action</genre>
		<studio>Bandai Co.</studio>
		<nplayers>1</nplayers>
		<perspective>3rd-Person</perspective>
		<rating>3.0</rating>
		<thegamesdb_id>27747</thegamesdb_id>
		<mobygames_url>https://www.mobygames.com/game/wonderswan-color/rhyme-rider-kerorican</mobygames_url>
		<giantbomb_url>https://www.giantbomb.com/rhyme-rider-kerorican/3030-18629/</giantbomb_url>
		<boxart1>kvfpucQ.jpg</boxart1>
		<boxart2>1AcUZN7.jpg</boxart2>
		<boxart3>Uwz25lo.jpg</boxart3>
		<snapshot1>JyslRbD.png</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>ENqkkVW.png</snapshot2>
		<snapshot3>VoMcLDC.png</snapshot3>
		<snapshot4>ixz4nj7.png</snapshot4>
		<snapshot5>WxRx1XX.png</snapshot5>
		<snapshot6>Pho9mzX.png</snapshot6>
		<snapshot7>zKT8Vfy.png</snapshot7>
		<snapshot8>m3OppoA.png</snapshot8>
		<snapshot9>jOySUtE.png</snapshot9>
		<snapshot10>53rw4Yk.png</snapshot10>
	</game>
	<game name="Riviera - Yakusoku no Chi Riviera (Japan)">
		<description>Riviera - Yakusoku no Chi Riviera (Japan)</description>
		<rom crc="2460B45A" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan%20Color.zip/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan%20Color%2FRiviera%20-%20Yakusoku%20no%20Chi%20Riviera%20%28Japan%29.zip" sha1="A8F8D3EFC9B2D5741081E05F517D746EE5437F87" size="4393716" />
		<title_clean>Riviera - Yakusoku no Chi Riviera</title_clean>
		<plot>Riviera: Yakusoku no Chi Riviera is a Role-Playing game, developed by Sting and published by Bandai, which was released in Japan in 2002.</plot>
		<releasedate>12/7/2002</releasedate>
		<year>2002</year>
		<genre>RPG</genre>
		<nplayers>1</nplayers>
		<thegamesdb_id>27748</thegamesdb_id>
		<boxart1>HF0Qwbr.jpg</boxart1>
		<snapshot1>kS0LNwa.png</snapshot1>
	</game>
	<game name="Rockman EXE - N1 Battle (Japan)">
		<description>Rockman EXE - N1 Battle (Japan)</description>
		<rom crc="1F10CA75" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan%20Color.zip/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan%20Color%2FRockman%20EXE%20-%20N1%20Battle%20%28Japan%29.zip" sha1="9B4786ADCA7B83FE66A9D4B9FD4FFAF32ABE7656" size="2973711" />
		<title_clean>Rockman EXE - N1 Battle</title_clean>
		<plot>RockMan EXE N1 Battle is a Role-Playing game, developed by Inti Creates and published by Capcom, which was released in Japan in 2003.</plot>
		<releasedate>8/8/2003</releasedate>
		<year>2003</year>
		<genre>RPG</genre>
		<nplayers>1</nplayers>
		<thegamesdb_id>27749</thegamesdb_id>
		<giantbomb_url>https://www.giantbomb.com/rockman-exe-ws/3030-24887/</giantbomb_url>
		<boxart1>IsZ36Uk.jpg</boxart1>
		<snapshot1>5uPoCwX.png</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>ckpPl3F.png</snapshot2>
	</game>
	<game name="Rockman EXE WS (Japan)">
		<description>Rockman EXE WS (Japan)</description>
		<rom crc="658C4B98" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan%20Color.zip/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan%20Color%2FRockman%20EXE%20WS%20%28Japan%29.zip" sha1="B4A3FF3B72639F27D1A6F449B0335074AEB9E603" size="956726" />
		<title_clean>Rockman EXE WS</title_clean>
		<plot>RockMan EXE WS is an Action game, developed by Capcom and published by Bandai, which was released in Japan in 2003.[CR]Like Mega Man Network Transmission, Rockman EXE WS is a side-scrolling, platform-based video game. The gameplay mainly consisted of shooting enemies and jumping through obstacles and platforms.[CR]As the game begin, players are given mission briefing through cutscenes. In the cutscenes there will be conversations between MegaMan and other character, which will explain players about the background of the mission.[CR]After the briefing, players are brought to a screen that shows a list of chips[jargon] the players have gained while playing and four boxes. By selecting a chip from the list, players choose which of the four boxes the chip will go into.[CR]Once chips are selected and the stage begins, players may use the chips by pressing the Y buttons on the console. Unlike the Mega Man Battle Network games, some chips can be used multiple times, or replace the Mega Buster attack (such as Wide Sword. Chips can be found lying in stage or by defeating enemies.[CR]As players battle through the level, the stage splits into two paths. Both paths lead to a different boss, which will be fought depending on player's completion percentage.</plot>
		<releasedate>8/2/2003</releasedate>
		<year>2003</year>
		<genre>Platform</genre>
		<nplayers>1</nplayers>
		<thegamesdb_id>19640</thegamesdb_id>
		<giantbomb_url>https://www.giantbomb.com/rockman-exe-ws/3030-24887/</giantbomb_url>
		<boxart1>0MI4KIR.jpg</boxart1>
		<snapshot1>tJtb4fU.png</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>ckpPl3F.png</snapshot2>
	</game>
	<game name="Romancing Sa-Ga (Japan)">
		<description>Romancing Sa-Ga (Japan)</description>
		<rom crc="9C98D97D" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan%20Color.zip/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan%20Color%2FRomancing%20Sa-Ga%20%28Japan%29.zip" sha1="06FCC9AAD3AE478DB6EED27621AF4F56A6488A67" size="992514" />
		<title_clean>Romancing Sa-Ga</title_clean>
		<plot>[CR][B]Overview:[/B][CR]Romancing SaGa is a turn-based RPG and one of the many to be produced by Squaresoft for Nintendo platforms. Directed by Akitoshi Kawazu, who also created 1988's Final Fantasy II for the Famicom, the SaGa series was conceived as an off-beat sister series to Squaresoft's core Final Fantasy franchise. The first three SaGa games were released for the Game Boy platform (known as Final Fantasy Legend overseas) before the introduction of the Super Famicom Romancing SaGa series, which also had three entries starting with this one.Romancing SaGa, and the SaGa games to follow, would be best known for presenting multiple scenarios with distinct protagonists that the player can progress through in any order they wish.The game was eventually released for three platforms: the Super Famicom, the Wonderswan, and the Playstation 2. The Super Famicom 1992 release was the original version. The Wonderswan version is just a port of the SFC version, only with minor additions like a new boss battle against Barbara. Both of these versions were not released outside Japan. The Playstation 2 version, however, was not only released in other regions, but is essentially a different game. In fact, the game was released as Romancing SaGa: Minstrel Song in Japan, the subtitle being dropped in other regions. Although it follows the same plot as its predecessors, Minstrel Song features new quests, abilities, characters, and vastly different gameplay mechanics.[CR][B]Story:[/B][CR]Some time before the beginning of the game, three dark gods (Death, Barbara and Saruin) wage a war against the high god Arol. They were unsuccessful, and all but Saruin were beaten. Instead, Arol locked him away with 10 gemstones, which are then scattered across the Earth. By the beginning of the game, however, the world becomes populated with monsters, and Saruin threatens to return.This is essentially the only common story element that links the different characters of the game. Instead of one storyline, Romancing SaGa consists of eight separate characters, each with different introductions and stories before they all come together to tackle the same quests.[CR][B]Gameplay:[/B][CR]NavigationInstead of being given a large overworld to explore, Romancing SaGa presents the player with an unexplorable world map with selectable locations they can explore. New locations are unlocked by talking to certain people, exploring other areas, or engaging in certain quests. Getting between other segments of the world map usually requires either passing through an area linking the two segments, or riding a boat between certain towns.BattleRomancing SaGa, much like other JRPGs of the time, employs a  traditional turn-based system of combat. However, unlike other RPGs, battles are not triggered through random encounters, but by approaching them on the map. The difficulty of the battle depends on the direction in which the player approaches them; it is better to sneak up from the sides or back than to engage in a direct attack. The same holds true for the enemies, who can change the player's in-battle formation by approaching their party from the sides or back.Formation plays an important role in battle, as it decides which characters can use which abilities. Bows, magic and certain abilities can be used from any position; spears can be used in the middle and front positions; and all other weapons and abilities can only be used from the front. Similarly, certain abilities can only hit certain rows of enemies. When all the characters in one row die, the next row moves up. The battle ends when all the combatants on one side die.Unlike many other RPGs, battles do not end with players gaining experience toward level ups. Instead, each statistic levels up according to how that character fought. For example, heavy use of the bow will cause that character's bow proficiency to level up. Characters learn new abilities (and are able to use abilities more often) by leveling up the corresponding weapon. Magic is bought from certain shops in certain towns, but there are certain magic types that cannot coexist within the same character (ex: fire and water). Both spells and abilities draw from collective pools of points necessary to use the move, but only magic shows these points. However, unlike later games in the series, weapon levels are not tied to the characters, but to the weapons themselves, meaning that upgrading equipment results in the loss of all abilities tied to that specific weapon.To use items in battle, each character must equip them individually. In addition to usual potions and MP restoring items (which, oddly enough, come specific to each type of magic), Romancing SaGa is the only SaGa game to feature summons, gained through a certain quest. Rather than behaving like an attack, the summons behave more like special characters, taking the place of the entire party for a given number of turns.Other gameplay mechanicsThe maximum amount of gold the player's party can carry at any given time is 9999 gold. However, upon selling an item that results in a gold count higher than 10000, the game gives them a jewel, equal to 10000 gold. Since the player stops gaining gold when they hit 9999, it is imperative to sell an item as soon as they hit this cap. This quirk only applies to the SFC and Wonderswan versions; jewels are not present in the PS2 remake.[CR]</plot>
		<releasedate>28/1/1992</releasedate>
		<year>2001</year>
		<genre>RPG</genre>
		<studio>Square Co.</studio>
		<nplayers>1</nplayers>
		<perspective>Top-Down</perspective>
		<rating>3.4</rating>
		<thegamesdb_id>27750</thegamesdb_id>
		<mobygames_url>https://www.mobygames.com/game/wonderswan-color/romancing-saga</mobygames_url>
		<giantbomb_url>https://www.giantbomb.com/romancing-saga/3030-1368/</giantbomb_url>
		<boxart1>8d6hYlJ.jpg</boxart1>
		<snapshot1>aTnm47b.png</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>Ff7iX8x.gif</snapshot2>
		<snapshot3>mAzI0B9.gif</snapshot3>
		<snapshot4>wDh1Gmj.gif</snapshot4>
		<snapshot5>KWpKk5V.gif</snapshot5>
		<snapshot6>4NSeiTP.gif</snapshot6>
		<snapshot7>OhUZo2i.gif</snapshot7>
		<snapshot8>fq7Lhsw.gif</snapshot8>
		<snapshot9>7WO1uHv.gif</snapshot9>
		<snapshot10>iDsSHX1.gif</snapshot10>
	</game>
	<game name="RUN=DIM - Return to Earth (Japan)">
		<description>RUN=DIM - Return to Earth (Japan)</description>
		<rom crc="15C4552E" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan%20Color.zip/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan%20Color%2FRUN%3DDIM%20-%20Return%20to%20Earth%20%28Japan%29.zip" sha1="3A41A3B8FC126DA07E2A82C21056A45C15EFBC98" size="1389856" />
		<title_clean>RUN=DIM - Return to Earth</title_clean>
		<plot>Run=Dim is a Role-Playing game, developed and published by Digital Dream, which was released in Japan in 2002.[CR]https://www.gamefaqs.com/portable/wscolor/home/566641.html[CR]</plot>
		<releasedate>4/7/2002</releasedate>
		<year>2002</year>
		<genre>RPG</genre>
		<studio>Digital Dream</studio>
		<nplayers>1</nplayers>
		<thegamesdb_id>19641</thegamesdb_id>
		<boxart1>iCHqZUM.jpg</boxart1>
		<snapshot1>mmhonRG.png</snapshot1>
	</game>
	<game name="Saint Seiya - Ougon Densetsu Hen - Perfect Edition (Japan)">
		<description>Saint Seiya - Ougon Densetsu Hen - Perfect Edition (Japan)</description>
		<rom crc="6E8A792D" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan%20Color.zip/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan%20Color%2FSaint%20Seiya%20-%20Ougon%20Densetsu%20Hen%20-%20Perfect%20Edition%20%28Japan%29.zip" sha1="8542649963EFE0976015759382C180B7C056BE9A" size="670159" />
		<title_clean>Saint Seiya - Ougon Densetsu Hen - Perfect Edition</title_clean>
		<plot>Saint Seiya: Ougon Densetsuhen Perfect Edition is a Role-Playing game, developed by TOSE and published by Bandai, which was released in Japan in 2003.</plot>
		<releasedate>31/7/2003</releasedate>
		<year>2003</year>
		<genre>RPG</genre>
		<nplayers>1</nplayers>
		<thegamesdb_id>27751</thegamesdb_id>
		<giantbomb_url>https://www.giantbomb.com/saint-seiya-ougon-densetsu-hen-perfect-edition/3030-42980/</giantbomb_url>
		<boxart1>k16Hchb.jpg</boxart1>
		<snapshot1>i2RqJAK.png</snapshot1>
	</game>
	<game name="SD Gundam - Operation U.C. (Japan)">
		<description>SD Gundam - Operation U.C. (Japan)</description>
		<rom crc="F0ACDA5C" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan%20Color.zip/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan%20Color%2FSD%20Gundam%20-%20Operation%20U.C.%20%28Japan%29.zip" sha1="152C4D63B1B17F2C717A43EFC75D718B614F9DDC" size="703936" />
		<title_clean>SD Gundam - Operation U.C.</title_clean>
		<plot>SD Gundam: Operation U.C. is an Action game, developed and published by Bandai, which was released in Japan in 2002.</plot>
		<releasedate>16/2/2002</releasedate>
		<year>2002</year>
		<genre>Shooter</genre>
		<nplayers>1</nplayers>
		<thegamesdb_id>27754</thegamesdb_id>
		<giantbomb_url>https://www.giantbomb.com/sd-gundam-operation-uc/3030-31326/</giantbomb_url>
		<boxart1>Br0IxSA.jpg</boxart1>
		<snapshot1>DjglyYV.png</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>bONNkJz.jpg</snapshot2>
		<snapshot3>Lbv2I6d.jpg</snapshot3>
		<snapshot4>003rWty.jpg</snapshot4>
		<snapshot5>EhYtCif.jpg</snapshot5>
	</game>
	<game name="SD Gundam Eiyuu Den - Kishi Densetsu (Japan)">
		<description>SD Gundam Eiyuu Den - Kishi Densetsu (Japan)</description>
		<rom crc="C60E5162" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan%20Color.zip/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan%20Color%2FSD%20Gundam%20Eiyuu%20Den%20-%20Kishi%20Densetsu%20%28Japan%29.zip" sha1="EBD4B37ADE6DF717F7B637747A4D3C45A6CCA037" size="1980975" />
		<title_clean>SD Gundam Eiyuu Den - Kishi Densetsu</title_clean>
		<plot>SD Gundam Eiyuuden: Kishi Densetsu is a Role-playing game, developed and published by Bandai, which was released in Japan in 2001.</plot>
		<releasedate>2/5/2003</releasedate>
		<year>2003</year>
		<genre>RPG</genre>
		<nplayers>1</nplayers>
		<thegamesdb_id>27752</thegamesdb_id>
		<giantbomb_url>https://www.giantbomb.com/kidou-senshi-gundam-giren-no-yabou-tokubetsu-hen-a/3030-37683/</giantbomb_url>
		<boxart1>Oa54sc9.jpg</boxart1>
		<snapshot1>rBfLfC0.png</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>ApmgvQT.jpg</snapshot2>
		<snapshot3>FvCbK6Y.jpg</snapshot3>
		<snapshot4>i6gGIxI.jpg</snapshot4>
		<snapshot5>JuQgtVF.jpg</snapshot5>
	</game>
	<game name="SD Gundam Eiyuu Den - Musha Densetsu (Japan)">
		<description>SD Gundam Eiyuu Den - Musha Densetsu (Japan)</description>
		<rom crc="18ECFFB8" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan%20Color.zip/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan%20Color%2FSD%20Gundam%20Eiyuu%20Den%20-%20Musha%20Densetsu%20%28Japan%29.zip" sha1="D8097E25431F0AD5183B2479EE0837599677A300" size="1940091" />
		<title_clean>SD Gundam Eiyuu Den - Musha Densetsu</title_clean>
		<plot>SD Gundam Eiyuuden: Musha Densetsu is a Role-Playing game, developed by Bec and published by Bandai, which was released in Japan in 2001.</plot>
		<releasedate>15/3/2001</releasedate>
		<year>2001</year>
		<genre>RPG</genre>
		<nplayers>1</nplayers>
		<thegamesdb_id>27753</thegamesdb_id>
		<boxart1>BL6ItWy.jpg</boxart1>
		<snapshot1>2Lr9k6b.png</snapshot1>
	</game>
	<game name="SD Gundam G Generation - Gather Beat 2 (Japan)">
		<description>SD Gundam G Generation - Gather Beat 2 (Japan)</description>
		<rom crc="4D21A347" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan%20Color.zip/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan%20Color%2FSD%20Gundam%20G%20Generation%20-%20Gather%20Beat%202%20%28Japan%29.zip" sha1="016FF46509CBFE57A7440A1755D3A41EF49C048F" size="3486721" />
		<title_clean>SD Gundam G Generation - Gather Beat 2</title_clean>
		<plot>SD Gundam G Generation: Gather Beat 2 is a Strategy game, developed by Vanguard Works and published by Bandai, which was released in Japan in 2001.</plot>
		<releasedate>14/6/2001</releasedate>
		<year>2001</year>
		<genre>Strategy</genre>
		<nplayers>1</nplayers>
		<thegamesdb_id>27755</thegamesdb_id>
		<boxart1>SsQkz2f.jpg</boxart1>
		<snapshot1>fNymE9B.png</snapshot1>
	</game>
	<game name="SD Gundam G Generation - Mono-Eye Gundams (Japan)">
		<description>SD Gundam G Generation - Mono-Eye Gundams (Japan)</description>
		<rom crc="6ACA1F04" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan%20Color.zip/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan%20Color%2FSD%20Gundam%20G%20Generation%20-%20Mono-Eye%20Gundams%20%28Japan%29.zip" sha1="91E087056207FCE21E782E25E383C203BC046897" size="3903133" />
		<title_clean>SD Gundam G Generation - Mono-Eye Gundams</title_clean>
		<plot>[CR]Featured Series[CR]List of Gundam series featured in the game:Mobile Suit GundamMobile Suit VariationsMobile Suit Gundam: The 08th MS TeamMobile Suit Gundam Side Story: The Blue DestinyMobile Suit Gundam 0080: War in the PocketMobile Suit Gundam 0083: Stardust MemoryMobile Suit Zeta GundamGundam SentinelMobile Suit Gundam ZZMobile Suit Gundam: Char's CounterattackMobile Suit Crossbone GundamMobile Suit Victory GundamMobile Fighter G GundamNew Mobile Report Gundam Wing: Endless WaltzAfter War Gundam XTurn A GundamMonoeye Gundams (original storyline)A prototype version of the Strike Gundam (from Mobile Suit Gundam SEED) is included.[CR]</plot>
		<releasedate>26/9/2002</releasedate>
		<year>2002</year>
		<genre>Strategy</genre>
		<nplayers>1</nplayers>
		<thegamesdb_id>27756</thegamesdb_id>
		<giantbomb_url>https://www.giantbomb.com/sd-gundam-g-generation-monoeye-gundams/3030-23735/</giantbomb_url>
		<boxart1>tk5pFvE.jpg</boxart1>
		<snapshot1>GoY3KI6.png</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>Cp77crJ.jpg</snapshot2>
		<snapshot3>NAnuI9O.jpg</snapshot3>
		<snapshot4>4LcwNQM.jpg</snapshot4>
		<snapshot5>PSomgIw.jpg</snapshot5>
	</game>
	<game name="Senkaiden Ni - TV Animation Senkaiden Houshin Engi Yori (Japan)">
		<description>Senkaiden Ni - TV Animation Senkaiden Houshin Engi Yori (Japan)</description>
		<rom crc="9F35D00F" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan%20Color.zip/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan%20Color%2FSenkaiden%20Ni%20-%20TV%20Animation%20Senkaiden%20Houshin%20Engi%20Yori%20%28Japan%29.zip" sha1="DF9E831842072D9AF613EFFBEE7162229849DE58" size="1477034" />
		<title_clean>Senkaiden Ni - TV Animation Senkaiden Houshin Engi Yori</title_clean>
		<releasedate>21/12/2000</releasedate>
		<year>2000</year>
		<genre>RPG</genre>
		<nplayers>1</nplayers>
		<thegamesdb_id>34145</thegamesdb_id>
		<boxart1>EgC40SO.jpg</boxart1>
		<snapshot1>VVldUWM.png</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>W0rq1rJ.jpg</snapshot2>
	</game>
	<game name="Shaman King - Asu e no Ishi (Japan) (v1.1)">
		<description>Shaman King - Asu e no Ishi (Japan) (v1.1)</description>
		<rom crc="34908CB4" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan%20Color.zip/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan%20Color%2FShaman%20King%20-%20Asu%20e%20no%20Ishi%20%28Japan%29%20%28v1.1%29.zip" sha1="473195666A633573C777D3BE98D7E8F46569C84B" size="1031128" />
		<title_clean>Shaman King - Asu e no Ishi</title_clean>
		<plot>Shaman King: Asu e no Ishi is an Action Adventure game, developed by Graphic Research and published by Bandai, which was released in Japan in 2002.</plot>
		<releasedate>29/8/2002</releasedate>
		<year>2002</year>
		<genre>Action, Adventure</genre>
		<nplayers>1</nplayers>
		<thegamesdb_id>27757</thegamesdb_id>
		<giantbomb_url>https://www.giantbomb.com/shaman-king-mirai-no-ishi/3030-26606/</giantbomb_url>
		<boxart1>u9DRJHq.jpg</boxart1>
		<snapshot1>zIm1mFf.png</snapshot1>
	</game>
	<game name="Shaman King - Asu e no Ishi (Japan)">
		<description>Shaman King - Asu e no Ishi (Japan)</description>
		<rom crc="6C029674" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan%20Color.zip/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan%20Color%2FShaman%20King%20-%20Asu%20e%20no%20Ishi%20%28Japan%29.zip" sha1="1E735D1E83A7BFA06C5C717C7E8A386D55A8E3F0" size="1030793" />
		<title_clean>Shaman King - Asu e no Ishi</title_clean>
		<plot>Shaman King: Asu e no Ishi is an Action Adventure game, developed by Graphic Research and published by Bandai, which was released in Japan in 2002.</plot>
		<releasedate>29/8/2002</releasedate>
		<year>2002</year>
		<genre>Action, Adventure</genre>
		<nplayers>1</nplayers>
		<thegamesdb_id>27757</thegamesdb_id>
		<giantbomb_url>https://www.giantbomb.com/shaman-king-mirai-no-ishi/3030-26606/</giantbomb_url>
		<boxart1>2Ynqqzf.jpg</boxart1>
		<snapshot1>zIm1mFf.png</snapshot1>
	</game>
	<game name="Sorobang (Japan)">
		<description>Sorobang (Japan)</description>
		<rom crc="0E467D97" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan%20Color.zip/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan%20Color%2FSorobang%20%28Japan%29.zip" sha1="983582FE8D18839DF30B6D29FB75780A9E32F4EC" size="150997" />
		<title_clean>Sorobang</title_clean>
		<snapshot1>XtKaO2o.png</snapshot1>
	</game>
	<game name="Star Hearts - Hoshi to Daichi no Shisha (Japan)">
		<description>Star Hearts - Hoshi to Daichi no Shisha (Japan)</description>
		<rom crc="138D1018" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan%20Color.zip/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan%20Color%2FStar%20Hearts%20-%20Hoshi%20to%20Daichi%20no%20Shisha%20%28Japan%29.zip" sha1="2B2C2A0566646156BCDDE2A00B728C5B8218AA23" size="1574207" />
		<title_clean>Star Hearts - Hoshi to Daichi no Shisha</title_clean>
		<plot>Star Hearts: Hoshi to Daichi no Shisha is a Role-Playing game, developed and published by Bandai, which was released in Japan in 2001.</plot>
		<releasedate>27/9/2001</releasedate>
		<year>2001</year>
		<genre>Action, RPG</genre>
		<studio>Bandai Co.</studio>
		<nplayers>1</nplayers>
		<videoid>Cyi9jU8gR-8</videoid>
		<thegamesdb_id>27761</thegamesdb_id>
		<mobygames_url>https://www.mobygames.com/game/wonderswan-color/star-hearts-hoshi-to-daichi-no-shisha</mobygames_url>
		<boxart1>6zRUUAW.jpg</boxart1>
		<boxart2>vvOSywY.jpg</boxart2>
		<boxart3>wNaRYV2.jpg</boxart3>
		<snapshot1>xx3yukC.png</snapshot1>
	</game>
	<game name="Star Hearts - Hoshi to Daichi no Shisha - Taikenban (Japan)">
		<description>Star Hearts - Hoshi to Daichi no Shisha - Taikenban (Japan)</description>
		<rom crc="9874E9A2" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan%20Color.zip/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan%20Color%2FStar%20Hearts%20-%20Hoshi%20to%20Daichi%20no%20Shisha%20-%20Taikenban%20%28Japan%29.zip" sha1="44940AE0140DF1BD91D742A166C459DF1B6C2339" size="1488136" />
		<title_clean>Star Hearts - Hoshi to Daichi no Shisha - Taikenban</title_clean>
		<snapshot1>VGrKFss.png</snapshot1>
	</game>
	<game name="Super Robot Taisen Compact 3 (Japan) (v1.5)">
		<description>Super Robot Taisen Compact 3 (Japan) (v1.5)</description>
		<rom crc="6918C824" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan%20Color.zip/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan%20Color%2FSuper%20Robot%20Taisen%20Compact%203%20%28Japan%29%20%28v1.5%29.zip" sha1="B579F204BE604EBEF4E8238E5883152B70399C4D" size="3688926" />
		<title_clean>Super Robot Taisen Compact 3</title_clean>
		<plot>[CR][B]Overview:[/B][CR]Super Robot Wars Compact 3 was the last SRW to be released on the WonderSwan line of handhelds, and is the only game in the series that exclusively appears on the Wonderswan Color. While elements of       Super Robot Wars F and      F Final remain (the Limit stat, lower HP values, visual style,     Londo Bell as the protagonist team), Compact 3's gameplay is influenced by    Super Robot Wars R,   Original Generation, and  Alpha 2; the ability to skip battle animations and the ability to purchase pilot skills are two of the many changes introduced.   The game has no outer space missions whatsoever; this may be due to the presence of The Vision of Escaflowne. Aside from the debuting series, every anime series included in Compact 3 was featured in the previous Compact games. New Story of Aura Battler Dunbine, which provided bonus units for the Dunbine TV characters in previous games, finally has its story utilized in Compact 3; it, along with The Vision of Escaflowne, is used to create a very fantasy-based setting. Mechander Robo is a 70s Super Robot series, while Betterman is more of a horror series then a proper robot anime.[CR][B]Story:[/B][CR]The Earth was nearing what seemed to be the end of a long, painful war. Dr. Hell, the Mikene Empire, the Hyakki Empire, Neo Zeon, and the Organization of the Zodiac have all been defeated, with the Cambellians and the Titans on the verge of destruction.However, the Earth Federation cuts back at the very last minute: the Argama is forced to finish off the Titans remnants on its own, while the Super Robot teams are left to deal with the remains of their respective enemies without assistance. Because of this, a half year passes with little-to-no progress being made against completely destroying the various factions.Little do they know that a new war is about to begin...[CR]Featured Series[CR] A list of the anime series which are featured in the game. Series that premiered in the Super Robot Wars series in this game are marked with "(new)".Mobile Suit Zeta Gundam Mobile Suit Gundam ZZ Mobile Suit Gundam: Char's Counterattack New Mobile Report Gundam Wing: Endless Waltz Mazinger Z Great Mazinger Getter Robo G Shin Getter Robo (manga version) Super Electromagnetic Robot Combattler V Combining Squadron Mechander Robo (new) Acrobunch (new) Aura Battler Dunbine New Story of Aura Battler Dunbine (storyline debut) The Vision of Escaflowne (new) Betterman (new) Banpresto Originals (original characters created for the game) [CR]New Features[CR]End-of-Mission PP System. Based on the player's performance during a mission, extra PP can be distributed to surviving pilots at the end of the scenario.[CR]</plot>
		<releasedate>17/7/2003</releasedate>
		<year>2003</year>
		<genre>Strategy</genre>
		<nplayers>1</nplayers>
		<thegamesdb_id>27762</thegamesdb_id>
		<giantbomb_url>https://www.giantbomb.com/super-robot-wars-compact-3/3030-23046/</giantbomb_url>
		<boxart1>XU8IqQl.jpg</boxart1>
		<snapshot1>a8v3ECc.png</snapshot1>
	</game>
	<game name="Super Robot Taisen Compact 3 (Japan) (v1.6)">
		<description>Super Robot Taisen Compact 3 (Japan) (v1.6)</description>
		<rom crc="188CA644" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan%20Color.zip/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan%20Color%2FSuper%20Robot%20Taisen%20Compact%203%20%28Japan%29%20%28v1.6%29.zip" sha1="DD6FE0F278CDEC2670D3BE8552DBB0CF6A3A2841" size="3688964" />
		<title_clean>Super Robot Taisen Compact 3</title_clean>
		<plot>[CR][B]Overview:[/B][CR]Super Robot Wars Compact 3 was the last SRW to be released on the WonderSwan line of handhelds, and is the only game in the series that exclusively appears on the Wonderswan Color. While elements of       Super Robot Wars F and      F Final remain (the Limit stat, lower HP values, visual style,     Londo Bell as the protagonist team), Compact 3's gameplay is influenced by    Super Robot Wars R,   Original Generation, and  Alpha 2; the ability to skip battle animations and the ability to purchase pilot skills are two of the many changes introduced.   The game has no outer space missions whatsoever; this may be due to the presence of The Vision of Escaflowne. Aside from the debuting series, every anime series included in Compact 3 was featured in the previous Compact games. New Story of Aura Battler Dunbine, which provided bonus units for the Dunbine TV characters in previous games, finally has its story utilized in Compact 3; it, along with The Vision of Escaflowne, is used to create a very fantasy-based setting. Mechander Robo is a 70s Super Robot series, while Betterman is more of a horror series then a proper robot anime.[CR][B]Story:[/B][CR]The Earth was nearing what seemed to be the end of a long, painful war. Dr. Hell, the Mikene Empire, the Hyakki Empire, Neo Zeon, and the Organization of the Zodiac have all been defeated, with the Cambellians and the Titans on the verge of destruction.However, the Earth Federation cuts back at the very last minute: the Argama is forced to finish off the Titans remnants on its own, while the Super Robot teams are left to deal with the remains of their respective enemies without assistance. Because of this, a half year passes with little-to-no progress being made against completely destroying the various factions.Little do they know that a new war is about to begin...[CR]Featured Series[CR] A list of the anime series which are featured in the game. Series that premiered in the Super Robot Wars series in this game are marked with "(new)".Mobile Suit Zeta Gundam Mobile Suit Gundam ZZ Mobile Suit Gundam: Char's Counterattack New Mobile Report Gundam Wing: Endless Waltz Mazinger Z Great Mazinger Getter Robo G Shin Getter Robo (manga version) Super Electromagnetic Robot Combattler V Combining Squadron Mechander Robo (new) Acrobunch (new) Aura Battler Dunbine New Story of Aura Battler Dunbine (storyline debut) The Vision of Escaflowne (new) Betterman (new) Banpresto Originals (original characters created for the game) [CR]New Features[CR]End-of-Mission PP System. Based on the player's performance during a mission, extra PP can be distributed to surviving pilots at the end of the scenario.[CR]</plot>
		<releasedate>17/7/2003</releasedate>
		<year>2003</year>
		<genre>Strategy</genre>
		<nplayers>1</nplayers>
		<thegamesdb_id>27762</thegamesdb_id>
		<giantbomb_url>https://www.giantbomb.com/super-robot-wars-compact-3/3030-23046/</giantbomb_url>
		<boxart1>ejfNAq1.jpg</boxart1>
		<snapshot1>a8v3ECc.png</snapshot1>
	</game>
	<game name="Super Robot Taisen Compact for WonderSwan Color (Japan)">
		<description>Super Robot Taisen Compact for WonderSwan Color (Japan)</description>
		<rom crc="16E0D929" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan%20Color.zip/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan%20Color%2FSuper%20Robot%20Taisen%20Compact%20for%20WonderSwan%20Color%20%28Japan%29.zip" sha1="BF212CECBBC51EE32EE2655A072F55E7BF70B9EC" size="1666884" />
		<title_clean>Super Robot Taisen Compact for WonderSwan Color</title_clean>
		<plot>[CR][B]Story:[/B][CR]With the brewing conflict between Oldtypes and Newtypes, Dr. Souzou Haran decided to usher in the next step in human evolution by way of the Meganoids. However, his experiment went terribly wrong, as two Meganoids (Zauser and Koros) destroyed Dr. Haran's Martian laboratory. Seeking to expand the Meganoid project, the two declared war on Earth. At the same time, the Muge Empire would stage an invasion, resulting in mass chaos. Luckily, the White Base (with cooperation from the Photon Power Plant, Saotome Research Institute, and Dancougar) would push back the invaders, causing them to scatter across space.One year later, just as Dr. Haran predicted, conflict between Earth Federation and the space-based Principality of Zeon broke out, resulting in the One Year War. The members of the White Base team would be renamed Londo Bell, and would be given the task of defending the Earth.Elsewhere, the aliens from Planet Barm have lost their homeland, and now plot to make the Earth their own...[CR]Featured Series[CR]A list of the anime series which are featured in the game. Super Robot Wars Compact introduced no new series.Mobile Suit Gundam Mobile Suit Gundam 0080: War in the Pocket Mobile Suit Gundam 0083: Stardust Memory Mobile Suit Zeta Gundam Mobile Suit Gundam ZZ Mobile Suit Gundam: Char's Counterattack Mobile Suit Gundam F91 New Mobile Report Gundam Wing: Endless Waltz Mazinger Z Great Mazinger Getter Robo Getter Robo G Shin Getter Robo (manga version) Brave Raideen Brave Leader Daimos Invincible Steel Man Daitarn 3 Aura Battler Dunbine Heavy Metal L-Gaim Super Beast Machine God Dancougar  [CR]New Features[CR]Select Scenario System. Instead of going through the missions in a predetermined path, the game is set up into several chapters. Each chapter has 3-5 missions that can be chosen in any order, before taking on a final mission that closes out that chapter. This is used in all other Compact games, Impact, and MX.End of Mission Bonus. The game rewards the player a skill based on how many turns it took to clear the stage.[CR]</plot>
		<releasedate>13/12/2001</releasedate>
		<year>2001</year>
		<genre>Strategy</genre>
		<nplayers>1</nplayers>
		<thegamesdb_id>27763</thegamesdb_id>
		<giantbomb_url>https://www.giantbomb.com/super-robot-wars-compact/3030-23090/</giantbomb_url>
		<boxart1>9kS1sn6.jpg</boxart1>
		<snapshot1>AUzixuD.png</snapshot1>
	</game>
	<game name="Terrors 2 (Japan)">
		<description>Terrors 2 (Japan)</description>
		<rom crc="9BD8F08C" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan%20Color.zip/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan%20Color%2FTerrors%202%20%28Japan%29.zip" sha1="9532113E14B03C95F034C015168E21273D42EFF1" size="3078900" />
		<title_clean>Terrors 2</title_clean>
		<plot>Terrors 2 is a interactive text-based story with accompanying images that feature the following Japanese pop stars: Risa Goto, Kaori Manabe, Erika Yamakawa, Nami Ichinohe, Yumi Uehara. The games story is one of horror slowly sneaking into a Japanese school. The plot is revealed through four scenarios. The choices you make in the story will affect the path it takes, as such there are numerous alternate ending to encourage multiple playthroughs. [CR]Terrors 2 could connect to the internet with the WonderGate so that ingame events would take place at the same time of day that the player was experiencing.</plot>
		<releasedate>21/12/2000</releasedate>
		<year>2000</year>
		<genre>Adventure</genre>
		<studio>Bandai Co.</studio>
		<nplayers>1</nplayers>
		<perspective>3rd-Person</perspective>
		<rating>4.0</rating>
		<thegamesdb_id>27764</thegamesdb_id>
		<mobygames_url>https://www.mobygames.com/game/wonderswan-color/terrors-2</mobygames_url>
		<giantbomb_url>https://www.giantbomb.com/terrors-2/3030-18739/</giantbomb_url>
		<boxart1>Op2eHS8.jpg</boxart1>
		<boxart2>sdVsO8l.jpg</boxart2>
		<boxart3>VRr0ZAf.jpg</boxart3>
		<snapshot1>9aeWmdH.png</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>IAsqoqA.jpg</snapshot2>
		<snapshot3>3aJO2DE.jpg</snapshot3>
		<snapshot4>Pfb5CBx.jpg</snapshot4>
		<snapshot5>KQEO4Ub.jpg</snapshot5>
		<snapshot6>DPsTK4z.jpg</snapshot6>
		<snapshot7>I8jkAyv.jpg</snapshot7>
		<snapshot8>F3svfAF.jpg</snapshot8>
		<snapshot9>8sXlcZT.jpg</snapshot9>
		<snapshot10>tf1LeC7.jpg</snapshot10>
	</game>
	<game name="Tetris (Japan)">
		<description>Tetris (Japan)</description>
		<rom crc="7B0CAEA9" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan%20Color.zip/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan%20Color%2FTetris%20%28Japan%29.zip" sha1="1A86403D7896D60FCB7A4C09367F5A976C7EA5A5" size="108518" />
		<title_clean>Tetris</title_clean>
		<plot>[CR][B]Overview:[/B][CR]A screenshot from the 1986 MS-DOS version of Tetris.Tetris was originally created by Alexey Pajitnov, who designed and programmed the game in June 1985 while working in the USSR at the Dorodnicyn Computing Centre of the Academy of Science in Moscow. The name Tetris is a portmanteau of the Greek prefix "tetra", which means "four", and Pajitnov's favorite sport, tennis.[CR][B]Gameplay:[/B][CR]Tetris challenges the player's spatial relation abilities by presenting them with different shapes made of four square blocks. The blocks are presented one at a time at the top of a rectangular play field, and quickly begin descending toward the bottom. The player can rotate the shapes and move them horizontally as they descend, and if you are able to make a complete horizontal line of blocks, that line will clear from the field. In its original form, Tetris was an endurance test, as the speed of the descending shapes would constantly increase as time went on, and the game would end when the play field filled completely with blocks.[CR]Tetris Variants[CR]A number of Tetris variations, both official and otherwise, have been released over the years, including Hatris, Welltris, Super Tetris 2, Tetris Blast and Tetris Attack. Aside from spawning its own spin-offs, Tetris has been highly influential on a large number of puzzle games released in its wake.[CR]IP Rights[CR]The rights to Tetris have been greatly disputed over the years. At one point a British software house named Andromeda was going to purchase the rights, but before the deal with Pajitnov was settled, they sold the rights to Spectrum Holobyte. Even though Andromeda's original deal with Pajitnov fell through, Spectrum Holobyte released what was essentially an unlicensed version of Tetris. After that point the rights began bouncing around, with Atari, Nintendo, the Soviet government, and other entities claiming ownership at various points.[CR]Additional Information[CR]Tetris GiantTetris became even more popular when the game was packaged with the Nintendo Gameboy and helped sell millions of handheld systems.Sega also published a game known as Tetris Giant, the largest licensed Tetris arcade machine.[CR]</plot>
		<releasedate>4/7/2002</releasedate>
		<year>2002</year>
		<genre>Puzzle</genre>
		<studio>Vanguard</studio>
		<nplayers>1</nplayers>
		<thegamesdb_id>27765</thegamesdb_id>
		<mobygames_url>https://www.mobygames.com/game/wonderswan-color/tetriswonderswan</mobygames_url>
		<giantbomb_url>https://www.giantbomb.com/tetris/3030-1896/</giantbomb_url>
		<boxart1>TI5KtKy.jpg</boxart1>
		<boxart2>BbTBPnL.jpg</boxart2>
		<snapshot1>PAVzEY4.png</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>rVLTDTQ.gif</snapshot2>
		<snapshot3>TarzPf8.gif</snapshot3>
		<snapshot4>SfCecGC.gif</snapshot4>
		<snapshot5>NcpuveP.gif</snapshot5>
		<snapshot6>NFdTObk.gif</snapshot6>
		<snapshot7>vqNfeWn.gif</snapshot7>
		<snapshot8>9UhEolO.gif</snapshot8>
		<snapshot9>WFST2MP.gif</snapshot9>
		<snapshot10>CXhMkXw.gif</snapshot10>
	</game>
	<game name="Tonpuusou (Japan)">
		<description>Tonpuusou (Japan)</description>
		<rom crc="47659B2C" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan%20Color.zip/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan%20Color%2FTonpuusou%20%28Japan%29.zip" sha1="FB53C28BD48174D3829467F1AB81D3F87F9A7F5B" size="523555" />
		<title_clean>Tonpuusou</title_clean>
		<releasedate>28/6/2001</releasedate>
		<year>2001</year>
		<genre>Puzzle</genre>
		<nplayers>1-2 Alt</nplayers>
		<thegamesdb_id>31925</thegamesdb_id>
		<boxart1>hhj3Hn2.jpg</boxart1>
		<snapshot1>alA6Lml.png</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>IrLzeUx.jpg</snapshot2>
	</game>
	<game name="Uchuu Senkan Yamato (Japan)">
		<description>Uchuu Senkan Yamato (Japan)</description>
		<rom crc="5793BDDA" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan%20Color.zip/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan%20Color%2FUchuu%20Senkan%20Yamato%20%28Japan%29.zip" sha1="DD1878279A6667FB66DD1AC44A2CDB9A5ACBE415" size="1909588" />
		<title_clean>Uchuu Senkan Yamato</title_clean>
		<plot>Uchuu Senkan Yamato is a Strategy game, developed by Tom Create and published by Bandai Visual, which was released in Japan in 2001.</plot>
		<releasedate>8/2/2001</releasedate>
		<year>2001</year>
		<genre>Strategy</genre>
		<nplayers>1</nplayers>
		<thegamesdb_id>27766</thegamesdb_id>
		<boxart1>TKBm7Mb.jpg</boxart1>
		<snapshot1>DF5LK8M.png</snapshot1>
	</game>
	<game name="Ultraman - Hikari no Kuni no Shisha (Japan)">
		<description>Ultraman - Hikari no Kuni no Shisha (Japan)</description>
		<rom crc="DE2208AB" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan%20Color.zip/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan%20Color%2FUltraman%20-%20Hikari%20no%20Kuni%20no%20Shisha%20%28Japan%29.zip" sha1="BD107BEFE5CE6C5508D2DA8BE351B9984166AE1D" size="1353745" />
		<title_clean>Ultraman - Hikari no Kuni no Shisha</title_clean>
		<plot>Ultraman is a 2D Fighting game, developed and published by Bandai, which was released in Japan in 2001.[CR]https://www.gamefaqs.com/portable/wscolor/home/581502.html[CR]</plot>
		<releasedate>4/7/2001</releasedate>
		<year>2001</year>
		<genre>Fighting</genre>
		<studio>Bandai</studio>
		<thegamesdb_id>19642</thegamesdb_id>
		<giantbomb_url>https://www.giantbomb.com/ultraman-hikari-no-kuni-no-shinja/3030-40741/</giantbomb_url>
		<boxart1>8Xx1eBY.jpg</boxart1>
		<snapshot1>PTdUXUj.png</snapshot1>
	</game>
	<game name="Wild Card (Japan)">
		<description>Wild Card (Japan)</description>
		<rom crc="D9401F0A" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan%20Color.zip/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan%20Color%2FWild%20Card%20%28Japan%29.zip" sha1="EA878A485A20ABD5251065FD66E82D9D8B8A669D" size="1182501" />
		<title_clean>Wild Card</title_clean>
		<plot>Although made by  Square, the famous Japanese RPG developer, "Wild Card" is a game that is very different from classic Asian RPGs. Most importantly, it is not story-driven. The game is based entirely on quests which are not connected by a story arc. You play a nameless character with no background and there is no plot information or development beside your own progress with the quests. The gameplay consists entirely of playing cards. In the beginning of the game, an enigmatic woman named Maria asks you a series of questions, to determine the cards you get. After that, your character begins an adventure in a town. Locations, other characters, inventory, your movement - everything appears in form of cards. To get quests, you must choose your correspondent cards when encountering different people. You can buy weapons and equipment, and also fight enemies in turn-based combat by choosing the cards from your deck. You gain levels and become stronger in a traditional RPG fashion.</plot>
		<releasedate>29/3/2001</releasedate>
		<year>2001</year>
		<genre>Adventure, RPG</genre>
		<studio>Square Co.</studio>
		<nplayers>1</nplayers>
		<perspective>1st-Person</perspective>
		<rating>3.2</rating>
		<thegamesdb_id>27767</thegamesdb_id>
		<mobygames_url>https://www.mobygames.com/game/wonderswan-color/wild-card</mobygames_url>
		<giantbomb_url>https://www.giantbomb.com/wild-card/3030-12421/</giantbomb_url>
		<boxart1>OjQGbok.jpg</boxart1>
		<boxart2>QpcCfkA.jpg</boxart2>
		<boxart3>yMJeU1K.jpg</boxart3>
		<snapshot1>QEFIzS0.png</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>ESQEE59.gif</snapshot2>
		<snapshot3>m9gZg2O.gif</snapshot3>
		<snapshot4>WwNUcOL.gif</snapshot4>
		<snapshot5>l7q4XoM.gif</snapshot5>
		<snapshot6>6oUjiMA.gif</snapshot6>
		<snapshot7>UqQWDlz.gif</snapshot7>
		<snapshot8>PWwb9OD.gif</snapshot8>
		<snapshot9>ui0Dlay.gif</snapshot9>
		<snapshot10>2aogAse.gif</snapshot10>
	</game>
	<game name="With You - Mitsumete Itai (Japan)">
		<description>With You - Mitsumete Itai (Japan)</description>
		<rom crc="E14E9D36" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan%20Color.zip/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan%20Color%2FWith%20You%20-%20Mitsumete%20Itai%20%28Japan%29.zip" sha1="6A4F4A03C367CCF00AA7462191C929A2736EB44B" size="1785978" />
		<title_clean>With You - Mitsumete Itai</title_clean>
		<plot>With You is an adventure game with static graphics, in which the game advances as you choose what to do from a list of possible actions. Long time ago, a man and a woman made a promise, stating that although they were destined to be lonely souls, they should always remain together. But by a cruel joke of fate, they were separated and sealed into two jewels that were hidden for generations. Manami, who left the country 6 years before, has found one of the jewels while traveling. He will return to Japan to meet with their friends from childhood. This will entail a meeting of the two jewels again, for the second jewel seems to be owned by his father.</plot>
		<releasedate>25/1/2001</releasedate>
		<year>2001</year>
		<genre>Adventure</genre>
		<studio>Shall Luck</studio>
		<nplayers>1</nplayers>
		<perspective>1st-Person</perspective>
		<rating>2.3</rating>
		<thegamesdb_id>27769</thegamesdb_id>
		<mobygames_url>https://www.mobygames.com/game/wonderswan-color/with-you-mitsumete-itai</mobygames_url>
		<giantbomb_url>https://www.giantbomb.com/with-you-mitsumete-itai/3030-441/</giantbomb_url>
		<boxart1>WBasNZh.jpg</boxart1>
		<boxart2>OqSy91h.jpg</boxart2>
		<boxart3>OQgIUFn.jpg</boxart3>
		<snapshot1>6MDW3hd.png</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>Y8fid76.png</snapshot2>
		<snapshot3>T6UjVKb.gif</snapshot3>
		<snapshot4>gIWxAZh.gif</snapshot4>
		<snapshot5>UlRr8Tj.gif</snapshot5>
		<snapshot6>Ru8bNJD.gif</snapshot6>
		<snapshot7>S3VVfaD.gif</snapshot7>
		<snapshot8>jq2d2GB.gif</snapshot8>
		<snapshot9>vatXlXN.gif</snapshot9>
	</game>
	<game name="Wizardry Scenario 1 - Proving Grounds of the Mad Overlord (Japan)">
		<description>Wizardry Scenario 1 - Proving Grounds of the Mad Overlord (Japan)</description>
		<rom crc="15E55706" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan%20Color.zip/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan%20Color%2FWizardry%20Scenario%201%20-%20Proving%20Grounds%20of%20the%20Mad%20Overlord%20%28Japan%29.zip" sha1="C1AD383D337DBA8A63295CFB8C7CA8470C893C67" size="525200" />
		<title_clean>Wizardry Scenario 1 - Proving Grounds of the Mad Overlord</title_clean>
		<plot>[CR][B]Overview:[/B] [CR]   Wizardry is a first-person,                       grid-based,  RPG that had helped to set many standards within the PC-RPG genre with its graphical interface and gameplay mechanics. It is regarded as the first true party-based RPG for computers and one of the first to feature a game system styled after TSR's Dungeons and Dragons. At the time, its graphical capabilities and gameplay mechanics were considered revolutionary and innovative for PCs. After assembling their party of adventurers, the player will confront many challenges and puzzles as they attempt to penetrate the dangers surrounding the ten-level Maze. The gameplay style of the title has been compared to that of a dungeon crawl in which players simply fight monsters for experience, treasure, and the necessary equipment to deal with the wizard, Werdna.The relatively simple and clear interface is organized around a series of commands and actions listed at the bottom of the screen as well as a combined inventory and statistics screen. Completing Wizardry was required if the player wished to transfer characters into the next two sequels,    Wizardry II: Knight of Diamonds and   Wizardry III: Legacy of Llylgamyn.  Among the other features of the game were: Over 50 spells were available for casting4 basic classes to choose from and four elite classes to upgrade to5 races to create classes with The game did not have any copy protection and creating  a Scenario Diskette was needed in order the game on. The CD-ROM version of the game automatically circumvented this by creating one on the drive when installed.  The manual was also noteworthy for being written in a way that made Wizardry appear appealing to newcomers with little to no experience with an RPG. Illustrated with humorous drawings and a great deal of detail worked into its text. A section walked a player through a fictional scenario that might occur within the game while explaining its concepts with several examples.[CR][B]Story:[/B][CR]   Wizardry's story is firmly rooted within fantasy and is considered the first module in a set of four that would end with  Wizardry IV: The Return of Werdna.  The Land of Llylgamyn is the home to many legends. It is considered the center of commerce and the home of an academy where the bravest would train themselves. It was ruled by a monarchy with a royal family, but as time passed, power shifted to the aristocrats and the theocrats and eventually, the royal family became a symbol of the land than a central source of power.  Under a more democratic system, the High Council of Sages appointed an overlord to govern over the kingdom, eliminating any power that hte royal family had left. The Overlord, Trebor, was a former warrior and a local hero. He governed wisely at first, but his thirst for power eventually led him to search for ways in which to expand his power. Eventually, through unknown means, he discovered the existence of an ancient amulet kept in a forgotten temple outside of the kingdom.  According to legend, it had great powers that were the stuff that legends were made of. Founding an expedition, he sent his best men out to find the temple and retrieve the amulet which they did with much success.  But only hours after the party had retrieved the amulet, an evil wizard named Werdna had follows his own trail to the amulet only to find it gone. Werdna, Trebor's arch-nemesis, was infuriated that someone had gotten to it first and using his considerable talents, used magic to discover who it was. When he found that it was Trebor, he plotted and schemed of a way to steal the amulet away.   As Trebor and a group of sages sat in his throne room studying the amulet, a great terror suddenly froze them cold as if the shadow of death has passed across their faces. When they came to, they discovered that his amulet was gone. Werdna knew that once they had recovered their senses, they would immediately cast their suspicions towards him. He couldn't return to his tower and wait for them to come for him anyway, so he needed a new place in which to hide. He decided on a bold plan. Werdna decided to use the amulet to make a new home right beneath the city of Llylgamym itself!  There was enough underground mining activity already and he should be able to go unnoticed within its depths. Upon the thought of this plan, the amulet began to glow. Suddenly, a tremendous earthquake shook the area and Werdna suddenly found himself within a giant, ten-level labyrinth in the ground below the city. Summoning monsters as allies, he made his way to the lowest levels where he could study the powers of the amulet undisturbed. In away, he also felt that he was secretly taunting his arch-nemesis by hiding right beneath his very nose with the object of his desire.    Trebor became unhinged at losing the amulet and surrounded himself with an elite guard of the best characters from each class all the while plotting to get his amulet back. He knew that the underground Maze was where his enemy had fled, but he could not get to him even with the best at his command. A year following his discovery of the Maze, he had managed to secure the first four floors. Most of the warriors that went deeper, however, never returned.  Trebor ordered the the passages to the deeper areas of the Maze sealed thus preventing the creatures there from finding their way to the surface. He also ordered that traps be set in the first three levels. Once all of this was done, he declared the Maze a Proving Ground for new cadets at the academy to prove their worth in the hopes of becoming one of the Elite guards. Trebor further sweetened the pot by saying that upon discovering the 'secret prize' at the lowest levels of the Maze. Those that survived their way down to the fourth level would be told the real reason for the Maze and the traps. The first four levels were only a test to see if those that survived were worthy of taking on the final challenges past them. It was then that they were told of Werdna and the amulet and be given permission to head deeper into the dungeon. Any adventurers who did recover the amulet would be inducted into his Elite guard, even by force if it comes to that. This is the situation that the player's party will find themselves in and it is from Trebor's castle that they will start their journey.  A journal entry from an adventurer named Hawkwind has also set the tone for the adventure to follow as he relates the story of his party getting ready to invade the the lower levels of the dungeon. He goes on to describe the pleasures that each of his party dream about in succeeding with their quest.   The journal describes how they made their way through zigzagging corridors down to the lower levels, suddenly discovering a secret door. Kicking it open, they enter the room and engage in battle against a myriad number of terrible beasts: hellhouds, demons, and even creeping coins. They fight their best, shaking the walls, and with a combination of hard steel and fantastic magic, destroy the enemy.   In the terrible battle, they discover a chute leading down into the bowels of the dungeon to the final level, setting the stage for the characters to do the same.  Ultimately, an unlikely group of characters prove themselves worthy of the challenge and manage to find their way down into the final level, confronting Werdna, and seizing back the amulet. As a reward, Trebor makes them Elite Guards and awards them a chevron for their troubles along with quite a prize in treasure.[CR][B]Gameplay:[/B][CR]   Wizardry is a tile, or                                             grid based movement, first-person RPG starting out within the Castle that serves as the base for party management and the Maze in which the adventure takes place. Party size is limited to six members, although smaller parties are even allowed but not suggested for survival. The player must find penetrate the dangers and mysteries of the Maze in order to seize a magical amulet held by the evil wizard, Werdna. But, in order to do, the party must also negotiate the Maze and deal with its dangerous inhabitants as well as solve the puzzles that stand in their way. The Maze comprises the central theater for the adventure and is comprised of several levels, each with its own distinct dangers and puzzles to solve. The lack of an automap  means that the player is required to draw his or her own maps or otherwise rely on unofficial game guides and walkthroughs in order to navigate the mazelike multi-level dungeon.  Saves could only be made anywhere, but Wizardry's setup on PCs had an additional side-benefit to doing so. It would allow players to quick-save their progress and quit out of the scenario and if they chose to start at the Castle with a fresh party, they could wander back into the Maze and even encounter their old party where they had left them. This was also treated as a backup in case of PC failure. The party would be marked as OUT until the player decided to restart the group or create another party of adventurers and headed down to find them. Levels were earned after gaining the requisite experience as well as resting at the Inn back at the Castle. It was possible to continue adventuring well after the previous experience limit was met and earning several levels at once after a restful stay at the Inn.  The CastleThis was the central location for the player's management options concerning their party. Here, several locations were available by hotkey: Gilgamesh's Tavern - A dim and smoke filled place with a perpetual haunch of boar roasting over the fire, small groups of adventurers congregate here discussing their latest exploits or hoping to join a party. This is where the player will build their party from characters they create.Adventurer's Inn - Rest is offered as long as the party can afford their stay. Several different rooms are provided ranging from the Stables to a Royal Suite, each with their own rate of healing. This is also where resting characters can level up once they have the requisite experience.Temple of Cant - More severe ailments are handled here, again for the right 'donation'. Paralysis, poison, and even the dead can be brought back to a sense of normalcy after enough coins are shared with the faithful. Boltac's Trading Post - A friendly dwarf named Boltac operates this in the Castle's market area, providing his services to anyone that can afford them. Arms, goods, and even his experience in identifying certain items can all be purchased with the right coin. The party can even sell their ill gotten gains here to free up their pockets for even more loot that they might come across. Boltac can even remove cursed items, although the party will also lose the item once it's "uncursed."Edge of Town - From here, the party can visit the Training Grounds, enter the Maze, or head back to the Castle.The Maze - Many adventurers seeking fame, glory, and experience eagerly dive into the dangers of the Maze otherwise known as the Proving Grounds of the Mad Overlord.Training Grounds - New characters are created here and players can also inspect older characters to see if they need a few changes of their own. Picking Locks and Disarming Traps There were no locks to pick in the game. Disarming traps, on the other hand, on treasure chests, was much more different. A character with the proper skill could inspect the chest and determine what kind of trap was on it. Once they made their assessment, it was up to the player to disarm the trap by opting to do so and then typing the trap's name in. If they are correct, the trap is disarmed. Spells could also be used to help disarm chests. CampingThis command allowed the party to camp out in the middle of the dungeon. This also enabled the player to inspect their party members and also re-order their party's marching order. This also allows the player to equip their entire party at once if they so choose. [CR]Character Development[CR]The player can opt to start with the batch of pre-made character provided for them by the game or create their own.  AgeCharacters can actually age in Wizardry V if they rest too much. Resting at the Inn can last anywhere from a single day to a year depending on how much gold you have in reserve. Resting replenishes a party's health and stamina, readying them for the road ahead, but rest enough times and a character will start to age. But when they first start out in the game, they are at an extremely young age. Death by old age is hardly expected, but it is a possibility.  Classes   The character classes belong to one of two categories; Base or Elite. Base classes (Fighter, Mage, Priest, Thief) are often considered the 'starting' class for a character whereas Elite classes (Lord, Bishop, Samurai, Lord, Ninja) typically benefit from having better fighting skills and eventual proficiency in magic. The initial statistics requirements for Elite classes are noticably higher than for the Base classes, making the former much more difficult to create at the start of the game.   As with quite a few RPGs, Wizardry includes the option to change character class during the course of the game at the Training Grounds when inspecting a character. The incentives to do so in Wizardry are comparatively strong as many abilities are retained from the original classes, and since characters who recently changed classes during mid-game can often gain levels rapidly (thus enabling the player to raise skill points and fill out spell books much faster than would otherwise have been possibly).    Alignment largely determines what kind of class a particular character can be. The four basic classes are:Fighter - High hit points and experts at using any weapon and piece of armor, they are a grounded class that can dish out the damage as well as take it. Thief - No party is complete without a competent thief to help disarm traps. While they aren't the greatest of fighters, they rely on their sneakiness to backstab their enemies.Priest - Long known as skilled healers, their talents are important for any party heading out into danger. They cannot be of neutral alignment.Mage - The classic wizard. As they become more powerful, their spellbooks will continue to add many new pages filled with deadly spells.  The four elite classes are: Bishop - Like a Priest, they are able to heal their friends and dispel the undead. They are also able to uncurse items that become permanently stuck to a character, freeing them. They can also learn any spell from any of the other schools. The downside is that their learning rate is also a bit slower, so the selection of spells that they may have will take more time to develop. But they can identify items without fear of being cursed. They must not be neutral.Samurai - A true swordsman. At the fourth level of experience, they begin to learn Mage spells. They cannot be of evil alignment because of their adherence to the code of Bushido.Lord - Skilled as a fighter as well as being pious enough to cast a few spells, they are likened to paladins and crusader knights. They start learning priestly spells around the fourth level of experience. They can also only be of good alignment.Ninja - An assassin and a rogue, they can kill with weapons or their bare hands, sometimes being able to kill the strongest enemy with a single blow. They disdain armor and become far harder to hit and tougher to kill as they gain levels. They also have all of the skills of thief and are able to disarm traps. They can also hide in shadows and ambush enemies. They must also be of evil alignment. RacesThe races include familiar fantasy characters such as the Elf, the Dwarf, the Gnome and the Hobbit.Humans - Balanced without any serious flaws, a good, even keeled race that can belong and excel at any profession.Elf - They excel at the intellectual classes, such as Mages, or Bishops. Keenly interested in study.Dwarf - Gruff, short in stature, but tough and reliable, dwarves make excellent Fighters while their piety can also find them a career as a Priest.Gnomes - Found underground and often overlooked by the larger races, their quiet and studious nature make them ideal as Mages or Priests.Hobbit - Friendly, nimble, and otherwise unassuming, they make surprisingly decent Ninja, Samurai, or Thieves.Statistics Attribute scores had a maximum value of 18 and determined a variety of effects and class eligibility requirements. Many of these attributes were particularly important across many classes across a variety of skills. Characters can improve their attributes thanks to the investment of points earned with every level.  Strength - Determines how much damage a character can lay into a monster as well as how much weight they can carry around with them. It also affects certain weapon skills and plays into staminaI.Q. - Important for spellcasters.Piety - This is important for a character's ability to concentrate on the task at hand. It also affects how many spells a character may be able to learn and their effectiveness with them.Vitality - Very important for hit points, the chance for resurrection, the ability to resist damage and disease, and general health.Luck - Ambiguous but it also has mysterious effects on many other factorsAs with many RPGs, character development was driven by experience points which translated into levels. When a character gains a level after resting an an inn: Spellcasters may be able to learn a new spellDepending on their statistics, a character may even change their classHit points will also improve [CR]Combat[CR]   Combat in Wizardry was a turn based affair with random encounters providing the cannon fodder that would feed the party's thirst for experience points.  When enemies encountered the party, a list of enemies along with a picture showing what they were onscreen would appear.   Similar to other RPGs of the era, its strict turn-based system halts the passage of time until the player performs an action (such as moving around or casting spells). In combat, the order in which characters act is determined primarily by their statistics, although the player issues orders to every character in the party before commencing a turn. Besides using melee and/or ranged weapons and casting spells, characters with the appropriate skills can hide (which means enemies cannot hurt them), use items in their inventory, equip new weapons or items or try to run away from battle which, if successful, results in the entire party fleeing from the enemies. It is not possible to save the game or restore a saved game while in combat mode, but there are no other restrictions on when and where the player can save the game.  In each round of combat, everyone makes their selection of actions as the game calculates who will have initiative and then executing their orders.[CR]</plot>
		<releasedate>1/3/2001</releasedate>
		<year>2001</year>
		<genre>RPG</genre>
		<nplayers>1</nplayers>
		<thegamesdb_id>27770</thegamesdb_id>
		<giantbomb_url>https://www.giantbomb.com/wizardry-proving-grounds-of-the-mad-overlord/3030-9180/</giantbomb_url>
		<boxart1>4wM5nlC.jpg</boxart1>
		<boxart2>dPVG53Q.jpg</boxart2>
		<snapshot1>l2bgYh4.png</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>rteJVKw.jpg</snapshot2>
		<snapshot3>zizVBKR.jpg</snapshot3>
		<snapshot4>rJ1INkg.jpg</snapshot4>
		<snapshot5>p5zN3Cr.jpg</snapshot5>
		<snapshot6>Lnn2lhu.jpg</snapshot6>
		<snapshot7>P8r8JSs.jpg</snapshot7>
		<snapshot8>r5Rwosi.jpg</snapshot8>
		<snapshot9>geKjGWo.jpg</snapshot9>
	</game>
	<game name="Wonder Classic (Japan)">
		<description>Wonder Classic (Japan)</description>
		<rom crc="12F10B27" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan%20Color.zip/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan%20Color%2FWonder%20Classic%20%28Japan%29.zip" sha1="55B54944EFD6E277FA7140925ED2457A8CFB40B8" size="1293489" />
		<title_clean>Wonder Classic</title_clean>
		<plot>Wonder Classic is a golfing game where you will use different characters with specific abilities to your advantage. For example the character, Reiko Nagase nullifies the effects of wind, most others have certain benefits to certain types of shot. There are two starting characters and twenty-two unlockable and downloadable characters.[CR]The game consists of the following modes:[CR]1. Training: play whatever field you like as long as you like.[CR]2. Character Get: you'll challenge your way through ten golfers, after you beat them you'll be able to play as them elsewhere in the game[CR]3. Stroke: play against the score[CR]4. Match: play by hole, each time golfer gets a hole he will go "1UP" while his opponent will go "1DOWN". Whoever is "UP" in the end wins. If the "DOWN" player cannot win given the number of remaining holes then the game will end.[CR]5. Mini Battle: Driving Contest: a match contest where the golfers will only drive.[CR]6. Mini Battle: Near-Pin: a match contest that will involve only shots near the pin.[CR]7. Mini Course: you play on a 3-par 9 hole course, you may play against a computer if you so wish.[CR]8. Tour: 32 contestants enter the tour, who will win? You'll have to hone your Wonder Classic golfing skills to best this. Winning in tour mode will unlock new courses.[CR]9. Net Tour: this mode will allow you the download the best 32 Tour scores that have been uploaded via the WonderGate. And then play a tour against those people, not the real people but against their scores, in a tour. You can also upload you own scores to compare them online.[CR]The gameplay of Wonder Classic includes the ability to use the Y-buttons to augment just how your club will come in contact with the ball, to subtlety alter its trajectory. You'll also have six "Power Shots" which will have to be carefully conserved in each match.[CR]Using the WonderGate you could get new clubs as well as stat altering equipment, such as gloves. You also could get new characters and courses through the WonderGate as well. This feature also allowed you to see your score as part of a "global" ranking.</plot>
		<releasedate>18/1/2001</releasedate>
		<year>2001</year>
		<studio>Bandai Co.</studio>
		<nplayers>1</nplayers>
		<rating>2.4</rating>
		<thegamesdb_id>19643</thegamesdb_id>
		<mobygames_url>https://www.mobygames.com/game/wonderswan-color/wonder-classic</mobygames_url>
		<giantbomb_url>https://www.giantbomb.com/wonder-classic/3030-6512/</giantbomb_url>
		<boxart1>4bVJsE8.jpg</boxart1>
		<boxart2>9Sl5Vxt.jpg</boxart2>
		<boxart3>WPcz2qm.jpg</boxart3>
		<snapshot1>2s5m3mf.png</snapshot1>
		<snapshot2>4XYhgSY.png</snapshot2>
		<snapshot3>bP3RkIw.png</snapshot3>
		<snapshot4>pbcz9hR.png</snapshot4>
		<snapshot5>fIEwsLP.png</snapshot5>
		<snapshot6>RsFdLtH.png</snapshot6>
		<snapshot7>9bheDRZ.png</snapshot7>
		<snapshot8>w9FMKdS.png</snapshot8>
		<snapshot9>viovWzQ.png</snapshot9>
		<snapshot10>uPCWHj1.png</snapshot10>
	</game>
	<game name="X - Card of Fate (Japan)">
		<description>X - Card of Fate (Japan)</description>
		<rom crc="66B617D5" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan%20Color.zip/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan%20Color%2FX%20-%20Card%20of%20Fate%20%28Japan%29.zip" sha1="C1AB4E24F261615CA59F937B866FCF7047B67796" size="2435701" />
		<title_clean>X - Card of Fate</title_clean>
		<plot>X: Card of Fate is a Strategy game, developed by Access and published by Bandai, which was released in Japan in 2002.</plot>
		<releasedate>27/6/2002</releasedate>
		<year>2002</year>
		<genre>Strategy</genre>
		<nplayers>1-2 Alt</nplayers>
		<thegamesdb_id>27768</thegamesdb_id>
		<giantbomb_url>https://www.giantbomb.com/x-card-of-fate/3030-52768/</giantbomb_url>
		<boxart1>PSqdBny.jpg</boxart1>
		<snapshot1>HhQ6b9R.png</snapshot1>
	</game>
	<game name="XI Little (Japan)">
		<description>XI Little (Japan)</description>
		<rom crc="25E2BA75" name="No-Intro-Collection_2015-03-03/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan%20Color.zip/Bandai%20-%20WonderSwan%20Color%2FXI%20Little%20%28Japan%29.zip" sha1="97C29917A78918A6905FD61A1466971CFD2A33C6" size="921332" />
		<title_clean>XI Little</title_clean>
		<plot>XI (sai) Little is a Puzzle game, developed by MBI and published by Bandai, which was released in Japan in 2001.</plot>
		<releasedate>20/12/2001</releasedate>
		<year>2001</year>
		<genre>Puzzle</genre>
		<nplayers>1-2 Alt</nplayers>
		<thegamesdb_id>27771</thegamesdb_id>
		<boxart1>ULjc8qX.jpg</boxart1>
		<snapshot1>RmIeDj7.png</snapshot1>
	</game>
</datafile>